<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>News - Followin</title><link>https://followin.io/en/news</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/followin/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>News - Followin - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://followin.io/favicon.ico</url><title>News - Followin</title><link>https://followin.io/en/news</link></image><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:22:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>The Fed slashed its 2025 growth forecast while raising its inflation forecast</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/a104735a013dbb53abcce4faac1947b5.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PANews reported on March 20 that according to Tonghuashun Finance, the Federal Reserve FOMC economic forecast shows that the median GDP growth forecast for the end of 2025 to 2027 is 1.7%, 1.8%, and 1.8%, respectively, and the forecasts in December are 2.1%, 2.0%, and 1.9%, respectively. The median forecasts for the federal funds rate from 2025 to 2027 are 3.9%, 3.4%, and 3.1%, respectively, and the forecasts in December are 3.9%, 3.4%, and 3.1%, respectively. The median forecasts for the unemployment rate from 2025 to 2027 are 4.4%, 4.3%, and 4.3%, respectively, and the forecasts in December are 4.3%, 4.3%, and 4.3%, respectively. The median forecasts for core PCE inflation from 2025 to 2027 are 2.8%, 2.2%, and 2.0%, respectively, and the forecasts in December are 2.5%, 2.2%, and 2.0%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16938152</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16938152</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:20:00 GMT</pubDate><author>PANews</author></item><item><title>The Federal Reserve kept its policy rate unchanged and began to slow down the pace of balance sheet reduction on April 1</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/a104735a013dbb53abcce4faac1947b5.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PANews, March 20 news, according to Wall Street Journal, the Federal Reserve held steady - maintaining the federal funds rate target range at 4.25%-4.50%, in line with market expectations. Starting April 1, the pace of balance sheet reduction will be slowed, with the monthly cap on the reduction of US Treasuries lowered to $50 billion, while the monthly reduction of mortgage-backed securities (MBS) will remain unchanged at $35 billion. The statement said: the uncertainty facing the economy has increased, the 2025 growth forecast has been lowered, and the inflation forecast has been raised. The language about the roughly balanced risks to the Federal Reserve&#39;s (maintaining price stability + achieving full employment) goals has been omitted. Federal Reserve Governor Waller supported the FOMC&#39;s interest rate decision this time, but dissented on the balance sheet decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16937904</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16937904</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:06:00 GMT</pubDate><author>PANews</author></item><item><title>Sources: Kraken considering acquiring trading platform NinjaTrader for $1.5 billion</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/a104735a013dbb53abcce4faac1947b5.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PANews reported on March 20 that, according to sources cited by The Wall Street Journal, Kraken is considering acquiring the foreign exchange and futures trading platform NinjaTrader for $1.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16937900</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16937900</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:05:00 GMT</pubDate><author>PANews</author></item><item><title>Bitcoin breaks through $86,000</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 20, according to HTX market data, Bitcoin surged above $86,000, currently quoted at $86,353.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16937657</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16937657</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 22:43:10 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title>BTC breaks through 86,000 USDT, up 4.56% in 24 hours</title><description>Odaily Odaily News OKX market shows that BTC has broken through 86,000 USDT and is now at 86,018.8 USDT, with a 24-hour increase of 4.56%. (This newsletter is generated by AI)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16937669</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16937669</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 22:41:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title>Bitcoin breaks through 86,000 USDT</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Foresight News reports that according to Bitget market data, Bitcoin has broken through 86,000 USDT, currently trading at 86,131.78 USDT, with a daily increase of 4.14%.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16937671</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16937671</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 22:41:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Foresight News</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category><category>Stablecoin</category></item><item><title>The operator of the Russian sanctioned crypto trading platform Garantex is suspected of transferring customer funds to a new platform</title><description>On March 20, according to The Block, a report by the analysis firm Global Ledger showed that the operator of the sanctioned Russian cryptocurrency exchange Garantex is suspected of launching a new trading platform called Grinex and transferring client funds to that platform. Grinex is still operating in Russia and has many similarities to Garantex, which was sanctioned by international agencies earlier this month. On-chain data shows that Grinex has already processed transactions worth nearly $30 million. Global Ledger stated: &quot;These investigation results indicate that Grinex is not an independent entity, but the official successor to Garantex, and although the trading platform has officially closed, it continues to conduct financial operations.&quot;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16937333</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16937333</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 22:13:24 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item><item><title>Analyst: The Fed&#39;s revision of economic expectations will not have a significant impact on financial markets</title><description>Odaily Odaily News: Josh Jamner, senior investment analyst at Clearbridge, an investment company, believes that the Fed&#39;s economic expectations suggest that policymakers now expect economic conditions to be less favorable this year, with a moderate slowdown in the economy and rising inflation and unemployment. These changes are consistent with the expectations of banks and macroeconomic research institutions circulating on Wall Street in recent weeks, so in our view, these changes will not have a significant impact on financial markets. Ultimately, the Fed&#39;s policy will give way to fiscal policy, and pricing in the federal funds futures market suggests that the next rate cut will not occur until July, and this dynamic is unlikely to change in the short term.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16936778</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16936778</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:42:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Circle minted approximately 250 million new USDC on Solana</title><description>Odaily Odaily reported that according to Cointelegraph monitoring data, Circle has minted about 250 million new USDC on Solana.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16936777</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16936777</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:42:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author><category>Solana</category><category>Solana Ecosystem</category><category>SEC Security Token</category><category>Layer 1</category></item><item><title>Powell: We are at a stage where we can cut interest rates or maintain the current clearly tight policy stance</title><description>&lt;p&gt;ChainCatcher news, Fed Chair Powell: We are now in a stage where we can cut interest rates or maintain the current clearly tightening policy stance.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934402</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934402</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Economists: Be cautious when betting on Fed rate cuts</title><description>Odaily News reports that Casey Bostic, an observer of the Federal Reserve and chief economist at the UK mortgage company Nationwide, has warned people to be cautious about betting on the Federal Reserve&#39;s rate cuts. She believes that investors are too eager to digest the impact of rate cuts, and as concerns about a sharp economic slowdown intensify, they generally expect the Federal Reserve&#39;s &quot;Fed put&quot; to cushion economic activity. Even if it is assumed that economic activity does not decline sharply, persistent high inflation and inflationary pressures from tariffs may cause the Federal Reserve to remain on hold for longer than the market expects. (Gold Ten)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934376</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934376</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Powell: Slowing the balance sheet reduction means it will happen at a slower pace but last longer</title><description>On March 20, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell said that slowing the balance sheet reduction means it will be done at a slower pace, but the duration will be longer. (Gold Ten)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934001</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934001</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:06:34 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item><item><title>Powell: There will be decisions and clarity in the coming months and throughout this year, and policies will be adjusted according to circumstances</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher news, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell: There will be decisions and clarity in the coming months and throughout this year, and we will adjust our policies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933978</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933978</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>In the past 4 hours, the entire network has liquidated 104 million US dollars, mainly short orders</title><description>Odaily Odaily reports that according to Coinglass data, the entire network has seen &amp;lt;1.04 billion USD&amp;gt; in liquidations over the past 4 hours, of which &amp;lt;337.472 million USD&amp;gt; were long positions and &amp;lt;702.417 million USD&amp;gt; were short positions.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933957</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933957</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:58:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Powell: If inflation subsides on its own, monetary policy should not be tightened</title><description>Federal Reserve Chairman Powell: If inflation subsides on its own, there is no need to tighten monetary policy.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933891</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933891</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Powell mentions &quot;tariffs&quot; and admits that Trump&#39;s policies affect the economy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher&#39;s message, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell first mentioned the &quot;tariff&quot; issue at the press conference. When asked about the revision of inflation forecasts and the extent to which tariffs have affected inflation forecasts, he said it was difficult to analyze how much inflation was driven by tariff policies, but they would strive to figure it out: &quot;It&#39;s clear that a large part of it comes from tariffs.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Powell pointed out that the policies of the new Trump administration would affect the economy, but he would cautiously avoid making too explicit judgments about this impact. Analysts pointed out that this might be his attempt, and he said he would closely monitor the monthly data to avoid the outside world&#39;s expectations about how all this would develop.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933892</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933892</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:50:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Data: Spot gold hits a new high of $3,047</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to ChainCatcher news, spot gold has refreshed its historical high to $3,047.52 per ounce, up 0.44% intraday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933581</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933581</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Gold hits record high after interest rate decision, US stocks rise</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 20, after the announcement of the Federal Reserve&#39;s March interest rate decision, spot gold hit a new high of $3,047 per ounce, up 0.44% intraday. U.S. stocks continued to rally, with the S&amp;amp;P 500 index up 1%, the Nasdaq up 1.47%, and the Dow Jones up 0.77%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933500</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933500</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:47:02 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item><item><title>Powell: The economy is strong, slowing the balance sheet reduction is a &quot;technical&quot; decision</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher news, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell stated in a press conference that the U.S. economy is strong, and the decision to slow the pace of quantitative tightening (QT) is a &quot;technical&quot; one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powell said he is currently evaluating economic data, and while recent data shows consumer spending has slowed and household uncertainty has increased, he added that this is occurring on the basis of rapid growth in recent years. Powell also stated that the labor market conditions remain solid.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933493</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933493</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:42:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Powell: Survey shows tariffs drive inflation expectations, no need to rush to adjust policy stance</title><description>On March 20, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell said in his speech that the Fed&#39;s survey showed that tariffs have driven up inflation expectations; there is currently no need to urgently adjust the policy stance, and some signs of tightening in the money market have already been seen. (Jinshi)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933401</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933401</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:37:05 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item></channel></rss>