<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>parliament - lordslibrary - research-briefing</title><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/type/research-briefing/</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/parliament.uk/lordslibrary/type/research-briefing" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>parliament - lordslibrary - research-briefing - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:42:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Employment Rights Bill: Bill 81 of 2024-25Research BriefingBusinessEmployment</title><description>The government introduced the Employment Rights Bill in the House of Lords on 14 March 2025. The House is scheduled to debate the bill at second reading on 27 March 2025.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0017/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0017/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance Bill: Bill 77 of 2024-25Research BriefingEconomy</title><description>The government introduced the Finance Bill in the House of Lords on 4 March 2025. The House is scheduled to debate the bill at second reading and all remaining stages on 19 March 2025.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0016/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0016/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>House of Lords (Peerage Nominations) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 36 of 2024-25Research BriefingGovernmentHouse of Lords</title><description>The House of Lords (Peerage Nominations) Bill [HL] is a private member’s bill sponsored by Lord Norton of Louth (Conservative). The bill seeks to strengthen the House of Lords Appointments Commission.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0014/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0014/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Church of Scotland (Lord High Commissioner) Bill: HL Bill 79 of 2024–25Research BriefingGovernmentParliament</title><description>The Church of Scotland (Lord High Commissioner) Bill would remove the restriction on people of the Roman Catholic faith holding the office of His Majesty’s lord high commissioner to the general assembly of the Church of Scotland.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0015/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0015/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Palestine Statehood (Recognition) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 37 of 2024-25Research BriefingForeign Policy</title><description>The Palestine Statehood (Recognition) Bill [HL] is a private member’s bill introduced by Baroness Northover (Liberal Democrat). The bill would require the UK government to formally recognise Palestine as a sovereign and independent state.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0013/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0013/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Education (Assemblies) Bill [HL]:HL Bill 35 of 2024-25Research BriefingCommunitiesEducationGovernment</title><description>The Education (Assemblies) Bill [HL] is a private member’s bill introduced by Baroness Burt of Solihull (Liberal Democrat). It would repeal the requirement for schools in England without a designated religious character to provide daily acts of collective religious worship. In its place, the bill would establish a new duty to provide non-religious assemblies which develop the spiritual, moral, social, and cultural education of pupils.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0010/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0010/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Armed Forces Commissioner Bill: HL Bill 63 of 2024–25Research BriefingDefence</title><description>The Armed Forces Commissioner Bill would establish an independent armed forces commissioner and provide them with powers to initiate investigations into general service welfare matters. It would also abolish the office of the service complaints ombudsman and transfer its functions and responsibilities to the newly established commissioner.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0012/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0012/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Permitted Development Rights (Extension) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 28 of 2024–25Research BriefingHousingLocal Government</title><description>The Permitted Development Rights (Extension) Bill [HL] is a private member’s bill introduced by Lord Lucas (Conservative). The bill would establish new permitted development rights to make additions and alterations to domestic properties. The House of Lords is scheduled to debate the bill at second reading on 7 February 2025.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0011/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0011/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Crown Estate (Wales) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 29 of 2024–25Research BriefingDevolution</title><description>This private member’s bill would transfer responsibility for the Crown Estate in Wales to the Welsh government.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0009/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0009/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mortgage Prisoners Inquiry Bill [HL]: HL Bill 33 of 2024–25Research BriefingHousing</title><description>This proposed law would require the government to hold a public inquiry as soon as reasonably practicable into the circumstances surrounding mortgage prisoners.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0008/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0008/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Renters’ Rights Bill: HL Bill 60 of 2024–25Research BriefingHousing</title><description>The Renters&#39; Rights Bill would enact significant reform of the private rental sector (PRS). The bill’s provisions are centred on the PRS in England, though some measures would apply to Scotland and Wales. Many of the provisions in the bill are similar to the Renters (Reform) Bill 2023–24 introduced by the then Conservative government, but with several key differences including ending rental bidding and curtailing rent payments in advance of a tenancy.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0007/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0007/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-Domestic Rating (Multipliers and Private Schools) Bill: HL Bill 61 of 2024–25Research BriefingBusinessEconomyEducation</title><description>This government bill would enable changes to the business rates regime. It would allow the introduction of additional business rate multipliers to increase business rates for larger properties and reduce business rates for retail, hospitality and leisure properties, and the removal of charitable rate relief from some private schools that are charities.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0006/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0006/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulated and Other Activities (Mandatory Reporting of Child Sexual Abuse) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 9 of 2024–25Research BriefingCrimeFamilies &amp; Social Ser...</title><description>The Regulated and Other Activities (Mandatory Reporting of Child Sexual Abuse) Bill [HL] is a private member’s bill introduced by Baroness Grey-Thompson (Crossbench). It received its first reading on 29 July 2024 and is scheduled to have its second reading in the House of Lords on 17 January 2025.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0005/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0005/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Universal Credit (Standard Allowance Entitlement of Care Leavers) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 30 of 2024-25Research BriefingWelfare &amp; Pensions</title><description>The bill would amend the Universal Credit Regulations 2013 to increase the standard allowance entitlement of universal credit for individuals leaving care once they turn 18 to match the amount available to claimants aged 25 or over.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0004/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0004/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Consumer Products (Control of Biocides) Bill [HL]: HL Bill 32 of 2024–25Research BriefingEconomyEnvironment</title><description>The Consumer Products (Control of Biocides) Bill [HL] is a private member’s bill sponsored by Baroness Bennett of Manor Castle (Green Party). It would restrict the use of substances with antimicrobial properties, known as biocides, in cosmetic, personal care and other treated products, for example clothing and period products, subject to certain exemptions. The House of Lords is scheduled to debate the bill at second reading on 17 January 2025.</description><link>https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0003/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://lordslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/lln-2025-0003/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>