<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Local News - Kelowna Capital News</title><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news</link><atom:link href="http://rss.owo.nz/kelownacapnews/local-news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Local News - Kelowna Capital News - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:37:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>City of Kelowna offers &#39;tree-mendous&#39; deal through NeighbourWoods program</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;30170265_web1_220825-KCN-neighbourwoods-is-back_1&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/lakecountry/import/2022-08/30170265_web1_220825-KCN-neighbourwoods-is-back_1.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The City of Kelowna’s popular NeighbourWoods is back for another year. (Photo/City of Kelowna)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Kelowna’s residential planting initiative has returned for spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program gives residents an opportunity to purchase up to two new trees for their yards at a reduced rate. Trees are available for pre-order starting Mon., March 31 until April 21, or until they are sold out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are eight tree varieties at a cost of $50 plus&amp;nbsp;GST per tree. This year’s varieties include the Admiration Oak, Amur Cork Tree, Crimson Sentry Norway Maple, Ginko Maidenhair, Ivory Silk Japanese Tree Lilac, Northern Acclaim Honey Locust, Parkland Pillar Birch and the Tulip Tree. The Ivory Silk Japanese Tree Lilac is restricted to one&amp;nbsp;tree per household.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re thrilled to offer the NeighbourWoods program twice this year – both this spring and fall,” said Todd Cashin, urban forestry supervisor. “We hope residents will join us in purchasing up to two trees at a great discount and, at the same time, helping to increase our city’s urban tree canopy.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information on ordering trees can be found on the city’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/city-of-kelowna-offers-tree-mendous-deal-through-neighbourwoods-program-7901373</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/city-of-kelowna-offers-tree-mendous-deal-through-neighbourwoods-program-7901373</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>West Kelowna residents can get &#39;re-leaf&#39; to plant trees on their properties</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;japanesemaple&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/westk/2025/japanesemaple.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Red-Leaf Japanese Maple Tree.&lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;City of West Kelowna&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The City of West Kelowna is providing homeowners a chance to spruce up their properties and contribute to the urban canopy with new trees at cost. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Urban Re-Leaf Program is offering several varieties&amp;nbsp;including the Ambassador Crabapple, Autumn Blaze Maple, and Ivory Silk Japanese Lilac at $75 each, and the Red-Leaf Japanese Maple for $90 each. New this year is the Quick Fire Hydrangea, for residents with limited yard space, for $75 each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purchases are limited to two trees per property. Residents can visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.westkelownacity.ca/en/parks-recreation-and-culture/urban-re-leaf.aspx&quot;&gt;city’s website between Mar. 24 and Apr. 25 to place an order&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Urban Re-Leaf&amp;nbsp;Program was launched in 2020 to help expand West Kelowna’s green canopy and support climate initiatives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/west-kelowna-residents-can-get-re-leaf-to-plant-trees-on-their-properties-7901467</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/west-kelowna-residents-can-get-re-leaf-to-plant-trees-on-their-properties-7901467</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kelowna athlete named top college hockey player in Alberta</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;kaedence_mollin&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/kelowna/2025-march/kaedence_mollin.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.468788249694;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mollin grew up playing for the Kelowna Minor Hockey Association and later joined&amp;nbsp;the Thompson-Okanagan Lakers before moving to Red Deer to play for the Queens.&lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;Red Deer Polytechnic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;An athlete from Kelowna is excelling both on and off the ice at College in Alberta.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaedence Mollin has been named&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;2024-2025 Women’s Hockey Player of the Year by the Alberta Colleges Athletic Conference (ACAC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As captain of the Red Deer Polytechnic Queens, she helped lead the team to third in the Conference with 10 goals and 15 assists in 25 games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;[Mollin] has been an excellent on-ice leader for our team. She plays the game with pride and passion,&quot; said &lt;a href=&quot;https://rdpolytechathletics.ca/general/2024-25/releases/20250310k43d37&quot;&gt;Kelly Coulter, the head coach of the&amp;nbsp;Red Deer Polytechnic&amp;nbsp;Queens.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mollin grew up playing for the Kelowna Minor Hockey Association and later joined&amp;nbsp;the Thompson-Okanagan Lakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to being crowned the Player of the Year for her role as captain of the Queens,&amp;nbsp;Mollin is also&amp;nbsp;a member of the ACAC Women’s Hockey First All-Conference team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to her success as an athlete, Mollin achieved a 4.0 GPA in the Bachelor of Science in Nursing program at Red Deer Polytechnic in the 2024 Fall term and has accumulated awards&amp;nbsp;for her achievements off the ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has been&amp;nbsp;awarded&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;title of ACAC Women’s Hockey Top Scholastic Achiever and is an ACAC Women’s Hockey Academic All-Canadian.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic All-Canadians are student-athletes who achieve both academic honours and&amp;nbsp;receive an ACAC All-Conference team selection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/kelowna-athlete-named-top-college-hockey-player-in-alberta-7901201</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/kelowna-athlete-named-top-college-hockey-player-in-alberta-7901201</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Jacqueline Gelineau</author></item><item><title>UPDATE: Westside Road traffic single-lane alternating at Traders Cove</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;486092748_10161393036327549_674541668297158521_n&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/kelowna/2025-march/486092748_10161393036327549_674541668297158521_n.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A tractor rolled on Westside Road near Traders Cove on Mar. 24, 2025. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;Krystal Kostuik/Facebook&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 2 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One lane has reopened on Westside Road after a tractor rolled near Traders Cove.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic is now moving in single-lane alternating fashion, but delays should be expected.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RCMP are asking motorists to slow down or find an alternate route.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&quot;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;504&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FRCMPKelowna%2Fposts%2Fpfbid02ffwgE8phNowJnvn1RLD8QnrUwdzeFeKCngD8m3xRcrLLkvWgxrSsXkd772G7sLrwl&amp;amp;show_text=true&amp;amp;width=500&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original 1:25 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic has stalled on Westside Road near Traders Cove after a tractor rolled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vehicle is blocking both lanes of traffic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emergency crews have been dispatched to the scene. The driver of the tractor was not injured in the crash.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story will be updated when more information is available.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/westside-road-closed-for-tractor-rollover-between-at-traders-cove-7901058</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/westside-road-closed-for-tractor-rollover-between-at-traders-cove-7901058</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:27:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Brittany Webster</author></item><item><title>Arts For Education event raises funds for Literacy in Okanagan and Uganda</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;artsforeduction&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/kelowna/2025-march/artsforeduction.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Arts For Education was founded by first-year Okanagan College student Annabelle Lee.&lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;Contributed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Arts For Education is back for another night of live music and local artistry.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event celebrates the arts while making a difference in children&#39;s lives in the Okanagan and Uganda.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Tickets are available online or at the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arts For Education was founded by Annabelle Lee, a first-year Okanagan College student studying International Development. The idea started in 2024 when Annabelle, then a high school senior at Okanagan Mission Secondary, launched the first event. That night, more than 150 people attended, helping raise over $3,000 for libraries in Uganda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The ability to read opens minds, hearts, and doors of opportunity,&quot; Lee said. &quot;Many children in Uganda do not have access to books, and I created Arts For Education to combine my love of the arts and passion for making an impact in children&#39;s lives.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event, presented by Beem Credit Union, will showcase local artists and performers. It takes place Sunday, March 30, from 5:30 to 8 p.m. at Okanagan College&#39;s E Building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entry is open to all ages, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zeffy.com/en-CA/ticketing/arts-for-education&quot;&gt;tickets priced at $15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every dollar raised goes toward literacy programs through the Niteo Africa Society, a Kelowna-based charity dedicated to furthering child and family literacy.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/arts-for-education-event-raises-funds-for-literacy-in-okanagan-and-uganda-7900738</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/arts-for-education-event-raises-funds-for-literacy-in-okanagan-and-uganda-7900738</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ride Don’t Hide for mental health returns to Kelowna</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ride Don&#39;t Hide&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/salmonarm/import/2017-02/519salmonarm20150621RideDon-tHideEB0015.jpg;w=725&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.23931623931624;&quot; width=&quot;725&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Participants of the Ride Don’t Hide event rest after completing the 10-kilometre ride in this undated photo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The Canadian Mental Health Association (CMHA) Kelowna is gearing up for the Payton and Dillon Budd Memorial Ride – Ride Don’t Hide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The annual event brings the community together to raise awareness and support mental health programs in the Central Okanagan. Last year, more than 600 riders took part, all working to break the stigma around mental health and ensure accessible support services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In partnership with The Thomas Alan Budd Foundation, the event honours the memory of Payton and Dillon Budd.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Payton and Dillon Budd Memorial Ride is not just about cycling, it’s about showing up for mental health,&quot; said CMHA Kelowna CEO Mike Gawliuk. &quot;It’s about creating a space where everyone feels supported and knows they are not alone. Every dollar raised goes directly into programs and supports that help people in our community.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event welcomes participants of all ages and abilities, whether they want to ride, walk, or cheer from the sidelines. Route options include a six kilometre walk, plus rides of 9km, 25km, 50km, and 100km. There will also be family-friendly activities, and food trucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Payton and Dillon Budd Memorial Ride is set for Sunday, June 8, at Sutherland Bay Park. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmha.donordrive.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=donorDrive.event&amp;amp;eventID=765&quot;&gt;Registration is now open&lt;/a&gt;, with early bird pricing available until April 18.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/ride-dont-hide-for-mental-health-returns-to-kelowna-7900519</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/ride-dont-hide-for-mental-health-returns-to-kelowna-7900519</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Okanagan distillery in great spirits after world awards domination</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;250327-vms-spirits&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/vernon/2025-march/250327-vms-spirits.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Representatives of Vernon-Kelowna&#39;s Okanagan Spirits distillery celebrate their 16 medals and title of World-Class Distillery in Worldwide Whisky won at the World Spirits Awards in Germany. Facebook photo&lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;Facebook photo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;The little&amp;nbsp;distillery that could...did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;Family-run Okanagan Spirits is the 2025 World-Class Distillery in Worldwide Whisky, dominating the World Spirts Awards in Germany by winning a staggering 16 medals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;In a blind tasting showdown with the globe&#39;s top distilleries, Okanagan Spirits captured 11 gold medals, five silvers, and the World-Class Distillery title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;It&#39;s the second time this decade the Vernon-Kelowna distillery has snagged that honour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;&quot;To represent Canada and claim the Worldwide Whisky designation again is a dream come true for our little family distillery,&quot; said Vernon&#39;s Tony Dyck, Okanagan Spirits president. &quot;We’re just proud to be in the room with the world’s best.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;CEO Tyler Dyck admitted they’re still picking their jaws off the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;“To sweep seven whisky categories and even nab gold for Poire Williams — a spirit that’s notoriously tough to nail — it’s beyond what we could’ve imagined,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;It’s not just fancy stills or magic barrels (though their team, led by Chris Burke and Francois Joubert, clearly knows their stuff). Tyler’s quick to point the spotlight elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;“Our local farmers deserve a huge shout-out,&quot; he said. &quot;The grain and fruit we use — it’s all 100 per cent&amp;nbsp;B.C.-grown. That’s the backbone of everything we do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;From bourbon-style whisky, to single malt, rye, hopped whisky, gins, fruit liqueurs, and even Canada’s original genuine absinthe, their lineup of more than&amp;nbsp;50&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://okanaganspirits.com/products/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;products&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a love letter to the Okanagan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awards list reads like a victory lap: golds for everything from the Laird of Fintry Single-Malt (aged in double-wood casks) to a cigar-blended whisky that sounds like it belongs in a detective novel. They even took top honours for a pear brandy that’s defined as &#39;the Everest of distilling.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silver medals&amp;nbsp;for a maple-brûlée rye and a raspberry liqueur didn’t hurt either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/okanagan-distillery-in-great-spirits-after-world-awards-domination-7900472</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/okanagan-distillery-in-great-spirits-after-world-awards-domination-7900472</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:57:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Roger Knox</author></item><item><title>Spring street sweeping starts in Peachland</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;street-sweeper&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/westk/2025/street-sweeper.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The District of Peachland expects street sweeping to completed in two weeks.&lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;District of Peachland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Street sweepers are out in Peachland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Residents are asked to avoid parking vehicles on the roads until the street has been swept. Residents are also asked to remove any items that may interfere with the sweeper, such as basketball hoops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Street sweeping is expected to be completed in two weeks.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Any questions or concerns or questions can be directed to the operations department at 250-767-2108 or operations@peachland.ca.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/spring-street-sweeping-starts-in-peachland-7900333</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/spring-street-sweeping-starts-in-peachland-7900333</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UBC Okanagan students start hunger strike to demand divestment</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;20050819_web1_ubco_1&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/kelowna/2025-march/20050819_web1_ubco_1.jpg;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;UBC Okanagan. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;(File photo) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Students at the University of B.C. Okanagan in Kelowna has begun a hunger strike to raise awareness about the genocide in Palestine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining students from UBC&#39;s Vancouver campus, who started striking on Mar. 17, the protest aims&amp;nbsp;to shed light on &quot;UBC&#39;s double standards in investment practices and ongoing financial ties to weapons manufacturers and corporations designated by the United Nations as complicit in violations of international law.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strike will take place daily from 11 a.m. to 5 p.m. at various locations on campus. Students will gather at the Sawchuk Theatre today, Mar. 24, starting at noon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A UBC Okanagan student named Ashley explained why she had joined the strike.&amp;nbsp;“I am hunger-striking because I understand that collective liberation requires collective responsibility and I believe that each and every one of us has the power to enact social change. I am hunger-striking because I would like to use the power of my body to actualize a future of collective liberation where Palestine and all of us are free. I am hunger striking because unlike the UBC administration and the UBCO School of Social Work, I refuse to look away from genocide.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A community rally will be held in the campus courtyard on Mar. 28 at 11:30 a.m. for anyone wishing to show their support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay up-to-date on the strike at &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubcdivest.org/&quot;&gt;UBCDivest.org&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/ubc-okanagan-students-start-hunger-strike-7900384</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/ubc-okanagan-students-start-hunger-strike-7900384</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Brittany Webster</author></item><item><title>Specialized construction training being offered in Kelowna</title><description>&lt;figure style=&quot;margin: 0&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;nudura-installation-3&quot; src=&quot;https://www.bpmcdn.com/f/files/kelowna/2025-march/nudura-installation-3.PNG;w=960&quot; style=&quot;aspect-ratio:1.5;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Nudura installation. &lt;span class=&quot;caption-byline&quot;&gt;Contributed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;AcuTruss Industries and Okanagan Insulated Concrete Forms (ICF) are sponsoring a specialized course aimed at supporting the construction industry and opening doors to new career opportunities across the Okanagan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Nudura Installation Training Course is a one-day program that will cover the concept, design, and basic installation techniques of ICF.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As a proudly Canadian-owned and operated company, we’re committed to offering local builders, contractors, framers, and architects the opportunity to stay ahead in an increasingly competitive job market,” says Angelo Cencig, Nudura ICF product manager at Okanagan ICF.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training course is open to both entry-level workers and experienced professionals, and participants who complete the course will be certified as trained installers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our goal is to equip local workers with the skills and knowledge they need to get the job done confidently and efficiently,” says Cencig. “By teaching cutting-edge techniques and skills in a dedicated environment, we’re helping to give our local workforce a competitive edge in the evolving construction industry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training course will be held on April 11 at the Ramada Hotel in Kelowna. For more information or to register, visit the Nadura Training website.&lt;/p&gt;

    </description><link>https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/specialized-construction-training-being-offered-in-kelowna-7900242</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.kelownacapnews.com/local-news/specialized-construction-training-being-offered-in-kelowna-7900242</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>