<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>GarageBand - Apple App Store</title><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.thzu.xyz/apple/apps/update/us/id408709785" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>GarageBand turns your iPad, and iPhone into a collection of Touch Instruments and a full-featured recording studio — so you can make music anywhere you go. And with Live Loops, it makes it easy for anyone to have fun creating music like a DJ. Use Multi-Touch gestures to play keyboards, guitars, and create beats that make you sound like a pro — even if you’ve never played a note before. Plug in a guitar or bass and play through classic amps and stompbox effects. Use a Touch Instrument, microphone, or a guitar to instantly record a performance, with support for up to 32 tracks. Use the Sound Library to download additional free instruments, loops, and sound packs created by some of the biggest producers in the world. And then share your song with friends and family. Live Loops. Make music like a DJ • Use Multi-Touch to tap and trigger a Live Loop cell or group of cells • Get started with templates or build your own grid from scratch with Apple Loops • Create custom loops by recording directly into a cell using any Touch Instrument • Use Remix FX to perform DJ-style effects • Tap record to capture your performance Play your iPad, and iPhone, like a musical instrument • Play a variety of musical instruments on the innovative Multi-Touch keyboard • Play and record using the Alchemy Touch Instrument • Build grooves inspired by classic electronic drum machines with the Beat Sequencer • Download free instruments, loops, and sound packs for GarageBand with the Sound Library • Capture any sound and apply studio-class effects • Recreate legendary guitar or bass rigs using virtual amps and stompboxes • Record performances from third-party music apps directly into GarageBand using Audio Unit Extensions* Drummer • Add virtual session drummers to your song, who take direction and play realistic grooves • Choose from acoustic, electronic drummers and percussionists** • Each character provides their own sound and the ability to create over a million realistic grooves and fills Sound like a virtuoso with Smart Instruments • Play an entire string orchestra using Smart Strings • Perform with Chord Strips and autoplay using any keyboard instrument • Groove with a variety of Smart Basses using upright, electric, and synth sounds • Strum chords or trigger autoplay patterns on an acoustic and electric Smart Guitar Create a song anywhere you go • Record, arrange, and mix your song with up to 32 tracks using Touch Instruments, audio recordings, and loops*** • Record multiple times over any song section and choose your favorite using Multi-Take Recording • Use professional mixing effects, including Visual EQ, Bitcrusher, and Overdrive • Recording, mixing and exporting a song can be done at 24-bit audio resolution • Trim and place musical regions exactly where you want them to play • Automate the volume and record the movement of controls on Touch Instruments • Add comments or lyric ideas to your song with an integrated notepad Share your songs • Keep your songs up to date across all devices using iCloud Drive • Create custom ringtones and alerts for your iPad, or iPhone • Share your songs using email or to social media sites like SoundCloud**** • Remotely add new tracks to your Logic Pro project from your iPhone, or iPad via iCloud * Requires compatible third-party Audio Unit Extensions apps from the App Store. ** Requires free download from GarageBand Sound Library. *** Multitrack recording requires a compatible third-party audio interface. **** Sharing to some social media sites may require apps like iMovie, Clips or other third-party apps - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-US</language><image><url>https://is1-ssl.mzstatic.com/image/thumb/Purple221/v4/e2/0a/db/e20adbdb-50a1-a3de-5caf-c0ce52edda1e/AppIcon-0-1x_U007epad-0-0-0-1-0-0-P3-85-220-0.png/1200x630wa.png</url><title>GarageBand - Apple App Store</title><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link></image><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:24:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.17 for iOS</title><description>This update includes stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.17</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 16:55:26 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.16 for iOS</title><description>This update includes stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.16</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 16:58:51 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.15 for iOS</title><description>This update includes stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.15</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 16:56:54 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.14 for iOS</title><description>This update includes stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.14</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 17:58:06 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.13 for iOS</title><description>• New downloadable “Beat Tape” sound pack with a collection of over 200 new Hip Hop loops and 5 drum kits&lt;br&gt;• Provides performance and stability improvements</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.13</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 16:59:06 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.12 for iOS</title><description>• Stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;• Contains multiple enhancements to Accessibility</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.12</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 19:59:26 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.11 for iOS</title><description>This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.11</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:56:07 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.10 for iOS</title><description>This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.10</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 18:00:11 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.9 for iOS</title><description>• New audio recordings can be quickly started from the Home screen by touching and holding the GarageBand app icon&lt;br&gt;• Maximum song length at default tempo has been increased from 23 to 72 minutes&lt;br&gt;• The ruler now offers an option to switch from musical bars and beats to minutes and seconds&lt;br&gt;• New downloadable &quot;Keyboard Collection&quot; sound pack includes over 150 keyboard loops and 50 instrument patches like pianos, organs, and electric pianos</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.9</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 17:00:07 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.8 for iOS</title><description>• Support for Dark Mode and new Share sheet in iOS 13&lt;br&gt;• Access files from external hard drives, SD card readers, and USB drives&lt;br&gt;• Improves audio fidelity of Apple Loops when making tempo and key changes&lt;br&gt;• New downloadable “Skyline Heat” sound pack with a collection of over 350 new Hip Hop loops and 6 drum kits&lt;br&gt;• Search for Apple Loops by Sound Library pack name&lt;br&gt;• Provides performance and stability improvements</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.8</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 17:02:52 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.7 for iOS</title><description>• Supports keyboard commands when using a Smart Keyboard or Bluetooth keyboard&lt;br&gt;• Adds the Wah stompbox pedal and Face Control to Smart Guitar&lt;br&gt;• Provides stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.7</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 18:00:12 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.6 for iOS</title><description>• Includes a collection of Touch Instrument and Drummer Apple Loops, which allow you to continue shaping their sound and performance after adding them to your project&lt;br&gt;• Supports import and playback of MIDI files&lt;br&gt;• This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.6</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 17:05:56 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.5 for iOS</title><description>This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 15:30:23 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.4 for iOS</title><description>• Adds support for Schoolwork including Handouts, app activities, and the ability for students to submit completed assignments as a GarageBand project&lt;br&gt;• Allows you to view note labels on any Touch Instrument&#39;s music keyboard&lt;br&gt;• Provides stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.4</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 17:01:19 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.3 for iOS</title><description>• New downloadable “Toy Box” sound pack with free educational sound effects, including animals, vehicles, and counting to ten in different languages&lt;br&gt;• Use facial expressions and the TrueDepth camera for hands-free control over musical effects like guitar wah and synth parameters*&lt;br&gt;• Adds Modern Wah guitar stompbox effect&lt;br&gt;• Provides stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* Requires iPhone X. GarageBand uses ARKit face tracking features to translate your facial expressions into instrument effect controls. Your face information is processed on device, and only music is captured during your performance.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.3</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 15:45:06 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.2 for iOS</title><description>This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.2</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 18:00:17 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3.1 for iOS</title><description>This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Introduced in Version 2.3&lt;br&gt;• Updated for Super Retina display on iPhone X&lt;br&gt;• Use the new Sound Library to download additional free instruments, loops and sound packs &lt;br&gt;• Adds 3 Drummers who play percussion in the styles of Pop, Songwriter, and Latin*&lt;br&gt;• Play and record using traditional instruments from China and Japan, including the Guzheng, Koto and Taiko drums*&lt;br&gt;• Build grooves inspired by classic electronic drum machines with the Beat Sequencer&lt;br&gt;• Support for expanded sharing and storage options with the Files app in iOS 11&lt;br&gt;• Enables a larger Audio Unit Extensions view for compatible third-party instruments and effects&lt;br&gt;• Recording, mixing and exporting a song can be done at 24-bit audio resolution &lt;br&gt;• Includes iMessage sticker pack that adds GarageBand instrument icons &lt;br&gt;• Provides stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* Requires free download from GarageBand Sound Library</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3.1</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 20:30:16 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.3 for iOS</title><description>• Updated for Super Retina display on iPhone X&lt;br&gt;• Use the new Sound Library to download additional free instruments, loops and sound packs &lt;br&gt;• Adds 3 Drummers who play percussion in the styles of Pop, Songwriter, and Latin*&lt;br&gt;• Play and record using traditional instruments from China and Japan, including the Guzheng, Koto and Taiko drums*&lt;br&gt;• Build grooves inspired by classic electronic drum machines with the Beat Sequencer&lt;br&gt;• Support for expanded sharing and storage options with the Files app in iOS 11&lt;br&gt;• Enables a larger Audio Unit Extensions view for compatible third-party instruments and effects&lt;br&gt;• Recording, mixing and exporting a song can be done at 24-bit audio resolution &lt;br&gt;• Includes iMessage sticker pack that adds GarageBand instrument icons &lt;br&gt;• Provides stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* Requires free download from GarageBand Sound Library</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.3</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:30:24 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.2.2 for iOS</title><description>This update contains stability improvements and bug fixes.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.2.2</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 19:36:20 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.2.1 for iOS</title><description>• Stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Introduced in Version 2.2&lt;br&gt;• Play and record using the new Alchemy Touch Instrument with over 150 synth patches*&lt;br&gt;• Quickly find Touch Instruments and patches with a redesigned sound browser&lt;br&gt;• Capture your voice or instrument and apply studio-class effects like pitch correction, distortion and delay with the new Audio Recorder&lt;br&gt;• Use new mixing effects, including Visual EQ, Bitcrusher, and Overdrive&lt;br&gt;• Add third-party effects using Audio Unit Extensions**&lt;br&gt;• Record multiple times over any song section and choose your favorite using Multi-Take Recording&lt;br&gt;• Perform with Chord Strips from any keyboard instrument&lt;br&gt;• Add comments or lyric ideas to your song with an integrated notepad &lt;br&gt;• Remotely add new tracks to your Logic Pro X project from your iPhone or iPad via iCloud&lt;br&gt;• Stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* The Alchemy synth is available on iPhone 6 or later, iPad Pro, iPad Air 2, and iPad mini 4.&lt;br&gt;** Requires compatible third-party Audio Unit Extension instruments apps from the App Store.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.2.1</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:28:41 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.2 for iOS</title><description>• Play and record using the new Alchemy Touch Instrument with over 150 synth patches*&lt;br&gt;• Quickly find Touch Instruments and patches with a redesigned sound browser&lt;br&gt;• Capture your voice or instrument and apply studio-class effects like pitch correction, distortion and delay with the new Audio Recorder&lt;br&gt;• Use new mixing effects, including Visual EQ, Bitcrusher, and Overdrive&lt;br&gt;• Add third-party effects using Audio Unit Extensions**&lt;br&gt;• Record multiple times over any song section and choose your favorite using Multi-Take Recording&lt;br&gt;• Perform with Chord Strips from any keyboard instrument&lt;br&gt;• Add comments or lyric ideas to your song with an integrated notepad &lt;br&gt;• Remotely add new tracks to your Logic Pro X project from your iPhone or iPad via iCloud&lt;br&gt;• Stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* The Alchemy synth is available on iPhone 6 or later, iPad Pro, iPad Air 2, and iPad mini 4.&lt;br&gt;** Requires compatible third-party Audio Unit Extension instruments apps from the App Store.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.2</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 18:00:22 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.1.2 for iOS</title><description>• Stability improvements and bug fixes</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.1.2</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 18:30:49 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.1.1 for iOS</title><description>• Quickly navigate long lists of Apple Loops using a new alphabetical sidebar&lt;br&gt;• Use Multi-Touch to select multiple regions simultaneously in the Tracks area&lt;br&gt;• Send songs as an audio file using AirDrop&lt;br&gt;• Share GarageBand songs via Mail as uncompressed audio&lt;br&gt;• Apply your own custom images to songs shared to YouTube and Facebook&lt;br&gt;• Support for Shared iPad in iOS 9.3</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.1.1</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 23:00:36 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.1 for iOS</title><description>• Use Live Loops to create music by triggering instrument loops and DJ-style effects in real time using Multi-Touch gestures*&lt;br&gt;• Add a virtual Drummer to your song who takes direction and performs realistic acoustic &amp;amp; electronic drum grooves&lt;br&gt;• Record adjustments of any Touch Instrument control knob in real time&lt;br&gt;• Create and edit automation curves to control the volume of any track&lt;br&gt;• Shape the sound of a Touch Instrument or audio recording using Simple EQ and Compressor&lt;br&gt;• Plug in a bass guitar and play through vintage and modern bass amp rigs&lt;br&gt;• Adds over 1,200 new Apple Loops and sounds&lt;br&gt;• Record up to 32 tracks simultaneously**&lt;br&gt;• Use third-party instrument apps in your song with Audio Unit Extensions***&lt;br&gt;• Directly import or export GarageBand projects using iCloud Drive&lt;br&gt;• Use 3D Touch to play keyboard sounds with polyphonic aftertouch****&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;* Live Loops is available on iPhone 5, iPhone 5c, iPad (4th generation), or later devices.&lt;br&gt;** 32 tracks is available on iPhone 5s, iPad Air, iPad mini 2, or later devices. Multi-track recording requires compatible third party audio interface.&lt;br&gt;*** Requires compatible third-party Audio Unit Extension instruments apps from the App Store.&lt;br&gt;**** Polyphonic aftertouch is available on iPhone 6s and iPhone 6s Plus.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.1</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 16:00:17 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item><item><title>GarageBand 2.0.7 for iOS</title><description>• Share directly from GarageBand to Apple Music Connect*&lt;br&gt;• Stability improvements and bug fixes&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;*  Requires Apple Music Connect account.</description><link>https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id408709785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">apple/apps/us/id408709785/ios#2.0.7</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 20:04:53 GMT</pubDate><category>iOS</category></item></channel></rss>