<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>dang&#39;s comments | Hacker News</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/threads?id=dang</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.thzu.xyz/hackernews/threads/comments_list/dang" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>dang&#39;s comments | Hacker News - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:22:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>on: Hacking Your Own AI Coding Assistant with Claude P...</title><description>Related ongoing thread:Show HN: Codemcp – Claude Code for Claude Pro subscribers – ditch API bills - https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43356016 - March 2025 (3 comments)
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43417211</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43417211-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>dang</author><category></category></item><item><title>on: Show HN: Codemcp – Claude Code for Claude Pro subs...</title><description>Related ongoing thread:Hacking Your Own AI Coding Assistant with Claude Pro and MCP - https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43410866
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43417208</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43417208-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>dang</author><category></category></item><item><title>on: Learning about Innovation from Half a Century of C...</title><description>[stub for offtopicness]
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416835</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416835-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>InkCanon</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Wolfram&#39;s problem is mindset IMO. There&#39;s a certain kind of highly intelligent mind, but because of fame, money, habit or personality, makes them intellectually lazy. Instead of doing the proofs, research, careful discussion and reconceptualizing that leads to useful theories and conclusion, they jump straight to the end, because they think they&#39;re smart. This produces some impressive sounding theory, but which upon closer inspection proves to be to be too vague to actually be testable, if not contain outright errors. People I put in this group including Wolfram and his computational theories, Langan and his Cognitive Theoretical model of the Universe, and the Italian school of algebraic geometry. There&#39;s a kind of interesting perception here. A reasonable person thinks one who makes correct theories is an intelligent man. Others think they are intelligent, so therefore their theories are correct.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416086</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416086-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>hollerith</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>My impression is different: I think Wolfram is plenty hard-working, but his internal mental life is so full of fantasies of unlimited success and fame that he cannot manage an impartial-enough evaluation of his own work output.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416129</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416129-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>FilosofumRex</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>&quot;your impression&quot;, is true only in the Ruliad. Ask people who knew him back in the 80&#39;s... he never worked on anything on his own that has amounted to anything.  He is a real life crank, crackpot and all around charlatan.Mathematica is the product of 30 years of work on Macsyma and Maple systems at MIT and elsewhere, which he cracked its codebase, usurped and sold to an unsuspecting academic community back when only the likes of Bill Gates would do such as thing.He also missed the entire LLM wave because he refused to open source WolframAlpha codebase and work with others in the NLP community.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416804</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416804-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>mentalgear</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>any specific source ? (fire time I hear that about Wolfram )
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416520</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416520-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>hollerith</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>My impression is based on hearing him speak for a few hours and maybe some biographical facts such as can be gotten from Wikipedia.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416917</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416917-[2 more]</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>ForHackernews</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>[flagged]                      
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43412024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43412024-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>gexaha</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>thanks; interesting note in the end about Turing morphogenesis
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43412497</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43412497-[8 more]</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>r00t-</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>[flagged]                      
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43411961</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43411961-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>procgen</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>There&#39;s much to be said!
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43412300</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43412300-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>seanw444</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>It&#39;s unfortunate that people seem to be prejudiced against Wolfram at this point, when the field has a lot to explore and learn from. Cellular automata are so powerful, yet so conceptually simple, it wouldn&#39;t surprise me if it did have revelations for more fundamental concepts of the universe.What if the fundamentals of the universe are so simple it&#39;d shock us, we just haven&#39;t looked at it from the right perspective yet, and we&#39;re over-complicating it?
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43413026</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43413026-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>slightwinder</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Maybe one reason for the reactions are that his articles start to smell like Maslow&#39;s hammer, where every problem is a nail.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43413785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43413785-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>criddell</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>&amp;gt; Cellular automata are so powerfulIn what ways?
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43414676</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43414676-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>9283409232</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>People should be able to separate the merits of the work from the worker but people didn&#39;t just randomly decide to not like Wolfram. He is a narcissist of the highest order.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43413294</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43413294-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>seanw444</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Perhaps he is, but the field isn&#39;t worth discounting nonetheless, and he&#39;s one of the most prominent researchers of it.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43413524</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43413524-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>karparov</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Prominent definitely.But researcher? Does he actually research anything? He just claims lots of things. He is half-way to being a fiction author, just that he would never acknowledge that.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43414105</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43414105-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>Suppafly</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Did I get in before the Wolfram hate train started?
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43414686</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43414686-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>moregrist</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>It’s more like a continuous eye roll since 2002 when he released _A New Kind of Science_.I spent around 15 years working on stochastic lattice models. They can be amazing. They can also fail to capture the essence of the problem. Same with cellular automata.They’re definitely not _new_. They weren’t new in 2002. I’ve always viewed Conway’s game of life as an interesting deterministic variant of an Ising model, and Ising models date back to the 1920s.Most physicists I knew at the time looked at the book, shrugged, and kept working on what they were doing. I love lattice models, cellular automata, lattice fluid models, and the like. But they’re just one class of useful model.And yet because Wolfram has a perpetual money machine called Mathematica, he’s got a huge megaphone to advocate for himself.I’ll keep rolling my eyes. I don’t hate the guy, but he is just a little too into self-promotion for my taste.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415169</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415169-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>SubjectToChange</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>And yet because Wolfram has a perpetual money machine called Mathematica, he’s got a huge megaphone to advocate for himself.Wolfram primarily posts to his blog and occasionally publishes a book. He’s not exactly buying a marketing blitz with all of his money. Wolfram Research itself is primarily focused on other things too.I don’t know what it is about Stephen Wolfram that drives people crazy. Yes, he’s self aggrandizing, but he’s hardly unique in that respect. Simply read past it or roll your eyes and move on. But apparently there are more than a few people who can’t help themselves (even this thread is an example).
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415613</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415613-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>nxobject</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Not to weigh against Wolfram one last time, but he&#39;s (finally?) renamed Mathematica just &quot;Wolfram&quot;. Why he would toss out years of brand-related goodwill is beyond me.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415554</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415554-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>SubjectToChange</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Have you opening Mathematica recently? Or visited the product page for Mathematica[1]? The only change has been branding the language itself as the “Wolfram Language” where Mathematica is just one of their product offerings.[1]: https://www.wolfram.com/mathematica/?source=nav
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415680</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415680-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>nxobject</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>Mathematica is open on my computer as we speak (or, rather, now Wolfram.app). The &quot;About&quot; screen indicates &quot;Wolfram 14.2&quot;. I have a seat on an site licence.https://imgur.com/a/WUpSsF8(If you&#39;re interested in what I&#39;m currently doing with it, I&#39;m playing around with Mathematica&#39;s neural network library.)
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415775</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415775-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>FilosofumRex</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>you got to be joking, do you play with slide rules and abacus tooNN in Mathematica is a just a toy and artifact of a bygone era.  Try HuggingFace https://github.com/huggingface/courseor Karpathy&#39;s intro https://github.com/karpathy/nanoGPT
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43417148</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43417148-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>SubjectToChange</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>The &quot;About&quot; screen indicates &quot;Wolfram 14.2&quot;Mathematica (MMA) and the Wolfram Language (WL) used to be the one and the same. But now a user could be using WL in a web based notebook, through Wolfram Alpha, or even on SystemModeler.The brand name “Mathematica” isn’t going anywhere, not after nearly forty years. It’s basically marketing being like “how do we communicate updates to WL as not just being updates to MMA?”.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416131</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416131-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>kgwgk</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>&amp;gt; The brand name “Mathematica” isn’t going anywhereBut it’s not what it used to be. Now you don’t “run” Mathematica - you “access” it running another program. It’s basically marketing to weaken one brand and strengthen the other.“Upgrading from Mathematica to Wolfram”https://reference.wolfram.com/language/tutorial/UpgradingFro...
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43416289</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43416289-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>Suppafly</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>&amp;gt;I’ll keep rolling my eyes. I don’t hate the guy, but he is just a little too into self-promotion for my taste.That&#39;s fair, but a lot of the hate here is unreasonable.
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415433</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415433-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>MengerSponge</author><category></category></item><item><title></title><description>&quot;Still not sure which will become self-aware first: Wolfram Alpha, or Stephen Wolfram&quot;
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43415298</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43415298-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>dang</author><category></category></item><item><title>on: Google announces agreement to acquire Wiz</title><description>Comments moved thither. Thanks!
                      
                      reply
                  
      </description><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43401110</link><guid isPermaLink="false">43401110-reply</guid><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><author>dang</author><category></category></item></channel></rss>