<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Reviews handle:flow page:1 – Shopify App Store</title><link>https://apps.shopify.com/flow/reviews</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.pseudoyu.com/shopify/apps/flow/reviews" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Reviews handle:flow page:1 – Shopify App Store - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:28:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Flow is incredible and a must-have to extract maximum value from your Shopify subscription. The amount of 3rd party services and subscriptions you can...</title><description>Flow is incredible and a must-have to extract maximum value from your Shopify subscription. The amount of 3rd party services and subscriptions you can avoid by dedicating your time to Flow is, quite frankly, unbelievable.</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1682608</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>IppodoTea.com (USA &amp; CA)</author></item><item><title>Shopify Flow is an absolute must-have for any Shopify store looking to automate tasks and streamline operations. The app has helped us save so much ti...</title><description>Shopify Flow is an absolute must-have for any Shopify store looking to automate tasks and streamline operations. The app has helped us save so much time by automating order management, customer tagging, and email notifications. The workflow builder is easy to use, even without coding experience, and it integrates perfectly with other apps. This has been a game-changer for our efficiency—highly recommended!</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1678767</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>RoadMate Hub</author></item><item><title>Great app that made my job a lot easier and saved me money</title><description>Great app that made my job a lot easier and saved me money</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1678372</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>SunliteBG</author></item><item><title>I don&#39;t understand why there never seems to be enough information for an easy start. Spend more time learning how to run some of these apps that runni...</title><description>I don&#39;t understand why there never seems to be enough information for an easy start.  Spend more time learning how to run some of these apps that running your store.  Will update later.</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1664910</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Nicks Corner Store</author></item><item><title>Totally uncool. Very hard to use if your are not IT wiz. It supposedly replaces fraud filter which worked perfectly well and impossible to migrate bec...</title><description>Totally uncool. Very hard to use if your are not IT wiz. It supposedly replaces fraud filter which worked perfectly well and impossible to migrate because Shopify Instruction don&#39;t work</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1664874</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>GoGun® USA</author></item><item><title>I contacted DSers for a couple questions and Zico answered me , he was able to direct me to the right pages to resolve my problems , he was a big help...</title><description>I contacted DSers for a couple questions and Zico answered me , he was able to direct me to the right pages to resolve my problems , he was a big help and i apprciat him. Thank you .</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1659659</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Natural Home Finds</author></item><item><title>Helpful app. must use to save time and creating task with logic.</title><description>Helpful app. must use to save time and creating task with logic.</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1656612</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>HRIDZ</author></item><item><title>We are deeply concerned about Shopify’s transition to Shopify Flow for abandoned cart emails, which has significantly impacted merchants operating in...</title><description>We are deeply concerned about Shopify’s transition to Shopify Flow for abandoned cart emails, which has significantly impacted merchants operating in multiple languages. The previous notification system handled multilingual workflows seamlessly, allowing businesses to provide localized experiences for their customers. However, Shopify Flow lacks native multilanguage support, forcing merchants to adopt a more complex and less effective solution. This abrupt change disrupts established workflows, increases the effort required to manage simple tasks, and risks alienating customers who receive communications in the wrong language. We urge Shopify to reintroduce native multilanguage capabilities or provide flexibility to continue using the previous system, ensuring that all merchants can maintain high standards of customer engagement and trust.</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1651455</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Benfida</author></item><item><title>Real mixed bag here. Flow has become an integral part of how we operate our store but my god is it frustrating to use at times. I&#39;m here today writing...</title><description>Real mixed bag here. Flow has become an integral part of how we operate our store but my god is it frustrating to use at times. I&#39;m here today writing this review out of frustration at recent depreciations. Flow needs to warn us when things are changing instead of just pushing out updates and letting us find out when we go to create new flows or update old ones. I know there is a five star app here but it needs work to show it. Giving it 4 stars because the app is capable of a lot and I&#39;m glad we have it despite the rough edges.</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1636301</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Session Goods</author></item><item><title>A must in the My store Shop/App arena.</title><description>A must in the My store Shop/App arena.</description><link/><guid isPermaLink="false">1620055</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Adorn&amp;Amuse</author></item></channel></rss>