<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Huggingface Daily Papers</title><link>https://huggingface.co/papers</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.isrss.com/huggingface/daily-papers" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Huggingface Daily Papers - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:06:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Aligning Multimodal LLM with Human Preference: A Survey</title><description>Large language models (LLMs) can handle a wide variety of general tasks with simple prompts, without the need for task-specific training. Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs), built upon LLMs, have demonstrated impressive potential in tackling complex tasks involving visual, auditory, and textual data. However, critical issues related to truthfulness, safety, o1-like reasoning, and alignment with human preference remain insufficiently addressed. This gap has spurred the emergence of various alignment algorithms, each targeting different application scenarios and optimization goals. Recent studies have shown that alignment algorithms are a powerful approach to resolving the aforementioned challenges. In this paper, we aim to provide a comprehensive and systematic review of alignment algorithms for MLLMs. Specifically, we explore four key aspects: (1) the application scenarios covered by alignment algorithms, including general image understanding, multi-image, video, and audio, and extended multimodal applications; (2) the core factors in constructing alignment datasets, including data sources, model responses, and preference annotations; (3) the benchmarks used to evaluate alignment algorithms; and (4) a discussion of potential future directions for the development of alignment algorithms. This work seeks to help researchers organize current advancements in the field and inspire better alignment methods. The project page of this paper is available at https://github.com/BradyFU/Awesome-Multimodal-Large-Language-Models/tree/Alignment.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14504</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14504</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:59:56 GMT</pubDate><author>Tao Yu, Yi-Fan Zhang, Chaoyou Fu, Junkang Wu, Jinda Lu, Kun Wang, Xingyu Lu, Yunhang Shen, Guibin Zhang, Dingjie Song, Yibo Yan, Tianlong Xu, Qingsong Wen, Zhang Zhang, Yan Huang, Liang Wang, Tieniu Tan</author></item><item><title>Measuring AI Ability to Complete Long Tasks</title><description>Despite rapid progress on AI benchmarks, the real-world meaning of benchmark performance remains unclear. To quantify the capabilities of AI systems in terms of human capabilities, we propose a new metric: 50%-task-completion time horizon. This is the time humans typically take to complete tasks that AI models can complete with 50% success rate. We first timed humans with relevant domain expertise on a combination of RE-Bench, HCAST, and 66 novel shorter tasks. On these tasks, current frontier AI models such as Claude 3.7 Sonnet have a 50% time horizon of around 50 minutes. Furthermore, frontier AI time horizon has been doubling approximately every seven months since 2019, though the trend may have accelerated in 2024. The increase in AI models&#39; time horizons seems to be primarily driven by greater reliability and ability to adapt to mistakes, combined with better logical reasoning and tool use capabilities. We discuss the limitations of our results -- including their degree of external validity -- and the implications of increased autonomy for dangerous capabilities. If these results generalize to real-world software tasks, extrapolation of this trend predicts that within 5 years, AI systems will be capable of automating many software tasks that currently take humans a month.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14499</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14499</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:59:31 GMT</pubDate><author>Thomas Kwa, Ben West, Joel Becker, Amy Deng, Katharyn Garcia, Max Hasin, Sami Jawhar, Megan Kinniment, Nate Rush, Sydney Von Arx, Ryan Bloom, Thomas Broadley, Haoxing Du, Brian Goodrich, Nikola Jurkovic, Luke Harold Miles, Seraphina Nix, Tao Lin, Neev Parikh, David Rein, Lucas Jun Koba Sato, Hjalmar Wijk, Daniel M. Ziegler, Elizabeth Barnes, Lawrence Chan</author></item><item><title>Temporal Consistency for LLM Reasoning Process Error Identification</title><description>Verification is crucial for effective mathematical reasoning. We present a new temporal consistency method where verifiers iteratively refine their judgments based on the previous assessment. Unlike one-round verification or multi-model debate approaches, our method leverages consistency in a sequence of self-reflection actions to improve verification accuracy. Empirical evaluations across diverse mathematical process error identification benchmarks (Mathcheck, ProcessBench, and PRM800K) show consistent performance improvements over baseline methods. When applied to the recent DeepSeek R1 distilled models, our method demonstrates strong performance, enabling 7B/8B distilled models to outperform all 70B/72B models and GPT-4o on ProcessBench. Notably, the distilled 14B model with our method achieves performance comparable to Deepseek-R1. Our codes are available at https://github.com/jcguo123/Temporal-Consistency</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14495</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14495</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:58:28 GMT</pubDate><author>Jiacheng Guo, Yue Wu, Jiahao Qiu, Kaixuan Huang, Xinzhe Juan, Ling Yang, Mengdi Wang</author></item><item><title>Cosmos-Transfer1: Conditional World Generation with Adaptive Multimodal Control</title><description>We introduce Cosmos-Transfer, a conditional world generation model that can generate world simulations based on multiple spatial control inputs of various modalities such as segmentation, depth, and edge. In the design, the spatial conditional scheme is adaptive and customizable. It allows weighting different conditional inputs differently at different spatial locations. This enables highly controllable world generation and finds use in various world-to-world transfer use cases, including Sim2Real. We conduct extensive evaluations to analyze the proposed model and demonstrate its applications for Physical AI, including robotics Sim2Real and autonomous vehicle data enrichment. We further demonstrate an inference scaling strategy to achieve real-time world generation with an NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 rack. To help accelerate research development in the field, we open-source our models and code at https://github.com/nvidia-cosmos/cosmos-transfer1.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14492</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14492</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:57:54 GMT</pubDate><author>NVIDIA, Hassan Abu Alhaija, Jose Alvarez, Maciej Bala, Tiffany Cai, Tianshi Cao, Liz Cha, Joshua Chen, Mike Chen, Francesco Ferroni, Sanja Fidler, Dieter Fox, Yunhao Ge, Jinwei Gu, Ali Hassani, Michael Isaev, Pooya Jannaty, Shiyi Lan, Tobias Lasser, Huan Ling, Ming-Yu Liu, Xian Liu, Yifan Lu, Alice Luo, Qianli Ma, Hanzi Mao, Fabio Ramos, Xuanchi Ren, Tianchang Shen, Shitao Tang, Ting-Chun Wang, Jay Wu, Jiashu Xu, Stella Xu, Kevin Xie, Yuchong Ye, Xiaodong Yang, Xiaohui Zeng, Yu Zeng</author></item><item><title>Creation-MMBench: Assessing Context-Aware Creative Intelligence in MLLM</title><description>Creativity is a fundamental aspect of intelligence, involving the ability to generate novel and appropriate solutions across diverse contexts. While Large Language Models (LLMs) have been extensively evaluated for their creative capabilities, the assessment of Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) in this domain remains largely unexplored. To address this gap, we introduce Creation-MMBench, a multimodal benchmark specifically designed to evaluate the creative capabilities of MLLMs in real-world, image-based tasks. The benchmark comprises 765 test cases spanning 51 fine-grained tasks. To ensure rigorous evaluation, we define instance-specific evaluation criteria for each test case, guiding the assessment of both general response quality and factual consistency with visual inputs. Experimental results reveal that current open-source MLLMs significantly underperform compared to proprietary models in creative tasks. Furthermore, our analysis demonstrates that visual fine-tuning can negatively impact the base LLM&#39;s creative abilities. Creation-MMBench provides valuable insights for advancing MLLM creativity and establishes a foundation for future improvements in multimodal generative intelligence. Full data and evaluation code is released on https://github.com/open-compass/Creation-MMBench.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14478</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14478</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:51:34 GMT</pubDate><author>Xinyu Fang, Zhijian Chen, Kai Lan, Shengyuan Ding, Yingji Liang, Xiangyu Zhao, Farong Wen, Zicheng Zhang, Guofeng Zhang, Haodong Duan, Kai Chen, Dahua Lin</author></item><item><title>DAPO: An Open-Source LLM Reinforcement Learning System at Scale</title><description>Inference scaling empowers LLMs with unprecedented reasoning ability, with reinforcement learning as the core technique to elicit complex reasoning. However, key technical details of state-of-the-art reasoning LLMs are concealed (such as in OpenAI o1 blog and DeepSeek R1 technical report), thus the community still struggles to reproduce their RL training results. We propose the Decoupled Clip and Dynamic sAmpling Policy Optimization (DAPO) algorithm, and fully open-source a state-of-the-art large-scale RL system that achieves 50 points on AIME 2024 using Qwen2.5-32B base model. Unlike previous works that withhold training details, we introduce four key techniques of our algorithm that make large-scale LLM RL a success. In addition, we open-source our training code, which is built on the verl framework, along with a carefully curated and processed dataset. These components of our open-source system enhance reproducibility and support future research in large-scale LLM RL.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14476</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14476</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:49:06 GMT</pubDate><author>Qiying Yu, Zheng Zhang, Ruofei Zhu, Yufeng Yuan, Xiaochen Zuo, Yu Yue, Tiantian Fan, Gaohong Liu, Lingjun Liu, Xin Liu, Haibin Lin, Zhiqi Lin, Bole Ma, Guangming Sheng, Yuxuan Tong, Chi Zhang, Mofan Zhang, Wang Zhang, Hang Zhu, Jinhua Zhu, Jiaze Chen, Jiangjie Chen, Chengyi Wang, Hongli Yu, Weinan Dai, Yuxuan Song, Xiangpeng Wei, Hao Zhou, Jingjing Liu, Wei-Ying Ma, Ya-Qin Zhang, Lin Yan, Mu Qiao, Yonghui Wu, Mingxuan Wang</author></item><item><title>RWKV-7 &quot;Goose&quot; with Expressive Dynamic State Evolution</title><description>We present RWKV-7 &quot;Goose&quot;, a new sequence modeling architecture, along with pre-trained language models that establish a new state-of-the-art in downstream performance at the 3 billion parameter scale on multilingual tasks, and match current SoTA English language performance despite being trained on dramatically fewer tokens than other top 3B models. Nevertheless, RWKV-7 models require only constant memory usage and constant inference time per token. RWKV-7 introduces a newly generalized formulation of the delta rule with vector-valued gating and in-context learning rates, as well as a relaxed value replacement rule. We show that RWKV-7 can perform state tracking and recognize all regular languages, while retaining parallelizability of training. This exceeds the capabilities of Transformers under standard complexity conjectures, which are limited to TC^0. To demonstrate RWKV-7&#39;s language modeling capability, we also present an extended open source 3.1 trillion token multilingual corpus, and train four RWKV-7 models ranging from 0.19 billion to 2.9 billion parameters on this dataset.   To foster openness, reproduction, and adoption, we release our models and dataset component listing at https://huggingface.co/RWKV, and our training and inference code at https://github.com/RWKV/RWKV-LM all under the Apache 2.0 License.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14456</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14456</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:31:05 GMT</pubDate><author>Bo Peng, Ruichong Zhang, Daniel Goldstein, Eric Alcaide, Haowen Hou, Janna Lu, William Merrill, Guangyu Song, Kaifeng Tan, Saiteja Utpala, Nathan Wilce, Johan S. Wind, Tianyi Wu, Daniel Wuttke, Christian Zhou-Zheng</author></item><item><title>Impossible Videos</title><description>Synthetic videos nowadays is widely used to complement data scarcity and diversity of real-world videos. Current synthetic datasets primarily replicate real-world scenarios, leaving impossible, counterfactual and anti-reality video concepts underexplored. This work aims to answer two questions: 1) Can today&#39;s video generation models effectively follow prompts to create impossible video content? 2) Are today&#39;s video understanding models good enough for understanding impossible videos? To this end, we introduce IPV-Bench, a novel benchmark designed to evaluate and foster progress in video understanding and generation. IPV-Bench is underpinned by a comprehensive taxonomy, encompassing 4 domains, 14 categories. It features diverse scenes that defy physical, biological, geographical, or social laws. Based on the taxonomy, a prompt suite is constructed to evaluate video generation models, challenging their prompt following and creativity capabilities. In addition, a video benchmark is curated to assess Video-LLMs on their ability of understanding impossible videos, which particularly requires reasoning on temporal dynamics and world knowledge. Comprehensive evaluations reveal limitations and insights for future directions of video models, paving the way for next-generation video models.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14378</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14378</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:10:24 GMT</pubDate><author>Zechen Bai, Hai Ci, Mike Zheng Shou</author></item><item><title>Concat-ID: Towards Universal Identity-Preserving Video Synthesis</title><description>We present Concat-ID, a unified framework for identity-preserving video generation. Concat-ID employs Variational Autoencoders to extract image features, which are concatenated with video latents along the sequence dimension, leveraging solely 3D self-attention mechanisms without the need for additional modules. A novel cross-video pairing strategy and a multi-stage training regimen are introduced to balance identity consistency and facial editability while enhancing video naturalness. Extensive experiments demonstrate Concat-ID&#39;s superiority over existing methods in both single and multi-identity generation, as well as its seamless scalability to multi-subject scenarios, including virtual try-on and background-controllable generation. Concat-ID establishes a new benchmark for identity-preserving video synthesis, providing a versatile and scalable solution for a wide range of applications.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14151</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14151</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:17:32 GMT</pubDate><author>Yong Zhong, Zhuoyi Yang, Jiayan Teng, Xiaotao Gu, Chongxuan Li</author></item><item><title>Frac-Connections: Fractional Extension of Hyper-Connections</title><description>Residual connections are central to modern deep learning architectures, enabling the training of very deep networks by mitigating gradient vanishing. Hyper-Connections recently generalized residual connections by introducing multiple connection strengths at different depths, thereby addressing the seesaw effect between gradient vanishing and representation collapse. However, Hyper-Connections increase memory access costs by expanding the width of hidden states. In this paper, we propose Frac-Connections, a novel approach that divides hidden states into multiple parts rather than expanding their width. Frac-Connections retain partial benefits of Hyper-Connections while reducing memory consumption. To validate their effectiveness, we conduct large-scale experiments on language tasks, with the largest being a 7B MoE model trained on up to 3T tokens, demonstrating that Frac-Connections significantly outperform residual connections.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14125</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14125</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 06:37:50 GMT</pubDate><author>Defa Zhu, Hongzhi Huang, Jundong Zhou, Zihao Huang, Yutao Zeng, Banggu Wu, Qiyang Min, Xun Zhou</author></item><item><title>MeshFleet: Filtered and Annotated 3D Vehicle Dataset for Domain Specific Generative Modeling</title><description>Generative models have recently made remarkable progress in the field of 3D objects. However, their practical application in fields like engineering remains limited since they fail to deliver the accuracy, quality, and controllability needed for domain-specific tasks. Fine-tuning large generative models is a promising perspective for making these models available in these fields. Creating high-quality, domain-specific 3D datasets is crucial for fine-tuning large generative models, yet the data filtering and annotation process remains a significant bottleneck. We present MeshFleet, a filtered and annotated 3D vehicle dataset extracted from Objaverse-XL, the most extensive publicly available collection of 3D objects. Our approach proposes a pipeline for automated data filtering based on a quality classifier. This classifier is trained on a manually labeled subset of Objaverse, incorporating DINOv2 and SigLIP embeddings, refined through caption-based analysis and uncertainty estimation. We demonstrate the efficacy of our filtering method through a comparative analysis against caption and image aesthetic score-based techniques and fine-tuning experiments with SV3D, highlighting the importance of targeted data selection for domain-specific 3D generative modeling.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14002</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.14002</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 04:09:24 GMT</pubDate><author>Damian Boborzi, Phillip Mueller, Jonas Emrich, Dominik Schmid, Sebastian Mueller, Lars Mikelsons</author></item><item><title>Pensez: Less Data, Better Reasoning -- Rethinking French LLM</title><description>Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in various natural language processing tasks. However, achieving strong performance in specialized domains like mathematical reasoning and non-English languages often requires extensive training on massive datasets. This paper investigates a contrasting approach: strategic fine-tuning on a small, high-quality, bilingual (English-French) dataset to enhance both the reasoning capabilities and French language proficiency of a large language model. Rather than relying on scale, we explore the hypothesis that targeted data curation and optimized training can achieve competitive, or even superior, performance. We demonstrate, through targeted supervised fine-tuning (SFT) on only 2,000 carefully selected samples, significant improvements in mathematical reasoning. Specifically, Pensez 7B exhibits an increase in accuracy of the base model up to 20% on the AIME25 and a 12% increase on a French MATH level 5 benchmark. These results challenge the prevailing assumption that massive datasets are aprerequisite for strong reasoning performance in LLMs, highlighting the potential of strategic data curation and optimized fine-tuning for enhancing both specialized skills and multilingual capabilities. Our findings have implications for the efficient development of high-performing, multilingual LLMs, especially in resource-constrained scenarios.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13661</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13661</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 15:09:11 GMT</pubDate><author>Huy Hoang Ha</author></item><item><title>Infinite Mobility: Scalable High-Fidelity Synthesis of Articulated Objects via Procedural Generation</title><description>Large-scale articulated objects with high quality are desperately needed for multiple tasks related to embodied AI. Most existing methods for creating articulated objects are either data-driven or simulation based, which are limited by the scale and quality of the training data or the fidelity and heavy labour of the simulation. In this paper, we propose Infinite Mobility, a novel method for synthesizing high-fidelity articulated objects through procedural generation. User study and quantitative evaluation demonstrate that our method can produce results that excel current state-of-the-art methods and are comparable to human-annotated datasets in both physics property and mesh quality. Furthermore, we show that our synthetic data can be used as training data for generative models, enabling next-step scaling up. Code is available at https://github.com/Intern-Nexus/Infinite-Mobility</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13424</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13424</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 13:53:56 GMT</pubDate><author>Xinyu Lian, Zichao Yu, Ruiming Liang, Yitong Wang, Li Ray Luo, Kaixu Chen, Yuanzhen Zhou, Qihong Tang, Xudong Xu, Zhaoyang Lyu, Bo Dai, Jiangmiao Pang</author></item><item><title>FlexWorld: Progressively Expanding 3D Scenes for Flexiable-View Synthesis</title><description>Generating flexible-view 3D scenes, including 360{\deg} rotation and zooming, from single images is challenging due to a lack of 3D data. To this end, we introduce FlexWorld, a novel framework consisting of two key components: (1) a strong video-to-video (V2V) diffusion model to generate high-quality novel view images from incomplete input rendered from a coarse scene, and (2) a progressive expansion process to construct a complete 3D scene. In particular, leveraging an advanced pre-trained video model and accurate depth-estimated training pairs, our V2V model can generate novel views under large camera pose variations. Building upon it, FlexWorld progressively generates new 3D content and integrates it into the global scene through geometry-aware scene fusion. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of FlexWorld in generating high-quality novel view videos and flexible-view 3D scenes from single images, achieving superior visual quality under multiple popular metrics and datasets compared to existing state-of-the-art methods. Qualitatively, we highlight that FlexWorld can generate high-fidelity scenes with flexible views like 360{\deg} rotations and zooming. Project page: https://ml-gsai.github.io/FlexWorld.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13265</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13265</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 11:18:38 GMT</pubDate><author>Luxi Chen, Zihan Zhou, Min Zhao, Yikai Wang, Ge Zhang, Wenhao Huang, Hao Sun, Ji-Rong Wen, Chongxuan Li</author></item><item><title>MM-Spatial: Exploring 3D Spatial Understanding in Multimodal LLMs</title><description>Multimodal large language models (MLLMs) excel at 2D visual understanding but remain limited in their ability to reason about 3D space. In this work, we leverage large-scale high-quality 3D scene data with open-set annotations to introduce 1) a novel supervised fine-tuning dataset and 2) a new evaluation benchmark, focused on indoor scenes. Our Cubify Anything VQA (CA-VQA) data covers diverse spatial tasks including spatial relationship prediction, metric size and distance estimation, and 3D grounding. We show that CA-VQA enables us to train MM-Spatial, a strong generalist MLLM that also achieves state-of-the-art performance on 3D spatial understanding benchmarks, including our own. We show how incorporating metric depth and multi-view inputs (provided in CA-VQA) can further improve 3D understanding, and demonstrate that data alone allows our model to achieve depth perception capabilities comparable to dedicated monocular depth estimation models. We will publish our SFT dataset and benchmark.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13111</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13111</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 08:34:22 GMT</pubDate><author>Erik Daxberger, Nina Wenzel, David Griffiths, Haiming Gang, Justin Lazarow, Gefen Kohavi, Kai Kang, Marcin Eichner, Yinfei Yang, Afshin Dehghan, Peter Grasch</author></item><item><title>DeepPerception: Advancing R1-like Cognitive Visual Perception in MLLMs for Knowledge-Intensive Visual Grounding</title><description>Human experts excel at fine-grained visual discrimination by leveraging domain knowledge to refine perceptual features, a capability that remains underdeveloped in current Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs). Despite possessing vast expert-level knowledge, MLLMs struggle to integrate reasoning into visual perception, often generating direct responses without deeper analysis. To bridge this gap, we introduce knowledge-intensive visual grounding (KVG), a novel visual grounding task that requires both fine-grained perception and domain-specific knowledge integration. To address the challenges of KVG, we propose DeepPerception, an MLLM enhanced with cognitive visual perception capabilities. Our approach consists of (1) an automated data synthesis pipeline that generates high-quality, knowledge-aligned training samples, and (2) a two-stage training framework combining supervised fine-tuning for cognitive reasoning scaffolding and reinforcement learning to optimize perception-cognition synergy. To benchmark performance, we introduce KVG-Bench a comprehensive dataset spanning 10 domains with 1.3K manually curated test cases. Experimental results demonstrate that DeepPerception significantly outperforms direct fine-tuning, achieving +8.08\% accuracy improvements on KVG-Bench and exhibiting +4.60\% superior cross-domain generalization over baseline approaches. Our findings highlight the importance of integrating cognitive processes into MLLMs for human-like visual perception and open new directions for multimodal reasoning research. The data, codes, and models are released at https://github.com/thunlp/DeepPerception.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12797</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12797</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:06:34 GMT</pubDate><author>Xinyu Ma, Ziyang Ding, Zhicong Luo, Chi Chen, Zonghao Guo, Derek F. Wong, Xiaoyi Feng, Maosong Sun</author></item><item><title>PEBench: A Fictitious Dataset to Benchmark Machine Unlearning for Multimodal Large Language Models</title><description>In recent years, Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have demonstrated remarkable advancements in tasks such as visual question answering, visual understanding, and reasoning. However, this impressive progress relies on vast amounts of data collected from the internet, raising significant concerns about privacy and security. To address these issues, machine unlearning (MU) has emerged as a promising solution, enabling the removal of specific knowledge from an already trained model without requiring retraining from scratch. Although MU for MLLMs has gained attention, current evaluations of its efficacy remain incomplete, and the underlying problem is often poorly defined, which hinders the development of strategies for creating more secure and trustworthy systems. To bridge this gap, we introduce a benchmark, named PEBench, which includes a dataset of personal entities and corresponding general event scenes, designed to comprehensively assess the performance of MU for MLLMs. Through PEBench, we aim to provide a standardized and robust framework to advance research in secure and privacy-preserving multimodal models. We benchmarked 6 MU methods, revealing their strengths and limitations, and shedding light on key challenges and opportunities for MU in MLLMs.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12545</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12545</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 11:26:20 GMT</pubDate><author>Zhaopan Xu, Pengfei Zhou, Weidong Tang, Jiaxin Ai, Wangbo Zhao, Xiaojiang Peng, Kai Wang, Yang You, Wenqi Shao, Hongxun Yao, Kaipeng Zhang</author></item><item><title>MPBench: A Comprehensive Multimodal Reasoning Benchmark for Process Errors Identification</title><description>Reasoning is an essential capacity for large language models (LLMs) to address complex tasks, where the identification of process errors is vital for improving this ability. Recently, process-level reward models (PRMs) were proposed to provide step-wise rewards that facilitate reinforcement learning and data production during training and guide LLMs toward correct steps during inference, thereby improving reasoning accuracy. However, existing benchmarks of PRMs are text-based and focus on error detection, neglecting other scenarios like reasoning search. To address this gap, we introduce MPBench, a comprehensive, multi-task, multimodal benchmark designed to systematically assess the effectiveness of PRMs in diverse scenarios. MPBench employs three evaluation paradigms, each targeting a specific role of PRMs in the reasoning process: (1) Step Correctness, which assesses the correctness of each intermediate reasoning step; (2) Answer Aggregation, which aggregates multiple solutions and selects the best one; and (3) Reasoning Process Search, which guides the search for optimal reasoning steps during inference. Through these paradigms, MPBench makes comprehensive evaluations and provides insights into the development of multimodal PRMs.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12505</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12505</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 09:50:38 GMT</pubDate><author>Zhaopan Xu, Pengfei Zhou, Jiaxin Ai, Wangbo Zhao, Kai Wang, Xiaojiang Peng, Wenqi Shao, Hongxun Yao, Kaipeng Zhang</author></item><item><title>Atlas: Multi-Scale Attention Improves Long Context Image Modeling</title><description>Efficiently modeling massive images is a long-standing challenge in machine learning. To this end, we introduce Multi-Scale Attention (MSA). MSA relies on two key ideas, (i) multi-scale representations (ii) bi-directional cross-scale communication. MSA creates O(log N) scales to represent the image across progressively coarser features and leverages cross-attention to propagate information across scales. We then introduce Atlas, a novel neural network architecture based on MSA. We demonstrate that Atlas significantly improves the compute-performance tradeoff of long-context image modeling in a high-resolution variant of ImageNet 100. At 1024px resolution, Atlas-B achieves 91.04% accuracy, comparable to ConvNext-B (91.92%) while being 4.3x faster. Atlas is 2.95x faster and 7.38% better than FasterViT, 2.25x faster and 4.96% better than LongViT. In comparisons against MambaVision-S, we find Atlas-S achieves 5%, 16% and 32% higher accuracy at 1024px, 2048px and 4096px respectively, while obtaining similar runtimes. Code for reproducing our experiments and pretrained models is available at https://github.com/yalalab/atlas.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12355</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12355</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:52:13 GMT</pubDate><author>Kumar Krishna Agrawal, Long Lian, Longchao Liu, Natalia Harguindeguy, Boyi Li, Alexander Bick, Maggie Chung, Trevor Darrell, Adam Yala</author></item><item><title>CapArena: Benchmarking and Analyzing Detailed Image Captioning in the LLM Era</title><description>Image captioning has been a longstanding challenge in vision-language research. With the rise of LLMs, modern Vision-Language Models (VLMs) generate detailed and comprehensive image descriptions. However, benchmarking the quality of such captions remains unresolved. This paper addresses two key questions: (1) How well do current VLMs actually perform on image captioning, particularly compared to humans? We built CapArena, a platform with over 6000 pairwise caption battles and high-quality human preference votes. Our arena-style evaluation marks a milestone, showing that leading models like GPT-4o achieve or even surpass human performance, while most open-source models lag behind. (2) Can automated metrics reliably assess detailed caption quality? Using human annotations from CapArena, we evaluate traditional and recent captioning metrics, as well as VLM-as-a-Judge. Our analysis reveals that while some metrics (e.g., METEOR) show decent caption-level agreement with humans, their systematic biases lead to inconsistencies in model ranking. In contrast, VLM-as-a-Judge demonstrates robust discernment at both the caption and model levels. Building on these insights, we release CapArena-Auto, an accurate and efficient automated benchmark for detailed captioning, achieving 94.3% correlation with human rankings at just $4 per test. Data and resources will be open-sourced at https://caparena.github.io.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12329</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12329</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 22:56:09 GMT</pubDate><author>Kanzhi Cheng, Wenpo Song, Jiaxin Fan, Zheng Ma, Qiushi Sun, Fangzhi Xu, Chenyang Yan, Nuo Chen, Jianbing Zhang, Jiajun Chen</author></item><item><title>Towards Self-Improving Systematic Cognition for Next-Generation Foundation MLLMs</title><description>Despite their impressive capabilities, Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) face challenges with fine-grained perception and complex reasoning. Prevalent multimodal pre-training approaches focus on enhancing perception by training on high-quality image captions due to the extremely high cost of collecting chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning data for improving reasoning. While leveraging advanced MLLMs for caption generation enhances scalability, the outputs often lack comprehensiveness and accuracy. In this paper, we introduce Self-Improving cognition (SIcog), a self-learning framework designed to construct next-generation foundation MLLMs by enhancing their systematic cognitive capabilities through multimodal pre-training with self-generated data. Specifically, we propose Chain-of-Description, an approach that improves an MLLM&#39;s systematic perception by enabling step-by-step visual understanding, ensuring greater comprehensiveness and accuracy. Additionally, we adopt a structured CoT reasoning technique to enable MLLMs to integrate in-depth multimodal reasoning. To construct a next-generation foundation MLLM with self-improved cognition, SIcog first equips an MLLM with systematic perception and reasoning abilities using minimal external annotations. The enhanced models then generate detailed captions and CoT reasoning data, which are further curated through self-consistency. This curated data is ultimately used for multimodal pre-training to develop next-generation foundation models. Extensive experiments on both low- and high-resolution MLLMs across diverse benchmarks demonstrate that, with merely 213K self-generated pre-training samples, SIcog produces next-generation foundation MLLMs with significantly improved cognition, achieving benchmark-leading performance compared to prevalent pre-training approaches.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12303</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12303</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:25:13 GMT</pubDate><author>Xiaoying Zhang, Da Peng, Yipeng Zhang, Zonghao Guo, Chengyue Wu, Chi Chen, Wei Ke, Helen Meng, Maosong Sun</author></item><item><title>Reflect-DiT: Inference-Time Scaling for Text-to-Image Diffusion Transformers via In-Context Reflection</title><description>The predominant approach to advancing text-to-image generation has been training-time scaling, where larger models are trained on more data using greater computational resources. While effective, this approach is computationally expensive, leading to growing interest in inference-time scaling to improve performance. Currently, inference-time scaling for text-to-image diffusion models is largely limited to best-of-N sampling, where multiple images are generated per prompt and a selection model chooses the best output. Inspired by the recent success of reasoning models like DeepSeek-R1 in the language domain, we introduce an alternative to naive best-of-N sampling by equipping text-to-image Diffusion Transformers with in-context reflection capabilities. We propose Reflect-DiT, a method that enables Diffusion Transformers to refine their generations using in-context examples of previously generated images alongside textual feedback describing necessary improvements. Instead of passively relying on random sampling and hoping for a better result in a future generation, Reflect-DiT explicitly tailors its generations to address specific aspects requiring enhancement. Experimental results demonstrate that Reflect-DiT improves performance on the GenEval benchmark (+0.19) using SANA-1.0-1.6B as a base model. Additionally, it achieves a new state-of-the-art score of 0.81 on GenEval while generating only 20 samples per prompt, surpassing the previous best score of 0.80, which was obtained using a significantly larger model (SANA-1.5-4.8B) with 2048 samples under the best-of-N approach.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12271</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12271</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 17:58:12 GMT</pubDate><author>Shufan Li, Konstantinos Kallidromitis, Akash Gokul, Arsh Koneru, Yusuke Kato, Kazuki Kozuka, Aditya Grover</author></item><item><title>Hyperbolic Safety-Aware Vision-Language Models</title><description>Addressing the retrieval of unsafe content from vision-language models such as CLIP is an important step towards real-world integration. Current efforts have relied on unlearning techniques that try to erase the model&#39;s knowledge of unsafe concepts. While effective in reducing unwanted outputs, unlearning limits the model&#39;s capacity to discern between safe and unsafe content. In this work, we introduce a novel approach that shifts from unlearning to an awareness paradigm by leveraging the inherent hierarchical properties of the hyperbolic space. We propose to encode safe and unsafe content as an entailment hierarchy, where both are placed in different regions of hyperbolic space. Our HySAC, Hyperbolic Safety-Aware CLIP, employs entailment loss functions to model the hierarchical and asymmetrical relations between safe and unsafe image-text pairs. This modelling, ineffective in standard vision-language models due to their reliance on Euclidean embeddings, endows the model with awareness of unsafe content, enabling it to serve as both a multimodal unsafe classifier and a flexible content retriever, with the option to dynamically redirect unsafe queries toward safer alternatives or retain the original output. Extensive experiments show that our approach not only enhances safety recognition but also establishes a more adaptable and interpretable framework for content moderation in vision-language models. Our source code is available at https://github.com/aimagelab/HySAC.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12127</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.12127</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 09:18:04 GMT</pubDate><author>Tobia Poppi, Tejaswi Kasarla, Pascal Mettes, Lorenzo Baraldi, Rita Cucchiara</author></item><item><title>Learning to Inference Adaptively for Multimodal Large Language Models</title><description>Multimodal Large Language Models (MLLMs) have shown impressive capabilities in reasoning, yet come with substantial computational cost, limiting their deployment in resource-constrained settings. Despite recent efforts on improving the efficiency of MLLMs, prior solutions fall short in responding to varying runtime conditions, in particular changing resource availability (e.g., contention due to the execution of other programs on the device). To bridge this gap, we introduce AdaLLaVA, an adaptive inference framework that learns to dynamically reconfigure operations in an MLLM during inference, accounting for the input data and a latency budget. We conduct extensive experiments across benchmarks involving question-answering, reasoning, and hallucination. Our results show that AdaLLaVA effectively adheres to input latency budget, achieving varying accuracy and latency tradeoffs at runtime. Further, we demonstrate that AdaLLaVA adapts to both input latency and content, can be integrated with token selection for enhanced efficiency, and generalizes across MLLMs. Our project webpage with code release is at https://zhuoyan-xu.github.io/ada-llava/.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10905</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10905</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 17:39:38 GMT</pubDate><author>Zhuoyan Xu, Khoi Duc Nguyen, Preeti Mukherjee, Saurabh Bagchi, Somali Chaterji, Yingyu Liang, Yin Li</author></item><item><title>KUDA: Keypoints to Unify Dynamics Learning and Visual Prompting for Open-Vocabulary Robotic Manipulation</title><description>With the rapid advancement of large language models (LLMs) and vision-language models (VLMs), significant progress has been made in developing open-vocabulary robotic manipulation systems. However, many existing approaches overlook the importance of object dynamics, limiting their applicability to more complex, dynamic tasks. In this work, we introduce KUDA, an open-vocabulary manipulation system that integrates dynamics learning and visual prompting through keypoints, leveraging both VLMs and learning-based neural dynamics models. Our key insight is that a keypoint-based target specification is simultaneously interpretable by VLMs and can be efficiently translated into cost functions for model-based planning. Given language instructions and visual observations, KUDA first assigns keypoints to the RGB image and queries the VLM to generate target specifications. These abstract keypoint-based representations are then converted into cost functions, which are optimized using a learned dynamics model to produce robotic trajectories. We evaluate KUDA on a range of manipulation tasks, including free-form language instructions across diverse object categories, multi-object interactions, and deformable or granular objects, demonstrating the effectiveness of our framework. The project page is available at http://kuda-dynamics.github.io.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10546</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10546</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 12:59:17 GMT</pubDate><author>Zixian Liu, Mingtong Zhang, Yunzhu Li</author></item><item><title>AudioX: Diffusion Transformer for Anything-to-Audio Generation</title><description>Audio and music generation have emerged as crucial tasks in many applications, yet existing approaches face significant limitations: they operate in isolation without unified capabilities across modalities, suffer from scarce high-quality, multi-modal training data, and struggle to effectively integrate diverse inputs. In this work, we propose AudioX, a unified Diffusion Transformer model for Anything-to-Audio and Music Generation. Unlike previous domain-specific models, AudioX can generate both general audio and music with high quality, while offering flexible natural language control and seamless processing of various modalities including text, video, image, music, and audio. Its key innovation is a multi-modal masked training strategy that masks inputs across modalities and forces the model to learn from masked inputs, yielding robust and unified cross-modal representations. To address data scarcity, we curate two comprehensive datasets: vggsound-caps with 190K audio captions based on the VGGSound dataset, and V2M-caps with 6 million music captions derived from the V2M dataset. Extensive experiments demonstrate that AudioX not only matches or outperforms state-of-the-art specialized models, but also offers remarkable versatility in handling diverse input modalities and generation tasks within a unified architecture. The code and datasets will be available at https://zeyuet.github.io/AudioX/</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10522</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10522</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 12:30:59 GMT</pubDate><author>Zeyue Tian, Yizhu Jin, Zhaoyang Liu, Ruibin Yuan, Xu Tan, Qifeng Chen, Wei Xue, Yike Guo</author></item><item><title>RoCo-Sim: Enhancing Roadside Collaborative Perception through Foreground Simulation</title><description>Roadside Collaborative Perception refers to a system where multiple roadside units collaborate to pool their perceptual data, assisting vehicles in enhancing their environmental awareness. Existing roadside perception methods concentrate on model design but overlook data issues like calibration errors, sparse information, and multi-view consistency, leading to poor performance on recent published datasets. To significantly enhance roadside collaborative perception and address critical data issues, we present the first simulation framework RoCo-Sim for road-side collaborative perception. RoCo-Sim is capable of generating diverse, multi-view consistent simulated roadside data through dynamic foreground editing and full-scene style transfer of a single image. RoCo-Sim consists of four components: (1) Camera Extrinsic Optimization ensures accurate 3D to 2D projection for roadside cameras; (2) A novel Multi-View Occlusion-Aware Sampler (MOAS) determines the placement of diverse digital assets within 3D space; (3) DepthSAM innovatively models foreground-background relationships from single-frame fixed-view images, ensuring multi-view consistency of foreground; and (4) Scalable Post-Processing Toolkit generates more realistic and enriched scenes through style transfer and other enhancements. RoCo-Sim significantly improves roadside 3D object detection, outperforming SOTA methods by 83.74 on Rcooper-Intersection and 83.12 on TUMTraf-V2X for AP70. RoCo-Sim fills a critical gap in roadside perception simulation. Code and pre-trained models will be released soon: https://github.com/duyuwen-duen/RoCo-Sim</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10410</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.10410</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 10:33:42 GMT</pubDate><author>Yuwen Du, Anning Hu, Zichen Chao, Yifan Lu, Junhao Ge, Genjia Liu, Weitao Wu, Lanjun Wang, Siheng Chen</author></item><item><title>Florenz: Scaling Laws for Systematic Generalization in Vision-Language Models</title><description>Cross-lingual transfer enables vision-language models (VLMs) to perform vision tasks in various languages with training data only in one language. Current approaches rely on large pre-trained multilingual language models. However, they face the curse of multilinguality, sacrificing downstream task performance for multilingual capabilities, struggling with lexical ambiguities, and falling behind recent advances. In this work, we study the scaling laws of systematic generalization with monolingual VLMs for multilingual tasks, focusing on the impact of model size and seen training samples. We propose Florenz, a monolingual encoder-decoder VLM with 0.4B to 11.2B parameters combining the pre-trained VLM Florence-2 and the large language model Gemma-2. Florenz is trained with varying compute budgets on a synthetic dataset that features intentionally incomplete language coverage for image captioning, thus, testing generalization from the fully covered translation task. We show that not only does indirectly learning unseen task-language pairs adhere to a scaling law, but also that with our data generation pipeline and the proposed Florenz model family, image captioning abilities can emerge in a specific language even when only data for the translation task is available. Fine-tuning on a mix of downstream datasets yields competitive performance and demonstrates promising scaling trends in multimodal machine translation (Multi30K, CoMMuTE), lexical disambiguation (CoMMuTE), and image captioning (Multi30K, XM3600, COCO Karpathy).</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.09443</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.09443</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 10:41:10 GMT</pubDate><author>Julian Spravil, Sebastian Houben, Sven Behnke</author></item><item><title>EvalTree: Profiling Language Model Weaknesses via Hierarchical Capability Trees</title><description>An ideal model evaluation should achieve two goals: identifying where the model fails and providing actionable improvement guidance. Toward these goals for Language Model (LM) evaluations, we formulate the problem of generating a weakness profile, a set of weaknesses expressed in natural language, given an LM&#39;s performance on every individual instance in a benchmark. We introduce a suite of quantitative assessments to compare different weakness profiling methods. We also propose a weakness profiling method EvalTree. It constructs a capability tree where each node represents a capability described in natural language and is linked to a subset of benchmark instances that specifically evaluate this capability; it then extracts nodes where the LM performs poorly to generate a weakness profile. On the MATH and WildChat benchmarks, we show that EvalTree outperforms baseline weakness profiling methods by identifying weaknesses more precisely and comprehensively. Weakness profiling further enables weakness-guided data collection, and training data collection guided by EvalTree-identified weaknesses improves LM performance more than other data collection strategies. We also show how EvalTree exposes flaws in Chatbot Arena&#39;s human-voter-based evaluation practice. To facilitate future work, we release our code and an interface that allows practitioners to interactively explore the capability trees built by EvalTree.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.08893</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.08893</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 17:12:48 GMT</pubDate><author>Zhiyuan Zeng, Yizhong Wang, Hannaneh Hajishirzi, Pang Wei Koh</author></item><item><title>CoLMDriver: LLM-based Negotiation Benefits Cooperative Autonomous Driving</title><description>Vehicle-to-vehicle (V2V) cooperative autonomous driving holds great promise for improving safety by addressing the perception and prediction uncertainties inherent in single-agent systems. However, traditional cooperative methods are constrained by rigid collaboration protocols and limited generalization to unseen interactive scenarios. While LLM-based approaches offer generalized reasoning capabilities, their challenges in spatial planning and unstable inference latency hinder their direct application in cooperative driving. To address these limitations, we propose CoLMDriver, the first full-pipeline LLM-based cooperative driving system, enabling effective language-based negotiation and real-time driving control. CoLMDriver features a parallel driving pipeline with two key components: (i) an LLM-based negotiation module under an actor-critic paradigm, which continuously refines cooperation policies through feedback from previous decisions of all vehicles; and (ii) an intention-guided waypoint generator, which translates negotiation outcomes into executable waypoints. Additionally, we introduce InterDrive, a CARLA-based simulation benchmark comprising 10 challenging interactive driving scenarios for evaluating V2V cooperation. Experimental results demonstrate that CoLMDriver significantly outperforms existing approaches, achieving an 11% higher success rate across diverse highly interactive V2V driving scenarios. Code will be released on https://github.com/cxliu0314/CoLMDriver.</description><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.08683</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.08683</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:58:42 GMT</pubDate><author>Changxing Liu, Genjia Liu, Zijun Wang, Jinchang Yang, Siheng Chen</author></item></channel></rss>