<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Followin</title><link>https://followin.io</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.speednet.icu/followin" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Followin - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://followin.io/favicon.ico</url><title>Followin</title><link>https://followin.io</link></image><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:20:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title></title><description>Bitcoin has now formed a high volume bar closing above the recent 9day CVAH. If we&#39;re going to see upside buyers will have to step in at 85k for a potential move into the pMonth VAL where the real test will be.
Any break back below the 9day CVAH indicates a failed break from… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902438392714912029 </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934461</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934461</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:13:53 GMT</pubDate><author>C2M</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>Abu Dhabi will invest $2B in the market to start a BIGGEST Bull Run&lt;br&gt;This week, we will see the last fluctuation and $BTC will go to $300k&lt;br&gt;We have little time left to buy low-caps before Alt Season kicks off 👇🧵  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/c80994878624f9a5b946ef3dfe4d0e39.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  I&#39;ll share $10,000 to 25 winners&lt;br&gt;To participate - like, rt &amp;amp; leave your wallet under the FIRST tweet&lt;br&gt;I hope you can multiply this money with low-caps in this thread  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/7690641e0d6b3345733fe29acbb7014d.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Every crypto cycle - is a series of shakes, and fake downstream that scare degens, allowing whales to buy cheap alts&lt;br&gt;The biggest shakes and fluctuations occur just before the uptrend phase&lt;br&gt;In this phase, ppl have the last chance to accumulate before the parabolic rally begins  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/6a19131dbf2b43069e095bfaef4696e9.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  By the end of this month, we will definitely come out of the oscillation phase&lt;br&gt;And see the last shakeout, after which the market will go parabolic, and $BTC will reach a new ATH&lt;br&gt;Look at the 2021 cycle chart, a big shakeout led to a massive bull run right after that  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/478becf117ab4008e284fd7ce53f23b7.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Another catalyst for $BTC to break new ATH - Abu Dhabi&#39;s recent $2B investment in Binance&lt;br&gt;CZ said: investment would flow into alts that Binance supports&lt;br&gt;I tracked Binance wallets to see what tokens they are currently accumulating&lt;br&gt;List of low-cap alts with 1000x perspective 👇  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/7ea0bbc241bc88d438f3cea834938c3a.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  The fastest SOL copy-trading bot with MEV protection&lt;br&gt;http://t.me/toxi_solana_bot?start=ref-jetstart&lt;br&gt;Tested for a month - nothing beats it &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  1 ✧ @JupiterExchange | $JUP | MC: $1.43B&lt;br&gt;Jupiter is a DEX aggregator for swapping tokens at optimal prices with low slippage and fees in the Solana ecosystem&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - JUPyiwrYJFskUPiHa7hkeR8VUtAeFoSYbKedZNsDvCN  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/be7f4f1083fb9514562356950123c0df.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  2 ✧ @helium | $HNT | MC: $582.15M&lt;br&gt;Helium is a blockchain network for IoT, enabling data sharing through specialized nodes&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - hntyVP6YFm1Hg25TN9WGLqM12b8TQmcknKrdu1oxWux  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/30efaf3ac154bb2890bcfc85dcb0bba0.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  3 ✧ @bandprotocol | $BAND | MC: $126.84M&lt;br&gt;Band Protocol is a cross-chain data oracle linking real-world data and APIs to smart contracts&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - 0xba11d00c5f74255f56a5e366f4f77f5a186d7f55  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/3ad1abafb48433576c42a823a686402c.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  4 ✧ @Filecoin | $FIL | MC: $1.93B&lt;br&gt;Filecoin is a leading open-source, decentralized data storage system to &quot;store humanity&#39;s crucial information&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - 0x0d8ce2a99bb6e3b7db580ed848240e4a0f9ae153  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/544ea23308cf33a44dca93f77b26eaa8.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  5 ✧ @PancakeSwap | $CAKE | MC: $681.48M&lt;br&gt;Pancakeswap is Binance&#39;s top DEX, known for low fees and fast transactions&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - 0x152649eA73beAb28c5b49B26eb48f7EAD6d4c898  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/158d172225e6a05d44d3bdca833a6b83.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Be sure to join my alpha-group for more alpha&lt;br&gt;https://t.me/start_threads &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933484</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933484</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:33:51 GMT</pubDate><author>JetStart 👾</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>1/3 RWA tokenization will be one of the main narratives when alt season starts.&lt;br&gt;$BKN - Brickken hits all the boxes to be one of the key tokens in this asset class.&lt;br&gt;With steadily increasing TVL, expanding their tokenization capabilities to Polygon PoS and having a AA Skynet… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902427401864548494  https://twitter.com/Brickken/status/1902330799975727560 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/d1913d937080444005acb4010fd4a174.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/b4d59cb74096c0731fd69e6a8fca1068.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  2/3 $BKN [1W] shows a strong consolidation in which price bounces between Fibonnacci resistance and support; Symmetrical Triangle.&lt;br&gt;Currently price is testing the lower ascending trend line.&lt;br&gt;$BKN / $ETH suggests that a breakout can go very fast (see 3/3)  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/ca189bca3aab669edb542552757836ef.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  3/3 $BKN / $ETH [1W] has formed also a consolidation structure, a so-called diamond.&lt;br&gt;Diamonds tend to break out aggressively.  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/a5db57986993e435a10427c3148eb36e.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933392</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933392</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:30:12 GMT</pubDate><author>Gert van Lagen</author><category>Brickken</category><category>RWA Token</category><category>Narratives</category><category>Layer 2</category><category>Modular Blockchain</category></item><item><title>EigenLayer expands restaking links with Mantle and ZKsync</title><description>&lt;p&gt;EigenLayer has enhanced two major integrations, with Mantle Network and ZKsync adopting EigenDA for data availability and ZKsync also incorporating EigenLayer’s Autonomous Verifiable Services (AVSs) for decentralized zero-knowledge (zk) proving. These partnerships expand EigenLayer’s role in Ethereum’s modular security landscape, reinforcing its position as the leading restaking protocol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Ethereum restaking, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/tag/eigenlayer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EigenLayer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/tag/symbiotic&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Symbiotic&lt;/a&gt; are the dominant players, though they have a wide gap in scale. EigenLayer &lt;a href=&quot;https://defillama.com/protocols/Restaking&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;commands&lt;/a&gt; approximately $9.4 billion in total value locked (TVL) — over 9 times Symbiotic’s $1 billion. A breakdown of the top five AVSs by economic security highlights this difference:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/e59f2d7953a06b4d91c55eb369626fbb.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top AVSs by Economic Security (USD) | Source: Blockworks/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://inceptionlrt.com/restaking-explorer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;InceptionLRT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;EigenLayer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;EigenDA: $8.8 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;eoracle: $7.9 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Witness Chain: $7.6 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lagrange ZK Prover: $7.3 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cyber MACH: $7.2 billion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Symbiotic:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ditto Network: $227.19 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Capx Cloud: $183.85 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Human Network: $158.60 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kalypso: $119.20 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Radius: $87.83 million&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;EigenLayer’s larger TVL reflects deeper adoption within Ethereum’s security model. However, the disparity is also influenced by differences in how each protocol enforces security risks today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The absence of slashing on EigenLayer’s mainnet means that restaked assets currently face no risk of penalties, effectively giving validators and stakers a “free roll” — they can earn additional rewards without the downside of losing their stake due to misbehavior or failure to meet service requirements. This significantly lowers the perceived risk of participating in EigenLayer, encouraging higher capital inflows and contributing to its $9.4 billion TVL. It also encourages participation with the EIGEN native token.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In contrast, Symbiotic has live slashing on mainnet, meaning operators and stakers must weigh potential rewards against the risk of losing funds if validation services fail to meet predefined security criteria. This added risk will likely make some participants more cautious, leading to lower total restaked capital. And while it has an ongoing points system, the scale and valuation of a future token distribution is uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until EigenLayer activates slashing on mainnet, its restaking model remains more attractive to risk-averse capital, further reinforcing the TVL disparity between the two protocols. If Symbiotic releases a token, it may also narrow the gap by incentivizing deposits more directly than points alone can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What Mantle Network and ZKsync are doing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mantle Network, which describes its design as an optimium — a hybrid of optimistic and zk rollup features — has integrated EigenDA as its primary data availability layer. Previously, Mantle operated MantleDA, a system limited to 10 operators. With this transition, the network now benefits from a 200+ operator set, improving censorship resistance and network resilience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Scalability increase: EigenDA supports 15MB/s throughput, compared to Ethereum’s 0.0625MB/s limit.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enhanced economic security: $335 million in restaked assets now back Mantle’s data availability.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Expanded validator set: More operators reduce downtime risks and improve service reliability.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This shift aligns Mantle with Ethereum’s broader modular scaling approach, allowing for increased throughput as a tradeoff against the full security of Ethereum mainnet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ZKsync’s Elastic Network, an ecosystem of customizable rollups, has designated EigenDA as its preferred alternative data availability (altDA) solution. Rollups within &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/tag/zksync&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ZKsync&lt;/a&gt; will now be able to use EigenDA for scalable data storage, reducing bottlenecks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond data availability, ZKsync is integrating EigenLayer AVSs for zk proving. This moves it away from centralized cloud providers like AWS and Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Competitive proving costs: EigenLayer introduces a marketplace for zk proving, where AVSs compete for jobs, driving down expenses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Modular security expansion: Using Ethereum restaked assets, ZKsync integrates EigenLayer’s AVSs directly into its proving system.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;EigenLayer founder Sreeram Kannan described these integrations as part of a shift toward a “verifiable cloud,” leveraging Ethereum’s cryptoeconomic security to support decentralized infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With 57+ AVSs live and over $8 billion in TVL, EigenLayer continues to expand beyond its initial restaking use case. While early enthusiasm around restaking has cooled, Mantle and ZKsync’s adoption of EigenLayer services reflects growing demand for modular blockchain infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the news in your inbox. Explore Blockworks newsletters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/daily&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockworks Daily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The newsletter that helps thousands of investors understand crypto and the markets, by Byron Gilliam.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/empire&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Start your morning with the top news and analysis to inform your day in crypto.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/forwardguidance&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Reporting and analysis on the growing intersection of crypto and macroeconomics, policy and finance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/0xresearch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0xResearch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Alpha directly in your inbox. Market highlights, data, degen trade ideas, governance updates, token performance and more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/lightspeed&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightspeed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Built for Solana investors, developers and community members. The latest from one of crypto’s hottest networks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/thedrop&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Drop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For crypto collectors and traders, covering apps, games, memes and more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16932570</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16932570</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:26:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockworks</author><category>EigenLayer</category><category>Mantle</category><category>Layer 2</category><category>ZKsync</category></item><item><title>NVIDIA Dynamo: Scaling AI inference with open-source efficiency</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvidia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NVIDIA&lt;/a&gt; has launched Dynamo, an open-source inference software designed to accelerate and scale reasoning models within AI factories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Efficiently managing and coordinating AI inference requests across a fleet of GPUs is a critical endeavour to ensure that AI factories can operate with optimal cost-effectiveness and maximise the generation of token revenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As AI reasoning becomes increasingly prevalent, each AI model is expected to generate tens of thousands of tokens with every prompt, essentially representing its “thinking” process. Enhancing inference performance while simultaneously reducing its cost is therefore crucial for accelerating growth and boosting revenue opportunities for service providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A new generation of AI inference software&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA Dynamo, which succeeds the NVIDIA Triton Inference Server, represents a new generation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.developer-tech.com/news/hugging-face-partners-nvidia-democratise-ai-inference/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;AI inference&lt;/a&gt; software specifically engineered to maximise token revenue generation for AI factories deploying reasoning AI models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dynamo orchestrates and accelerates inference communication across potentially thousands of GPUs. It employs disaggregated serving, a technique that separates the processing and generation phases of large language models (LLMs) onto distinct GPUs. This approach allows each phase to be optimised independently, catering to its specific computational needs and ensuring maximum utilisation of GPU resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Industries around the world are training AI models to think and learn in different ways, making them more sophisticated over time,” stated Jensen Huang, founder and CEO of NVIDIA. “To enable a future of custom reasoning AI, NVIDIA Dynamo helps serve these models at scale, driving cost savings and efficiencies across AI factories.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the same number of GPUs, Dynamo has demonstrated the ability to double the performance and revenue of AI factories serving Llama models on NVIDIA’s current Hopper platform. Furthermore, when running the DeepSeek-R1 model on a large cluster of GB200 NVL72 racks, NVIDIA Dynamo’s intelligent inference optimisations have shown to boost the number of tokens generated by over 30 times per GPU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To achieve these improvements in inference performance, NVIDIA Dynamo incorporates several key features designed to increase throughput and reduce operational costs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dynamo can dynamically add, remove, and reallocate GPUs in real-time to adapt to fluctuating request volumes and types. The software can also pinpoint specific GPUs within large clusters that are best suited to minimise response computations and efficiently route queries. Dynamo can also offload inference data to more cost-effective memory and storage devices while retrieving it rapidly when required, thereby minimising overall inference costs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA Dynamo is being released as a fully open-source project, offering broad compatibility with popular frameworks such as PyTorch, SGLang, NVIDIA TensorRT-LLM, and vLLM. This open approach supports enterprises, startups, and researchers in developing and optimising novel methods for serving AI models across disaggregated inference infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA expects Dynamo to accelerate the adoption of AI inference across a wide range of organisations, including major cloud providers and AI innovators like AWS, Cohere, CoreWeave, Dell, Fireworks, Google Cloud, Lambda, Meta, Microsoft Azure, Nebius, NetApp, OCI, Perplexity, Together AI, and VAST.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;NVIDIA Dynamo: Supercharging inference and agentic AI&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key innovation of NVIDIA Dynamo lies in its ability to map the knowledge that inference systems hold in memory from serving previous requests, known as the KV cache, across potentially thousands of GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The software then intelligently routes new inference requests to the GPUs that possess the best knowledge match, effectively avoiding costly recomputations and freeing up other GPUs to handle new incoming requests. This smart routing mechanism significantly enhances efficiency and reduces latency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“To handle hundreds of millions of requests monthly, we rely on NVIDIA GPUs and inference software to deliver the performance, reliability and scale our business and users demand,” said Denis Yarats, CTO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/telefonica-wayra-ai-answer-engine-perplexity/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Perplexity AI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We look forward to leveraging Dynamo, with its enhanced distributed serving capabilities, to drive even more inference-serving efficiencies and meet the compute demands of new AI reasoning models.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://cohere.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cohere&lt;/a&gt; is already planning to leverage NVIDIA Dynamo to enhance the agentic AI capabilities within its Command series of models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Scaling advanced AI models requires sophisticated multi-GPU scheduling, seamless coordination and low-latency communication libraries that transfer reasoning contexts seamlessly across memory and storage,” explained Saurabh Baji, SVP of engineering at Cohere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We expect NVIDIA Dynamo will help us deliver a premier user experience to our enterprise customers.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Support for disaggregated serving&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NVIDIA Dynamo inference platform also features robust support for disaggregated serving. This advanced technique assigns the different computational phases of LLMs – including the crucial steps of understanding the user query and then generating the most appropriate response – to different GPUs within the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disaggregated serving is particularly well-suited for reasoning models, such as the new NVIDIA Llama Nemotron model family, which employs advanced inference techniques for improved contextual understanding and response generation. By allowing each phase to be fine-tuned and resourced independently, disaggregated serving improves overall throughput and delivers faster response times to users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.together.ai/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Together AI&lt;/a&gt;, a prominent player in the AI Acceleration Cloud space, is also looking to integrate its proprietary Together Inference Engine with NVIDIA Dynamo. This integration aims to enable seamless scaling of inference workloads across multiple GPU nodes. Furthermore, it will allow Together AI to dynamically address traffic bottlenecks that may arise at various stages of the model pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Scaling reasoning models cost effectively requires new advanced inference techniques, including disaggregated serving and context-aware routing,” stated Ce Zhang, CTO of Together AI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The openness and modularity of NVIDIA Dynamo will allow us to seamlessly plug its components into our engine to serve more requests while optimising resource utilisation—maximising our accelerated computing investment. We’re excited to leverage the platform’s breakthrough capabilities to cost-effectively bring open-source reasoning models to our users.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Four key innovations of NVIDIA Dynamo&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA has highlighted four key innovations within Dynamo that contribute to reducing inference serving costs and enhancing the overall user experience:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPU Planner:&lt;/strong&gt; A sophisticated planning engine that dynamically adds and removes GPUs based on fluctuating user demand. This ensures optimal resource allocation, preventing both over-provisioning and under-provisioning of GPU capacity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Router:&lt;/strong&gt; An intelligent, LLM-aware router that directs inference requests across large fleets of GPUs. Its primary function is to minimise costly GPU recomputations of repeat or overlapping requests, thereby freeing up valuable GPU resources to handle new incoming requests more efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low-Latency Communication Library:&lt;/strong&gt; An inference-optimised library designed to support state-of-the-art GPU-to-GPU communication. It abstracts the complexities of data exchange across heterogeneous devices, significantly accelerating data transfer speeds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory Manager:&lt;/strong&gt; An intelligent engine that manages the offloading and reloading of inference data to and from lower-cost memory and storage devices. This process is designed to be seamless, ensuring no negative impact on the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA Dynamo will be made available within NIM microservices and will be supported in a future release of the company’s AI Enterprise software platform.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See also: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/lg-exaone-deep-maths-science-and-coding-buff/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LG EXAONE Deep is a maths, science, and coding buff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ai-expo.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/4a794fbd5bc45fd981f688dfbed9aa3b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to learn more about AI and big data from industry leaders?&lt;/strong&gt; Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ai-expo.net/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;AI &amp;amp; Big Data Expo&lt;/a&gt; taking place in Amsterdam, California, and London. The comprehensive event is co-located with other leading events including &lt;a href=&quot;https://intelligentautomation-conference.com/northamerica/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Intelligent Automation Conference&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blockchain-expo.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BlockX&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://digitaltransformation-week.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt; Digital Transformation Week&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cybersecuritycloudexpo.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Cyber Security &amp;amp; Cloud Expo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore other upcoming enterprise technology events and webinars powered by TechForge &lt;a href=&quot;https://techforge.pub/events/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/news/nvidia-dynamo-scaling-ai-inference-open-source-efficiency/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;NVIDIA Dynamo: Scaling AI inference with open-source efficiency&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artificialintelligence-news.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;AI News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16930797</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16930797</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:49:00 GMT</pubDate><author>AI News</author><category>Storage</category><category>Interoperability</category><category>Linea Ecosystem</category></item><item><title></title><description>PENDING sell signal on #Bitcoin dominance daily chart.&lt;br&gt;After some altcoins have dropped -70% over the past 90-100 days. Are we going to see a significant bounce or just a baby bounce?&lt;br&gt;DO NOT say alt_________ and ruin it for everyone, lol. https://x.com/i/web/status/1902387039364137395  https://twitter.com/JesseOlson/status/1900574063816519726 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/32abbeb31a05691a34d02bebfa8d5ddd.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Bullish divergence, a possible sneaky higher low, and pending buy signal on #XLM daily chart.  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/0e41aac591402cec497c9fb91ed15a2d.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Bullish divergence on $ALGO daily chart with a pending MACD bullish crossover.  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/92ad497ffa7592cb1a6bd7605fe67716.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Bullish divergence on $HBAR daily chart.  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/0d1f772568644478e4fd72844ebbc529.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16929828</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16929828</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:49:49 GMT</pubDate><author>Jesse Olson</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>$BTC - D1&lt;br&gt;Back at fighting with key &quot;Must break/reclaim&quot; confluence of D1 downtrend &amp;amp; D1 200 EMA.&lt;br&gt;The main idea remains the same thing:&lt;br&gt;- Break/flip D1 downtrend x D1 200 EMA = open door to D1 100 MA gap fill&lt;br&gt;- Must hold D1 300 MA&lt;br&gt;- Chopfest in between&lt;br&gt;The longer we… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902383360288116808  https://twitter.com/pierre_crypt0/status/1902018606084272155 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/cd7cbe12a6e203ebf931f4e9a787b963.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  $BTC - H4&lt;br&gt;- Defended 81/82k area&lt;br&gt;- Almost back at H4 100 MA &quot;must break/flip&quot;&lt;br&gt;Main idea remains the same:&lt;br&gt;- Must break H4 100 MA, fill gap to H4 200 EMA if/when done (maybe on a positive market reaction to FOMC ?)&lt;br&gt;- Must hold 81/82k, fill gap down to D1 300 MA again if/when… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902383364692115720  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/1944f7d6ca129c7be1374f986008cc14.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  &quot;must break&quot; = must break&lt;br&gt;&quot;must hold&quot; = must hold&lt;br&gt;chopfest = chopfest &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  H4 100 MA tapped, may the market gods offer us a nice volatility for the second part of the week and post FOMC &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16929376</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16929376</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:35:12 GMT</pubDate><author>Pierre</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>I like Trump’s plan on crypto / bitcoin. I seriously don’t like everything else. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  The tariffs are a really bad idea.&lt;br&gt;Annexing Canada is insane.&lt;br&gt;Insulting the UK, France and Germany is not productive.&lt;br&gt;Getting rid of any judicial guardrails is disturbing.&lt;br&gt;And, Putin is a genocidal dictator, not a “bro” &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  The Russians bombed a power plant literally yesterday &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16926522</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16926522</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:20:33 GMT</pubDate><author>Fred Krueger</author><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>If you think Polymarket is just a betting platform, you are mistaken.&lt;br&gt;It is a tool that can reveal market outcomes and give you an advantage.&lt;br&gt;Here are three examples of how you can leverage it for your income. 🧵👇  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  2/ First and foremost, Polymarket is a Web3 betting platform whose fame has spread far beyond Web3.&lt;br&gt;To give you an example, I suggest you take a look at some of those who follow @Polymarket account.&lt;br&gt;Success is inevitable, isn&#39;t it?  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/46d82c4b0bba142c04d017191f58d461.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  3/ If we look closer, the platform offers much more than just betting. I&#39;ve identified three key use cases for myself.&lt;br&gt;Let&#39;s examine each use case and review the statistics (spoiler: we are still early here). &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  4/ Polymarket as betting platform.&lt;br&gt;It would be strange not to mention this because this is the main functionality of the platform. Yes, there are people who make money on it, and yes, it is very high risk.&lt;br&gt;To get started, all you need to do is deposit USDC, select a market,… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902344909669199883  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/819a94a1bed0b44a33ce992b04530bb0.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  5/ Polymarket as InfoFi Narrative&lt;br&gt;Let&#39;s delve deeper into this concept. Polymarket enables you to accurately gauge mass user sentiment and make informed decisions based on this insight.&lt;br&gt;For instance, you could open a long or short position based on crowd expectations or… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902344921836916880 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  6/ &quot;If you are a bettor, then you can deposit to Polymarket, and for you it&#39;s a betting site. If you are not a bettor, then you can read the charts, and for you it&#39;s a news site.&quot;&lt;br&gt;This is how @VitalikButerin described Polymarket in his article analyzing the platform in case of… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902344933861957848 https://twitter.com/295218901/status/1855063184039633378 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  7/ Polymarket as the $POLY Airdrop&lt;br&gt;Airdrops remain a significant part of the Web3 world and are a main activity for many. So, let&#39;s include Polymarket in this discussion.&lt;br&gt;From personal experience, I can say the platform is overrun with bots, leading to minimal competition among… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902344946214150387 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  8/ Statistics say that to be in the top 10% of users, you need:&lt;br&gt;➢ Number of Trades: 50+&lt;br&gt;➢ Trade Volume: $5K+&lt;br&gt;➢ Active Days: 10+&lt;br&gt;➢ Realized Profit: $100+&lt;br&gt;The total number of users is just over 1 million.  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/e45587659507507b743d097f418c9354.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  9/ Does the project really need a token? Let&#39;s examine each point:&lt;br&gt;➢ Marketing: The project is among the most popular in its field and definitely doesn&#39;t need a token for marketing purposes.&lt;br&gt;➢ Revenue: According to @DefiLlama, Polymarket earns about $200k in fees daily, so… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902345029160726589 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  10/ Make sure to join my alpha channel so you don&#39;t miss out on the hottest updates and news.&lt;br&gt;➢ Link - http://bit.ly/3KbglyH.  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/0963daa4e291a3092dbef0bd1a72cdc1.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  11/ Do you use Polymarket? For what purposes?&lt;br&gt;@williamlegate / @nickbytes / @HugoMartingale / @niraek / @_loset&lt;br&gt;/ @theodoroswhite / @digitdustin / @MichaelJWenner / @sherrbss&lt;br&gt;/ @mahdiofalltime / @nperlaw / @LiamKovatch / @MatthewModabber / @2irl4u / @shayne_coplan /… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902345060232130900 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  12/ Thank you for your attention. I hope this thread helps you get closer to the other sides of using Polymarket.&lt;br&gt;Follow me and save this thread in your bookmarks. https://twitter.com/1447592829786669056/status/1902344782829273172 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16925975</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16925975</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:01:54 GMT</pubDate><author>Crypp | DeFi</author></item><item><title></title><description>#BTC
Bitcoin continues to successfully retest the CME Gap as support (orange box, $78k-$80.7k)
More, BTC has been doing so at a Higher Low (black)
If this continues BTC will soon be able to completely fill the $82245-$87000 CME Gap above (orange circle)
$BTC #Crypto #Bitcoin  https://twitter.com/rektcapital/status/1900496325688348749</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16924337</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16924337</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:43:18 GMT</pubDate><author>Rekt Capital</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title>‘Notcoin’ Studio Expands From Telegram Tapping to ‘Not Games’ Platform</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Open Builders, the company behind influential Telegram tap-to-earn game &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-notcoin-telegram-based-game-airdrop&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Notcoin&lt;/a&gt;, announced Wednesday that it is expanding beyond individual games with the rollout of Not Games, a platform with unified progression and rewards shared across multiple new games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/playnotgames/status/1899905213386916022&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;teased by Notcoin&lt;/a&gt;, the platform aims to unify what has previously been a fragmented gaming experience on Telegram by creating persistent player profiles, shared inventories, and an integrated economy across multiple games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not Games will feature a single player profile that maintains achievements and rankings across all titles within the ecosystem. Players will also have a unified balance and inventory system, allowing assets earned in one game to potentially have utility in others. And earned items can be sold via secondary marketplaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not Games will be powered by the existing NOT token on &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-toncoin-the-cryptocurrency-conceived-by-telegram&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;The Open Network&lt;/a&gt; (TON), which Notcoin launched last year in a large-scale airdrop to millions of players. NOT surged to a peak market cap of nearly $3 billion last year, making it &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/219999/biggest-crypto-gaming-tokens-launched-2024&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;last year’s top gaming token launch&lt;/a&gt; by that metric. However, its price has fallen substantially since then, like many other gaming tokens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Players can use NOT for purchases, upgrades, and rewards across all titles in Not Games. According to Open Builders, the top players will compete for NOT rewards every three weeks in skill-based challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first game that will be integrated via Not Games is VOID, a real-time skill-based game inspired by popular web game Agar.io—a simple multiplayer game set in a petri dish. VOID &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/voidnotherex/status/1899891957733712329&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;launched to the public last week&lt;/a&gt; following a closed beta period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it’s just the start for the planned Not Games ecosystem, with Open Builders promising at least five more games in development for the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Builders founder Sasha Plotvinov had previously teased plans for a Not Games-like platform last spring, ahead of the NOT token launch, saying that the studio hoped to cultivate a Netflix-like platform for discovering and playing a steady selection of new games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We want it to become the Netflix of social, viral games,” he &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/227970/notcoin-next-move-netflix-social-viral-games-interview&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;told &lt;i&gt;Decrypt&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last April.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16923293</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16923293</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:01:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Decrypt</author><category>Items</category></item><item><title>OKX Friends Episode 9｜Dialogue with Madman, Past, Present and Future</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/38a108143f3b2f58458bda514091c86c.jpg&quot; data-filename=&quot;图片2.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 724px;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The crypto world is in turmoil again. Do you still remember the top “madman” @liujia0224 in the crypto in 2017?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The &quot;digital currency trend maniac&quot; who updates his articles every day and points the way for countless traders with a &quot;responsible, focused and sincere&quot; attitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This public account was once a daily must-read for Bitcoin traders. As soon as the article came out, it instantly received over 100,000 views. It can be called the &quot;weather forecast&quot;of the crypto, accurately predicting the ups and downs of digital currencies such as Bitcoin, Litecoin, and Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On social media, he was once a top figure, known to everyone. The threshold for joining his group of big investors was shockingly high (rumor has it that it starts at 10 bitcoins), and those who could join the group were either rich or noble, which was invisibly a symbol of status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; However, after several rounds of bull and bear markets, KOLs have also turned to YouTube and Twitter, and rumors about the &quot;madman&quot;&#39;s retirement have also been rampant. Now, the crypto is in turmoil again. What is the &quot;madman&quot; who once dominated the crypto doing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is the &quot;Friends of OKX&quot; series of interviews. This series aims to explore the career stories, industry thinking and lessons of KOLs from different backgrounds for new users to learn from. This interviewer is Mercy @Mercy_okx, welcome to follow~&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Main &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;article navigation:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;Chapter 1: The Madman Says - The Past&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Chapter 2: Madman Says—Now and Future&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Chapter 3: Madman Says: Advice for Newbies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Chapter 1: The Madman Says - The Past&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;1. Why did you get into the industry? When you first learned about BTC, it was only about 600 RMB.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mercy, hello, everyone, I am very happy to have a space with friends from OKX. Let me briefly introduce myself. I have a master&#39;s degree in finance. I have worked in many large financial institutions, including securities companies, trust companies, and insurance companies. I have a deep understanding of various financial products and financial derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I started investing in stocks in 2008, and that was when I fell in love with trading. Of course, when I was young, I also experienced the accidents that all traders must experience, such as leverage liquidation. The profits that I worked hard to make more than ten times over several years were gone in just a few days. That year, the stock market circuit breaker occurred.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; While I was trading stocks, I was also happy to look for some new trading targets. It was 2013, and I played with precious metals trading, stamps and coins, and Bitcoin. What impressed me most was Bitcoin. At that time, an exchange had just been established and was promoting it crazily on Baidu. Registering an account would give you 0.1 Bitcoin. The first time I saw the price of Bitcoin was more than 600 yuan. Then, in the one month that I participated in the transaction, Bitcoin rose from 600 to 8,000 yuan, which was the accelerated bull market in 2013. There was not much money in that wave, and the focus was on A-shares, but I also made 100,000 yuan. Later, as the buy the dips, I kept buying at the bottom. After all the trouble, I didn’t have much money left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But it planted the seed of my love for Bitcoin trading. Bitcoin trading has three advantages over A-shares. The first is no transaction fee, the second is 24/7 trading, and the third is T+0 trading. These three points are really a paradise for someone who loves trading. But then Bitcoin entered a bear market in 2014 and 2015, and the volatility was too small. It coincided with the bull market in A-shares at that time, so not much attention was paid to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In 2016, the A-share market was in a bear market, and I thought about Bitcoin again. Then I thought, since I was so obsessed with it, why not try to work in an exchange? So with many years of experience in A-shares and cryptocurrency trading, I successfully entered the exchange as an analyst. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since then, I have started my own virtual currency life. In today&#39;s words, I have entered the crypto industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;2. Why did you start writing public accounts? How to become the number one self-media in the crypto?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It was a coincidence that I started writing WeChat public accounts. At that time, WeChat public accounts were very popular and were the iconic products that opened the era of self-media. I also like to try new things. At that time, I was just writing for fun on Huobi. The content was all about finance, not the crypto. For an account with zero followers, the second article had 2.5 million views, which made me feel the power of WeChat public accounts. So I thought, if I share my years of stock trading experience in the crypto, wouldn’t this be a dimensionality reduction attack?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As expected, because of his professionalism, his number of fans soon surpassed that of the few analysts at the time, and he has been at the top of the rankings ever since until his official account was banned five years later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As for the community, I didn’t build it specifically, because I put enough effort into writing the official account, so all my interactions with the community were placed in the message area of the official account. I also received continuous positive motivation by writing the official account, and I persisted in daily updates for more than 6 years, 5 of which were on the official account. The madman-style community was naturally formed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The process of content output was quite bumpy. 2017 was the year with the fastest fan growth, because the money-making effect was strong and many trading websites had a large number of copycat benefits. In the second half of 2018, the market suddenly cooled down, and there was a dead silence. No one read what I wrote, and users kept losing money. Every day, there was nothing but scolding, which made me doubt my life. At that time, almost 90% of the big KOLs in the same industry stopped doing it, but I chose to persist because I believed that Bitcoin still had a future. I believed that blockchain was the technology needed in the future. As the originator of blockchain, Bitcoin&#39;s future is bright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It was also in that year that I kept recharging everyone’s faith, telling everyone about the future of Bitcoin, and telling everyone that Bitcoin would replace gold in the future, and would more likely become a national strategic reserve and a circulating currency around the world. Bitcoin would eventually be priced in Satoshi, with 1 Bitcoin = 100 million Satoshi. To this day, I still believe this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Until 2021, the market saw the light of day again, and my fans were celebrating. They said, &quot;Luckily I held on at that time, because I made millions and changed my life. There are countless people like this. At that time, I felt that I was truly successful. I not only changed myself, but also changed those who were willing to believe in me. But later, looking back, I realized that I just did the right thing. These efforts in A-shares may not be able to change my life, so choice is more important than effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Chapter 2: Madman Says—Now and Future&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;1. What impact will the United States&#39; use of cryptocurrencies as national asset reserves have on the crypto market in the short and long term?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Let&#39;s talk about the short-term impact first. Trump&#39;s policy is a policy that is bearish when it comes to good news. Why? Because the market&#39;s expectation for strategic reserves is to push the US government to buy Bitcoin with real money, but in the end, Trump&#39;s policy was to confiscate property to make strategic reserves of Bitcoin. Therefore, in the short term, it is obviously not as expected. The market directly turned its face away, sold the news, and responded to this news in a waterfall-like way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the long run, the significance of the US strategic reserve is huge. First of all, the US dollar is the most important currency in the world. Sovereign countries in the world used to only reserve US dollars and gold. Now that Bitcoin is included in the US strategic reserve, it means that Bitcoin will be recognized by the world in the future. Although the United States does not buy it (now), if other countries want to include it in the strategic reserve, they obviously need to increase their holdings by buying it. The logic is similar to the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust back then, which can only be bought but not sold, but the volume may be hundreds or thousands of times that of Grayscale, so the expectation and boost to the long-term currency price is obvious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; What we need to pay attention to now is who will be the second country to propose a strategic reserve. I believe it won’t be long before countries one after another include it in the reserves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In addition to value storage, from a monetary perspective, the deeper meaning of Bitcoin&#39;s inclusion in the strategic reserve is Bitcoin&#39;s liquidity. Compared to gold, Bitcoin is easier to circulate and carry. You can even take it to any place in the world by memorizing the private key in your mind. It is not restricted by any national currency. This is a function that no currency or gold currently has. If such a currency becomes a global currency, it means that billions of people have a small amount of Bitcoin in their wallets for circulation and payment. The era of global currency unification will come. At that time, Bitcoin will be the value anchor, and all commodities will fluctuate around Bitcoin. But this may be the ultimate form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; We just need to know that before the ultimate form arrives, its price is not high at any time. This process will continue to push up the price of Bitcoin. As for how many years it will take, I believe there is still a long way to go. My attitude towards Bitcoin is that it is a long-term bull market, the industry is far from over, and innovation has just begun. Bitcoin will be left to the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;2. Now that all the positive things Trump promised have been implemented, is there any new news that can push the market up further? Or do you think the market has already gone bearish?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the short term, all the positive news has indeed been realized, and there are no new policies worth looking forward to. The only thing we still hope for this year is that the Federal Reserve will be able to resume QE in the second half of the year to increase market liquidity. Judging from a series of operations since Trump came to power, Trump is creating an artificial economic crisis to force the Federal Reserve to release money, so we are now in this artificial crisis, and it is normal to feel uncomfortable. But we must have a deeper understanding of the word crisis, that there is opportunity only when there is crisis. Every crisis will wash away a large number of undetermined bulls, but in the end the market will always rebound, and those who dare to increase their positions in the pit will eventually get great results. Since we know that Trump is creating a crisis, then this pit will definitely be filled in the end, but how deep this pit will be dug requires us to think more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Regarding the bull and bear markets, from the perspective of Bitcoin alone, I think it is still in the bull market process. At present, whether from the on-chain data or the capital situation, it does not conform to the logic of the bear market. It is more likely to be in the bull market callback cycle, and the callback amplitude of previous bull markets is often 30-40%, so from 110,000 back, the callback low point is probably 66,000-77,000. The market has already touched this range, but whether it has bottomed out or not, we can combine the trend of the US stock market. The US stock market has had a big negative line for three consecutive weeks, with a drop of more than 10%. This level of callback often does not end quickly. In previous crises, a 10% drop in the US stock market is an appetizer, 20% buy the dips may succeed, and 30% is basically a sure win, so I personally think that the Bitcoin 77,000 position is most likely not the bottom of this callback. In the short term, 77,000 is a good support level, so with the oversold rebound of the US stock market, it is very likely to touch more than 90,000. For medium and short-term band players, it may be a good choice to reduce the price above 90,000 and adjust it down before buying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Overall, Bitcoin does not meet the bear market criteria yet, but the correction is likely not over, and it is a market of selling high and buying low.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the long run, I think the following news will push Bitcoin to a new peak:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; First, the Federal Reserve will release liquidity again, which I have mentioned before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Second, the globalization of Bitcoin strategic reserves and the follow-up of strategic reserves in various countries will bring huge growth to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Third, and most importantly, if cryptocurrency is legalized in mainland China, it will be a huge boon. In terms of purchasing power, no country can compare with the Chinese. Ordinary people have money in their pockets, but there are no good investment targets. The stock market has been at 3,000 for more than ten years, and the capacity has continued to expand but the index has not risen. The loss effect is obvious. Now the real estate market is not very prosperous. With the end of the demographic dividend, the real estate market has been in a bear market for more than ten years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; So if this is really open, trillions of funds will rush in every minute, and it will not be difficult to double the price of Bitcoin. However, if China opens up, it must not open the current cryptocurrency exchanges, but to create a Chinese version of ETF, where money can be bought and sold within the wall, and withdrawals are not allowed, but the price is anchored to the global Bitcoin. To put it bluntly, it is a pool of its own and takes it outside the wall for hedging. After all, the foreign exchange wall cannot fall, which is the foundation of the economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;3. Which sectors are worth paying attention to in the future, and what types of projects are likely to generate new alpha returns?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; OK, let me tell you a few sectors that I think have more opportunities for your reference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 1. RWA: Tokenization of real assets is a very big concept and covers a wide range. First of all, it can be combined with traditional finance on the basis of Defi. Defi is already mature enough in the crypto. If blockchain technology can be used to superimpose the traditional market, then the imagination is infinite. For example, tokenized bonds can be used for mortgage lending, and tokenized equity can greatly increase the liquidity of the financial market and will be of great help to the future economic environment. In addition, the splitting of real estate ownership, using tokens to confirm rights to obtain future income and growth, and the token splitting of artworks are all examples of virtualizing real assets. In short, there are clear landing opportunities here, but the step of putting assets on the chain requires the endorsement of traditional large institutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;2.AI: Needless to say, AI is the hottest topic at the moment and a sector that will continue to innovate in the future. The integration of AI and blockchain is mainly reflected in AI algorithms. AI requires a large amount of data for machine learning, and blockchain happens to protect data privacy and even turns data into a kind of value transmission, which can enable centralized AI to evolve towards a safer decentralization. At present, except for some simple AI AGENTs, most are still in the concept stage and are far less practical than centralized AI. However, there will always be bubbles. What the market wants is dreams, so there will be expectations of hype.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 3. Public chain: This is a sector that has been talked about for a long time. Public chains will be hyped in every bull market cycle, and a few new chains will emerge in each cycle. However, alpha often exists in new chains, not old public chains. This is the logic of standing on the shoulders of giants. Before all chains converge, public chains will continue to iterate and break through the &quot;Blockchain Trilemma&quot; of blockchain until they catch up with the current Internet transmission speed and cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;4. Payment: Cross-border payment plays an important role in the process of global integration, and traditional finance is notorious for its slow settlement and high cost. The advantages of using blockchain to do these things are obvious, but these pitfalls have basically been occupied by stablecoins, such as USDT and USDC. What we need to pay attention to in the future payment is the integration of payment and smart contracts, such as some IoT devices that earn data value through data transmission, and blockchain projects that replace the banking system. In some backward areas such as South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia, a large number of blockchain projects are being used to replace the banking system because the cost of opening a bank account is too high for the poor. For example, the Filipino maid I hired before was paid in legal currency, but she settled slowly, the procedures were complicated, and the wear and tear was high through the traditional financial system. Later, I taught her to use the exchange, use U to settle and then exchange it into local currency, which is convenient and has much less wear and tear.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 5.MEME: The MEME coin craze has passed, but this thing will not end. Low-cost and high-return PVP will always exist in casinos because it is in line with the gambling consciousness. In the future, celebrities and brand owners may issue their own tokens on the chain. At that time, there may be more ways to play. For example, tokens can be used to exchange company products. The current hype is only the most basic form. MEME will eventually be empowered, whether it is brand value or consensus value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;From the perspective of the sector, the overall logic is to speculate on new things rather than old things. The big opportunities in the future are still in new projects. 90% of old projects cannot escape the fate of lower prices in each round. After all, for most project parties, the easiest way to make money is to launch a new project rather than to save old projects with dispersed chips.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;4. Traditional financial institutions are entering the crypto. Which crypto assets do you think these huge amounts of funds will be allocated to? Where will the funds flow in the future?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Looking at traditional capital, you can refer to four directions: strategic reserves, ETFs, Grayscale and the Trump Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The types of tokens in the U.S. strategic reserve, such as BTC ETH SOL XRP, etc., may be the first ones that traditional institutions will configure when entering the crypto in the future. Because for most traditional institutions, they don’t understand the crypto at all, and they invest with investors’ money with their eyes closed. They configure because they configure, and they absolutely dare not touch those projects that may return to zero. With the endorsement of the strategic reserve, traditional funds don’t have to bear this blame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;Another thing is the future approval of major ETFs in the United States. Currently, only BTC, ETH, SOL, XRP, and LTC are in preparation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The configuration of Grayscale Trust represents the direction and expectations of early institutional investors in the U.S. crypto. Currently, Grayscale Trust&#39;s single asset trusts include BTC, ETH, BCH, ETC, LTC, SOL, LINK, MANA, FIL, BAT, LPT, XLM, ZEC, and ZEN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Finally, there is the Trump Crypto Fund, which is also an important reference standard. It currently holds BTC, ETH, TRX, LINK, AAVE, ENA, MOVE, ONDO, and SEI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;Chapter 3: Madman Says: Advice for Newbies&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. What advice would you give to newcomers to the cryptocurrency space? How should they start learning and gaining experience?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;For newcomers, the threshold to the crypto is relatively high now. It is not like when we entered the crypto back then. We could just rush in as long as we knew how to buy and sell, and we could do it as long as we had some basic knowledge. After so many years, the crypto has spawned too many ways to play, especially with too much content on the chain. It can be said that everything that traditional finance had before has been copied. The crypto itself is also innovating what traditional finance does not have. This requires a lot of financial knowledge, a strong blockchain reserve, and an understanding of the Internet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 7*24 hours of non-stop trading will make newcomers exhausted, so for newcomers, you can first understand the entire framework of the crypto, such as secondary market transactions, primary market analysis or macro analysis, exchange-related businesses, on-chain treasure hunting, Defi, etc. Newcomers need to focus on niche areas, fully understand a certain field, accumulate experience in practice, talk more with industry veterans and gain more experience, especially those pitfalls that others have stepped on, which are the most valuable assets for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The last thing is to learn quickly. Only by running faster than others can you have the opportunity to achieve great results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;2. What common misunderstandings or traps do you think newcomers need to avoid during market transactions?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As for trading, I have been in the market for nearly 20 years, which may make me older than many of the friends who listen to Space. I am not that old. I just started trading when I was in school. I have stepped on many pitfalls over the years. I think the most important thing is to have the right mindset. I often say in tweets that trading is a marathon, not a 50-meter sprint. Don&#39;t expect to get rich overnight, but a steady stream of income. As long as you are alive, opportunities are always there. So I pay more attention to how to allocate assets, how to make assets grow steadily every year, which are risky assets, which are cash assets, and which are value-preserving assets, and how to allocate according to my own risk preferences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;If you don’t have much assets now, just work hard in this industry and think about how to make money first. Don’t just think about getting rich quickly through trading, because I have seen too many people who got rich quickly and eventually gave them all back to the market. Many times, the money earned was due to luck, but lost again due to strength.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Also, don&#39;t take out loans, and don&#39;t use money that affects your life to trade cryptocurrencies, because this will affect the most important thing in your trading: your mentality. Once your mentality is distorted, all operations will be distorted. Once you find that your mentality is not good, stop trading immediately, slow down, and then get back on track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: ui-sans-serif, system-ui, -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Roboto, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Arial, &amp;quot;Noto Sans&amp;quot;, sans-serif, &amp;quot;Apple Color Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Emoji&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Segoe UI Symbol&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Noto Color Emoji&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;If you use leverage, remember to set a stop loss for each order before opening it. This is the key to survival. If you cannot comply with this, please do not open contracts or leveraged transactions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;3. How do you suggest newcomers build their own analysis framework and model? What practical tools or methods can you recommend?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In terms of trading, I think the most important thing is not to read books, but to start first, accept failure, accept every stop loss, admit that you are imperfect, even mentally retarded, and learn to respect the market first. So my suggestion is to use very little money to try, to make mistakes, find your own problems from the transaction, and then solve the problems and find a trading method that suits you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; After you accept your failure, you can start learning some theoretical knowledge, look at the indicators, and see what kind of operating rules the K-line has. Here I recommend a few books about trading that I think are more helpful, &quot;Wyckoff Trading Method&quot;, &quot;Japanese Candlestick Chart Technique&quot;, &quot;Reminiscences of a Stock Operator&quot;, &quot;Turtle Trading Rules&quot;, and &quot;Stop Loss&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Finally, combine various types of knowledge to increase the success rate of market judgment. Trading is not a simple road, it is a system. It is difficult to get the correct result from a single indicator. Over the years, I have been constantly improving and learning. Trading is a hard road, so if there is a better way to make money, it is recommended not to consider this road. This is a road to wealth with a life-and-death experience. Most people live in mediocrity, and those who can make stable returns are rare. More often, I feel that it is a bit of a competition of talent, or whether your personality is suitable for trading. The key is to find a way to make money that suits you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mercy is honored to invite the legendary trader Madman to share this time. &quot;Responsible, focused, and sincere&quot; are the qualities I deeply feel from my teacher. In the boring market situation, I hope everyone can gain something from his sincere and profound cognitive sharing and regain confidence!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Finally, Mercy excerpted a sentence from the madman’s recommended book, Reminiscences of a Stock Operator, and shared it with everyone:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “There is nothing new on Wall Street, for speculation is as old as the hills. What happens in the stock market today has happened before and will happen again.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Risk Warning and Disclaimer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This article is for reference only. This article only represents the author&#39;s views and does not represent the position of OKX. This article is not intended to provide (i) investment advice or investment recommendations; (ii) an offer or solicitation to buy, sell or hold digital assets; (iii) financial, accounting, legal or tax advice. We do not guarantee the accuracy, completeness or usefulness of such information. Holding digital assets (including stablecoins and NFTs) involves high risks and may fluctuate significantly. You should carefully consider whether trading or holding digital assets is suitable for you based on your financial situation. Please consult your legal/tax/investment professionals for your specific situation. Please be responsible for understanding and complying with local applicable laws and regulations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16922154</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16922154</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 09:55:53 GMT</pubDate><author>Followin News</author><category>Halving Tokens</category><category>ETF</category></item><item><title></title><description>Asia Colour - 19 Mar 25&lt;br&gt;1/ It’s been a month since the S&amp;amp;P 500 hit a new high, but the mood has soured. Market exuberance is gone, and risk assets remain under pressure. How much longer can this last? https://x.com/i/web/status/1902292649543090649 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  2/ Hedge fund casualties are piling up:&lt;br&gt;- Millennium lost $900M from two teams&lt;br&gt;- Brevan Howard’s Master Fund is down 5% YTD&lt;br&gt;Risk limits are tightening, and the music, while still playing, is undeniably slowing. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  3/ Geopolitical risks are mounting. Tit-for-tat tariff moves from Canada, China &amp;amp; the EU are driving costs higher for the US. The April 2 deadline for Trump’s next round of tariffs looms large, threatening more pain for risk assets. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  4/ Middle East tensions remain high, yet energy markets are barely reacting. Why? US oil policy uncertainty + trade war fears are capping prices. We prefer gold over oil as a risk sentiment barometer for now. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  5/ Tonight’s FOMC meeting – No rate cuts expected, but we’re watching for a dovish tilt. With tariffs set to impact the economy in the coming months, the Fed is likely to stay in &quot;wait-and-see&quot; mode. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  6/ $BTC at $80K: A real floor or a mirage? Momentum &amp;amp; carry trades are unwinding. While BTC has found some support, the macro backdrop suggests it could be short-lived.&lt;br&gt;Looking ahead, we remain cautious. Tailwinds are scarce, and we prefer principal-protected yield strategies… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902292662339916079 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  Read more: https://www.qcpgroup.com/insights/asia-colour-91/ &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16921869</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16921869</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 09:34:45 GMT</pubDate><author>QCP</author></item><item><title></title><description>🔥 Bitcoin is at a decision point! Will it break out or retrace?&lt;br&gt;📊 BTC is testing resistance near $83.5K - $84K – a key level where short liquidations could trigger a squeeze. If bulls push through, we might see $85K+ next. But failure? A drop toward $81.5K - $80K is on the… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902277349783044327  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/44ad92caaaa6153c5b62c074f8c37314.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Get FREE premium analytics for 7 days with&lt;br&gt;@coinank_com&lt;br&gt;Want to track market trends like a pro?&lt;br&gt;🔗 Sign up now using my referral link:&lt;br&gt;👉 https://coinank.com/register?referral=84095&lt;br&gt;📊 What You Get:&lt;br&gt;✅ Advanced market data &amp;amp; liquidation maps&lt;br&gt;✅ Real-time order flow insights&lt;br&gt;✅ Powerful trading… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902277844681527534 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16920865</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16920865</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:33:57 GMT</pubDate><author>IT Tech</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title>ABCDE: From the perspective of VC, let’s talk about the recent changes in the RWA track</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The previous article discussed the views of the East and West on the market from a first-level perspective. Today, taking the opportunity of YZi Labs&#39; announcement of investment in the Plume Network, a real-world asset (RWA) platform, I will talk about the changes I have observed in the RWA track recently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This needs to be divided into four parts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Whether RWA really has application scenarios, or in other words, product-market fit (PMF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Which RWA assets are suitable for on-chain, and which are not&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. What were the previous solutions, and what are the current solutions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. The recent trends in the RWA sector, and whether you have any perception of them&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Let&#39;s start with 1 - Whether RWA really has application scenarios&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or in other words, PMF (excluding the stablecoin track of US Treasuries being on-chain, as Usual and MKR have already found PMF). Taking the on-chain of US stocks as an example, this is the most fiercely debated category on Twitter. Many people think that on-chain US stocks are redundant, as those who really want to trade US stocks already have their own channels, and any on-chain asset is more volatile than US stocks, so there&#39;s no need to play stocks on-chain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a different view on this. I personally believe that US stocks on-chain have their significance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. In terms of channels - it&#39;s true that most of the big shots above A8 and A9 use platforms like Futu and FirstTrade for diversified investments in cryptocurrencies, stocks, and gold. But I believe that most of the retail investors in the circle don&#39;t have US stock accounts. On-chain US stock trading can at least open up their purchase channels without any threshold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From another perspective, the total market value of stablecoins like USDT/USDC is getting larger and larger, which is another way for the US dollar hegemony to spread relative to traditional finance. If Crypto really achieves Mass Adoption through stablecoins + Payfi + smart wallet experiences like Alipay, do you think the Americans will be willing to let the rest of the world take over their US stocks? Most people in other countries around the world are more willing to go through the hassle of opening accounts with various banks and brokers to buy their own country&#39;s half-dead stocks, rather than simply placing one-click orders to invest in the world&#39;s number one economy like shopping on Taobao.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. In terms of application scenarios, imagine this case: as a P-level investor, you&#39;ve made $100,000 U in a few days by rushing to Mubarak, and you know that Tesla has recently halved, which is a good opportunity to buy the dips. You want to convert the $100,000 U into Tesla stocks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if you have a US stock account, you first need to OTC the $100,000 U into fiat currency, transfer the fiat currency to the broker&#39;s account through the bank, and then start buying at the broker&#39;s end. This whole process will take 3-5 business days (back in 2017 when I was exposed to Bitcoin before, I bought US stocks through FirstTrade in Australia, and the SWIFT transfer alone took 4-5 days, plus a hefty fee of several tens of dollars). If Tesla goes up one day and you want to sell it and convert it to BTC or U, you have to go through this process again... Imagine if there were US stocks on-chain, you could instantly convert your Meme-earned U into Tesla, the reduction in friction cost is not just a little bit, but a 10x or even 100x improvement in user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Then let&#39;s talk about 2 - Which RWA assets are suitable for on-chain&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, T-Bills, which have already proven themselves, are not up for discussion. For other RWA assets, it really depends on who the target audience is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the C-end, stocks are undoubtedly the most suitable. Most retail investors are unlikely to have exposure to primary private equity, and if you Tokenize the equity of an unlisted company, I doubt many people would be able to understand it, let alone buy and hold it long-term. There are also things like the private credit collateral on Centrifuge, such as bridge loans in the real estate market and corporate receivables, which are similarly unsuitable for the C-end. The vast majority of C-end users should only be familiar with stocks. More C-end scenarios should be about using the chain to open up purchase channels for users who previously had no access to an asset, a process from 0 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the B-end, there are many more things that can be Tokenized, but compared to the 0 to 1 for the C-end, the B-end should be more about reducing friction from 1 to 100. Just as primary private equity was already circulating among some institutions and high-net-worth investors, the bridge loan collateral on Centrifuge is likely to be lendable by banks. It&#39;s just that the circulation process is relatively cumbersome and the friction is greater. Putting it on-chain is like Payfi to Swift, which can greatly enhance user experience and flow speed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I remember discussing an RWA project last year, whose parent company was one of the top asset management firms in the US. They plan to issue Tokens representing the primary equity of their clients, such as SpaceX, on their own trading platform, so that the Tokens can be easily circulated and traded, and settled in one go when SpaceX goes public. So for the B-end, in addition to the trading users being limited to institutions and enterprises, the issuers are also relatively limited, just like the example above. Unless you already have a large amount of SpaceX equity under your own asset management, as a pure STO or RWA platform, you want to attract SpaceX equity holders to issue Tokens representing SpaceX equity on your platform, which involves a lot of friction in terms of resource cooperation, legal terms, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are also many intermediate states that can be both C-end and B-end, such as the IP on-chain like Story Protocol, or the royalties of a novel, the box office of a movie, the sales of a game, etc. These things seem to be still in the early exploratory stage, and need to be tried and falsified one by one. Like influence Tokenization, FT failed, Kaito was relatively successful. Celebrity time Tokenization, http://Time.Fun was hot for a few days and then disappeared... These things need to be taken slowly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Next is 3 - What were the previous solutions, and what are the current solutions?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still taking US stocks as an example - the previous solutions were mainly synthetic assets, represented by SNX, Terra&#39;s Mirror, and GNS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This path has basically been falsified so far, and the above three platforms have also removed the synthetic US stock assets they had previously. There are two reasons for this: one is that people are not enthusiastic about the &quot;fake assets&quot; synthesized with stablecoins or native tokens (SNX, etc.), and you can see the volume comparison between BTC, WBTC, and SNX&#39;s SBTC to get a sense of it. Synthetic assets are really no better than WBTC-like &quot;mapped assets&quot; in terms of holding peace of mind. The second is that the SEC used to check on these platforms at the drop of a hat, and although synthetic assets are fake, the SEC doesn&#39;t need a reason to investigate you, so it&#39;s better to do less than more, and these platforms have all removed these synthetic US stocks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that Trump is in office and the SEC chairman has changed, the regulation in this area is much better than the previous two years. I&#39;ve seen two new solutions for on-chain US stocks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One is to go the traditional compliant Broker Dealer route, where the moment the user buys the tokenized stock on the chain, it triggers the corresponding operation in the US stock market by the compliant Broker on the off-chain. The essence is the same as Robinhood placing orders, it&#39;s just that Citadel is &quot;buying on behalf&quot; in the stock market. The advantage is that the stock you buy is &quot;real stock&quot;, or at least 1:1 truly backed by that Broker. The downside is that the trading time is completely tied to the stock market, and you can&#39;t trade 24x7 like Crypto. You also need to build trust in that Broker or platform. And when you sell, it will trigger a Taxation Event, where US citizens may need to submit tax-related forms, and non-US citizens will at least need to do KYC and the like, which is a hassle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second is Ondo Global Market&#39;s approach. From what I&#39;ve read in their docs, they originally wanted to go the Broker Dealer route, but later changed to a stablecoin-like approach, allowing their cooperating or Authorized Issuers to directly issue tokenized stocks (just like Tether issuing USDT and Circle issuing USDC). The advantage seems to be more flexibility, and there may be a chance to break free of the US stock trading time restrictions, and settle through the Issuer at a certain time. The downside is that it&#39;s most likely only available to non-US users, US users can&#39;t use it. And there may be the issue of different CAs for the same stock issued by different Issuers (like the incompatibility of USDC from different chains), the specific details of which are not covered in the docs, as the product is not scheduled to launch until next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last one is like Plume, a RWA platform that feels more like a Framework, which includes KYC/AML, data storage/execution, consensus, ZKTLS verification, etc. In theory, it can allow cooperating institutions to issue various Tokenized RWA assets here, which brings us back to the previous topic of &quot;which assets are suitable for on-chain&quot;, no need to elaborate further&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Finally, let&#39;s talk about the wind direction of 4 - RWA in the past few months, have you noticed it&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have been observing, the wind of RWA has been blowing quite strongly in the past two months. I&#39;ll just mention a few &quot;news&quot; that I&#39;ve observed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. The Ondo plan mentioned above plans to launch the Ondo Global Market, an on-chain stock market, at the end of the year or next year, and Ondo has recently been getting very close to Trump&#39;s WLFI, and there will be cooperation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Sui has also been leaning on WLFI recently&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Frax is actively embracing Cedefi, and has recently launched frxUSD, which is a collaboration with BlackRock+Superstate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Ethena released a new product today called Converge - focusing on one of the two scenarios they believe are the most important for blockchain - Storage and settlement for stablecoins and tokenized assets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5. AAVE plans to issue a new token called Horizen, which has caused a huge stir in the community, and Stani personally came out to clarify - &quot;The Horizen plan aims to fill the gap in AAVE&#39;s current RWA business segment, and the plan is expected to surpass the revenue of AAVE&#39;s current business lines in 5 years&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6. The Financial Services Commission of Korea plans to allow corporate entities to engage in virtual asset trading in phases, with a release scheduled for February 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From my friends in the Korean circle, I learned that Korea may restart the STO (the previous term for RWA) plan. You see, allowing &quot;corporate entities to trade virtual assets&quot; is certainly not for you to speculate on coins, but to tokenize some real financial assets into &quot;virtual assets&quot; for circulation between companies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;7. YZi Labs officially announced today that they have invested in the recently hot Plume Network RWA platform&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These news form a Momentum, and we can&#39;t just turn a blind eye to it, so my current view on the next main track of Circle is PayFI+RWA+a Web2.5-like Consumer APP, as for AI+Crypto, I can only say there is hope, still in the talking+observing stage. After I finish the next piece &quot;Some things worth mentioning on ETH and Solana&quot;, I will write a separate piece on my recent thoughts on AI+Crypto as the fourth part of this collection&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.panewslab.com/zh/articledetails/4viv6zel.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Original link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to join the official BlockBeats community:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telegram subscription group: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/theblockbeats&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://t.me/theblockbeats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telegram discussion group: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/BlockBeats_App&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://t.me/BlockBeats_App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter official account: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BlockBeatsAsia&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/BlockBeatsAsia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16918969</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16918969</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 06:30:23 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author><category>RWA Token</category></item><item><title>Pi Coin Gains CoinEx Listing Amid Market Woes and Transparency Demands</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Pi Network’s cryptocurrency, Pi Coin (PI), has secured another exchange listing with CoinEx, marking a notable milestone for the project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the listing comes at a turbulent time for the project, as pioneers push for clarity on Pi Network’s funding sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pi Coin Listed on CoinEx Exchange&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;PI officially launched for trading on CoinEx on March 18, 2025. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-buy-pi-coin/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;deposit and withdrawal window opened at 11:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;, followed by trading at 11:30 UTC, allowing Pi holders to trade against &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/price/tether/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tether (USDT)&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“After rigorous reviews, CoinEx will list PI (Pi) on March 18, 2025,” the exchange &lt;a href=&quot;https://announcement.coinex.com/hc/en-us/articles/35760215179796-CoinEx-Will-List-PI-Pi-on-Mar-18-2025&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; in its announcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this latest listing, Pi Coin is now available on 12 exchanges, as per Coinranking &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinranking.com/coin/54I_A3MXKhHjZ+pinetworkcoin-pi/exchanges&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;. Despite this expansion, the possibility of a Binance listing remains uncertain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/pi-coin-binance-listing-survey-results/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Although 86% of the Pi community voted in favor&lt;/a&gt; of a Binance listing, the exchange has yet to confirm if or when it will list PI. This has raised concerns about the project’s credibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The failure to get listed on Binance, despite 86% of the community voting in favor, raises serious concerns about public trust in the project,” a pioneer &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Dr_Picoin/status/1901827132474724824&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; on X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pioneers Demand Transparency on Pi Network’s Funding Sources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/pi-network-pi-domains-launch/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;concerns surrounding Pi Network continue to rise&lt;/a&gt;, the project is now embroiled in another controversy. A growing number of users are calling for &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/pi-coin-centralized-control-raises-concerns/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;transparency about the network’s &lt;/a&gt;funding sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An investigation by one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/pi-crypto-network/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Pi Network’s pioneers uncovered that &lt;/a&gt;SocialChain Inc., the company behind Pi Network, has received investments from three firms: 137 Ventures, Ulu Ventures, and Designer Fund. However, the investigation revealed a key issue: two of these investors have not included Pi Network in their official investment portfolios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, none of these firms have disclosed the amount of money they have invested in Pi Network despite being forthcoming with investment details for other companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Why is Pi Core Team keeping this under wraps? Pioneers deserve transparency. If Pi Network aims for long-term sustainability, the team must be more open about its financial backing and key partnerships,” the &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Pi81Mall/status/1901932053475860780&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notably, a previous lawsuit by former co-founder Vince McPhillip against Pi Network offers additional insight into the project’s funding methods. The complaint outlined a series of claims, including wrongful termination, intentional and negligent infliction of emotional distress, and breach of fiduciary duty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it detailed that the project had raised funds by selling financial instruments called SAFE (Simple Agreement for Future Equity).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the lawsuit, Pi Network sold SAFE agreements in September 2019 with a maximum valuation of $20 million. During this fundraising round, the project raised $500,000. A few months later, in February 2020, Pi Network conducted another fundraising round at the same $20 million valuation, raising an additional $300,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite these fundraising efforts, the lack of clear financial disclosure continues to fuel concerns within the Pi Network community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pi Coin Sees Double-Digit Price Decline&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amid these challenges, PI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/pi-price-prediction/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;price performance has also taken a hit&lt;/a&gt;. The altcoin has seen a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/pi-bulls-exit-market-price-drops/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;sharp decline in value&lt;/a&gt;, shedding 19.3% of its gains over the past week.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This drop has pushed the coin further down the cryptocurrency rankings, with PI falling from 12th to 21st place on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coingecko.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;CoinGecko&lt;/a&gt;. While the broader cryptocurrency market has also faced a downturn, PI’s losses have been more pronounced. At press time, PI was trading at $1.1, down 16.5% in the past 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;pi listing&quot; src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/415eef192067df9c7c825ea7656c6294.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;Pi Coin Price Performance. Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/price/pi-network/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;BeInCrypto&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;Despite this, Pi Network’s community engagement remains vibrant, &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/pifest-2025-pi-network/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;particularly through PiFest 2025.&lt;/a&gt; The event has attracted 100,000 registered sellers worldwide, including 49,000 active participants on the Map of Pi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media posts highlight strong participation from communities in &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Pichainmallvn/status/1901596168427315545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/dewaart31279101/status/1901243191082565665&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;, and beyond, where users exchange goods and services using PI tokens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notably, the Pioneer Korea community has &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/PiNetworkVNes/status/1901956250184614371&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-sell-pi-coin/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;consensus valuation of 1 PI at $50 &lt;/a&gt;—starkly contrasting its current market price on exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16920577</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16920577</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 06:13:00 GMT</pubDate><author>BeInCrypto</author><category>Pi</category><category>CoinEx</category></item><item><title>Issuing 70 billion tokens out of thin air and abusing the &quot;veto power&quot; - a brief review of the CRO governance farce</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Author: Azuma, Odaily&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/081f53a0fa11e19df78caee0af2be246.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recapping the CRO governance farce: Minting 70 billion tokens out of thin air and abusing the &#39;veto power&#39;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crypto.com and its affiliated blockchain Cronos have recently staged one of the most absurd governance farces in the history of blockchain - 70 billion tokens (the current total supply of CRO is 30 billion) were minted out of thin air, and despite the strong opposition from retail investors, their voices were completely turned into a joke in the face of the official &#39;veto power&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Cause: The official proposed to re-mint 70 billion tokens&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The event can be traced back to March 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On that day, Cronos announced a bold plan (truly bold) to reshape the golden age of Cronos, and invested a large amount of funds to support the Cronos roadmap (including ETF) and the ambition to make the US the capital of the cryptocurrency world. To support this plan, Cronos proposed to reverse the 700 million token burn event in February 2021 (note, Cronos&#39; X announcement didn&#39;t even dare to explicitly mention this figure), and use this share to build a Cronos strategic reserve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, Cronos proposed to re-issue these 70 billion CRO to the Cronos strategic reserve custody wallet, restoring the total CRO supply to the original 100 billion at genesis. The newly minted tokens will be locked for 10 years (calculated from the genesis of CRO), and then linearly unlocked on a monthly basis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Progress: The community strongly opposed, the official may have &#39;rigged the vote&#39;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, no matter how Cronos trumpets this proposal, such a large-scale issuance will inevitably dilute the value of CRO, and ordinary token holders cannot ignore this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mintscan governance voting record shows that on the first day of the proposal voting, the opposition rate reached as high as 95.7%, which can basically be said to have been met with extreme opposition from the community... However, this was of no use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As shown in the figure below, with the intervention of some mysterious force, the approval rate (green line) was difficult to overturn the opposition rate (red line) - temporarily ignoring the sudden rise of the green line at the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/ad5111ca9ad908c24b7424243b18e0fc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recapping the CRO governance farce: Minting 70 billion tokens out of thin air and abusing the &#39;veto power&#39;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason why it is called a mysterious force is that during the vast majority of the governance cycle from March 3 to March 17, the approval votes always led the opposition votes in a very unnatural weak advantage - it seems that this mysterious force once wanted to maintain a kind of intense &#39;illusion&#39; of pro and con opinions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Climax: This time they didn&#39;t even bother to pretend!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This jarring balance lasted until just before the end of the vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Cronos&#39; governance rules (why bother with this set-up anyway), in addition to the requirement for the approval rate, the governance proposal also requires a participation rate of more than 33.4% to pass. At that time, the participation rate of this proposal did not meet this condition. In other words, even if the approval rate was higher at that time, the proposal could not be passed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Cronos simply didn&#39;t bother to pretend - about 3.35 billion CRO directly cast their votes in favor at the last moment. This is also why the green line in the figure above suddenly rose at the end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the disclosure of UnChained, three independent sources revealed that Crypto.com and Cronos actually control 70-80% of the voting rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason why a balance was maintained for a while before was that among the verification nodes controlled by Crypto.com, only Starship and Falcon Heavy had taken action, and at the last moment, the other three verification nodes Electron, Antares and Minotaur IV also joined the fray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can clearly see the huge disparity between the official power and the retail investors&#39; voting rights in the figure below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/29e0816d427ae2fe2f40ee23495fd708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recapping the CRO governance farce: Minting 70 billion tokens out of thin air and abusing the &#39;veto power&#39;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, the proposal was &#39;safely&#39; passed with the participation of the official forces, and the 70 billion CRO will be officially minted and await entry into circulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding this absurd governance farce, a large number of CRO holders have expressed extremely disappointed attitudes, and some even directly said that this is an insult to the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Bonus: Let me tell you what real insult is!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is this considered an insult? Cronos obviously doesn&#39;t think so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the above proposal was passed, Cronos X announced another proposal in a high-profile manner, proposing to burn 50 million CRO - a mere 0.07% of the 70 billion, this is what real insult is!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/ddc18e06b065de6266a569e16193e1f6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recapping the CRO governance farce: Minting 70 billion tokens out of thin air and abusing the &#39;veto power&#39;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the historical burn records posted by Cronos, two burn periods will be executed each year, 50 million CRO per period, totaling 100 million CRO per year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A community member joked about this, saying: &quot;It looks like it will only take about 1,400 burns to eliminate these 70 billion CRO. So it will only take another 700 years to restore the current supply.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s Cronos for you, this may be the mindset of building a &quot;century-old enterprise&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16916192</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16916192</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>PANews</author></item><item><title></title><description>Do you want to be right or make money?&lt;br&gt;An OG founder is willing to post something like this, I am willing to revisit&lt;br&gt;might be crime or actual fundamentals coming back? @vechainofficial&lt;br&gt;🧵  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  🔹 Why ?&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Lambro saw an interesting slap video&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Realise CEO is bull posting token price&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; Vechain is currently launching a campaign to trying to bring back attention to their chain&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; VeChain ($VET) is UFC’s exclusive partner ($100m deal) for the next 8 years&lt;br&gt;&amp;gt; $VTHO, the… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902171667121762389 https://twitter.com/1559193198605774850/status/1901667194884534594 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  🔹 Quick Background:&lt;br&gt;VeChain is a blockchain platform founded in 2015 by  @sunshinelu, the former CIO of Louis Vuitton China.&lt;br&gt;Major events  markers for VeChain&lt;br&gt;• VeChain partnered with PwC to integrate blockchain into supply chain and logistics.&lt;br&gt;• VeCarbon initiative launched,… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902171687501848870  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/27a867be3f39ca6f60e8a9febcc3f509.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  🔹 What is Vechain?&lt;br&gt;Primarily, Vechain is focused on improving supply chain management and business processes through transparency and traceability.&lt;br&gt;It aims to solve real-world problems like counterfeiting, fraud, and inefficiencies in industries such as logistics, luxury goods,… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902171700030328981 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  🔹 What is B3TR?&lt;br&gt;bB3TR is a community initiative from veChain to reward participators for activities performed that aligns with the chain.&lt;br&gt;for better info check:&lt;br&gt;https://x.com/vechainofficial/status/1879862605478514962&lt;br&gt;can check the community vibes here&lt;br&gt;https://t.me/B3TRMAXICHAT &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  🔹 Vechain USP&lt;br&gt;• Supply Chain Transparency – Immutable tracking &amp;amp; verification of goods (luxury, food, pharmaceuticals).&lt;br&gt;• Dual-Token Model – $VET (store of value) &amp;amp; $VTHO (gas token) for fee delegation.&lt;br&gt;• Enterprise Adoption – Partnerships with @bmw , Walmart China, and more.… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902171724302663731 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  &amp;gt; Founder is bullish about price action so am I ?&lt;br&gt;https://x.com/sunshinelu24/status/1900230341203275888 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  🔹 Step by step guide&lt;br&gt;1️⃣ download the veWorld wallet extension and setup your wallet&lt;br&gt;2️⃣ Get $VET and $VTHO  from CEX ( i used mexc)&lt;br&gt;3️⃣ go to @veswaporg_ and swap $VET for $B3TR  ( FYI Every 10,000 $VET transaction = 1 VeSwap Point, max 4 Points per day.)  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/d7428b78913eb8eeed0a54f265c5f4b1.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  4️⃣ Providing Lp- select a pool&amp;nbsp; ‘$VET-$B3TR’&lt;br&gt;🔹Deposit at least 10,000 $VET into the LP, and confirm the deposit.&lt;br&gt;🔹Keep your deposit for 7 days to earn extra 14 Points.&lt;br&gt;🔹The maximum earning is 140 points per week. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  5️⃣ Stake your $B3TR for Voting &amp;amp; Earn Extra $B3TR + VeStation Points!&lt;br&gt;its an airdrop lego&lt;br&gt;you also get- VeSwap Points and VeStation Points ($ token airdrops).  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  I hope u find this insightful or valuable somehow. Feel free to support me in my substack, use my referral link or just come chat with me in medium rare  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/ecf3167ab45da86a5f96747ed7f82442.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16915111</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16915111</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 01:33:57 GMT</pubDate><author>2Lambroz.eth 🐑 (🧑‍🍳🥩🤌)</author><category>VeChain</category><category>Smart Contracts</category><category>Fan Token</category><category>VeThor Token</category></item><item><title>Chasing the Bitcoin God: A reporter&#39;s 15-year investigation into Satoshi Nakamoto</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Perhaps one day, artificial intelligence will be able to help us confirm Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s identity.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt;By Benjamin Wallace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt;Compiled by: ChainCather, Riley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Editor&#39;s note: This article is excerpted from &quot;The Mysterious Mr. Satoshi Nakamoto: Fifteen Years of Uncovering the Genius Behind the Crypto World&quot; by Benjamin Wallace. Benjamin Wallace, one of the earliest journalists to report on Bitcoin, spent fifteen years conducting in-depth investigations, from technical analysis, stylistic identification to cross-border tracking, trying to uncover the true face of Satoshi Nakamoto. In the end, the clues pointed to a programmer in his seventies, James A. Donald. However, after meeting and talking with Donald, Wallace chose to put down his pen and gave up on continuing to investigate Satoshi Nakamoto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; I first reported on Satoshi Nakamoto in 2011. After 15 years of investigation and searching, I now believe that I have solved the mystery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sahil Gupta emailed me and said that Musk is &quot;very likely&quot; to be Satoshi Nakamoto. Sahil believes that the public is ready to accept that Satoshi Nakamoto and Musk are the same person. He claimed to be &quot;99% sure&quot; and attributed the outside world&#39;s doubts to &quot;prejudice against Musk.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; The author describes the details of how Satoshi Nakamoto created Bitcoin. After Gavin Andresen informed the CIA that he would go to explain Bitcoin but received no response, Satoshi Nakamoto completely retired in 2011, leaving only a suspected forum post and never appeared again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; The author found that Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s idiomatic word &quot;hosed&quot; only appeared four times in the early Bitcoin mailing list, two of which came from the first questioner James Donald, becoming the key linguistic fingerprint to lock in his identity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; The author has identified James Donald through multiple clues, but when questioned, the top Satoshi Nakamoto suspect simply said &quot;cannot disclose&quot; to end the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; Perhaps one day, artificial intelligence will be able to help us confirm Satoshi Nakamoto’s identity. But unless the government declassifies some unforeseen secrets, we will probably never know his true identity beyond a reasonable doubt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt; If Satoshi Nakamoto, the anonymous inventor of Bitcoin, is who I think he is, he will never admit it. He probably won’t even talk to me. To meet him, I’d have to take a 20-hour flight and drive another 8 hours. But I had to try to talk to him face to face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the spring of 2011, Satoshi Nakamoto disappeared. I first heard about him that summer, when I wrote one of the first in-depth stories about Bitcoin for a magazine. The currency is independent of governments and banks. Twelve years later, Bitcoin&#39;s creator remains a mystery, and his multi-billion-dollar fortune remains intact. Never before in the history of science has anyone created a revolutionary technology and taken no credit or profit from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Unable to worship a flesh and blood body, believers have attached a legendary aura to this pseudonym. In 2022, Kanye West stepped out of a luxury car in Beverly Hills wearing a baseball cap with &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; printed on it; Budapest erected the first bronze statue of Satoshi Nakamoto - a hooded ghost; a group of libertarians bought the retired cruise ship &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; and recruited residents to establish the first Bitcoin sovereign society; more than one technical expert called for him to be awarded the Nobel Prize.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; When I first reported on Satoshi Nakamoto in 2011, I never expected that his identity would remain a mystery more than a decade later. Since then, countless attempts to &quot;reveal&quot; have failed, and some have even become farces. In 2014, Newsweek confidently identified California system engineer Dorian Nakamoto, triggering a media siege of his residence for several days. Even &quot;60 Minutes&quot;, which has top resources, was helpless and called the task &quot;impossible.&quot; But at this moment, I am sure that I have solved the mystery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I was a little uneasy. This guy had gone to great lengths to hide his tracks, and the truth I discovered was disturbing—he was nothing like the Satoshi people imagined. He repeatedly called himself a “dangerous person” and had guns hidden in his home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He also owns at least four properties on two continents. I had thought he was hiding somewhere on the Big Island of Hawaii, but in the summer of 2023, clues pointed to a small seaside town on the east coast of Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As I was getting anxious about this, I had dinner with my sister. She had been a TV news producer for 20 years and had been with the &quot;48 Hours&quot; crew when the FBI raided the home of the &quot;college bomber.&quot; She suggested that I bring professional security, wear a bulletproof vest, and notify the local police in advance. &quot;Thanks,&quot; I muttered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; That night she texted: &quot;I can&#39;t sleep, I don&#39;t know why.&quot; The time was 4:09 a.m. &quot;Two suggestions: If the target goes out, try to block him in a public place; it&#39;s best to arrange for someone to record a video remotely to keep evidence.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Could it be Elon Musk?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; On New Year’s Eve 2021, I received an email in my mailbox with the title “New Clues about Satoshi Nakamoto”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I&#39;ve been getting emails like this since I started writing about Bitcoin in the early days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The sender, Sahil Gupta, published a blog four years ago speculating that Musk was &quot;very likely&quot; Satoshi Nakamoto. This time he provided new &quot;evidence&quot;: a conversation with Musk&#39;s chief of staff, Sam Taylor. The content was vague, so I did not respond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Two days later, Gupta&#39;s detailed arguments were sent to the same email. The arguments ranged from vague to technical. I decided to reply. Sahil told me that when he was an undergraduate at Yale in 2015, he interned at the SpaceX rocket factory. Musk came to the office three days a week, and the two often met in the hallway. Sahil majored in computer science, and his graduation thesis proposed a central bank digital currency called &quot;Federal Coin&quot;, and thanked &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto, a true legend&quot; in the article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; While researching the paper, he read the cryptocurrency literature in depth, including Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s nine-page white paper. He noticed that Satoshi&#39;s word choice style was strikingly similar to Musk&#39;s: both of them liked to use expressions such as &quot;order of magnitude&quot; and &quot;bloody&quot;. Satoshi talked about currency in an abstract way, just as Musk did when he was working at PayPal. In addition, both were proficient in C++ and cryptography. Sahil began to wonder: Has the father of Bitcoin been hiding in the spotlight?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; After graduation, Sahil tried to work for Musk. After several emails, he got a phone interview with Chief of Staff Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At the end of the interview, he mustered up the courage to ask, “Is Elon Satoshi?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sahil recalled: &quot;Taylor was silent for 15 seconds, then said: &#39;What can I say?&#39;&quot; This was regarded by him as a key clue. In the same year, he wrote an article titled &quot;Elon Musk May Have Invented Bitcoin&quot;, arguing that the Bitcoin community needs the return of the founder. Although Musk tweeted to deny it (&quot;False news. A few years ago, a friend gave me some Bitcoin, but I don&#39;t know where it was lost&quot;), Sahil still believed in his theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He cited more &quot;evidence&quot;: PayPal co-founder Luke Nosek once said that the company&#39;s original intention was to create a currency independent of banks; Satoshi Nakamoto and Musk are both accustomed to leaving two spaces after periods; Musk often goes in and out of Van Nuys Airport, and the IP address accidentally exposed in an early Bitcoin email is located in northern Los Angeles; early developers commented that Satoshi Nakamoto was &quot;tyrannical&quot;, and so was Musk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At the end of 2021, Musk had just been named Time&#39;s Person of the Year, SpaceX had successfully docked with the International Space Station, and he had even joked about Dogecoin on Twitter (which subsequently soared and plummeted). Sahil believes that the public is ready to accept that Satoshi Nakamoto and Musk are the same person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He claimed to be &quot;99% sure&quot; and attributed outside doubts to &quot;prejudice against Musk.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;But Musk is not humble, why deny it?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sahil explained this by saying, “Businesses need marketing, but Bitcoin is different. The mystery of the early anonymous founders made it stronger and faster - this is where Musk’s shrewdness lies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I can&#39;t say whether Sahil is right, but I can understand his obsession. At that time, the price of Bitcoin soared to nearly $70,000, and the total market value exceeded $1 trillion. El Salvador made it legal tender. In 2011, the mystery of Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s identity seemed insignificant, but it is still an unsolved mystery today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Half a year later, I quit my job and devoted myself to this mystery that had been bothering me for more than a decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; The missing founder&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the paper, Nakamoto described a new type of currency that would run on a network of volunteer computers and rely on a transparent public ledger maintained by the entire network rather than a bank or government system of record-keeping for loans and borrowings. Nakamoto included a link to a more detailed formal description, which became known as the Bitcoin white paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Several members of the mailing list offered feedback on the software Nakamoto had written, and he gladly accepted it. “Thanks for your questions,” he wrote in one email. “My approach is actually a bit reversed: I have to write all the code first, make sure all the problems are solved, and then go back to write the paper.” In early January 2009, Nakamoto released the initial version of Bitcoin on the open source platform SourceForge. According to early participants, there were only 127 downloads on the first day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Many of the first users were programmers who believed that “currency urgently needs to be upgraded.” Paper money fades, wrinkles, tears, and becomes infected with germs; it has a fixed face value, is easy to forge, and is difficult to transfer large amounts. Bitcoin, on the other hand, is durable, unforgeable, and can be split into almost unlimited amounts, and is expected to realize the ideal of Internet micropayments—any amount can be instantly transferred to the global account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As a digital currency maintained by ordinary individuals, Bitcoin is not subject to central authority intervention. Gold can be confiscated, bank accounts can be frozen, and fiat currencies can be devalued by central bank decisions or subject to capital controls by dictators, but Bitcoin does not need to rely on these traditional systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The core of Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s creation is the blockchain - a continuously expanding system of transaction records (buys and sells, etc.). About every ten minutes, the latest transaction records are packaged into &quot;blocks&quot; and linked to the previous blocks through sophisticated mathematical algorithms, making it almost impossible to tamper with the content. In traditional finance, such ledgers are maintained by banks or government agencies; in the Bitcoin network, the ledgers are stored and updated by computers of volunteers around the world, and each device runs the Bitcoin software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Although Bitcoin is an open source project (a “many hands on” collaboration), someone still needs to coordinate. For the first 20 months, Satoshi Nakamoto took on this role. He published the code, other developers proposed changes, and he integrated the parts he approved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Four months after software developer Gavin Andresen joined the Bitcoin project, his commitment and computer science skills won Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s trust. Satoshi Nakamoto first granted him direct access to the source code, and then informed Gavin around September 2010 that he would be busy with other projects and would hand over control of the SourceForge code base and the project&#39;s &quot;alert key&quot; in the next few months - the key can broadcast emergency messages to all devices running Bitcoin software. For open source projects, these two are almost &quot;leader&#39;s scepter&quot;; at this point, Gavin officially became the chief developer of Bitcoin, leading a team of five volunteer programmers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the months that followed, Satoshi Nakamoto still occasionally participated in technical discussions, but Gavin&#39;s high-profile interactions with the outside world gradually rubbed against his reclusive style. When PayPal and Visa froze WikiLeaks&#39; accounts, some Bitcoin supporters advocated using cryptocurrency to support the controversial organization. Someone shouted on the BitcoinTalk forum: &quot;Let them come!&quot; Satoshi Nakamoto objected sharply: &quot;No! Don&#39;t let them come. The project needs to grow gradually so that the software can be improved synchronously. I implore WikiLeaks not to use Bitcoin... The attention at this moment will destroy us.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; For journalists reporting on Bitcoin, Gavin became the first choice for interviews. He was gentle and rational, willing to use his real name, and filled the role of &quot;Bitcoin ambassador&quot; that Satoshi Nakamoto never played. But this seemed to make Satoshi Nakamoto uneasy. In late April 2011, he sent an email to remind Gavin: &quot;I hope you will stop describing me as a mysterious shadow - the media will only hype Bitcoin as a label of &quot;black market currency.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This became the last email Gavin received. When I first contacted Gavin in July of the same year, he said that he had not communicated with Satoshi for several months. On April 26, Gavin emailed Satoshi to inform him that he would go to the CIA headquarters (located in Langley, Virginia) to explain Bitcoin to intelligence personnel, but received no response. On the same day, Satoshi sent an email to at least one programmer who collaborated on the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; After that, he completely disappeared. Except for a post on a forum by a suspected account many years later (it is hard to tell whether it is real or fake), Satoshi Nakamoto has never appeared again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Gavin and other early Bitcoin developers agree on a few points about Satoshi Nakamoto’s identity. The second channel for Satoshi to publish the white paper was the P2P Foundation website, an idealistic nonprofit dedicated to promoting peer-to-peer networks of all kinds. He listed his residence as Japan in his profile on the website, but no one believed he was really Japanese. His English was flawless, with a British accent: in the Bitcoin source code and BitcoinTalk forum posts, he preferred British spellings such as “colour” and “optimise”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Satoshi Nakamoto guarded his identity closely. When registering the domain bitcoin.org, he hid his information through the anonymous service anonymousspeech.com, which was registered by a short-term apartment agency in Tokyo. The service provided him with an email address at vistomail.com (which could fake the time of email sending), and he also used the free email address gmx.com. In his correspondence, he displayed a carefully trained ambiguity: he only answered technical questions and avoided personal topics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; His programming style is slightly old-fashioned, suggesting that he may be older: for example, he uses &quot;Hungarian notation,&quot; a variable naming convention popular among Windows programmers in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Gavin believes that the Bitcoin code may have been completed by a small team or even a single person. When programmers collaborate, they usually add comments to the code to explain the functions of the instructions, but there are very few such comments in the Bitcoin software. However, some people question that Bitcoin ran too smoothly in the early days of its launch, and it did not seem like it was completed independently by an individual. In addition, the white paper uses &quot;we&quot; many times, suggesting that &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; may be a nickname for a team or organization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Satoshi Nakamoto was deified before he retired. On April 16, 2011, BitcoinTalk user Wobber pointed out the complexity of his knowledge system and the abnormality of his behavior - he created such a disruptive technology but neither took credit nor profited, and quietly withdrew. Some people compared him to Zorro, or the masked David who aimed his slingshot at the banks and the government &quot;Goliath&quot; (a giant warrior among the Philistines, symbolizing overwhelming power).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Is there a clue in the name? &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; can be literally translated as &quot;Central Intelligence&quot;, which may imply that spy agencies were involved in the birth of Bitcoin. For example, the National Security Agency (NSA) of the United States may have a long-term plan: to create an unregulated financial network that is used for global agent fund dispatch and serves as a &quot;honeypot&quot; - allowing opponents to reveal their whereabouts in transactions that they think are safe and allow the NSA to monitor them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This is not entirely absurd. The U.S. Naval Research Laboratory once developed the anonymous software &quot;The Onion Router&quot; (TOR), which gave birth to the Dark Web; the FBI secretly launched the encrypted mobile phone and communication service ANOM, which was misused by criminal groups and eventually led to the arrest of more than 800 people; in the summer of 1996, the NSA&#39;s cryptography department even published an internal paper &quot;How to Forge Anonymous Electronic Cash&quot; (later made public), detailing the principles of cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Another interpretation breaks down &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; into a combination of the names of technology giants - SAmsung, TOSHIba, NAKAmichi, MOTOrola - suggesting that corporate cabals are in control of everything. Reddit users have come up with absurd sentences such as &quot;Ma, I took NSA&#39;s oath&quot; or &quot;So a man took a shit&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Dan Kaminsky, a programmer who rose to prominence in 2008 for discovering a technical vulnerability that could destroy the Internet, believes that Nakamoto may be a team inside a bank. &quot;I suspect he&#39;s a small team at a financial institution,&quot; Dan told me. &quot;That&#39;s my hunch.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But he added that Satoshi’s identity “is not important to the essence of Bitcoin. Bitcoin has long since transcended Satoshi.” This echoes a mainstream view: Satoshi’s design of quietly exiting as an anonymous entity is the foundation of Bitcoin’s decentralized spirit - his disappearance makes this technology truly a global experiment that does not require a leader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “We don’t know who Satoshi Nakamoto is”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At the 2022 Miami Bitcoin Conference, Satoshi Nakamoto was not present, but he was everywhere. The main stage was named &quot;Satoshi Hall&quot;, and screens on both sides rotated his text fragments, like Scientology&#39;s &quot;Dianetics&quot; - outsiders read it plainly, but believers take it as a motto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;Imagine gold being stolen and turned into lead.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “Twenty years from now, Bitcoin transaction volume will either be extremely high or zero.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “The robustness of the network lies in its naive decentralization.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; PayPal founder and venture capitalist Peter Thiel emerged from the right side of the stage and threw a stack of $100 bills to the front row: &quot;It&#39;s crazy that this thing still works?&quot; He declared that Bitcoin is the ultimate warning to the legal currency system, and named &quot;enemies of the crypto revolution&quot; - Warren Buffett, JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon, and BlackRock Group CEO Larry Fink. Thiel called these people &quot;extensions of state power&quot; and that Bitcoin &quot;has no board of directors, and we don&#39;t even know who Satoshi Nakamoto is&quot; - the last sentence was deliberately emphasized by him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;We don&#39;t know who Satoshi Nakamoto is.&quot; In 2011, he was an anonymous programmer followed by a fringe geek circle; ten years later, he became the &quot;myth maker&quot; of a trillion-dollar project, with Bitcoin becoming the ninth largest asset in the world, second only to Tesla and surpassing Meta. Whoever he is, he has a huge fortune. Computer scientist Sergio Demian Lerner speculated through analysis of early blockchains that the Bitcoin held by Satoshi Nakamoto was worth about $40 billion at the time (even more today), firmly ranking as the richest Bitcoiner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the spring of 2021, when the cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase went public, its prospectus submitted to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission listed &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s identity being exposed&quot; as a risk factor. It is not difficult to imagine the potential crisis: if Satoshi Nakamoto is proven to be a spy, extremist or financial criminal of a certain country, the legitimacy of Bitcoin may collapse. But the Bitcoin community gradually regards this mystery as a necessary design - decentralization requires a &quot;pure birth&quot;. Without a specific persona, it is possible to avoid divisions due to disputes over the identity of the founder, thereby maximizing universal acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Thus, the pseudonym &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; was sanctified. Although some people believed that he hid for tax avoidance or self-defense, the mainstream view portrayed him as a &quot;selfless martyr.&quot; The most fanatical believers regarded exploring his identity as blasphemy, just like asking Scientologists about the existence of Xenu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; But what if the creator of Bitcoin was a villain?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the summer of 2022, I taped a spreadsheet to my office wall that listed more than a hundred candidates who had been proposed as Satoshi Nakamoto. Most of the leading candidates were in the cypherpunk space, whose names had been proposed as Satoshi Nakamoto multiple times over the years. There were also some obscure names from adjacent fields like mathematics, cryptography, and economics. Some were programmers who had participated in the early days of the Bitcoin software project. Still others were creators of new cryptocurrencies. Many were just famous smart people: Bill Gates, Steve Jobs, Elon Musk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; For years, Nick Szabo, Adam Back, and Hal Finney were widely considered to be the leading candidates. Szabo was a programmer who advocated for decentralized currencies years before Bitcoin, and conceived a Bitcoin precursor called &quot;Bit Gold&quot; in the late 1990s. He had the necessary technical skills, and his writing style also had superficial similarities to Satoshi Nakamoto. But he has always denied being Satoshi Nakamoto, and there is no definitive evidence that he was involved with Satoshi Nakamoto or the early development of Bitcoin. Separately, Adam Back is mentioned in the Bitcoin white paper as the creator of another cryptocurrency precursor, Hashcash, and his email address was one of the first people contacted by Satoshi Nakamoto. He also denied being Satoshi Nakamoto, and his writing style did not match up as well as Szabo. Hal Finney was a legendary programmer and cryptographer who received the first Bitcoin transaction ever from Satoshi Nakamoto. But Finney, who also denies being Satoshi, was diagnosed with ALS in 2009, and his condition rapidly worsened, ultimately rendering him incapable of working. If Nakamoto were to be unmasked, Finney is the candidate Bitcoin enthusiasts would most likely want to see because of his tragic hero story and his aura of kindness and benevolence — and because he’s dead (he died in 2014), so he can’t create shady news with shady actions or connections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; There has always been opposition to the investigation of Satoshi Nakamoto&#39;s identity in the Bitcoin community. Last fall, when an HBO documentary considered libertarian, Canadian computer programmer and cryptography enthusiast Peter Todd as the most likely candidate, the Bitcoin community responded not only with strong doubts about the conclusions of the documentary, but also anger at the launch of such a project. He has made valuable contributions, so his wish for anonymity should be respected. It&#39;s not the people who matter, but the ideas and the code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But Satoshi has put his invention in the public square, so I think it’s reasonable to explore who put it there and why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I carefully combed through the 60,000 words left by Satoshi Nakamoto. His writing is plain and simple, rarely revealing personal opinions or personality. Whenever I caught a trace of his unique style, I added it to the &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto Language Library&quot; - this list eventually accumulated more than 200 distinctive words and phrases. &quot;Wet blanket&quot;, &quot;sweet&quot;, &quot;clobbering&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I wrote a computer program called &quot;Satoshitizer&quot; that goes through the archived articles of various suspected &quot;Satoshis,&quot; scans them for Satoshi terms, and generates a statistical table. I can instantly rank the archives using a dozen criteria, including users of Satoshi terms, users of electronic cash terms, and discussers of software tools used by Satoshi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; One day in late April 2023, I found myself thinking about a word I had seen in Satoshi Nakamoto’s article: hosed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Given Satoshi’s writing style’s tendency to dispense with personality or connection to any particular context, the word “hosed” stands out. I haven’t heard of the word recently, but it means to screw or break, and I vaguely associate it with 1990s surf or frat lingo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I went back through my archived data and carefully annotated every instance where the word was used. In the Metzdowd mailing list, the word “hosed” was used a total of four times in the three years before October 31, 2008, when Satoshi Nakamoto first published the Bitcoin white paper. Two of those times were by the same person: James A. Donald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Although Donald was not active in public discussions about Bitcoin, he made a brief appearance in the early history of Bitcoin as the first person to respond to Satoshi Nakamoto on the mailing list. At the time, he raised technical questions about Bitcoin&#39;s scalability and withdrew from the discussion after several rounds of exchanges with Satoshi Nakamoto. He was just one of the many cypherpunks interested in digital currency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At that time, Donald was only ranked 42nd in my suspect spreadsheet, not only far behind the three most popular candidates, but also because he was a cypherpunk and libertarian who was proficient in C++ programming. But attracted by the coincidence of the word &quot;hosed&quot;, I re-checked the rare word list generated by the &quot;Satoshi Fingerprint Analyzer&quot; to try to verify whether Donald had used other rare Satoshi-style expressions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sure enough. In my corpus spanning two decades, Donald was the only person to ever use the word “fencible”—a word that Satoshi Nakamoto had only used once in his writings as “non-fencible.” Even more shocking, Donald’s use of the word dates back to a speech on the Cypherpunks mailing list in October 1998. My brain started to ring alarm bells. “Fence” as a verb to sell stolen goods is common slang, but “fencible” as an adjective is rare. Google results turned up very few results, and even when I searched the New York Times historical database of 13 million articles (dating back to 1857), the word appeared zero times in the relevant sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Unlike conventional terms in the field of digital currency or cryptography, such as &quot;trusted third party&quot; or &quot;zero-knowledge proof&quot;, &quot;fencible&quot; and &quot;hosed&quot; are not professional terms in computer science or cryptography. They are more like fingerprints that reflect a person&#39;s language style.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I began to dig deeper into Donald. His online presence was erratic: various websites claimed he was Canadian, said he was dead, and pointed out that &quot;James A. Donald&quot; was not his real name. Although he rarely revealed personal information in his posts, there were still details scattered among them. He was from Australia but lived in Silicon Valley. Similar to Satoshi Nakamoto, his text sometimes used American spelling and sometimes used Commonwealth spelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On an ideological level, Donald combined extreme libertarianism (which was essentially anarcho-capitalism) with a passionate belief in the transformative power of cryptography. “Here, folks,” he wrote in 1996, “is our plan—we are going to destroy the state with advanced mathematics. We will do this by replacing the current corporate institutional structure with cryptographic mechanisms that will allow more people to evade and resist taxation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He showed a special interest in digital currencies. In 1995, he predicted that &quot;people will eventually bypass banks and transfer funds directly.&quot; Between 2006 and 2009, Donald used more Satoshi-style electronic cash terms on the Metzdowd mailing list than any other participant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; When examining his programming style, it was found that Donald promoted a communication encryption software called &quot;Crypto Kong&quot; in the late 1990s. The software is written in the same C++ language as Bitcoin. The source code obtained through the Internet Archive shows that Crypto Kong and Bitcoin have many similarities: both support Windows systems; both use the Hungarian naming method preferred by Satoshi Nakamoto; the code partitions use eye-catching slash separators; and both use elliptic curve cryptography to generate public and private key pairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Digging deeper into personal information, Donald was born in 1952 and is now over 70 years old, which is consistent with the feature pointed out by early Bitcoin developers that &quot;Satoshi&#39;s code style suggests that he is old.&quot; He is not active on mainstream social platforms under his real name. His $2.8 million Palo Alto home and $400,000 Austin property are blurred in Google Street View (this feature requires formal application to Google, or internal permissions like one of Donald&#39;s sons who works at Google). It is difficult to find his photos in public channels. Similar to Satoshi Nakamoto, he uses the Swiss privacy mailbox Proton Mail and runs the anonymous blog &quot;Jim&#39;s Log&quot;, saying that he has &quot;lived in seclusion for a long time.&quot; The clues clicked like gears.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At this moment, re-examining the significance of Donald as the first responder, Satoshi Nakamoto in 2008 came to my mind: he threw his amazing work to the world but no one was interested, so he directed and acted out technical doubts, which both promoted discussion and created misleading information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; His blog revealed more clues: On the eve of October 31, 2008, Donald was paying close attention to the financial crisis. His October 11 blog post, “The Roots of the Crisis,” began by asserting that “the rescue will fail,” and the headline of the Times sealed in the Bitcoin Genesis Block was “The Chancellor is about to implement a second rescue plan.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; More clues surfaced: Donald owned several properties in Hawaii. On June 19, 2008 (a few months before Satoshi Nakamoto announced his invention to the world), the Honolulu Star-Telegram published an obituary for a World War II veteran named &quot;Satoshi Nakamoto&quot; who died at the age of 84. Was this identity theft to find an alias?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Although &quot;James&quot; rarely reveals his identity, his ideological trajectory is clearly discernible in his blog posts: he was a radical leftist in his early years. At the age of 15, he joined the Trotskyist organization Spartacus League, but later left because he was &quot;disillusioned with participatory democracy and had no good feelings about representative democracy.&quot; At the age of 17, he joined anarcho-socialist and Maoist organizations, &quot;just because these two factions were the most hated by the Trotskyists.&quot; In the end, he believed that property rights were freedom and transformed into an anarcho-capitalist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; To verify his academic background, I contacted an insider at the School of Physics at the University of Sydney. Professor Bob Hewitt, who participated in the interview, recalled that this applicant from Melbourne was &quot;quite bohemian&quot; - when asked about accommodation arrangements, Donald declared that he was &quot;prepared to sleep under the bridge.&quot; Although he gave people the impression of being &quot;friendly but weird&quot;, his doctoral thesis &quot;Assumptions of the Singularity Theorems and the Rejuvenation of Universes&quot; was rejected because &quot;no one could understand it&quot;, and he eventually dropped out of school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; His career trajectory shows that Donald first wrote software for Apple Computer, then went to the United States to develop video games for Epyx, and then moved to the database field. His blog reveals a deep insight into the nature of Bitcoin: &quot;This is just a prototype system, but it was used as a final solution too early.&quot; He always looks at Bitcoin from a historical perspective and sees it as a stepping stone to an ideal future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I have never subscribed to the prevalent assumption in the Bitcoin community that Satoshi Nakamoto must be a benevolent being. I have always felt that those Bitcoin believers who deify Satoshi Nakamoto as a demigod are merely projecting a wishful thinking: that he is selfless, humble, and a prophet who has traveled from the future to save humanity. Hal Finney is an attractive candidate for Satoshi Nakamoto precisely because he fits this idealized image perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Donald is very different. In his blog, he promotes a dark ideology called &quot;neo-reactionism&quot; - a trend that has fascinated some people in Silicon Valley. Neo-reactionaries believe that society has been hijacked by what they call the &quot;temple&quot; (a group of academic, media and bureaucratic elites). They disdain efforts to pursue social justice and advocate abandoning democracy and restoring monarchy as the best path for humanity to move forward. Donald&#39;s variant of neo-reactionism is mixed with naked Christian fundamentalism and an excessive amount of paranoia: he blames the coronavirus pandemic on a Jesuit conspiracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In addition to his elaborate political manifestos, Donald continues to output racist, homophobic, misogynistic and offensive language. His sharp words were banned from Slate Star Code in 2014, a Silicon Valley heavyweight blog known for its tolerance of taboo topics such as IQ science. But on a relatively uncensored domain in Laos, he openly advocated &quot;whipping women&#39;s buttocks or upper backs to make them submissive&quot; and claimed that &quot;most rape allegations are not true.&quot; Donald has a large number of fans in the &quot;woke&quot; and alternative right blog circles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; If Donald is Satoshi Nakamoto, isn&#39;t his motivation for choosing to release Bitcoin under a pseudonym obvious? He hopes that the world will accept this genius invention purely based on the value of the work itself, rather than stifling it due to prejudice against his identity. He kept his name secret not because Bitcoin might endanger himself, but because he was afraid that his existence would endanger the future of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I doubt if anyone in the community knows or suspects that Donald is Satoshi. If Satoshi is a harmless citizen like &quot;Dorian Nakamoto&quot;, &quot;respecting Satoshi&#39;s privacy&quot; is at least a tenable position; if he is a dissident living under an authoritarian regime, I am willing to protect this secret. But what if Satoshi is really Donald? This will completely undermine the narrative of Bitcoin&#39;s inventor as a &quot;crypto messiah&quot; - the sacred image of giving up fame and fortune for lofty ideals. Among those who shouted &quot;respect Nakamoto&#39;s privacy&quot;, did some people already know that if the creator of Bitcoin is proven to be a far-right lunatic, it will inevitably cause a public relations disaster. What they really want to protect is actually the reputation of this belief system and the value of their own investment portfolio? In June 2020, Adam Back, the founder of Hashcash (long suspected to be Satoshi Nakamoto), hinted on Twitter: &quot;Perhaps we should be prepared to cut ties with Satoshi. To be on the safe side, it is best to completely erase this pseudonym.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “The identity of Satoshi Nakamoto is irrelevant,” wrote Ray Dillinger, who co-reviewed Bitcoin’s code with Hal Finney. “The protocol itself exists. Whether its creator is a Third World dictator, a homeless person under a bridge in Belize, a Bedouin working on his cell phone while riding a camel across the Bir Tawil Desert, or a pushcart vendor in Nairobi, the protocol is no different than one created by an NSA cryptanalyst, a GRU-funded ‘troll’, a well-known security researcher, or a cypherpunk. ‘Satoshi Nakamoto’ does not exist outside of the protocol. He is just a hat worn by someone during its development. As for who wore the hat—it doesn’t matter.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; “I know who Satoshi Nakamoto is”&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; I wrote to James Donald, requesting an interview. A few days later, I received a surprising response. “Email is more convenient,” Donald wrote, but he also said he might be willing to talk by phone or video. He would need a few days to confirm the arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Two months later, Donald still hasn&#39;t agreed to a live conversation. Should I go to Australia to meet him in person? What makes me doubt the hypothesis that Donald is Satoshi Nakamoto is that Satoshi Nakamoto has shown a rich spectrum of emotions in his past correspondence. He would express gratitude (&quot;Thank you very much&quot;), pity (&quot;Poor guy&quot;), humility (&quot;I&#39;m very sorry&quot;) and self-deprecation (&quot;I&#39;m better at programming than writing&quot;). When I looked through Donald&#39;s long archive of texts, trying to find traces of empathy, gratitude or enthusiasm - even an exclamation point, an apology, a moment of empathy or friendship - all I saw was an emotional desert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But among all the crypto-currency-obsessed cypherpunks, only one person claimed to know the real Satoshi Nakamoto. “I know who Satoshi Nakamoto is,” James Donald once wrote in the comments section of a post on his blog, “and his political and social aspirations.” If this was true, he would be the only credible insider in existence. I was determined to meet this person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Although Donald spent much of his career in California, he apparently owns or has owned property in Australia. By looking through the real estate appraisal records of his various properties in the United States, I found that at some point in the early 2000s, the registered address of a property in Austin under his name pointed to a street on the northeast coast of Australia. In recent appraisals, his US property is still registered in the same Australian town, but the address has been changed to a post office box. Knowing that his wife died in 2016, I found a photo of a plaque commemorating her in the town&#39;s cemetery through the &quot;grave search website&quot;. Five years later, he posted a photo on his blog that seemed to be from the terrace: in the foreground were glasses and pottery jars filled with homemade moonshine, and in the distance, the horizon of the blue sea was dotted with a few small islands. Comparing this scene with other seascape photos in the same town, the geographical features are exactly the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I contacted private investigator Daniel Quinn, who lived within driving distance of the seaside town where Donald was suspected to be. I provided Quinn with the house address and a twenty-year-old photo - this one, taken on Donald&#39;s son&#39;s abandoned college blog, was the most recent image of Donald I could find.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; A few days later, Daniel sent a surveillance report. &quot;The yard is overgrown with weeds and bushes. This person is definitely not a flower lover.&quot; The photo of the house attached to the letter showed that in front of the house that shared the driveway with two other households, there was an elevated bungalow on the hillside next to a lonely palm tree. Through the overgrown vegetation, a wooden terrace facing the Coral Sea could be seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Although I didn&#39;t see James in person that day, I received good news a few weeks later: Daniel successfully captured the man standing in front of the house. Compared with the photo taken 20 years ago, although his hair and beard were completely white, his thick beard, metal-framed glasses and plump nose were perfectly matched. Three days later, I boarded a flight to Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;I have a problem, I talk too much.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; There was no doorbell on the screen door, so I knocked on James&#39; doorframe. My throat was dry from nervousness. While I wasn&#39;t sure James himself was Satoshi, I suspected he might be part of the collective identity of &quot;Satoshi&quot;. Regardless, he was the only person I knew who had publicly claimed to know the true identity of Satoshi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I worried about how he would receive me. James had obviously gone to great lengths to make himself difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As I walked through the porch toward the front door, I saw Donald sitting in front of his computer in the living room with headphones on. His latest blog post, published a few hours ago, was a long rant about how Georgians (referring to the country Georgia) don’t want their churches to be destroyed or turned into shrines for Gaia worship and homosexuality, or that they don’t want to see ancient, beautiful buildings bulldozed and replaced by demonic, postmodern monstrosities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Western NGOs are trying to &quot;homosexualize Georgia and throw it into the meat grinder against Russia&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Seeing no response from my knocks on the door frame, I knocked directly on the front door. A moment later, James opened the door and walked out, wearing a red camouflage long-sleeved shirt and black thermal underwear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I immediately began to explain that I had emailed him—&quot;Oh, I rarely check my email,&quot; James said. I reminded him of our correspondence over the past year, and of the book I was writing. And I told him that I would be remiss if I didn&#39;t make every effort to engage in conversation with him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;In short, I can&#39;t tell you anything I can&#39;t reveal,&quot; James said, his tone gentle and with a bemused sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I pointed out that he had publicly insisted that he knew Satoshi’s identity and his sociopolitical goals. Could you elaborate? “No, sorry.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;Okay... do you really know? Or do you just have a strong suspicion?&quot; &quot;I have a good guess as to who it might be, but actually--uh, I can&#39;t be sure.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;Do you think it was Hal Finney?&quot; &quot;That&#39;s a question I can&#39;t answer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;Is it because of respecting his privacy?&quot; &quot;I am forbidden to disclose any information to anyone, including what has been said.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I suggested buying him a beer. James declined. &quot;How about lunch?&quot; I suggested. James smiled. &quot;Look,&quot; he said, &quot;I have a problem of talking too much, and after a few drinks, I talk too much, so forget it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I tried to continue the conversation—handing over my contact information and a previous book—but his responses became brief and perfunctory. &quot;It&#39;s really nice to live here,&quot; I said, pointing to the magnificent ocean view. &quot;Yeah,&quot; James nodded. I thanked him and walked down the hill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; There is no DNA test for Bitcoin&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; I have spent 15 years chasing Satoshi Nakamoto. I have learned to code, hired machine learning experts, literary analysis experts, and private investigators, and traveled 37 hours for a three-minute meeting. I am convinced that no one is as obsessed with solving this mystery as I am. I am beginning to understand why Sahil Gupta is convinced that Elon Musk is Satoshi Nakamoto. It is time to stop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Perhaps one day, artificial intelligence will help us confirm Satoshi Nakamoto’s identity. But at this point, I’m convinced that unless the government declassifies some unforeseen secrets, we will probably never know his true identity beyond a reasonable doubt. Memories fade, witnesses die. There is no paternity test for Bitcoin, and to prove who Satoshi Nakamoto is, you have to show up and show the relevant private keys, or at least provide unforged contemporary documents. As time goes by, even if there were clues, the trail becomes increasingly blurred.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I was relieved to accept this. I am still fascinated by what Satoshi created—but almost as fascinated by how perfectly he disappeared. As a utopian idea, Bitcoin has no chance of success; but as a new asset class, it has shown tenacious vitality. The price has risen and fallen, reaching new highs, exceeding $109,000 in January this year (it has fallen back to $85,000 at the time of writing). Fidelity Investments now recommends that retail investors have a small allocation of cryptocurrencies in their portfolios. The popularity of blockchain technology is unstoppable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Satoshi Nakamoto has become an existence that the people behind him can never reach - this idea, which does not need the burden of flesh and history, will eventually live forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; (Excerpt from &quot;The Mysterious Mr. Nakamoto: Fifteen Years of Uncovering the Genius Behind the Encryption World&quot; by Benjamin Wallace, Crown Publishing, available on March 18)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16914245</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16914245</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:38:13 GMT</pubDate><author>TechFlow</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>Oh my 🤔  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/dbe3ec0a63b99eb01546a7d2cc76b7b2.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  FYI&lt;br&gt;https://x.com/4_frenz/status/1902146758756491468 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  Direct link:&lt;br&gt;https://www.archives.gov/files/research/jfk/releases/2025/0318/104-10170-10145.pdf &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16913774</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16913774</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:48:03 GMT</pubDate><author>Autism Capital 🧩</author></item></channel></rss>