<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Top Rated TV Shows — TMDB</title><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/top-rated</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.thzu.xyz/themoviedb/tv/top-rated/en-US" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Top Rated TV Shows — TMDB - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:47:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Dan Da Dan</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/6qfZAOEUFIrbUH3JvePclx1nXzz.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.747&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 439 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a bet to prove whether ghosts or aliens exist, two high schoolers face terrifying paranormal threats, gain superpowers and maybe even fall in love?!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/240411</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/240411</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No One Will Miss Us</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/py0s87C9214KRbZ4kWLQfgsE9ET.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.673&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 225 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the &#39;90s, and five losers run an illegal business at their high school. They sell homework and assignments to their classmates. The advantage is that no one ever suspects the nerds. Their business brings them money and popularity. But hormones and an unexpected death threaten to ruin everything. If the business collapses, their futures and their friendships are at risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/259666</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/259666</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hazbin Hotel</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/rXojaQcxVUubPLSrFV8PD4xdjrs.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.769&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 1237 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In attempt to find a non-violent alternative for reducing Hell&#39;s overpopulation, the daughter of Lucifer opens a rehabilitation hotel that offers a group of misfit demons a chance at redemption.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/94954</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/94954</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Apothecary Diaries</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/e3ojpANrFnmJCyeBNTinYwyBCIN.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.8&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 277 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maomao lived a peaceful life with her apothecary father. Until one day, she&#39;s sold as a lowly servant to the emperor&#39;s palace. But she wasn&#39;t meant for a compliant life among royalty. So when imperial heirs fall ill, she decides to step in and find a cure! This catches the eye of Jinshi, a handsome palace official who promotes her. Now, she&#39;s making a name for herself solving medical mysteries!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/220542</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/220542</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Frieren: Beyond Journey&#39;s End</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/dqZENchTd7lp5zht7BdlqM7RBhD.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.8&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 402 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the party of heroes defeated the Demon King, they restored peace to the land and returned to lives of solitude. Generations pass, and the elven mage Frieren comes face to face with humanity’s mortality. She takes on a new apprentice and promises to fulfill old friends’ dying wishes. Can an elven mind make peace with the nature of life and death? Frieren embarks on her quest to find out.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/209867</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/209867</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adventure Time: Fionna &amp; Cake</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/fi1b6U1kp73xheECzqwzMn8u3mX.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.8&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 214 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fionna and Cake – with the help of the former Ice King, Simon Petrikov - embark on a multiverse-hopping adventure and journey of self-discovery. All the while a powerful new antagonist determined to track them down and erase them from existence, lurks in the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/131378</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/131378</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Arcane</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/fqldf2t8ztc9aiwn3k6mlX3tvRT.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.777&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 4985 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amid the stark discord of twin cities Piltover and Zaun, two sisters fight on rival sides of a war between magic technologies and clashing convictions.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/94605</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/94605</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Owl House</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/zqjSex7DZn7p4dU7mMktdJ8zQV5.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.663&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 1652 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An animated fantasy-comedy series that follows Luz, a self-assured teenage girl who accidentally stumbles upon a portal to a magical world where she befriends a rebellious witch, Eda, and an adorably tiny warrior, King. Despite not having magical abilities, Luz pursues her dream of becoming a witch by serving as Eda&#39;s apprentice at the Owl House and ultimately finds a new family in an unlikely setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/92685</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/92685</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chernobyl</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/hlLXt2tOPT6RRnjiUmoxyG1LTFi.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 6682 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The true story of one of the worst man-made catastrophes in history: the catastrophic nuclear accident at Chernobyl. A tale of the brave men and women who sacrificed to save Europe from unimaginable disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/87108</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/87108</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/xUfRZu2mi8jH6SzQEJGP6tjBuYj.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.651&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 6615 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the Taisho Period in Japan. Tanjiro, a kindhearted boy who sells charcoal for a living, finds his family slaughtered by a demon. To make matters worse, his younger sister Nezuko, the sole survivor, has been transformed into a demon herself. Though devastated by this grim reality, Tanjiro resolves to become a “demon slayer” so that he can turn his sister back into a human, and kill the demon that massacred his family.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/85937</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/85937</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Anne with an E</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/6P6tXhjT5tK3qOXzxF9OMLlG7iz.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.661&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 4727 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A coming-of-age story about an outsider who, against all odds and numerous challenges, fights for love and acceptance and for her place in the world. The series centers on a young orphaned girl in the late 1890’s, who, after an abusive childhood spent in orphanages and the homes of strangers, is mistakenly sent to live with an elderly woman and her aging brother. Over time, 13-year-old Anne will transform their lives and eventually the small town in which they live with her unique spirit, fierce intellect and brilliant imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/70785</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/70785</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Better Call Saul</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/zjg4jpK1Wp2kiRvtt5ND0kznako.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 5524 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six years before Saul Goodman meets Walter White. We meet him when the man who will become Saul Goodman is known as Jimmy McGill, a small-time lawyer searching for his destiny, and, more immediately, hustling to make ends meet. Working alongside, and, often, against Jimmy, is “fixer” Mike Ehrmantraut. The series tracks Jimmy’s transformation into Saul Goodman, the man who puts “criminal” in “criminal lawyer&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/60059</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/60059</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rick and Morty</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/gdIrmf2DdY5mgN6ycVP0XlzKzbE.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 10040 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rick is a mentally-unbalanced but scientifically gifted old man who has recently reconnected with his family. He spends most of his time involving his young grandson Morty in dangerous, outlandish adventures throughout space and alternate universes. Compounded with Morty&#39;s already unstable family life, these events cause Morty much distress at home and school.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/60625</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/60625</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Titan</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/hTP1DtLGFamjfu8WqjnuQdP1n4i.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 6650 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, the last remnants of humanity were forced to retreat behind the towering walls of a fortified city to escape the massive, man-eating Titans that roamed the land outside their fortress. Only the heroic members of the Scouting Legion dared to stray beyond the safety of the walls – but even those brave warriors seldom returned alive. Those within the city clung to the illusion of a peaceful existence until the day that dream was shattered, and their slim chance at survival was reduced to one horrifying choice: kill – or be devoured!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/1429</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/1429</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/5ZFUEOULaVml7pQuXxhpR2SmVUw.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 2145 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disregard for alchemy’s laws ripped half of Edward Elric’s limbs from his body and left his brother Alphonse’s soul clinging to a suit of armor. To restore what was lost, the brothers seek the Philosopher’s Stone. Enemies and allies – the corrupt military, the Homunculi, and foreign alchemists – will alter the Elric brothers course, but their purpose will remain unchanged and their bond unbreakable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/31911</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/31911</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Breaking Bad</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/ineLOBPG8AZsluYwnkMpHRyu7L.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.922&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 15251 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walter White, a New Mexico chemistry teacher, is diagnosed with Stage III cancer and given a prognosis of only two years left to live. He becomes filled with a sense of fearlessness and an unrelenting desire to secure his family&#39;s financial future at any cost as he enters the dangerous world of drugs and crime.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/1396</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/1396</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Avatar: The Last Airbender</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/v2vn1coUMPKw0GI1KGC5J4IXtqp.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 4277 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a war-torn world of elemental magic, a young boy reawakens to undertake a dangerous mystic quest to fulfill his destiny as the Avatar, and bring peace to the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/246</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/246</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2005 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fighting Spirit</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/i3U3J2MWovIBZBnZYYiOLBXqNJZ.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 1103 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Makunouchi Ippo is an ordinary high school student in Japan. Since he spends most of his time away from school helping his mother run the family business, he doesn&#39;t get to enjoy his younger years like most teenagers. Always a target for bullying at school (the family fishing business grants him a distinct odor), Ippo&#39;s life is one of hardship. One of these after-school bullying sessions turns Ippo&#39;s life around for the better, as he is saved by a boxer named Takamura. He decides to follow in Takamura&#39;s footsteps and train to become a boxer, giving his life direction and purpose. Ippo&#39;s path to perfecting his pugilistic prowess is just beginning...&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/42705</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/42705</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2000 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>One Piece</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/cMD9Ygz11zjJzAovURpO75Qg7rT.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 4827 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Years ago, the fearsome Pirate King, Gol D. Roger was executed leaving a huge pile of treasure and the famous &quot;One Piece&quot; behind. Whoever claims the &quot;One Piece&quot; will be named the new King of the Pirates.

Monkey D. Luffy, a boy who consumed a &quot;Devil Fruit,&quot; decides to follow in the footsteps of his idol, the pirate Shanks, and find the One Piece. It helps, of course, that his body has the properties of rubber and that he&#39;s surrounded by a bevy of skilled fighters and thieves to help him along the way.

Luffy will do anything to get the One Piece and become King of the Pirates!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/37854</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/37854</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 1999 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Sopranos</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.tmdb.org/t/p/original/rTc7ZXdroqjkKivFPvCPX0Ru7uw.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Score: 8.7&lt;br&gt;Vote Count: 2894 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story of New Jersey-based Italian-American mobster Tony Soprano and the difficulties he faces as he tries to balance the conflicting requirements of his home life and the criminal organization he heads. Those difficulties are often highlighted through his ongoing professional relationship with psychiatrist Jennifer Melfi. The show features Tony&#39;s family members and Mafia associates in prominent roles and story arcs, most notably his wife Carmela and his cousin and protégé Christopher Moltisanti.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/1398</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.themoviedb.org/tv/1398</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 1999 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>