<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Exhibition Reviews</title><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/exhibition</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.pseudoyu.com/caareviews/exhibition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Exhibition Reviews - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:26:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Charles Atlas: About Time</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4480//Charles%20Atlas.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4480&quot; data-title=&quot;&lt;em&gt;Charles Atlas: About Time&lt;/em&gt;, the Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston, 2024–2025. Photo by Mel Taing. Courtesy the artist and Luhring Augustine, New York&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4480//Charles%20Atlas.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4480//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            &lt;em&gt;Charles Atlas: About Time&lt;/em&gt;, the Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston, 2024–2025. Photo by Mel Taing. Courtesy the artist and Luhring Augustine, New York
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;One of the challenges with performance art is the exhibition and presentation of it. How do you capture the “liveness” of the live event in a stationary museum setting? Jeffrey De Bois&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;; font-size: 11px;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; with Max Gruber, curators&amp;nbsp;of &lt;i&gt;Charles Atlas: About Time&lt;/i&gt; at the Institute of Contemporary Art (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ICA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), Boston, managed to do just that. Viewers are confronted with movement and the concept of time from the start of the exhibition to the very end. Meandering through a succession of rooms, viewers encounter a series of screens and labyrinths, and only pause near the end for a respite, before the final room of sunsets and—the grand finale—a disco song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Upon entering the exhibition, viewers stand face to face with four “tweens” who stare in judgment—motionless, expressionless—with only a slow blink to indicate any kind of acknowledgment of visitors. Behind them, space—a starlit sky—expands. In front of them stand four screens that offer up a taste of what is yet to come, a series of videos created over the span of Atlas’s lifetime. Entitled &lt;i&gt;The Years &lt;/i&gt;(2019),&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;Atlas imagined it as a “stand-alone retrospective of his career” (&lt;i&gt;Charles Atlas: About Time&lt;/i&gt;, Museum Label, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ICA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Boston, 2024). The screens are unironically shaped like gravestones, a recognition that the bell tolls for all eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;After this relatively staid introduction, the exhibition gets going, and the next several rooms are comparatively chaotic and involved, starting with &lt;i&gt;MC9 &lt;/i&gt;(2013). For those unfamiliar with the Boston &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ICA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, one of its strengths is the massive and flexible space it offers. &lt;i&gt;Charles Atlas: About Time&lt;/i&gt; takes full advantage of that. What regular visitors to the museum know as a bland rectangular concrete space has been turned into a warren of large screens, visible from both sides. Merce Cunningham is immediately recognizable on many of them. &lt;i&gt;MC9&lt;/i&gt; is in fact a homage to Cunningham, who recognized Atlas for his filmmaking ability. After moving to New York City in 1970, Atlas took a job as an assistant stage manager for the Merce Cunningham Dance Company, then, in 1974, Cunningham made him the filmmaker in residence for the company. Together, they created what they referred to as “media dance.” Just as performance artists can create live works or “performances for the camera,” where the only witness at the time of action is the camera, “media dance” is a way of filming dance where the camera moves around with the dancers, rather than filming from a fixed point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The effect of this set-up is a mesmerizing experience where one feels as if in constant motion. Sound comes from all directions, different screens project varying scenes, and viewers wander directionless between it all. But there is a constant reminder of time ticking away in the form of “countdown reels,” the screen changing to a solid bright color, numbers ticking down from nine, eight, seven . . . with the expected beep, beep, beep to accompany it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The next room provides no break from the action. In &lt;i&gt;Personalities&lt;/i&gt; (2024), ten monitors are set up in a spiral in the center of an orange room, with orange polka dots, made of light projections, dotting the floor. Two monitors sit on the wall at either end of the room. As viewers navigate this smaller space they are presented with disjointed audio and video. Occasionally, the audio matches the action, but other times, the screen in view plays the audio belonging to another screen blaring in the background. It is disorienting, to say the least. The only grounding elements are the familiar faces, or “personalities” that pop up on the screens—Atlas’s collaborators, among them Marina Abramović, Leigh Bowery, the rock band Sonic Youth, and filmmaker John Waters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;If one’s head were not spinning by now, it would be in the next room, which contains another large-scale installation reminiscent of &lt;i&gt;MC9&lt;/i&gt;. But this time viewers are confronted with a mash-up of two different works: Atlas’s “antidocumentary,” &lt;i&gt;Hail the New Puritan&lt;/i&gt; (1986), a fictionalized life-in-the-day of dancer Michael Clark, Atlas’s long-time collaborator; and &lt;i&gt;Because we Must&lt;/i&gt; (1989) a film based on a theatrical stage production showing the behind-the-scenes drama. In between interview scenes with Clark from &lt;i&gt;Hail the New Puritan,&lt;/i&gt; the viewer is assaulted with over-the-top dance and theatrical scenes, lavish Baroque sets, and costumes. Leigh Bowery features prominently in these scenes, including his performance of Paul McCartney and Stevie Wonder’s “Ebony and Ivory.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;By the time viewers arrive in the next, and penultimate, room, they will no doubt need an interlude. Unlike the previous three rooms, seating takes center stage here. Viewers are invited to sit and don headphones to listen to the audio accompanying the individual video works. In addition to the room being quieter, the videos in this room are much smaller scale, and invite quiet looking. Some of these, like &lt;i&gt;The Geometry of Thought&lt;/i&gt; (2019) were created as large-scale projections onto existing architectural structures. The videos provide only an approximation of the original works. The sound was composed by Lazar Bozic in conjunction with Atlas and offers an atmospheric addition to the visuals on the screen. At the end of the room sits &lt;i&gt;Plato’s Alley&lt;/i&gt; (2008), a mesmerizing single-channel video projection that projects into a site-specific architectural installation. And once again time is foregrounded, with numbers ticking away. One anomaly in this room is &lt;i&gt;The Mathematics of Consciousness&lt;/i&gt; (2022), a video collage that includes some of Atlas’s favorite TikTok clips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The final room reminded me of the gentle swaying of an amusement park ride that has just thrown riders up and down and back and forth. A bit of rocking can return one to the steadiness of the earth, and that is what &lt;i&gt;The Tyranny of Consciousness&lt;/i&gt; (2017) provides.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Unlike many of the previous rooms, what this gallery offers is space. A large-scale video collage sits on the far wall, showing thirty-six various stages of a sunset, and a single large screen stands in the corner with a doomsday clock providing yet another countdown. In the background, ambient music and even bagpipes play as drag performer Lady Bunny laments the state of the world—noting various economic crises, social injustices, and political upheavals from the last century. As the suns continue to set, viewers wait, and after eighteen minutes, darkness comes. Then, the room erupts in song—a video performance for the camera of Lady Bunny belting out “You Were the One” complete with costume changes and wig changes that grow ever larger. Atlas ends his exhibition the way he said the world should end, with a disco song (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/disco-apocalypse-charles-atlas-films-the-end-of-times-with-sunsets-and-lady-bunny-405/&quot;&gt;Charles Atlas, in Emily Colucci, “Disco Apocalypse: Charles Atlas Films the End Times,” &lt;i&gt;Vice,&lt;/i&gt; March 11, 2015&lt;/a&gt;.) The stark contrast between the dramatic sunset and doomsday clock with the joyous disco song reminded me of Oliver’s dance to “Panic at the Disco” at the end of &lt;i&gt;Saltburn&lt;/i&gt; (dir. Emerald Fennell, 2023) a completely outlandish display among both the decadence and despair of the preceding action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Charles Atlas: About Time&lt;/i&gt; is everything one would expect it to be and more. As a person who is not easily overstimulated, my first viewing of the exhibition was disorienting and overwhelming. I felt both exhausted and at the same time inspired to move and dance, imitating some of the dancers on the screen. Walking through the maze of screens, with asynchronous sound and movement, watching the images in reverse when standing on the other side of the screen, all felt a bit much. But on my second pass through the exhibition, perhaps having been a bit more oriented, I was able to let the cacophony envelop me and embrace it, rather than fighting against it, wishing for order and logic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;It is no surprise that Charles Atlas is fascinated with TikTok. In some ways, his retrospective provides perhaps the perfect exhibition for Gen Z, or even for the tweens that stood in judgment at the entrance—an exhibition that is meant to be consumed in bite-sized pieces, because you cannot consume it all at once. Much like performance art in general, one will never absorb the entire performance. Every position offers a different view and experience. The entire layout of the exhibition reminded me of one of the first performance art pieces, &lt;i&gt;Untitled Theater Piece&lt;/i&gt; by John Cage (in which Merce Cunningham participated) at Black Mountain College in 1953, with different events and actions taking place all on the same stage. It is peculiar, then, that the last image Atlas leaves us with is one of a close-up, tight-framed video of Lady Bunny singing us out. But perhaps it is an equally fitting metaphor for life—the end is singular and finite, unlike the variability of life and one’s experiences, a diversity reflected throughout the entirety of the exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/2782&quot;&gt;Amy Bryzgel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Amy Bryzgel, Teaching Professor, Northeastern University, Department of Art + Design&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4281</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4281</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Meot: Korean Art from the Frank Bayley Collection</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4472//Moet.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4472&quot; data-title=&quot;Installation view of &lt;em&gt;Buncheong ceramics, Joseon Dynasty, Flower Jar with iron pigment floral motifs, Korean Art from the Frank Bayley Collection &lt;/em&gt; at the Seattle Asian Art Museum. August 28, 2024–Mar 9, 2025. (Photograph by the author).&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4472//Moet.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4472//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            Installation view of &lt;em&gt;Buncheong ceramics, Joseon Dynasty, Flower Jar with iron pigment floral motifs, Korean Art from the Frank Bayley Collection &lt;/em&gt; at the Seattle Asian Art Museum. August 28, 2024–Mar 9, 2025. (Photograph by the author).
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Meot: Korean Art from the Frank Bayley Collection&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;at the Seattle Asian Art Museum,&lt;/i&gt; curated by Hyonjeong “HJ” Kim Han, celebrates Frank Bayley’s sustained admiration for Korean ceramics by framing his collection through the concept of &lt;i&gt;meot&lt;/i&gt;—an aesthetic of balanced elegance that embraces imperfection. Presenting over sixty works spanning the Goryeo (918–1392) and Joseon (1392–1897) dynasties as well as contemporary reinterpretations, the exhibition reflects Bayley’s vision to capture Korean art’s evolution. While the exhibition gestures toward the layered complexities within Korean art, a more robust historical framework might better illuminate how shifting cultural values and aesthetic sensibilities influenced Korean art, particularly in ways that resonated with Western collectors like Bayley.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The concept of &lt;i&gt;meot&lt;/i&gt; serves as both an interpretive framework and organizing principle, inviting viewers to appreciate Korean art’s subtlety, understated elegance, and acceptance of imperfection, developed in close association with Confucian aesthetics, which prized humility, restraint, and simplicity over grandiosity. By emphasizing &lt;i&gt;meot&lt;/i&gt;, the exhibition not only underscores the particular qualities that characterize Korean ceramics but also draws attention to Bayley’s sensitivity to these cultural nuances with the domestic and international history of contact, innovation, and persistence in the Korean peninsula. In this way, the exhibition suggests that Bayley saw Korean art as embodying a quiet strength and beauty rooted in unpretentious forms—qualities that are not immediately striking, but resonate with a deeper sense of cultural pride and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The exhibition opens with a striking display of Joseon-dynasty &lt;i&gt;buncheong&lt;/i&gt; ware that sits between two contemporary works. Amidst this display, a &lt;i&gt;Bottle with flower design&lt;/i&gt; serves as a visual thesis for understanding the transition of Korean ceramics during the Joseon period. In contrast to the jade-like refinement of Goryeo celadons, which prioritized smooth surfaces and translucent pigmentation,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;buncheong&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;ware embodies a more expressive and folk-oriented character, marked by looser, tactile surfaces and dynamic brushstrokes. The jar’s floral motifs, rendered in the artist’s gestures in its iron pigment, convey a whimsical immediacy that diverges from the technical precision of celadon ceramics and aligns with Joseon’s literary and folk culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Within the exhibition, the buncheong &lt;i&gt;Bottle with flower design&lt;/i&gt; becomes a powerful statement on the evolution of Korean art, highlighting a shift toward materiality and simplicity resonant with Confucian values. These values, emphasizing unembellished beauty and a grounded aesthetic, reflect a broader societal movement during the Joseon dynasty. This deliberate departure from the ornate stylizations of Goryeo ceramics was achieved while building upon the peninsula’s rich natural resources—namely, its abundant high-quality clay. Potters skillfully integrated these materials into a new artistic vocabulary that aligned with the ethos of Joseon society, forging a style both organically rooted and culturally resonant. Bayley’s focus on such works reflects his appreciation for the evolution within Korean ceramics from highly refined, technically complex surfaces to a more unadorned, organic aesthetic. This perspective aligns with his broader appreciation for art that communicates strength through modest aesthetics and quiet resilience. The &lt;i&gt;Bottle with flower design&lt;/i&gt;, along with other key historical pieces in Bayley’s collection, illustrates how Korean artists moved from a focus on pristine surfaces to a more lived-in elegance, one that embraced everyday materials and a sense of immediacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;This connection of historicity within Korean art continues through works by contemporary artists such as Yoon Kwang-cho and Kim Yik-yung, whose ceramics reinterpret traditional buncheong and &lt;i&gt;baekja&lt;/i&gt; forms with a distinctly modern sensibility. Yoon’s ceramic vessels, with their rough, layered surfaces and spontaneous applications of white slip, evoke traditional buncheong techniques while offering a personal interpretation of Korean aesthetics as a living and evolving tradition. His brushwork recalls both Hangul and Hanja scripts, subtly nodding to Korea’s linguistic history and its complex interactions with Chinese culture. However, the exhibition does not provide much context for these linguistic influences, which might enhance understanding of Yoon’s references to Korean identity. His approach to surface and form reflects a spiritual yet assertive embrace of tradition, bridging the past with his own interpretation of Korean aesthetics as something continuously renewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Contemporary artist Kim’s Moon Jar offers another compelling example of how contemporary artists engage with traditional forms while subtly reimagining them. The &amp;nbsp;jar’s unadorned white porcelain, a hallmark of Joseon-era Confucian values, conveys a restrained elegance that embodies ideals of purity and humility. Her reinterpretation introduces modified proportions and textures that lend a contemporary gaze to the iconic form without diminishing its historical significance. This delicate evolution from tradition to innovation mirrors Bayley’s admiration for Korean art’s capacity to adapt without losing its essence. The seemingly simple form of Kim’s jar, however, is deceptive; its soft, irregular shape demands technical precision and skill, showcasing Korean art’s dual ability to balance fragility with resilience—a duality that Bayley found deeply compelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;While the exhibition effectively conveys its donor’s appreciation for Korean ceramics, it could benefit from a broader examination of the cultural intersections that shaped Korean art’s trajectory. For instance, Son Manjin’s calligraphic work, rooted in Chinese influences, celebrates Hangul’s unique role in asserting Korean identity. Similarly, Yoon’s inscriptions reflect the continuity of tradition while calling attention to Korea’s distinctive aesthetic heritage. However, the exhibition’s limited framing of calligraphy and language traditions misses an opportunity to explore these rich intercultural dialogues, which have historically been integral to Korean art’s evolution. By incorporating more historical context into these exchanges, the exhibition could deepen viewers’ understanding of Korean art as a narrative of resilience and cultural self-definition amid external influences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Even as the aesthetic brilliance, technical mastery, and collector’s vision of the artworks merit attention, it is worth reflecting on the historical weight of Japanese colonial influence on Korean visual culture. During Japan’s colonial rule over Korea (1910–45), artistic and cultural practices were often subject to censorship and stylistic regulation, influencing how artists navigated traditional forms under constraint. Recognizing these colonial dynamics, even briefly, would provide valuable context, as many pieces in the exhibition reveal both adaptation to and resistance against these imposed influences. Considering these external pressures would align with an increasing trend in museums to present colonized cultures’ art within frameworks that acknowledge resilience and survival under oppression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Through the juxtaposition of traditional and contemporary works, the exhibition captures an ongoing dialogue between Korea’s past and present. By placing these works side by side, the curatorial choice allows viewers to trace a continuous thread that highlights the adaptability and continuity of Korean art traditions. The display reveals how traditional aesthetics can coexist with and inspire modern innovation, illustrating Bayley’s vision of Korean art as a cultural lineage that transcends historical boundaries. The arrangement offers a cohesive narrative of Korean art that values its origins while celebrating its capacity to evolve in response to modernity, reaffirming Bayley’s commitment to honoring both the past and the living heritage of Korean aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Ultimately, &lt;i&gt;Meot: Korean Art from the Frank Bayley Collection&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;at the Seattle Asian Art Museum&lt;/i&gt; presents Bayley’s collection as a tribute to Korean art’s unique blend of refinement and strength. By situating traditional and contemporary works alongside each other, the exhibition underscores a deep and enduring connection between Korea’s historical identity and its contemporary expression, embodied in ceramics that have survived centuries of change. Through Bayley’s legacy, the exhibition honors Korean art as a resilient, evolving form that retains its core values while remaining open to subtle innovation. Although further historical context might amplify the narrative, &lt;i&gt;Meot &lt;/i&gt;stands as an homage to Bayley’s vision and a testament to the depth of Korean artistic tradition—a lineage as enduring and multifaceted as the high-fired ceramics it celebrates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3514&quot;&gt;Inji Kim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
PhD Student, Department of Art History, School of Art + Art History + Design, University of Washington&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4317</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4317</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Keith Haring: Art Is for Everybody To My Friends at Horn: Keith Haring and Iowa City</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4455//Haring%20at%20Walker_Installation%20View.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4455&quot; data-title=&quot;&lt;em&gt;Keith Haring: Art is for Everybody&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, Walker Art Center, 2024 (photograph by the author)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4455//Haring%20at%20Walker_Installation%20View.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4455//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            &lt;em&gt;Keith Haring: Art is for Everybody&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, Walker Art Center, 2024 (photograph by the author)
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4456&quot; data-title=&quot;&lt;em&gt;To My Friends at Horn: Keith Haring and Iowa City&lt;/em/&gt;, installation view, The University of Iowa Stanley Museum of Art, 2024–25 (photograph by the author)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4456//Haring%20at%20Stanley_Installation%20View%201.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4456//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            &lt;em&gt;To My Friends at Horn: Keith Haring and Iowa City&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, The University of Iowa Stanley Museum of Art, 2024–25 (photograph by the author)
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Keith Haring’s journals (Penguin Books, 2010) open with the nineteen-year-old burgeoning artist hitchhiking across the Midwest. Before he moved to New York and enrolled in the School of Visual Arts, the kid from Kutztown, Pennsylvania followed the Grateful Dead, selling t-shirts, getting high, and seeing the country. In Minnesota he found a tree by the St. Croix River that he was “gonna come back to, someday” (2). After the Dead show in Minneapolis, he and his companion hitched a ride and ate in a bar on the North Dakota border surrounded by farmers who commented on Haring’s hair when he went to the bathroom (“Rednecks!” he writes, though it’s unclear if this is a complaint or just observation) (3). Later, they get “a ride to Des Moines, Iowa, with a really neat guy who had tame raccoons” (6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In New York, Haring embraced his sexuality and developed the style that made him one of the most recognizable and widely reproduced artists in the world. Throughout the remarkably productive later years of his too-short life, he only sporadically found time to return to his journal; the Minnesota tree forgotten like so many of the whims we move past as we grow up and our worlds get bigger. Yet, even when his world was very big, Haring returned to the Midwest in residencies that demonstrate how he realized the goals he made for himself in that first anxious journal entry when he decided to live “life my way . . . forget all my silly preconceptions, misconceptions, and live . . . Just live till I die.” Everywhere he went until his death at thirty-one from &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;-related illness, Haring brought an energetic spirit that inspired people to expand their ideas and optimism with which he faced the world’s most challenging realities. Two recent exhibitions at Midwest museums put this tireless creativity, generosity, and compassion on display, emphasizing Haring’s global importance but also the ongoing significance of his presence in places far from the New York art scene that made him famous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Keith Haring:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Art is for Everybody&lt;/i&gt;, organized by The Broad, concluded at the Walker Art Center in Minneapolis this past September. An ambitious, blockbuster survey of Haring’s visual style, artistic biography, and activism, it weaves expansively through several galleries and is accompanied by a richly illustrated full-color catalog. On view forty years after Haring’s short-term residency in Minneapolis, the exhibition’s Minnesota iteration includes small additions based on his time there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;To My Friends at Horn: Keith Haring and Iowa City&lt;/i&gt; at the University of Iowa’s Stanley Museum of Art is a smaller and more focused exhibition that considers Haring’s trips to Iowa City in 1984 and 1989, the result of his correspondence with Colleen Ernst, an art teacher at Ernest Horn Elementary School, that began when Ernst sent Haring a postcard in 1982. The Stanley features two rarely seen murals made during those visits. &lt;i&gt;Untitled&lt;/i&gt; (1984) depicts a mutant Day-Glo caterpillar with eight legs, a computer head, and a dollar sign face ridden by headless human figures and surrounded by radiating lines. Painted with live jazz accompaniment at a local mall, the work references Haring’s ongoing concerns about capitalism and technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;A Book Full of Fun&lt;/i&gt; (1989), Haring’s second Iowa City mural is, deservedly, the exhibition’s primary subject. Made for Horn’s library, it depicts an open book (playfully labeled “Book” with a corresponding arrow) with a smiling face spread across its pages. A large thought bubble emerges from its spine, crowded with fantastical characters, letters, and numbers. Photos in a neighboring display case document how Haring started by painting irregular shapes in primary colors, green, and turquoise across the plain white ground, using those shapes as the basis for completing his figures with bold black lines. A polka-dot-bikini-clad elephant falls off a surfboard above a bewildered slice of just-popped toast. A daisy grows out of a grinning head with legs, no body, and a big red nose, and a kangaroo carries a frowning baby in their pouch. These and the many other exuberant figures that play in the bubble and extend beyond its borders make the mural an absorbing “I spy” game that presents reading as the foundation for unlimited imagination. Painted with the artist’s instruction that it never be removed or sold, the mural came to the Stanley on a thick section of wall (it could not be moved safely otherwise) and will return to Horn following renovations to the building, making this the first and likely only time it will be exhibited outside the school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;While the scale of the Walker exhibition offers a more comprehensive look at Haring’s life and career, the Stanley show is a touching case study of the larger exhibition’s titular sentiment, “art is for everybody” (a quote taken from Haring’s journals), and its lasting impact on one community. At their best, both exhibitions demonstrate how Haring’s art acts as a “fallout shelter against cynics in the atmosphere” (Robert Farris Thompson, &lt;i&gt;Journals&lt;/i&gt;, xxiv) without shying away from protest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Both exhibitions aim to introduce Haring to a broad viewership. Curators likely rightfully assume that while his distinctive iconography and visual style will be familiar to most casually interested visitors, the details of his biography, activism, and the longer arc of his artistic practice may be significantly less so. Each show thus opens with the guerilla origins of Haring’s famous figures and public persona on subway platforms. In 1980, characters such as his barking dog and “radiant baby” emerged as simple, speedy drawings in white chalk on the black paper that occupied temporarily empty advertising spaces. The Walker effectively illustrates this formative period in the first of its several galleries. There, multiple, near-life-size slideshow projections display Tseng Kwong Chi’s documentary photographs of Haring’s subway artworks. A record of the artist’s arrest for a misdemeanor for reckless property damage appears next to a poster advertising a publication of Tseng’s photographs and, a couple of galleries over, a 1982 &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CBS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Evening News&lt;/i&gt; profile on Haring shows one of his many brief arrests interspersed with scenes from his first Soho gallery show. All indicate the almost immediate contradictory multiplicity of Haring’s career as simultaneously an antiestablishment rebel, art world darling, and highly commercial popular artist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Tseng’s role as Haring’s long-term documentarian receives at least a brief mention in both exhibitions, as do many of Haring’s predecessors and collaborators, including choreographer Bill T. Jones, and graffiti artists such as Fab 5 Freddy (Fred Brathwaite), Lee Quiñones, and LA II (Angel Ortiz). Jones contributes a nuanced reflection to The Broad’s catalog, describing both the racial power dynamics involved in his project with Haring as well as its “spirit of fun and freedom” (143), and Tom Finkelpearl’s excellent essay further considers Tseng as both his friend’s photographer and an artist in his own right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;That Haring was entering an already established street art community populated primarily by Black and Latinx artists receives some elaboration in a brief wall text at the Walker, as does the at-times vaguely appropriative nature of the artist’s line and style. Performance studies scholar Ricardo Montez discusses Haring’s complex relationship to other artists, cultural histories, and racial identities at length in &lt;i&gt;Keith Haring’s Line &lt;/i&gt;(Duke University Press, 2020) and is quoted in curator Sarah Loyer’s catalog essay. Kimberly Drew addresses Haring’s white privilege (even as he faced significant discrimination as a gay man during the early days of the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HIV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; epidemic) and his sincere engagements with community more fully in her illuminating contribution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The Walker exhibition benefits from space for monumentality and breadth, encompassing Haring’s art school days, sexually explicit images, performance collaborations, environmental and antiapartheid activism, and commercialization of his own work through the Pop Shop. Its scale and variety are exciting, and some of Haring’s largest and most colorful artworks are displayed to awesome effect. It’s also clear that part of Haring’s brilliance as a communicator came from knowing precisely who he was making art for at any given moment. Art for everybody is not necessarily the same art for everybody all at once. This creates a difficult task for curators, however, and leads to penis drawings cordoned off from designs for children’s chairs and public murals appearing only in small-scale photos. A flashing video projection somewhat overshadows the corner dedicated to Haring’s time at the Walker which is represented on a small scale by his black-and-white Art Fest poster, photos of a children’s theatrical performance with Haring-designed sets, and a no-longer-extant mural of another computer-headed mutant similar to his Iowa City mural of the same year. More than an issue of curation, this awkwardness is a testament to the diversity of Haring’s work and its effectiveness outside of traditional gallery spaces, a quality that can make the many vivid billboards and bus stop ads promoting the show around Minneapolis seem almost as impactful as the exhibition itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;At the Stanley, a three-dimensional lithograph by Red Grooms introduces Haring. &lt;i&gt;Subway&lt;/i&gt; (1986) is a small (roughly one square foot) cutaway of passengers on a crowded and graffitied &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NYC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; subway car pulling into a station where the artist is nearly finished with a new drawing. The crouched Haring, in his distinctive glasses with chalk in hand, looks back over his shoulder at the viewer and smiles. Like a pop-up book or shoebox diorama, &lt;i&gt;Subway &lt;/i&gt;offers a delightfully playful entry into a show that centers around Haring’s visits to an elementary school while refraining from offering a diluted portrayal of the artist’s career. Turning a corner, visitors enter a compact but well-arranged gallery space&lt;a name=&quot;_Hlk175572016&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;where Haring’s Iowa City murals hang opposite a timeline describing the artist’s life alongside Iowa City’s early relationship to the gay rights movement and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; activism. A pair of artworks on loan from the Haring Foundation is installed to the left and right, and there is a small reading nook stocked with picture books on Haring, art, and queer identity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Most impactful in providing context for the murals, however, is the comprehensive display of archival materials from Haring’s visits to Horn. This collection features moving tributes to the children’s fondness for Haring and his care for them (including a bulletin board of photographs, video footage of students singing Happy Birthday to the artist less than a year before his death, interviews with some of those students today, and a case of handwritten doodles and notes), now made more poignant by the recent death of the beloved art teacher and Haring’s initial Iowa City contact, Ernst, known to twenty-five years of students as “Dr. Art.” One of her self-portraits is also on view. These two people believed in the importance of art—especially accessible and empathetic art—to children’s education. In one letter from Haring to Ernst, the artist notes that “it’s really incredible to me that the school took the initiative to institute a discussion about &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; . . . It makes me proud I had the courage to talk about it . . . Education is the key to stopping this thing!” Haring’s joyous library mural and earnest emphasis on education feel as important now as they were forty years ago. In August, Iowa’s SF 496, a book ban and “don’t say gay” bill, challenged by educators, mental health experts, and the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ACLU&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, went into effect. A children’s biography of Harvey Milk included in the Stanley exhibition’s reading nook is among the texts that could be banned in schools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The Walker exhibition concludes powerfully with Haring’s &lt;i&gt;Unfinished Painting&lt;/i&gt; (1989). Energetic lines and dancing figures appear in purple, black, and white in the painting’s upper-left corner but stop abruptly giving way to uneven drips and blank canvas. It is a testament to the many artworks left unfinished or never made by those who have died in the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HIV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; epidemic. We will never know what else Haring might have done. Yet his work continues in these exhibitions—creating a safe space for reading banned books in Iowa and making Minneapolis more colorful. Around the University of Minnesota’s campus, inspired hands have even taken to doodling Haring-esque dancers on light poles and window frames, out on the street for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3484&quot;&gt;Amy Meehleder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
PhD Candidate, University of Minnesota, Twin Cities&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4279</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4279</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Sarah Loyer, ed.</author></item><item><title>Jaune Quick-To-See Smith: Memory Map</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4426//Jane%20Quick%20.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4426&quot; data-title=&quot;&lt;em&gt;Jaune Quick-to-See Smith&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, Seattle Art Museum, February 29–May 12, 2024. (photograph by author)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4426//Jane%20Quick%20.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4426//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            &lt;em&gt;Jaune Quick-to-See Smith&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, Seattle Art Museum, February 29–May 12, 2024. (photograph by author)
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;If any single person is responsible for the momentum that contemporary Native American art is having at this moment it is Jaune Quick-to-See Smith (1940–2025, enrolled Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes). This is, at least, one of the central takeaways of &lt;i&gt;Jaune Quick-to-See Smith: Memory Map&lt;/i&gt;, which traces five decades of Smith’s career as both one of the leading artists and influential curators of Contemporary Native American art. The retrospective is an exciting, nearly dizzying, display of Smith’s artistic oeuvre that provides a textural depth to the artist’s career for those familiar with her work while still being a welcoming introduction for those encountering Smith’s art for the first time. The accessibility of the show is due mostly to Smith’s art itself, which provides innumerable aesthetic and intellectual inroads to understanding the overarching themes of colonial disruption, Indigenous resilience, and ecological responsibility through vignettes of Smith’s anticapitalistic sentiment, Salish Kootenai knowledge, and critiques of Western art history. Ultimately, &lt;i&gt;Memory Map &lt;/i&gt;overwhelms us with the work of an artist whose life’s work has engendered a sense of Native place and belonging with the contemporary art world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;As the exhibition title suggests, &lt;i&gt;Memory Map &lt;/i&gt;is a collection and recollection of Smith’s over eighty years of memories and experiences, with the artist representing colonial histories and contemporary politics through both Salish ways of being and a wider Native American worldview. Curated by Laura Phipps, from the Whitney Museum, the exhibition contextualizes and enriches Smith’s art through a sweeping layout as the show chronologically and thematically traces a portrait of Smith as a consummate artist-activist and artist-curator. Paraphernalia from Smith’s curatorial interventions, such as brochures and candy from the quincentennial exhibition &lt;i&gt;Submuloc show/Columbus wohs&lt;/i&gt;, frame the main entry points to the galleries and punctuate the importance of the artist’s role as a curator. Additionally, at the Seattle Art Museum (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), where this reviewer saw the show on its over year-long tour through three US cities, Phipps and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; curator Theresa Papanikolas ensure that decades worth of the artist’s works, thoughts, and themes are visible from any given vantage point in the exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The ability to view multiple galleries and dozens of artworks at once constantly reiterates the interconnectedness of Smith’s art, life, curation, and activism. Much like Smith’s artistically layered and textually dense artworks, there is no single experience of the exhibition. With multiple entryways to any gallery or niche, visitors can experience the show in any direction and order, encountering Smith’s earliest artworks alongside some of her most recent creations. The layout often forces people to double back past artworks they have already seen to access corners they missed, which always resituates the cumulative experience of Smith’s art. Consequently, the curatorial choices stress the deep relationality between artworks often separated in creation by decades, imparting the persistence of the issues faced by Indigenous Americans and Smith’s dedication to articulating her experiences of and responses to the colonial pressures of contemporary Native life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;One such revelatory moment for this reviewer was while standing in an open, octagonal “room” near the center of the exhibition containing Smith’s &lt;i&gt;Memories of Childhood&lt;/i&gt; series (1994). The nine collages in this space recount the people, culture, and landscape that the artist grew up with as well as her imaginative dreams, such as flying as a butterfly, becoming an artist, and knowing her mother’s face. In the prints, Smith often situates herself among the flora and fauna of the places she grew up. Washingtonians will feel comfortable among Smith’s remembrances of living alongside Western Red Cedars, Blue Huckleberry, Camas, Douglas Firs, and Yew trees while those from Big Sky country might recall the time they too slept under the stars among the Lodgepole Pines. Simultaneously, while visitors wander the representational landscapes of Smith’s childhood memories, they can see dozens of the artist’s most iconic artworks and motifs through the four missing walls of the octagonal space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In the view to the north sits &lt;i&gt;Trade (Gifts for Trading Land with White People)&lt;/i&gt;, a title which references the apocryphal tale of the Lenape selling Manhattan to the Dutch for a handful of beads. The triptych is collaged with found paper materials and overlayed with a painterly canoe while a string of commercial items from the 1990s that depict the Indian stereotypes sits above the canvases: a Braves’ terry towel, two Redskins’ ball caps, several colleges’ bumper stickers, six different Indian costume items including a plastic tomahawk, seven beaded fashion accessories, some liquor shooters, and one doll. To the east and south sit &lt;i&gt;Trade Canoe: Making Medicine&lt;/i&gt; (2018)—cocreated with Smith’s son Neal Ambrose-Smith—and &lt;i&gt;Tongass Trade Canoe &lt;/i&gt;(1996). The two trade canoes, though separated by over two decades and different mediums, both consider how the impact of colonialism has disrupted Native ways of being, especially around food sovereignty and security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Finally, or firstly, at the exhibition entrance in the west sits &lt;i&gt;Indian Madonna&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Enthroned&lt;/i&gt; (1974). Reminiscent of Edward Kienholz’s &lt;i&gt;The Wait&lt;/i&gt; (1964), the sculpture portrays an American Indian Movement (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AIM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) era woman who has a heart of maze, carries her child in a cradleboard on her back, and holds Vine Deloria Jr.’s seminal book &lt;i&gt;God is Red&lt;/i&gt; in her hand. Consequently, this Madonna epitomizes Smith’s view of contemporary Native identity as she bridges tradition, politics, and futurity. Moreover, with a trading canoe—a motif Smith has used for over three decades—visible in all four cardinal directions, Smith further closes the temporal distances between some of the earliest events of colonial history, her life’s experiences, and contemporary Native resurgence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;By articulating how deeply intertwined personal experiences are with the historical, political, and cultural pressures of colonialism, &lt;i&gt;Memory Map’s&lt;/i&gt; network-like web of artwork creates its own kind of cartography of Smith’s personhood. Seneca scholar Mishuana Goeman calls this a Native narrative map in her 2013 book &lt;i&gt;Mark My Words: Native Women Mapping Our Nations&lt;/i&gt;. Goeman explains, “Unlike Western maps whose intent is often to represent the “real,” Native narrative maps . . . are not absolute but instead present multiple perspectives—&lt;i&gt;as do all maps&lt;/i&gt;,” (Goeman, Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 2013: 25). Just in the examples above, Smith’s atlases her reality through critical colonial history, radical Native politics, Indigenous world views, and her own intimate dreams. As a result, the space of the exhibition creates Smith’s memory map by emphasizing the personal, cultural, and historic stories the artist continuously tells through her art and curation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The arrival of &lt;i&gt;Jaune Quick-to-See Smith: Memory Map&lt;/i&gt; at the Seattle Art Museum marked a kind of coming home for the eighty-four-year-old artist. Having spent many of her child and adolescent years in and around Seattle, Smith’s connection to the Duwamish and Coast Salish lands the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SAM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; now occupies is evident. Seattleites will enjoy spying Smith’s witty appropriations of formline, reading quotes from Chief Seattle’s famous 1854 speech, and learning about her contributions to the West Seattle Cultural Trail. For those not from the Pacific Northwest, or who saw &lt;i&gt;Memory Map &lt;/i&gt;in either New York City or Fort Worth, Texas, Smith’s paintings, sculptures, and prints always reward those who take the time to look closely at them. A visitor could happily spend several hours reading the decades-old news articles pasted into Smith’s painting, following the reoccurrence of phrases, characters, and visual motifs across multiple artworks, and reveling in the artist’s interpolation of the Western art canon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;If this reviewer does have any critique of &lt;i&gt;Memory Map&lt;/i&gt; it is the sprawling mass of the show, with over one hundred and thirty objects in the exhibition. The size and expanse of the exhibition are necessary to adequately showcase the five-decade career of such a prolific artist. However, combined with the density of Smith’s art, &lt;i&gt;Memory Map&lt;/i&gt; might threaten to overwhelm the casual museumgoer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Simultaneously, it is also because of the exhibition’s critical mass that even just a cursory visit imparts the weight and complexity of Indigenous peoples’ experiences of dispossession and oppression under colonialism. Smith is an incredibly deft communicator as she introduces and expands viewers’ understanding of a variety of interconnected topics, such as forced relocation and assimilation’s effects on Native cultures and the ongoing problem of the environment’s destruction under colonial capitalism. In many ways, the discursive didacticism of Smith’s art is produced through the visual and textual density of her oeuvre, not despite it. Consequently, every vignette, story, and prescient message Smith shares is worth absorbing. &lt;i&gt;Memory Map&lt;/i&gt; has an exceptional sense of being thereness for the past fifty years of Native American art and activism that few individuals—Smith being one of them—could offer, and a generation of artists and art lovers are indebted to the landscapes she imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3470&quot;&gt;Mariah Ribeiro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
PhD Student, Department of Art History, University of Washington&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4262</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4262</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond Hope: Kienholz and the Inland Northwest</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4428//Beyond%20Hope.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4428&quot; data-title=&quot;Edward Kienholz and Nancy Reddin Kienholz, &lt;em&gt;The Returning, 1976. Estate of Nancy Reddin Kienholz&lt;/em&gt;. Courtesy of L.A. Louver, Venice, CA&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4428//Beyond%20Hope.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4428//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            Edward Kienholz and Nancy Reddin Kienholz, &lt;em&gt;The Returning, 1976. Estate of Nancy Reddin Kienholz&lt;/em&gt;. Courtesy of L.A. Louver, Venice, CA
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Greeting the visitor to &lt;i&gt;Beyond Hope: Kienholz and the Inland Northwest &lt;/i&gt;in a gallery of Washington State University’s Jordan Schnitzer Museum of Art is a wall-mounted assemblage featuring a black-and-white photograph of elderly figures in their Sunday best moving into a starkly empty field surrounded by high hills. The sepia-toned stain of liquid resin applied across the image enhances the sense of time past and the idea that it represents a fragile memory of a momentous change in the lives of the people depicted. Titled&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Returning&lt;/i&gt; (1976), the landscape recalls the open rolling hills of the Palouse region of the Washington/Idaho state border that surround the campus. Framed by galvanized sheet metal, working electric lights, and a small, ceramic space heater, this curious image (repeated in a smaller print mounted behind the heater’s wire grill) announces some of the key themes of this show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;After first achieving fame and notoriety in Los Angeles as a leading West Coast assemblage artist, Ed Kienholz moved to Hope, Idaho (population about 50) in 1973, the area where he grew up. Shortly after his marriage to Nancy Reddin, Kienholz “returned” to the inland Pacific Northwest to start a new phase of his career in collaboration with his wife.&amp;nbsp; At the same time, he established another studio in West Berlin where the artists split their time until the mid-1990s. In this surprising show, guest curator Johanna Gosse (formerly of the University of Idaho, now at The Courtauld Institute, London) turns attention to the history and nature of this region as seen through the work and community that Ed and Nancy made there and revises our understanding of the way place resonates in Kienholz’s art.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Known primarily for his groundbreaking found-object sculptures with which he took on hot-button social issues—desegregation, abortion, teen sex—in a decidedly more figurative and politically-engaged approach than East Coast assemblage makers, Kienholz was central to early efforts to promote avant-garde art within the conservative culture of Cold War Los Angeles. He famously cofounded the city’s most important gallery of the period, Ferus, by signing an agreement with his partner Walter Hopps on a hot dog stand napkin in 1957. Hopps and Kienholz both embodied the “frontier” spirit of this new art scene, with Kienholz being called a “lumberjack” by some LA artists who looked down on his rural origins, but Gosse astutely connects the historical resonance of this kind of language to Kienholz’s relationship with settler-colonialism, violence, and the environment in the American West through her selection of work from the late 1960s to the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The frontier may be glimpsed in the landscape featured in &lt;i&gt;The Returning&lt;/i&gt; but is also symbolized by the multipart bronze sculptural installation of &lt;i&gt;Mine Camp&lt;/i&gt; (1991), reproduced in a photographic print that spans the entire back wall of the large gallery adjacent to the museum entrance. The photograph documents this large-scale work where it is&amp;nbsp;currently installed in the woods near the Kienholz compound in Hope. &lt;i&gt;Mine Camp&lt;/i&gt; is an homage to Kienholz’s love of the outdoors instilled in him by his father on numerous camping and hunting trips in the region. An astounding work entirely in cast bronze, it features a full-size replica of a pickup truck, a deer carcass strung up on a pine tree, a log pile, a campfire, and the figure of Kienholz as a middle-aged man sitting at the edge of the campsite, with his hunting rifle, tools, cookware, and canned and bottled goods all arranged nearby. The Schnitzer Museum was able to secure a few of the smaller bronze items for display—a bag of potatoes, some individual pinecones, a carton of eggs, and a bottle of Jack Daniels—whose striking realism invites close examination and creates a visual dialog with the reproduction of the entire work on the wall behind them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;This artwork, fabricated in Washington state at the innovative Walla Walla Foundry, is the most traditional mode of sculpture in the show, which may appeal to a broader public than most of the other assemblage and conceptual work in &lt;i&gt;Beyond Hope&lt;/i&gt; and anchors the exhibition in a landscape and set of activities familiar to the show’s largely local audience in this rural college town. However, the title is crucial, as for many of Kienholz’s works, because it alludes to the more complex issues animating the artist’s practice via its pun on Hitler’s &lt;i&gt;Mein Kampf&lt;/i&gt;. Kienholz’s “struggle” represented here may only be with different aspects of his identity and the contrast of his rural roots with the slick art world of the 1980s, but Gosse boldly sets this piece, and the eponymous pun, as the entry point into the exhibition’s larger themes by alluding to the histories of white supremacy, neofascism, and right-wing terrorism that haunt the region’s first settlement and its recent history in the wall text and her exhibition essay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mine Camp&lt;/i&gt; served as a backdrop for vitrines and video screens which presented archival material documenting the Kienholzes’ various artistic projects based in Hope (an artist’s residency, an art gallery, guest speakers), their connections to art scenes across the Northwest, as well as their life with family and friends in Hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Through the Faith and Charity in Hope Gallery, the Kienholzes brought the work of artists such as Francis Bacon, Jasper Johns, Alberto Giacometti, Jay DeFeo, and Emil Nolde to this tiny town. In a 1980s video tape, Kienholz and a group of friends, including the art critic Robert Hughes, are shown returning from a hunting trip and cleaning their pheasants together outside the house. This is remarkable proof of how the international art world and rural American pursuits mixed in the Kienholzes’ Hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;One of the more compelling works in the exhibition, &lt;i&gt;The Non-War Memorial&lt;/i&gt; (1970), reveals that Kienholz was contemplating working in the area even while he was active in the Los Angeles art world of the late sixties. One of the series of “concept tableaux,” typed proposals for larger-scale work or more conceptual projects than the work he had become known for (framed and accompanied by an engraved brass title plaque), &lt;i&gt;The Non-War Memorial&lt;/i&gt; is a haunting, site-specific piece to be created in the town of Clark Fork, Idaho, nearby Hope. If fully realized, the piece would bring a group of artists, activists, students and local residents together to fill fifty thousand surplus US military uniforms with slurried clay and then scatter them over a 75-acre field, echoing the forty-eight thousand &amp;nbsp;American soldiers that had been killed in the Vietnam War by 1970 when the piece was conceived. Managed by a partnering museum, the uniforms would be allowed to rot for five years, letting the clay and fabric disintegrate and become embedded in the soil before the site was plowed over and planted with alfalfa grass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In 1970, this was a very forward-thinking conception of land and environmental art in a memorial mode. But as Gosse highlights, the specific location that Kienholz chose for The &lt;i&gt;Non-War Memorial&lt;/i&gt; and his emphasis on the land and natural processes suggests a relationship between the violence of the Vietnam War and the landscape that was the site of the decimation and dispossession of the region’s Indigenous population during the Nez Perce Wars of the 1870s. Waged near the town of Clark Fork, this violent episode made way for the establishment of the state of Idaho in 1890. With its five, sand-filled, olive green, unmarked military uniforms arranged on the floor in a corner of the gallery, &lt;i&gt;The Non-War Memorial &lt;/i&gt;is one of the most striking pieces in the show. It can also be seen when looking at &lt;i&gt;The Returning&lt;/i&gt;, putting the landscape evocative of the Palouse hills in dialog with histories of military violence. The gallery presentation of the work includes a three-ring binder containing gridded pages of small black-and-white photographs depicting the stuffed uniforms arranged in various poses on the ground. This thousand-page document evokes the bureaucratic tallying of war deaths which characterized the US media coverage and the American military “progress” reports on the Vietnam War.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt; Many of the other works in the exhibition, such as the sparse abstract compositions of &lt;i&gt;The H.I.D Series&lt;/i&gt; and galvanized metal, wood and found object constructions of The &lt;i&gt;White Easel Series&lt;/i&gt;, demonstrate Kienholz’s engagement with minimalism, an influence not often registered in accounts of his practice. Select “barter works,” which consist of the printed name of the item for which Kienholz would trade the artwork, such as &lt;i&gt;For A Tent and Fishing Gear &lt;/i&gt;(1974), show Kienholz’s dialog with conceptual art routed through the concerns of a working artist in a rural area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Overall, &lt;i&gt;Beyond Hope: Kienholz and the Inland Northwest&lt;/i&gt; provides a much-needed exploration of the way the cultures and histories of this often-overlooked region shaped Kienholz’s work and career. Kienholz’s roots there and his return to them after the 1960s, as this exhibition reveals, made his work more ambiguous, complex, and prescient than has previously been understood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; *************&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The curator of this exhibition, Johanna Gosse, is currently a Field Editor at&amp;nbsp;caa.reviews. Gosse was in no way involved in the commissioning or editing of this review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Aptos, sans-serif; font-size: 16px; text-align: start;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/1051&quot;&gt;Ken D. Allan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Associate Professor of Art History, Seattle University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4265</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4265</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Afterlives: Contemporary Art in the Byzantine Crypt</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4424//Picture1.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4424&quot; data-title=&quot;Installation view, &lt;em&gt;Afterlives: Contemporary Art in the Byzantine Crypt&lt;/em&gt;. Photo by Emily Allen, 2024, courtesy of The Metropolitan Museum of Art, NY. &quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4424//Picture1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4424//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            Installation view, &lt;em&gt;Afterlives: Contemporary Art in the Byzantine Crypt&lt;/em&gt;. Photo by Emily Allen, 2024, courtesy of The Metropolitan Museum of Art, NY. 
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Beneath the grand staircase at the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York City, a dark and intimate gallery sits tucked away. It would be easy to walk quickly through this space as viewers weave their way through the encyclopedic institution, but it would also be a mistake. Through 2026, a thoughtful and moving transhistorical exhibition is enlivening this interstitial space by centering the subject of death. &lt;i&gt;Afterlives: Contemporary Art in the Byzantine Crypt &lt;/i&gt;brings together a selection of thirty collection objects addressing loss, mourning, memory, and the afterlife by contemporary artists alongside jewelry, textiles, vessels, and architectural fragments from Byzantine Egypt. Exposing its viewers to life in death, and offering a chance to sit with the precarity of human beings, &lt;i&gt;Afterlives&lt;/i&gt; was cocurated by Andrea Meyers Achi, the Mary and Michael Jaharis associate curator of Byzantine Art, and Akili Tommasino, associate curator in modern and contemporary art.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Cocurator Achi remarked that she has never seen so many visitors in the Mary and Michael Jaharis Gallery (302), which opened to the public in November 2000. Over the last twenty-four years, this gallery, referred to as “the Byzantine Crypt,” has featured a rotating selection of exhibitions of Byzantine Egyptian material. On walking into &lt;i&gt;Afterlives&lt;/i&gt; through one of the arched portals from either Gallery 301 or 300 (which both flank the Crypt)&lt;i&gt;, &lt;/i&gt;the dimly lit space requires some optical adjustment. A small plaque in the gallery explains that the lighting has been “deliberately dimmed in order to protect the centuries-old textiles on display; they are fragile and susceptible to damage from bright light.” Creating a darker, more soulful space, the lighting (while necessary for the fragility of the objects on display) is also a fitting challenge as viewers must take a moment to adjust their eyes as well as their mindsets to the different emotional and conceptual space they have entered.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Once your eyes have adjusted, it is not immediately clear which objects in the exhibit are contemporary or which are Byzantine. In 2021, when Achi and Tommasino began collaborating on this project, they intentionally selected artwork created after 1960, such as Ana Mendieta’s &lt;i&gt;Amategram series—The Vivification of the Flesh &lt;/i&gt;(1981), and Walid Raad’s &lt;i&gt;Preface to the third edition_Acknowledgement (Coupe II) &lt;/i&gt;(2014), choices that queer our assumptions of what ancient or contemporary objects should look like. Raad’s &lt;i&gt;Preface &lt;/i&gt;is a 3D-printed plaster sculpture that has been painted to mimic an ancient stone fragment to call out how Islamic artworks get transported to and from global museums amid wars in the Arab world. &lt;i&gt;Preface &lt;/i&gt;is displayed alongside a limestone &lt;i&gt;Corbel with Human Bust and Acanthus Leaves&lt;/i&gt; carved between 400 and 600 CE. Both &lt;i&gt;Preface &lt;/i&gt;and the &lt;i&gt;Corbel &lt;/i&gt;depict visages and look like they might have been sculpted in the same era. Raad uses a new technology, 3D printing, to craft an object that mimics an ancient material (limestone) and motif. In contrast, Mendieta’s &lt;i&gt;Vivification of the Flesh &lt;/i&gt;features a gouache and acrylic painted outline of a body on an ancestral material, amate&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;bark paper, made by the Indigenous Otomi craftspeople in Mexico. Amate paper dates to the Aztecs and as such, in painting on it, Mendieta activates a Mesoamerican cultural tradition to speak to issues of bodily sovereignty for women in the 20th century. &lt;i&gt;Vivification of the Flesh &lt;/i&gt;is hung in dialogue with an Egyptian wool tunic dated to 660–870 CE whose faded, light brown hue resembles the amate bark. Wrapped around the deceased in death, the tunic bears visible discoloration and maintains the outlined trace of the deceased’s corporeal form. Both &lt;i&gt;Vivification of the Flesh &lt;/i&gt;and the Egyptian tunic play subtly with the once present, now absent human body.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Pairings like these constitute the crux of this exhibition. They are not intended to test viewers to identify what was crafted between the 4th and 7th centuries versus what was made after 1960; instead, they are a curatorial offering for contemplation. By displaying cross-temporal objects in dialogue, Achi and Tommasino collapse time, conveying the formal and conceptual eternity of fragmentation, grief, and death, thus enabling viewers to recognize their proximity to, rather than distance from, the past.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Despite its emphasis on grief and death, &lt;i&gt;Afterlives &lt;/i&gt;does not feel melancholic, as the artworks on view evidence the capacity for creativity and multiplicity in the wake of loss. Achi explains that the wool &lt;i&gt;Decorated Tunic &lt;/i&gt;next to the Mendieta has had multiple lives: it was worn in life, in death, and then after its excavation collected and displayed at The Met. Considering the object’s life at the Met as an afterlife expands the ways in which the concept of life after death functions in this show. Kevin Beasley’s &lt;i&gt;I.W.M.S.B. &lt;/i&gt;(2014) is an audio artwork that also alludes to the possibility of multiple lives after death by amplifying the haunting and distorted voices of deceased Black rappers such as Tupac, Ol’ Dirty Bastard, and Notorious &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BIG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Beasley’s work calls out the disproportionately early deaths of these musicians, demonstrating an important point that the exhibition makes: while grief and death are universal experiences, not all lives are made equally vulnerable to death.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Another pairing, Melvin Edwards’s &lt;i&gt;Ready Now Now (Lynch Fragment) &lt;/i&gt;(1988) and a Byzantine architectural frieze, focuses our attention on identity-based destruction. The limestone fragment features Christ with his hand extended toward twelve baskets and is dated to the 6th–7th centuries CE. The Coptic fragment was likely intentionally chipped during the Islamic period to make its sacred power inoperable through an act of iconoclasm. While iconoclasm has a complex—and not always negative—history, the violence enacted on this fragment evokes the violence against contemporary Coptic Egyptians that continues to this day. Edwards began creating his steel assemblages in 1963 to confront the violent practice of lynching Black US citizens. &lt;i&gt;Ready Now Now &lt;/i&gt;features a protruding pickaxe and is displayed confrontationally across from the fragment of Christ. This positionality creates a connection between&amp;nbsp;destruction via iconoclasm and the destruction of Black life in the US, but it also recalls the strategic and powerful use of iconoclasm by the Black Lives Matter movement in the removal of Confederate monuments which represents the upholding of white supremacist violence in the US.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;While encyclopedic institutions frequently&amp;nbsp;call upon contemporary artists (often artists of color) to trouble their collection displays which maintain longstanding relations to colonial looting practices and the transatlantic slave trade, oftentimes these collaborations are temporary, and the institution does not actually invest in collecting the artist’s work. &lt;i&gt;Afterlives &lt;/i&gt;is an antidote to this practice, as most of the objects on view are from The Met’s permanent collection. The one exception is that three editions of &lt;i&gt;Everything #4 &lt;/i&gt;(2004) by Adrian Piper were acquired for the exhibition, and three editions were loaned. &lt;i&gt;Everything #4 &lt;/i&gt;is a succinct work of conceptual sculpture: a small, oval, mahogany framed mirror is inscribed in gold with the phrase: “EVERYTHING &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;WILL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; BE &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TAKEN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AWAY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.” As part of &lt;i&gt;Afterlives, &lt;/i&gt;this sculpture&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;is installed in five different galleries in The Met’s Fifth Avenue location (302, 512, 617, 726, and 917) and in Gallery 9 at The Met Cloisters in Fort Tryon Park. Within &lt;i&gt;Afterlives,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Everything #4 &lt;/i&gt;reflects viewers’ images back to themselves, implicating each person visually in the message of the exhibition: life is precarious. In the American, European Sculpture and Decorative Arts, and the European Painting wings, Piper produces an act of institutional critique, calling out the potential of collections themselves to be taken away. In Gallery 512, its message of extraction hangs beside a bust of Britain’s Queen Elizabeth I, who notoriously authorized the capture of Africans in what would become the transatlantic slave trade in 1564.&amp;nbsp;This imperialist exploitation expanded&amp;nbsp;Euro-American wealth beyond nobility and fueled art collection practices as we know them&amp;nbsp;today. The juxtaposition provides a sobering chance to reflect on the relationship between aesthetics, cultural property, and violent bodily capture. &lt;i&gt;Everything #4&lt;/i&gt; does not redeem the institution, but like &lt;i&gt;Afterlives &lt;/i&gt;as an exhibition, the series invites viewers to dwell in discomfort. Piper’s sculpture also inspires a gentle discomfort within The Met Cloisters. While it would have been exciting to see more than just one edition installed at the medieval satellite space, the work creates tension and resonance among the effigies of the Gothic Chapel. As one gazes into the mirror from different angles, stone tombs emerge in the mirror reflected next to one’s own face in what is a moving opportunity to recognize inevitable mortality.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;From its inception, &lt;i&gt;Afterlives &lt;/i&gt;mobilized cross-departmental, curatorial partnership and play.&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;For eight months prior to the exhibition’s opening, Achi and Tommasino&amp;nbsp;brought collection objects into Gallery 302 and experimented with the pairings in situ. When the thirty works on view rotate four different times during the exhibit’s run, viewers will see the results of this curatorial experimentation. While future rotations remain surprises, I am certain that Achi and Tommasino’s collaboration will engender a selection of works worth viewing. If encyclopedic museums like The Met are about separation, divisions, and categorization by design, this exhibition intervenes in that system of knowledge and display. As you exit the Byzantine Crypt, you likely pause once again to adjust your eyes to the institution’s typically brighter lighting strategies. In that moment of pause, you might apply the adjusted optic that &lt;i&gt;Afterlives: Contemporary Art in the Byzantine Crypt &lt;/i&gt;required to the remainder of your visit at The Met. In this way, the exhibit opens the potential for a more productively critical mode of seeing. While &lt;i&gt;Afterlives&lt;/i&gt; does not claim that all human lives are equally precarious, it does demonstrate that universal mortal precarity could be what binds us. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3459&quot;&gt;Emily Shoyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Doctoral Student, History of Art Department, Bryn Mawr College&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4250</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4250</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raúl de Nieves: and imagine you are here</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4412//Picture1.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4412&quot; data-title=&quot;&lt;em&gt;Raúl de Nieves: and imagine you are here &lt;/em&gt;, installation view, Baltimore Museum of Art, November 19, 2023–May 4, 2025 (photograph by the author)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4412//Picture1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4412//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            &lt;em&gt;Raúl de Nieves: and imagine you are here &lt;/em&gt;, installation view, Baltimore Museum of Art, November 19, 2023–May 4, 2025 (photograph by the author)
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In the second installment of the Robert E. Meyerhoff and Rheda Becker Biennial Commission at the Baltimore Museum of Art (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BMA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), artist Raúl de Nieves (b. 1983) bathes the lobby in colored light. The central feature of the public exhibition is a twenty-seven-paned window that spans the length of the building’s east facade. The Mexico-born, Brooklyn-based sculptor hand-crafted the panels from everyday materials like tape and sheets of acetate to recreate the look of stained glass. Monumental in size and dazzling in effect, the installation presents a series of vignettes, each depicting creatures that reappear frequently in de Nieves’s iconographically rich work. Frogs and butterflies line the edges of the window; brightly winged cicadas frame the falcon at its center. The “stained glass” overlooks three highly embellished effigies that don vibrant arrays of feathers, beads, and bells. The window installation serves as a fitting anchor for the exhibition, which evokes the rhythmic changes of the natural world—migration, hibernation, metamorphosis—as a mirror for cultural transformation. &lt;i&gt;Raúl de Nieves:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;and imagine you are here &lt;/i&gt;succeeds as an immersive installation precisely because it communicates its place in the Baltimore museum to be both a consequence and catalyst of institutional transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BMA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has weathered several changes of its own since the Meyerhoff-Becker Commission was first established in 2018. News of the biennial program came shortly after the institution incited a firestorm of controversy over its decision to deaccession several objects and commit the proceeds to acquire new works by underrepresented artists. The Meyerhoff-Becker Commission was part of this ongoing effort to diversify its collection. “How do you remake the faith in a public institution in such a way that far more diverse populations see the museum as a welcoming environment?” asked then director Christopher Bedford in an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artnews.com/art-news/news/baltimore-museum-art-launches-diversity-minded-commission-series-curatorial-fellowship-11427/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Artnews&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The inaugural commission by painter and patternist Mickalene Thomas answered Bedford’s call and converted the two-story lobby into a well-worn living room representative of the artist’s seventies-inspired style. When Bedford departed Baltimore in 2022, interim codirector and chief curator Asma Naeem stepped in as custodian of the museum’s future, which was to include a major renovation of the Patricia and Mark Joseph Education Center, the reinstallation of its Asian collection, and the acquisition of more than one hundred works. De Nieves’s exhibition further reflects &lt;a href=&quot;https://artbma.org/about/press/release/the-baltimore-museum-of-art-appoints-dr-asma-naeem-as-director&quot;&gt;Naeem’s vision&lt;/a&gt; for the museum as the site of urgent “dialogues about the history and evolution of art, about museums as community spaces, and about the relationship between internal culture to external experience.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Upon entering the east lobby, visitors encounter a playful reimagination of the museum, where de Nieves relaxes the Euro-American norms of proper gallery etiquette. The artist invites the audience to join his humanoid sculptures on the benches where they sit and touch their beaded forms. These are chimeric creatures. A frog-headed figure rests to the right of the lobby doors. Gold and silver baubles adorn her arms and legs, the rest of her a kaleidoscope of flashy pinks and greens. The colorful beadwork is characteristic of de Nieves’s practice, which incorporates the Mexican craft traditions of his childhood. It was in the colonial city of Morelia that de Nieves first learned needlecraft and embroidery. De Nieves attributes his careful craftsmanship to his mother’s example. “She never stopped working,” he said of his mother in a 2014 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bombmagazine.org/articles/2014/01/23/raul-de-nieves/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BOMB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Magazine&lt;/i&gt;, “she taught me to be the best at what I do with my mind and hands. She always expressed the craftsmanship of the human . . . That’s where the love of labor comes from in my work.” This deft handiwork is also evident in the hundreds of semitransparent resin-cast flies that dot the lobby walls, containing beads, dirt, and the delicate tangles of de Nieves’s own hair. De Nieves is especially adept at repurposing these commonplace and castoff materials. Under his artistry, detritus seems to sparkle. The glittering beads that encrust his sculptures appear almost crystalline. Only after placing a gentle hand on the structure does one recognize them as the cheap plastic stuff of schooldays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Just as de Nieves transforms these everyday materials into gaudy embellishments, &lt;i&gt;Raúl de Nieves &lt;/i&gt;transforms the austere space of the museum into a place where visitors of all ages and experience can see themselves. The sculpture seated opposite the welcome desk sports a look not unlike many one might encounter at The Crown, the no-frills venue nearby where DJ Trillnatured (Jessica Hyman) and emcee Kotic Couture host a&lt;a href=&quot;https://baltimorebeat.com/version-is-a-necessary-space/&quot;&gt; monthly dance party&lt;/a&gt; for queer and trans people of color. The creatural figure dons shoulder pads, a pair of open-toed pumps, and a manicure. In his work, de Nieves invokes the club culture and punk scene in which he came of age. After an early childhood in Michoacán, de Nieves moved with his mother and siblings to San Diego. There he identified a formal similarity between the ribboned costumes of Mexican folk dances and the leather fringe of California punk. When de Nieves moved to San Francisco at twenty years old, he found his place in the drag scene. The bedazzled heels he often wore to the dancefloor were among his first sculptures. Now based in Brooklyn, de Nieves continues to amass an eclectic collection of references: the tarot deck, Catholic icons, baroque ornamentation, ziggurats, and ballroom vernacular all recur throughout his work. One imagines then that de Nieves felt at home in Baltimore, a city long regarded for its rather queer character and thriving counterculture. If John Waters is Baltimore’s “Pope of Trash,” de Nieves has rightfully secured his place as archbishop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;But the titular “here” of de Nieves’s exhibition remains somewhat ambiguous. Much like he plays upon unexpected associations between forms, de Nieves likes to chart otherwise unfamiliar paths between places. His is a queer geography, an amalgam of diverse regional symbols and environmental markers. In his monumental stained glass, there are the Brood X cicadas, also known as the Great Eastern Brood, that last emerged from their seventeen-year slumber in 2021; the Crested Caracara, a formidable bird of prey endemic to Central and South America; and the brilliant orange Monarchs that pass through Maryland every fall as they migrate southward to Mexico. For de Nieves, the very experience of moving is itself a kind of placedness. To “imagine [one’s self] here” is to be present in the process of change, a perennial process without any one destination. A similar claim serves as the theoretical foundation on which trans studies stand. Today, “transition” names the process of moving across the social and juridico-medical boundaries that define gender. But, as many trans studies scholars have observed, that process is rarely if ever complete (see, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1215/23289252-2400145&quot;&gt;Julian Carter in &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1215/23289252-2400145&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Trans Studies Quarterly&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Because gender itself is contingent, the measures by which a person or the regulatory state in which they exist might determine a transition has occurred are subject to change: if the destination is always already unfixed, how does one ever arrive there? The works in &lt;i&gt;Raúl de Nieves&lt;/i&gt; thereby provide an ecological analog for this open-ended experience of queer becoming and a necessary reminder that—while much anti-trans rhetoric relies on staid references to “science”—transness and transition are in fact integral parts of our so-called natural world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The formal centerpiece of the exhibition, the stained-glass window suggests that if transition is natural, it is also sacred. Cast in its light, the rest of the exhibition takes on a cathedral quality. Three bejeweled creatures perch like gargoyles atop the adjacent terrace. Visitors move through the lobby like they would a nave, glancing upward at the four-tiered chandelier suspended over the east staircase. The fixture features an enrobed body at its center, floating overhead as if an angel might, haloed in the electric glow of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; candles. De Nieves does not shy away from these religious resonances but integrates them into his syncretic practice. His stairway installation is an adept intermediary between the second-floor galleries, which presently feature works from the museum’s robust European collection in one wing and a vibrant exhibition of more than one hundred works—wall hangings, sculptural costumes, beaded jewelry, and performance footage—from &lt;a href=&quot;https://artbma.org/exhibition/joyce-j-scott-walk-a-mile-in-my-dreams/images&quot;&gt;Baltimore visionary Joyce Scott&lt;/a&gt; in the other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Raúl de Nieves&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;i&gt;and imagine you are here&lt;/i&gt; owes its success to the dexterity with which the artist maneuvers between these many points of reference. The exhibition prompts audiences to reconsider the space of the museum—as a site for reverence, for performance, for play—and their place therein. Recognizing that the lobby is itself a transitional space, de Nieves harnesses its metamorphic energy. Visitors who return to the lobby as they exit the museum are likely to find the installation changed. The shifting sun reflects a new light through the stained glass; the many beaded sculptures shine in different colors, and their forms leave new shadows. De Nieves embraces these changing conditions as one hopes the Baltimore Museum might embrace its changing audience, and the art world, a changing &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BMA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3422&quot;&gt;Dylan Volk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
PhD Candidate, Department of History of Art, University of Michigan–Ann Arbor&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4208</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4208</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tai Shani: My Bodily Remains</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4393//nOlgpNzY.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4393&quot; data-title=&quot;Tai Shani, &lt;em&gt;Bodily Remains &lt;/em&gt; (2023), Installation view, &lt;em&gt; MBR: And above the beautiful commune. &lt;/em&gt; Photo: Wes Battoclette, 2023. Image courtesy of the Contemporary Arts Center, Cincinnati, OH.&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4393//nOlgpNzY.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4393//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            Tai Shani, &lt;em&gt;Bodily Remains &lt;/em&gt; (2023), Installation view, &lt;em&gt; MBR: And above the beautiful commune. &lt;/em&gt; Photo: Wes Battoclette, 2023. Image courtesy of the Contemporary Arts Center, Cincinnati, OH.
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Tai Shani is a conjurer of worlds. Out of the murk and miasma of millennia of forgotten histories and suppressed mythologies, she sets a stage for rituals and revelations, for psychedelic hallucinations and deeply embodied experiences of other potential realities. The 2019 Turner Prize winner’s first show in the United States, &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MBR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;And above the beautiful commune,&lt;/i&gt; curated by Amara Antilla, transforms an entire floor of Zaha Hadid’s iconic building for Cincinnati’s Contemporary Art Center (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CAC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) into a cryptic occult space that evokes contradictory senses of scale and emotion. It is as enveloping as a womb and as expansive as a spiraling galaxy, suffused with simmering indignant anger and smoldering sensual passion. Across the suite of tightly interconnecting works, which span sculpture, installation, film, video, assemblage, and watercolor, Shani produces trembling tensions between apparent opposites—the intimate and the epic, the enraged and the eroticized, the downtrodden and the insurgent. The overwhelming call of the exhibition, and its primary seduction, is for the viewer to imagine things otherwise, to create the conditions through which a more just and more equitable world seems possible. The only way to do so, Shani suggests, is by collectively dreaming our way out of the hegemonies, cosmologies, and conventional epistemologies that structure this world and constrain conceivable futures. Against the authoritarian racism and fascism that permeate the present, Shani draws on suppressed pasts and radical historical practices that might have new potential to light a path toward a queer, antiracist, and anticapitalist communal future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Anchoring the exhibition is an enormous scarlet-red stepped platform, &lt;i&gt;Bodily Remains&lt;/i&gt; (2023), decorated in raised paths that take the patterns of what could equally be circuit boards or labyrinthine ceremonial paths. Dotted throughout the sculpture are huge orbs, simultaneously appearing as gargantuan pearls and tiny planets. A glass vitrine holding the jewel-like remains of what Shani identifies as &lt;i&gt;Baby Osiris, Baby Metatron, Baby Persephone&lt;/i&gt; (2022) marks the scene as a sacred space of mysteries and relics. Each religious figure named in the sculpture evokes various themes of resurrection, transition, and fertility. Their remains are jumbled, with cultures and times incongruously imbricated: fossilized bones protect glistening organs; hands, still fleshy but speckled by spores of mold, clutch gilded ears of grain. Two human-scale, bejeweled canopic jars preside over the arrangement. One fits as a caryatid into an impossibly hovering column in Shani’s virtualized architecture, which rises to Hadid’s cavernous ceiling. &amp;nbsp;Unlike their diminutive and stoic-faced Egyptian models, which contained the preserved organs that mummified pharaohs would need upon their resurrection, Shani’s jars grimace and wail in sorrow and anger. They bear their pearl teeth like harpies or exhausted maenads. What is inside, and at what scale, Shani leaves to the imagination. One expects that, at any moment, priestesses of this cosmic temple might return to perform the rites that could set this obscure machine in motion. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;A series of nine delicate, rosy-toned watercolors, reproduced for the exhibition as prints, lead to ancillary, low-ceilinged rooms that screen two of Shani’s moving image works. The watercolors, collectively titled &lt;i&gt;The Passion&lt;/i&gt; (2023), depict hazy architectural scenes, inspired by Theodore Dryer’s 1928 film, &lt;i&gt;The Passion of Joan of Arc,&lt;/i&gt; about the gender-nonconforming saint accused of heresy and demonic possession. The invented architectures, which merge Art Deco and medieval elements, appear through tromp l’oeil frames of veined, green marble. Each is punctuated by three dark circles, the color of dried blood. They read as wounds in the image, but their bleeding edges cite the enveloping visceral light that spills from &lt;i&gt;My Bodily Remains&lt;/i&gt;. The wounds, then, might also be portals summoned open only by acts both sacred and profane. A related work, &lt;i&gt;Our Astrolatraus Commune IV &lt;/i&gt;(2023), explodes the watercolor prints into three dimensions, taking the shape of an alcove altarpiece with hinged doors that materializes the process of opening portals, both spiritual and spatial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Shani’s 2021 film, &lt;i&gt;The Neon Hieroglyph&lt;/i&gt;, is a trippy and unnerving meditation on the effects of ingesting ergot, a psychoactive fungus that taints rye crops and provides the lysergic acid in &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LSD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Shani’s film woozily surfaces medieval histories that recount whole villages succumbing to mass hallucination from ergot-blighted crops. From this hardship are born myths of witches who, in their fugue states, sack neighboring towns and merchant ships like Robin Hoods to deliver their families from poisoning or privation. Ethereal Irish actress Molly Moody narrates Shani’s poetic rumination on the dissolving boundaries between the real and surreal. Moody’s body slides from naked solidity into digital simulation in eerie moments of misaligned superimposition, simultaneously evoking vulnerable intimacy and uncanny horror.&amp;nbsp; Structured as a series of vignettes, each introduced by a scene of smoke-filled darkness and the vibrating sounds of a cello, the film traces the shifting contours of the “neon hieroglyph,” a common visual phenomenon of the psychedelic experience. Shani’s narrator aligns it with both the birth of cinema, which preserves and shares fleeting images from the world as seen by an individual eye and “the prisoner’s cinema,” the brain’s automatic, hallucinatory production of phosphene imagery when faced with sensory deprivation. As in &lt;i&gt;My Bodily Remains&lt;/i&gt;, everywhere in &lt;i&gt;The Neon Hieroglyph&lt;/i&gt; is the suggestion that shifts in consciousness may be necessary for meaningful social transformation. We might need new or reconfigured myths to dream ourselves into better futures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Throughout &lt;i&gt;The Neon Hieroglyph&lt;/i&gt;, Shani alludes to themes that appear elsewhere in the exhibition—to baby Osiris and Persephone, and the rhyming of cosmic and microscopic scales, for example, as well as citing the entire, lengthy title of the other moving image work in the show, &lt;i&gt;My Bodily Remains, Your Bodily Remains, and all the Bodily Remains that Ever Were and Ever Will Be&lt;/i&gt; (2023). Moody returns in this video as one in a small cast of female archetypes who preach revolution and passionate love. Playing the “Ghost of the Revolution” and again toggling between fleshy and digital versions, the ghost is matched by the “Reader of the Book of Love” (Maya Lubinsky), who passionately reads quotations from leftist revolutionaries like Lucy Parsons, Ulrike Meinhof, Sean Bonny, Bernardine Dohrn, and Raoul Vaneigem. Shani’s camera tails the ghost’s Mercedes Benz through the dark, wet streets of London. She’s in the back seat, looking through the rear window. No matter how far away her car pulls, her whispering voice is impossibly close in the viewer’s ear.&amp;nbsp; Speaking in the erotic poetics that typifies Shani’s writing, she analogizes human bodies to geological and celestial ones—eyes like solar eclipses, the boundaries of hot bodies liquifying like magma. Her words are an incantation, a witchy recipe for crossing borders and changing form. As she speaks, Moody’s eyes loll and roll in her head, her mouth contorts and goes slack, seamlessly slipping from seizure to ecstasy, from grand mal to petite mort. It is never certain if we are witnessing a moment of catastrophic collapse or rapturous rebirth. Perhaps there’s no way to tell the difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;These two characters lead the viewer on a journey across space and time, from satellite imagery of Mars’s unfathomably deep canyon, Valles Marineris, to platelets crowding through the choked channels of veins. Recurring images of the solar system show the sun dark, casting all the planets as merely blank absences of stars, only to light up again in a fiery whorl, rebooting and sending everything back into spinning, lively motion. Another pair of figures, both named “Them Who Love,” speak to each other across time and space. Their direct addresses and second-person pronouns catch the viewer in the snare of their exchange. One (Jo Kukathas) wanders in a many-chambered subterranean cave, which echoes the CAC’s structure with its tall caverns and small side galleries. She wears a chiton and appears like Pythia coming out of a trance, an oracle seeing past and present. She speaks across the viewer to her counterpart (Candice Nembhard), who stands in a placeless pink and white mist, as if suspended in the first light of sunrise. Dressed in a studded and frilled white leather harness and garters, she stands, arms akimbo, like a superhero professing passionate and tender love across the cosmos. The cave-dweller pleads for a friend “at the end of the world,” but clarifies her request: “if you can’t imagine pleasures that do not brutalize others, then we can’t be friends. If you hate the riots, we can never be friends.” The other “Them Who Love” answers this call at the end of the video with a “secular prayer” that functions as Shani’s first principles for entering the new world she diagrams across &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MBR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;And above the beautiful commune&lt;/i&gt;: “This is my secular prayer: all cops are bastards. This is my prayer: Free Palestine. This is my prayer: Fuck the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TERFS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Property is theft is my prayer. My prayer is a spectacle of remembering that they have made a world that is hell. But this is paradise. My prayer is not to forget that this is paradise, and it is ours.” Exhibitions and artworks often produce utopian visions to swaddle and placate viewers who need shelter and respite from the horrors of the outside world. But this final prayer, which works at every alter and ritual location in Shani’s immersive, seductive installation, also works when one leaves the gallery. It clearly tasks the viewer to not just dream how the world could be otherwise but asks for a commitment to its active remaking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/2524&quot;&gt;Kris Paulsen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Associate Professor, Department of History of Art, The Ohio State University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4245</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4245</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Sky’s the Limit</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4386//The%20Sky&#39;s%20the%20Limit.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4386&quot; data-title=&quot;&lt;em&gt;The Sky’s the Limit&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, National Museum of Women in the Arts, 2023–24 (photograph by Jennifer Hughes, courtesy of National Museum of Women in the Arts)&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4386//The%20Sky&#39;s%20the%20Limit.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4386//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            &lt;em&gt;The Sky’s the Limit&lt;/em&gt;, installation view, National Museum of Women in the Arts, 2023–24 (photograph by Jennifer Hughes, courtesy of National Museum of Women in the Arts)
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;When the National Museum of Women in the Arts (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NMWA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) reopened in October 2023 following a two-year renovation, visitors encountered not only a reimagined space—and roughly fifteen percent more of it—but also fresh takes on the institution’s collection and mission of promoting art by women. The most sweeping manifestation of the latter is &lt;i&gt;Remix&lt;/i&gt;, a reinstallation of works in the NMWA’s permanent collection that stretches across six centuries (and much of the building), eschewing chronology in favor of thematic groupings like “Seeing Red” or “Elemental.”&amp;nbsp; While the historical specificity of particular works is lost in these clusters, the installation does reveal thought-provoking connections among women artists and their conditions across time. A related thread runs through the more tightly focused &lt;i&gt;The Sky’s the Limit, &lt;/i&gt;staged in the museum’s special exhibition galleries. This show features&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;thirty-two sculptures made by twelve artists between 1997 and 2023, including never-before displayed collection works, recent acquisitions, and loans. Practically, and seemingly primarily, the exhibition highlights the potential of the museum’s redesigned galleries, especially their ability to support large-scale work and suspended sculptures; as the introductory panel announces, &lt;i&gt;The Sky’s the Limit&lt;/i&gt; renews NMWA’s mission of “collecting and exhibiting transformational sculpture.” Beyond this, the selected artists are described as inviting viewers to “move into, around, and sometimes under artworks” to arrive at “a new perspective on a range of themes” and as signaling the “impact and influence of women and nonbinary artists throughout history and into a bright future.” Although this conceptual framework at first appears as broad as the sky in the exhibition’s title, that capaciousness turns out to be pointed, offering room for the works and their installation to reveal something of the multiplicity of lived experiences at play in the twenty-first century. Perhaps paradoxically, what the show’s expansive bent ultimately brings into view is the fundamental knottiness of the contemporary moment, the coincident complications and promises inherent to its navigation.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;On entering the exhibition, an outsized title against a pale blue background greets us, a gesture towards the ceiling-hung nature of much of the work and the show’s aspirational ambitions. A broad opening gallery features a maze of bronze bells made by Davina Semo between 2019 and 2022 and hung by chains from the ceiling. Diversity is central to these variously shaped and scaled bells, with distinctions between them—smooth or textured, solid or perforated, matte or reflective—echoed internally by each form—installed neither high nor low, casting shadows that at once dematerialize and enrich, teasing sound and pointing up its absence. Irregularly spaced and suspended such that their humanoid forms rest around eye level, Semo’s bells come to appear so many singularities, markers of the array of notes individuals within a collective might sound, and prompt viewers to consider their own situations relationally. The complexities spread across and within Semo’s work manifest anew within Rina Banerjee’s maximalist quasi-figural sculptures from 2012 and 2014, which bracket the gallery. Built from intentionally disparate found objects ranging from pewter soldiers to glass chandeliers to acrylic horns, these riotous constructions embody the mess of contradictions that is contemporary, commodified global living. As a label has Banerjee remarking, her art “depicts a delicate world that is also aggressive, tangled, manipulated, fragile, and very, very dense.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Delicacy and density alike characterize the remainder of the exhibition’s layout. From the opening gallery, the viewer is directed down one of two aisles, each featuring niches with work or works by a different artist off either side. This arrangement sets the scene for a focused engagement with individual pieces and encourages ongoing toggling between installations. A related back-and-forth informs Sonya Clark’s impactful &lt;i&gt;Curls &lt;/i&gt;(2005). Comprised of black combs joined together and suspended as strands from the ceiling, each segment resists the straightening that is its material’s ostensible goal as it insistently twists towards the floor. That curling, an assertion of Black visibility, is amplified by the totality of strands and their lighting, which creates coils of shadows against the walls. As a circumambulating viewer enters into those shadowed curls, their cultural meanings and histories are rendered newly proximate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;As Clark’s work drifts towards the ground, across from it, the blue-black female figure of Alison Saar’s &lt;i&gt;Undone &lt;/i&gt;(2012) levitates, seated atop a floating chair with a gauzy dress pooling on the floor below and a red root stretching downward from between her legs. Perhaps inadvertently, the work’s installation underscores ambiguities Saar has put in place. The figure’s positioning might signal ascent or an overcoming of historical weight—a label notes the deep blue skin tone is owed to Saar’s interest in indigo dye, brought to the Americas from Africa—with the root reading as generative, conjuring menstrual cycles or an umbilical cord, and the bottles attached to it read as vessels for all the body contains. However, with the figure nearly touching the ceiling, limitations rather than boundlessness are conjured: a bumping against a barrier unprepared to break, with the red protrusion and its bottles quickly transforming into so many anchors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Catty-cornered, Cornelia Parker’s &lt;i&gt;Thirty Pieces of Silver (exhaled) Sugar Bowl &lt;/i&gt;(2003) moves propulsively downward. Composed of silver-plated items (cutlery, serving dishes) crushed by a two-hundred-fifty-ton industrial press and then strung from the ceiling such that they hover just above the floor, the sculpture casts doubt on long-standing Western cultural values. As what was once held in high esteem comes crashing down, the work’s glistening delicacy testifies to the beauty of reimagined concepts of worth. Challenging historical standards and stereotypes around class and race, the juxtaposition of Parker’s revalued silver and Clark’s charged&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;combs exemplifies the show’s range of concerns. Fittingly, across from Parker’s work, Johanna Unzueta’s oversized wood and felt hinges from the 2010s are cannily positioned in corners. There, they playfully amplify the potential for further opening, their material softening and emblematizing a curious, outward orientation to the world—modeling our movement across the exhibition’s varied terrain. At the end of this aisle, spread across but not quite holding a more open area, is Mariah Robertson’s &lt;i&gt;9 &lt;/i&gt;(2012), created with photographic materials exclusive of a camera. Her singular actions are cued by the variety of marks across more than one hundred feet of metallic paper, which animatedly folds over and into itself as if running through a projector.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;One of the exhibition’s most striking moments is a pairing of works by Petah Coyne: &lt;i&gt;Untitled #1273 (The Age of Innocence)&lt;/i&gt; (2008) and &lt;i&gt;Untitled #1458 (Marguerite Duras)&lt;/i&gt; (2019–20). Positioned in a darkly painted, spacious gallery, the former is predominantly white and the latter black, with both, again, hung from the ceiling.&amp;nbsp; In &lt;i&gt;Untitled #1273&lt;/i&gt;, delicate silk flowers entombed by wax are woven into a rectangular support, split down the middle to emphasize the dualities materialized within—life and death, organic and manufactured, open and impenetrable. Set against its haunting romance is the menacing snare of wire-wrapped black glass balls that make up &lt;i&gt;Untitled #1458&lt;/i&gt;. Bomb-like or, given its &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;COVID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;-era context, viral, this work gives form to how the pandemic left us at once isolated and uneasily entangled with one another. Despite differences in tenor, the works feel undeniably of a piece, in keeping with the show’s both/and instead of either/or thematics. This passage also opens onto the most compelling sight line of the show, with the volatile downward arc of the black Coyne offset by the upward lilt of Ursula von Rydingsvard’s large, abstract cedar sculpture. Installed in an airier, light-filled room that points up the relative tightness we find elsewhere, von Rydingsvard’s intricately faceted works suggest ongoing expansion, even respiration. The viewer has space to breathe with them, perhaps taking stock of their idiosyncratic rhythms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Sharing this organicism are Yuriko Yamaguchi’s sculptures, dating from the last few years. The exhibition’s niches serve the works well, bringing viewers into concentrated contact with their wending masses of wire and resin. The sculptures’ apparent upward drift seems facilitated by their constitutive tensions—manufactured/organic, opaque/transparent, tactile/ethereal—and opens onto an idealistic vision of difference’s power. The adjacent sculpture of Beatriz Milhazes answers the quiet of Yamaguchi with a cacophony of colored spheres, circles, and polyester flowers strung from multiple shaped forms. The installation’s dynamic asymmetries and globe-like components conspire to spin the viewer around, a choreography registering the joy that can accompany fullness. Those orbs find a pared-down counterpart across from them in Shinique Smith’s &lt;i&gt;Daisies up your butterfly &lt;/i&gt;(2013). A ceiling-hung compact sphere of textiles, Smith bundles the histories of each item together to form a whole. While Smith’s slight work might be less forceful on its own, here it constitutes the purest expression of the knots so critical throughout the exhibition, from the works themselves to how they are hung.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;One question that might (and has) been posed of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NMWA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is whether a museum devoted exclusively to women artists remains necessary when many cultural institutions are actively pursuing a diversification of their collections. The quiet richness of &lt;i&gt;The Sky’s the Limit &lt;/i&gt;suggests the answer is yes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3389&quot;&gt;Katherine Markoski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Adjunct Professor in Art History, Corcoran School of the Arts &amp;amp; Design, George Washington University, American Women’s History Initiative Writer and Editor, Smithsonian American Art Museum&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4177</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4177</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>María Magdalena Campos-Pons: Behold</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4371//Mari%CC%81a%20Magdalena.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image_caption&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a data-lightbox=&quot;image-4371&quot; data-title=&quot;María Magdalena Campos-Pons (Born Matanzas, Cuba, 1959), &lt;em&gt;Finding Balance&lt;/em&gt;, 2018. Image courtesy of the Brooklyn Museum of Art&quot; href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4371//Mari%CC%81a%20Magdalena.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Large&quot; src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//review/4371//large.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
            María Magdalena Campos-Pons (Born Matanzas, Cuba, 1959), &lt;em&gt;Finding Balance&lt;/em&gt;, 2018. Image courtesy of the Brooklyn Museum of Art
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;For four decades, María Magdalena Campos-Pons has created works that deftly interweave the particular and the expansive, utilizing her body, memory, and familial history as conduits to attend to transatlantic histories of diaspora and racial violence. Campos-Pons was born in 1959 in the Afro-Cuban province of Matanzas, Cuba as the descendant of enslaved African individuals and indentured Chinese laborers brought forcefully to the island. Since 1991, she has resided primarily in the United States, initially unable to return to Cuba for over a decade due to the US embargo. Her practice has centered on the journeys––both forced and forbidden—that are at once particular to her individual experience and entwined within multigenerational histories of imperial violence, forced dislocation, and survival. Movement through, behind, and beyond boundaries is a persistent motif in the artist’s work, where images extend beyond their frames and threads tether disparate surfaces.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;María Magdalena Campos-Pons: Behold&lt;/i&gt; at the Brooklyn Museum is the artist’s first multimedia survey since 2007 and first-ever survey in New York. Co-organized with the J. Paul Getty Museum, it travels through spring 2025. The exhibition’s fall 2023 opening in Brooklyn was followed quickly by news of Campos-Pons’s MacArthur Genius grant. Bringing together works from 1990 to the present, &lt;i&gt;Behold &lt;/i&gt;demonstrates the breadth of the artist’s practice from large format polaroids and multimedia installations—for which she is best known—to glass mobiles and layered ephemeral collages of more recent decades. An attempt to sufficiently encapsulate the range of material reflected is futile given Campos-Pons’s ever-present experimentation with and refusal of traditional media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Though presented in the distinct space of the Elizabeth A. Sackler Center for Feminist Art, &lt;i&gt;Behold &lt;/i&gt;begins outside of the center’s self-contained galleries, which are triangularly bound to the permanent installation of Judy Chicago’s &lt;i&gt;Dinner Party&lt;/i&gt;. It is fitting that a retrospective of Campos-Pons’s work, which plays with the transcendence of boundaries, begins in overflow, defying the delineated footprint of feminist art. Spilling into the museum’s atrium, faint sounds of a woman singing and the soft glow of light draw the viewer to the fourth-floor overlook, where Campos-Pons’s mesmerizing 1998 installation &lt;i&gt;Spoken Softly with Mama &lt;/i&gt;has transformed the institutional environment. The milestone work was created in collaboration with composer and sound artist Neil Leonard for the Museum of Modern Art in 1998. Seven large ironing boards stand upright, like arched passageways, illuminated by the photographs and videos projected on their silk surfaces. An excavation of personal and collective history, the photographs projected in the work were culled from family archives and depict women of Campos-Pons’s family, including her mother, who had worked in the home of a wealthy family as a domestic laborer while dreaming of being an educator. Like architectural pillars, the ironing boards dedicate a space for the untold stories of generations of Black women constrained to lives of domestic labor. On the floor, radial arrangements of irons and trivets cast in glass are luminescent with the projector glow, appearing to float like ships across the dark surface. Honoring women’s work as worthy history, &lt;i&gt;Spoken Softly &lt;/i&gt;is the second work in a tripartite series, “History of a People Who Were Not Heroes”&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(1994). The series represents a process Campos-Pons refers to as working from a dismantled archive, in which she addresses the absent histories and dearth of records that followed the violent caesura of diasporic dislocation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Inside the center, &lt;i&gt;Behold&lt;/i&gt; extends across six galleries that highlight conceptual throughlines in Campos-Pons’s work, such as witnessing, labor, and movement. Section titles provide background information allowing ideas to come cogently into focus, but stop short of acting as thematic containers. The first gallery, “The Calling,” identifies Campos-Pons’s conception of her work as spiritually guided, highlighting the undercurrent of ritual encoded in her works, most prominently as references to Santería, the African diasporic syncretic religion rooted in Yoruba traditions of which her grandmother was a priestess. A captivating early video piece, &lt;i&gt;Baño Sagrado (Rite of Initiation, Sacred Bath) &lt;/i&gt;(1991), is a standout—a nonlinear portrayal of cleansing rituals that employ sound and early video editing techniques to dissolve the boundary between body and water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Drawing upon Christina Sharpe’s 2016 book &lt;i&gt;In the Wake: On Blackness and Being&lt;/i&gt;, the section&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;“Extreme Weather” speaks to the enduring, pervasive persistence of racial and imperial violence as an environmental condition to which Campos-Pons responds. A layered installation of works on paper, with blue water-based pigments that fluctuate in density and hue, heightens the structural and conceptual heft of the nearby installation &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TRA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(1991)&lt;i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TRA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;debuted at the 1992 Havana Biennial, a challenge and juxtaposition to concurrent 1992 “celebrations” of the quincentenary of Christopher Columbus’s voyage to the Caribbean, as noted in the label. Addressing modes of commemoration and history-making by adopting the shapes and materials of memorials, Campos-Pons’s installation centers around the distinct, yet inseparable forced voyages of enslaved African people through the Middle Passage. A textual shorthand for &lt;i&gt;travesía &lt;/i&gt;(crossing), &lt;i&gt;trata &lt;/i&gt;(trade), and &lt;i&gt;tragedia &lt;/i&gt;(tragedy), &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TRA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;collocates grids of photographs of three generations of Afro-Cubans in Matanzas with planks of wood cut into ships, on the surface of which Campos-Pons carved schematic diagrams of nameless bodies abstracted into human cargo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The artist’s dedication to witnessing that which has preceded and unfolded before her is foregrounded in “Voyeurs and Beholders,” a grouping of works that take up the manifestations and implications of vision. A glass mobile from the 2021 series “The Rise of the Butterflies” suspends the eyespots of butterfly wings, an evolutionary tool of mimicry thought to ward off predators, taken up by Campos-Pons to symbolize practices of community protection and collective witnessing within the Black Lives Matter movement. In a triptych from “When I am Not Here/Estoy Alla”&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(1996), photographs of the artist with the texts “Patria una trampa” and “Identity could be a tragedy” written across her chest convey the visual construction of identity as a technology of confinement: the ethnographic violence of pinning down discrete identities and the restriction of movement based on categorical frames of race and nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Such confinement is made material in &lt;i&gt;Invocazione alla Questura–Rita of Nigeria&lt;/i&gt;, a 2006 collage in the subsequent gallery, “Picturing Labor,” which abstracts the image of Rita, a Nigerian woman Campos-Pons met in Italy. Rita’s precarious existence as a Nigerian laborer precipitated their encounter at a police station. In Campos-Pons’s representation, Rita’s identity is abstracted and shrouded in symbolism. It is concealed by gold chains suspended from her baseball cap, but also celebrated in the gold leaf bird atop the hat, a reference to traditional Yoruba garments. Rita’s image is rendered atop a grid of translucent Italian tissue paper, fused with swaths of gold leaf.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Campos-Pons’s transgression of the grid, a belabored motif in art history, is readily apparent in “Roots and Routes,” a selection of works demonstrating the artist’s historical examination and personal experience of itinerancy and the recurrent negotiation of distance in her work. Cross-continental and transgenerational linkages are manifest in two striking works that face each other. Visualizing matrilineal tethering, the series “Umbilical Cord”&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;(1991), was created through transnational collaboration when the artist was unable to return to Cuba. Photographs of the artist’s mother and sisters were taken and sent by photographer Ramón Pacheco to Campos-Pons, who combined them sequentially with her own photograph, binding their bodies together with a three-dimensional wire umbilical cord that extends from the wall. Situated diagonally across the gallery is &lt;i&gt;Finding Balance &lt;/i&gt;(2015) a twenty-eight-photograph installation, the artist’s largest to date. With her face painted in &lt;i&gt;cascarilla, &lt;/i&gt;a white powder used in Santería created from eggshells, and her body donning an imperial dragon robe, Campos-Pons holds in simultaneous complexity her Nigerian and Cantonese ancestry. The monumental self-portrait is more complex and frenzied than the earlier polaroid works, an accumulation of ideas and imagery the artist has developed over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;A distinct appendage gallery, “Process &amp;amp; Performance” contains performance footage, a striking costume designed by Zinda Lee Williams, and notebooks of planning sketches as well as photographs of additional performances (some which activated works elsewhere in the show). Though the gallery provides exciting insight into the artist’s practice, the limitation of the latter materials to vitrines in a process-oriented gallery unnecessarily reaffirmed a hierarchy of art versus nonart objects that could’ve been abandoned with a more dynamic integration consistent with the rest of the exhibition.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;Body&quot; style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;A substantial and rich retrospective, &lt;i&gt;Behold&lt;/i&gt; resists articulating a linear progression of artistic development and integrates distinct series and decades of the artist’s practice, eschewing categorical imposition. It’s an appropriate condition for the fluid resonances that appear across the artist’s body of work and the multiple temporalities to which they attend. Across the locations, identities, and histories that converge in her work, Campos Pons reflects “I am grounded in my mobility, my understanding of transitions, and my flexibility to adapt to experiences that are not completely new, but that I need to explore by choice or necessity” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://brooklynrail.org/2023/10/art/Mara-Magdalena-Campos-Pons-with-Joyce-Beckenstein&quot;&gt;“María Magdalena Campos-Pons with Joyce Beckenstein,”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;The&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Brooklyn Rail&lt;/i&gt;, October 2023).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3432&quot;&gt;Elise Armani&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
PhD Candidate, Art History &amp;amp; Criticism, Stony Brook University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4220</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4220</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>