<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0"><channel><title>Extreme-heat - Gist Articles</title><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/grist/topic/extreme-heat" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Extreme-heat Articles on grist.org - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:05:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Utilities are shutting off power to a growing number of households</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Electric utilities across the United States are shutting off power to a growing number of households, according to a recent report that also found most shutoffs happened during last year’s record-hot summer, a reminder that &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/how-climate-change-drives-hotter-more-frequent-heat-waves/&quot;&gt;climate change&lt;/a&gt; fuels more intense, frequent, and prolonged heat waves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Shutoffs can be deadly, especially during extreme freezes and blistering heat. And while health issues are the most worrisome risk, there are other threats to daily life such as losing access to phone, internet, medical equipment, and food storage. Basic physical comfort can prove impossible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biologicaldiversity.org/programs/energy-justice/pdfs/Powerless_Report_2025.pdf?_gl=1*hpe2sd*_gcl_aw*R0NMLjE3MzY4NzA5NDguQ2owS0NRaUFzNWk4QmhEbUFSSXNBR0U0eEh3cml0RnBhekQ5M1o3V2hWTHVtQkpUdjFXZEZrUzdGRU1fS01VMEF1SDhOM1FqTkpEZXdNTWFBbm1JRUFMd193Y0I.*_gcl_au*MTc4MTAyMzI3NC4xNzM2ODcwOTQ4&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by the nonprofit Center for Biological Diversity revealed that six investor-owned utilities disconnected customers between January and September 2024 more than 662,000 times, an over 20 percent jump from the same period in 2023. Those companies included Georgia Power, DTE Energy, Duke Energy, Ameren Corporation, Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric, and Arizona Public Service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But all shutoffs, and the harms they cause, are avoidable, said Selah Goodson Bell, lead author of the report. States and local governments have the power to protect customers by enacting policies like comprehensive shutoff bans during extreme heat and reining in utility rate hikes. While most states already ban shutoffs during cold weather, more and more are starting to ban it during heat waves. “It’s going to be up to cities, municipalities, and states to remedy ongoing energy injustices and hold these utility companies accountable,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It’s hard to know the true extent and nature of shutoffs because only &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;a patchwork of data&lt;/a&gt; exists nationwide. Twenty-two states don’t require utilities to report disconnections at all, and among the ones that do, only 20 states and Washington, D.C., have up-to-date data. Report authors analyzed the six power companies because they provide current disconnection data and collectively serve more than 200 million customers, spanning most regions of the U.S. from California to the Carolinas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Georgia, the state’s largest electric utility Georgia Power disconnected customers for nonpayment over 180,000 times from January to September 2024 — a more than 20 percent increase from the same period in 2023. Duke Energy in North and South Carolina also increased shutoffs by nearly 20 percent last year. DTE Energy in Michigan disconnected customers more than 150,000 times, and Ameren in Illinois and Missouri shut off power more than 120,000 times, with both raising shutoff rates in the past few years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric in California and Phoenix-based Arizona Public Service cut off power to fewer customers than the other utilities, the report still found a steady growth in shutoffs since 2022.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lingering inflation, rate hikes, and climate change have all contributed to the rise in shutoffs, the report found. But the core issue is an “antiquated and broken” utility business model that effectively punishes low-income customers by aggressively raising rates, and then cutting off power when households can’t pay, said Goodson Bell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As shutoffs increased, the six utilities analyzed in the report also netted $10 billion in profits between January and September 2024, a more than 20 percent increase from the same period in 2023. Less than 2 percent of their shareholder dividends would have prevented all shutoffs last year, the report found. “Customers are losing access to an essential service they need to survive while shareholders line their pockets with lavish returns,” Goodson Bell said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Besides using more electricity to cope with extreme temperatures, customers are also paying for the mounting costs of repairing and hardening the grid after disasters like wildfires or hurricanes. Yet the report documents efforts by utilities that would worsen climate-driven costs: Almost all the utilities mentioned in the report have worked to expand gas infrastructure and fossil fuel energy supply, and lobbied to weaken rooftop solar and other climate policies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;digital collage of a Black hand turning off a light switch, an electric meter, and the logo for Xcel Energy&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;A lack of data hampers efforts to fix racial disparities in utility cutoffs&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/akielly-hu/&quot;&gt;Akielly Hu&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Representatives from Ameren, Arizona Public Service, DTE Energy, and PG&amp;amp;E told Grist that disconnection is a last resort, and that the utilities offer a range of energy assistance and flexible payment plans. “We recognize that higher costs, including energy bills, can be a challenge for customers,” said PG&amp;amp;E spokesperson Mike Gazda. Duke Energy and Georgia Power did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For most of the utilities in the report, shutoffs peaked in the summer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While 42 states already ban shutoffs during cold weather, 23 have now passed heat-based shutoff bans, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.leg.wa.gov/billsummary?BillNumber=1329&amp;amp;Year=2023&amp;amp;Initiative=false&quot;&gt;Washington state in 2023&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lis.virginia.gov/cgi-bin/legp604.exe?241+sum+HB906&quot;&gt;Virginia in 2024&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilga.gov/legislation/publicacts/fulltext.asp?Name=103-0019&quot;&gt;Illinois strengthened an existing ban&lt;/a&gt; by lowering the previous threshold of 95 degrees Fahrenheit to 90. That change appears to have already had a measurable impact: According to the Center for Biological Diversity’s report, summertime shutoffs in Illinois were 13 percent lower in 2024 than in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But in Michigan and California, which both have temperature-based shutoff bans for extreme heat, disconnections by DTE Energy and PG&amp;amp;E still peaked during the summer. Temperature-based shutoff bans in those states fail to adequately protect customers because they don’t require utilities to automatically restore power to households that get disconnected prior to a heat event, said Goodson Bell. That means that even if a household gets their power shut off right before a ban takes effect, if they can’t pay in time, “They will be forced to endure harsh conditions without access to electricity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Arizona Public Service, on the other hand, has avoided a summertime spike in shutoffs by using a date-based shutoff moratorium from June 1 to October 15. The policy was &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/arizona-heat-death-legacy-3fce53af423293d9fb15d7889dee9e13&quot;&gt;introduced by state regulators&lt;/a&gt; after Arizona Public Service cut off power to a 72-year-old woman who owed $51 on her electricity bill, resulting in her death in 2018. But even date-based protections may not be enough because extreme heat is increasingly happening on days outside summer months, Goodson Bell pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;States should instead use both temperature and date-based restrictions to widen the period of time customers are protected, and ban shutoffs completely for certain customers such as those with medical conditions, he said. Such measures are small steps to address widespread harms, said Sanya Carley, a professor at the University of Pennsylvania who studies utility disconnections. “When it comes to disconnections, I think states need to adopt as many protections as they possibly can.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Akielly Hu</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Climate &amp;amp; Energy</category><category>Economics</category><category>Extreme Heat</category></item><item><title>Extreme heat is forcing farmers to work overnight, an adaptation that comes with a cost</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Every morning, for years, Josana Pinto da Costa would venture out onto the waterways lining Óbidos, Brazil, in a small fishing boat. She would glide over the murky, churning currents of the Amazon River Basin, her flat nets bringing in writhing hauls as the sun ascended into the cerulean skies above.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Scorching temperatures in the Brazilian state of Pará have now made that routine unsafe. The heat has “been really intense” this year, said Pinto da Costa in Portuguese. It feels as if the “sun has gotten stronger,” so much so that it’s led her to shift her working hours from daytime to the dead of night.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Abandoning the practice that defined most of her days, she now sets off to the river in the pitch dark to chase what fish are also awake before dawn. It’s taken a toll on her catch, and her life. But it’s the only way she can continue her work in the face of &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/hottest-year-on-record-2024-climate-threshold-1-5c/&quot;&gt;increasingly dangerous temperatures&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“A lot of our fishing communities have shifted to fishing in the nighttime,” said Pinto da Costa, who advocates nationally for fisherfolk communities like hers through the Movimento de Pescadores e Pescadoras Artesanais do Brasil, or the Movement of Artisanal Fishermen and Fisherwomen of Brazil.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/night-fishing-belem-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;An aerial of a fishing town with lights and boats on the water at night&quot; data-caption=&quot;Fishing boats float in the harbor at the historic Old Town district of Belém at night in November 2023.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ricardo Lima / Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Fishing boats float in the harbor at the historic Old Town district of Belém at night in November 2023.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Ricardo Lima / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Moving from daytime to overnight work is often presented as the most practical solution for agricultural laborers struggling with rising temperatures as a result of climate change. But it is no longer simply a proposal: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aghealth.ucdavis.edu/news/night-work-growing-trend-western-agriculture&quot;&gt;This shift is already underway&lt;/a&gt; among many of the communities that catch, grow, and harvest the world’s food supply, from Brazil to India to the United States. Studies show the &lt;a href=&quot;https://lamont.columbia.edu/news/many-major-crop-regions-workers-plant-and-harvest-spiraling-heat-and-humidity&quot;&gt;most common means of adapting to rising temperatures in most crop-growing regions&lt;/a&gt; has been to start working when it’s still dark out, or even to &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/gcb.17142&quot;&gt;shift to a fully overnight schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The obvious piece of advice that you’ll see given is, ‘Work at night. Give workers head torches,’ and so on,” said Zia Mehrabi, a food security and climate researcher at the University of Colorado, Boulder. “But the reality is, that can lead to other rights violations, other negative impacts.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;That’s been the case for Pinto da Costa and her fishing community in Brazil. Nighttime work has been an additional hardship for a community already struggling with the impacts of climate change. The region has experienced decades of severe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-024-01530-4#:~:text=The%202023%20drought%20proved%20to,%2C11%2C12%2C13.&quot;&gt;drought conditions, causing fish to die off&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.mongabay.com/2024/07/after-historic-2023-drought-amazon-communities-brace-for-more-in-brazil/&quot;&gt;physically isolating people as waterways dried up&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31955278/&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; shows that regularly working during the night is&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10218650/&quot;&gt; physically and mentally disruptive&lt;/a&gt; and can lead to &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsinhealth.nih.gov/2022/02/reducing-health-risks-night-shifts&quot;&gt;long-term health complications&lt;/a&gt;. Nighttime fishing is also threatening social and communal routines among the fisherfolk. A daytime sleep schedule can curb quality time spent with loved ones, as well as limit when wares can be sold or traded in local markets.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It’s also impacting their ability to support themselves and their families through a generations-old trade. “We’ve actually been working more hours with less food, with less production,” said Pinto da Costa, noting that working at night has made their work less efficient and led them to find less fish. “This is across all regions of Brazil,” she added.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The impact of a shift to nighttime hours is an understudied piece of the puzzle of how climate change and rising temperatures threaten the world’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/one-in-11-people-went-hungry-last-year-climate-change-is-a-big-reason-why/&quot;&gt;food supply&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/heat-week-workers-rally-extreme-heat-protection/&quot;&gt;workforce&lt;/a&gt;. But for many experts, and those on the front lines, one thing is clear: Overnight work is far from a straightforward solution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s a very scary time for us,” said Pinto da Costa.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/fishing-para-state-brazil.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;fishermen silhouetted against a boat at sunset or sunrise&quot; data-caption=&quot;Fishermen walk on their boat as they fish in the Tapajos river in the Pará state of Brazil in August 2020.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Andre Penner / AP Photo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Fishermen walk on their boat as they fish in the Tapajos river in the Pará state of Brazil in August 2020.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Andre Penner / AP Photo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Outdoor workers, with their typical midday hours and limited access to shade, face some of the most perilous health risks during periods of extreme heat. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@naiacasina/the-silent-crisis-heat-stress-and-the-future-of-agriculture-in-key-global-regions-b2ad5ccb6403&quot;&gt;forthcoming analysis&lt;/a&gt; —&amp;nbsp;previewed exclusively by Grist — found that, on average, the amount of time considered unsafe to work outside during a typical 9-to-5 workday will increase 8 percent by 2050, assuming greenhouse gas emissions stay on their current trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Led by Naia Ormaza Zulueta, a Ph.D. student at the University of Colorado, Boulder, and Mehrabi, the analysis measures the number of extreme heat days by geographic region, and then breaks down daily and hourly temperatures by the estimated amount of population exposed. The research reveals that an estimated 21 percent of the global population already faces dangerous levels of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10334395/&quot;&gt;heat stress&lt;/a&gt; during typical workday hours for more than a third of the year. By 2050, without cuts to planet-warming greenhouse gas emissions (known as the “business-as-usual” scenario), that portion will jump to 39 percent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The number of days that people will experience a violation of their rights to a safe climate is going to substantially increase, but then also the number of possible working hours in a season, and productivity, is going to be substantially reduced,” said Mehrabi. “It’s a massive lose-lose situation.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/heat-week-workers-rally-extreme-heat-protection/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A group of people rally at an airport, holding up signs&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/heat-week-workers-rally-extreme-heat-protection/&quot;&gt;Workers across the US rally after string of heat-related deaths&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/ayurella-horn-muller/&quot;&gt;Ayurella Horn-Muller&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Their analysis finds that outdoor agricultural workers will encounter the largest health-related risks, with laborers in some areas being hit harder than others.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;India, in particular, is projected to be one of the countries whose workforce will be most exposed to heat stress under the business-as-usual climate scenario. There are roughly 260 million agricultural workers in India. By 2050, 94 percent of the country’s population could face more than 100 days in a year when at least one daytime working hour exceeds a wet-bulb temperature of 28 degrees Celsius, or 82.4 degrees Fahrenheit —&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/niosh/docs/2016-106/pdfs/2016-106.pdf&quot;&gt;a conservative threshold of what is considered safe for acclimatized workers&lt;/a&gt; experiencing moderate rates of work. (Unacclimatized workers, or those unaccustomed to working in such environments, will face greater levels of heat risk at the same temperature and amount of work.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Brazil, another of the world’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ers.usda.gov/amber-waves/2022/september/brazil-s-momentum-as-a-global-agricultural-supplier-faces-headwinds/#:~:text=By%20bringing%20into%20production%20vast,the%20United%20Nations%20(FAO).&quot;&gt;top agricultural suppliers&lt;/a&gt;, heat risk is not as dire, but still poses a substantial risk for outdoor workers, including Pinto da Costa’s community of fisherfolk. By 2050, roughly 41 percent of the country’s population could experience more than 100 days a year when wet-bulb temperatures exceed the recommended threshold for at least one hour a day, according to the Boulder team’s analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Mary Jo Dudley, the director of Cornell University’s Farmworker Program and the chair of the U.S. National Advisory Council of Migrant Health, said that the analysis is significant for what it reveals about the human health consequences of extreme heat, particularly as it relates to the world’s agricultural laborers. She’s seeing more and more outdoor agricultural workers in the U.S. adopt overnight schedules, which is only adding to the burdens and inequities the wider workforce already suffers from. This is poised to get worse. Zulueta and Mehrabi found that 35 percent of the total U.S. population will experience more than 100 days of wet-bulb temperatures exceeding 28 degrees C, or 82.4 degrees F, for at least one hour a day every year by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-embed__wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe loading=&quot;lazy&quot; title=&quot;The temperature threshold the human body can&#39;t survive&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/35Orkd9vzHQ?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This transition to a nighttime schedule pushes an extremely vulnerable population into more difficult work conditions that have significant mental and physical health impacts,” said Dudley.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Rebuking the human body’s circadian rhythms — that 24-hour internal clock that regulates when you sleep and wake — ramps up a person’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10218650/&quot;&gt;risk of health complications&lt;/a&gt;, such as cardiovascular disease and types of cancer, and diminishes their body’s ability to handle injury and stress. Working untraditional hours also can reduce a person’s ability to socialize or participate in cultural, communal activities, which are associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2808248&quot;&gt;positive impacts on brain and body health&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Women are particularly vulnerable to the social and economic impacts of transitioning to nighttime schedules. Despite making up nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/fishery/en/facp/BRA&quot;&gt;45 percent&lt;/a&gt; of artisanal fishers in Brazil, women receive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2015/05/why-we-need-to-close-the-fishing-industry-gender-gap/#:~:text=Women%20make%20up%20nearly%20half,U.N.%20report%20said%20on%20Tuesday.&quot;&gt;lower pay than their male counterparts&lt;/a&gt;. That means that when harvests decline with nighttime fishing, their margins are even smaller.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the Brazilian state of &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthjournalism.net/stories/women-shellfish-gatherers-return-to-the-bay-of-all-saints-in-brazil&quot;&gt;Bahia&lt;/a&gt;, tens of thousands of women fishers work to collect shellfish en masse, while in &lt;a href=&quot;https://feru.oceans.ubc.ca/2016/01/29/how-many-women-fish-in-brazil/&quot;&gt;Maranhão&lt;/a&gt;, women fisherfolk herd shrimp to the shore using small nets. Clam harvesting in Brazil’s northeast is also dominated by women. Because these jobs traditionally happened during the day and close to home, they allowed women to balance cultural or gendered family roles, including managing the household and being the caregiver to children. Shifting to evening hours to avoid extreme heat “poses a fundamental challenge,” said Mehrabi. “When you talk about changing working hours, you talk about disrupting families.”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/indigenous-women-gather-fish-brazil-para-state.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Two women stand in the water near a beach gathering fish into buckets&quot; data-caption=&quot;Two women clean fish at the Xingu River on the Paquicamba Indigenous Land in the Brazilian state of Pará in September 2022. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Carlos Fabal / AFP via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Two women clean fish at the Xingu River on the Paquicamba Indigenous Land in the Brazilian state of Pará in September 2022. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Carlos Fabal / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Overnight work comes with other risks too. In many areas of Brazil, nighttime work is “either impossible” or “very complicated” because there are procedures and regulations as to when fisherfolk in different regions can fish, said Pinto da Costa. Nighttime fishing is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icmbio.gov.br/cepsul/images/stories/legislacao/Portaria/1999/p_ibama_17_n_1999_planoutilizacaoresexarraialdocabo_rj.pdf&quot;&gt;regulated in some parts of Brazil&lt;/a&gt; — measures that have been shown to disproportionately impact artisanal fishers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Even so, says Pinto da Costa, many are braving the risks “just to reduce the amount of exposure to the sun.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Honestly, when I saw that this was accepted in the literature, that people were giving this advice of changing their working shifts to the night, I was shocked,” said Zulueta, the author of the Boulder study, citing &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/gcb.17142&quot;&gt;a paper published earlier this year where overnight work is recommended&lt;/a&gt; as an adaptation tool to reduce agricultural productivity losses to heat exposure. Under a policy of “avoiding unsafe working hours,” shifting those hours to the nighttime “is not a universally applicable solution,” she said. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Growing up a pastoralist in Ahmedabad, India, Bhavana Rabari has spent much of her life helping tend to her family’s herd of buffalo. Although she now spends her days advocating for pastoralists across the Indian state of Gujarat, the routine of her childhood is still ingrained in her: Wake up, feed and milk the herd, and then tend to the fields that surround their home.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But extreme heat threatens to change that, as well as the preservation of her community. When temperatures soar past 90 degrees F in Ahmedabad —&amp;nbsp;now a regular occurrence —&amp;nbsp;Rabari worries about her mom, who hand-collects feed for their buffalo to graze on. Other pastoralists are nomadic, walking at least 10 miles a day herding cattle from region to region in the hunt for pastureland.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bhavana-Rabari-pictured-on-right-near-Ahmedabad-Gujarat-India-2022.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 960w&quot; alt=&quot;A man and a woman tend to a herd of goats&quot; data-caption=&quot;Bhavana Rabari kneels while tending a herd of goats and sheep near Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India, in 2022.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Bhavana Rabari&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Bhavana Rabari kneels while tending a herd of goats and sheep near Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India, in 2022.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Bhavana Rabari&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“If we lose our livestock, we lose our culture, our dignity,” said Rabari. “If we continue our occupations, then we are dignified. We live with the dignity of our work.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But rapidly rising temperatures are making it hard to hold on to that dignity of work. “The heat affects every life, every thing,” said Rabari.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Working overnight is a tactic Rabari has heard of other agricultural workers trying. But the idea of tending to the herd in the dark isn’t something she sees as safe or accessible for either her family or other pastoralists in her community. It’s less efficient and more dangerous to work outdoors with animals in the dark, and it would require them to overhaul daily lives and traditions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We are not working at night,” said Rabari. But what the family is already doing is waking up at 5 a.m. to beat the heat, collecting milk from their buffalo and preparing products to sell in the market during the dusky hours of the morning.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/livestock-dying-heat-solution-silvopasture/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Cows graze among olive trees on a farm in Texas.&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?resize=330%2C220&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/grazing-cattle.jpeg?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1067&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/livestock-dying-heat-solution-silvopasture/&quot;&gt;Livestock are dying in the heat. This little-known farming method offers a solution.&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/jmccracken/&quot;&gt;John McCracken&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Rabari’s family and other pastoralists across Gujarat are increasingly in an untenable position. Hotter temperatures have already caused pastureland to wither, meaning animals are grazing less and producing less milk. More unsafe working hours means lost work time on top of that, which, in turn, changes how much income pastoralist families are able to take home.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The result has been not adaptation, but an exodus. Most pastoralists Rabari knows, particularly younger generations, are leaving the trade, seeking employment instead as drivers or cleaners in Ahmedabad. Rabari, who organizes for women pastoralists through the Maldhari Mahila Sangathan, or the Pastoral Women Alliance, says women are most often the ones left behind to tend to the herds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;They “have to take care of their children, they have to take care of the food, and they have to take care of the water,” she said. “They face the heat, they face the floods, or the excess rain.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Halfway across the world, April Hemmes is facing off against unrelenting bouts of heat amid verdant fields of soybeans and corn in Hampton, north-central Iowa. A fourth-generation small Midwestern farmer, Hemmes works more than 900 acres entirely on her own — year in and year out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Midwest is the largest agricultural area in the United States, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.climatehubs.usda.gov/hubs/midwest/topic/agriculture-midwest#:~:text=The%20Midwest%20represents%20one%20of,consistently%20affects%20the%20global%20economy.&quot;&gt;one of the leading agricultural producers&lt;/a&gt; in the world. It’s also an area that has been battered by human-caused climate change. In fact, scientists just recently declared an end to the drought that had devastated the region for a whopping &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegazette.com/environment-nature/severe-drought-enters-western-iowa-moderate-drought-spreading/&quot;&gt;203 weeks&lt;/a&gt;. The conditions &lt;a href=&quot;https://mississippitoday.org/2024/09/16/another-midwest-drought-is-causing-transportation-headaches-on-the-mississippi-river/#:~:text=Since%202022%2C%20much%20of%20the,%2C%20Missouri%2C%20Nebraska%20and%20Kansas.&quot;&gt;impacted&lt;/a&gt; crop yields, livestock, the transportation of goods, and the larger supply chain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Hemmes has the luxury of not having to face the same degree of heat stress that Rabari and Pinto da Costa are confronting elsewhere in the world, per the Boulder analysis. When compared to India and Brazil, the U.S. is on the lowest end of the worker health impact scale for extreme heat. And yet, heat is also already the deadliest extreme weather event in the U.S., responsible for more deaths every year than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weather.gov/hazstat/&quot;&gt;hurricanes, floods, and tornadoes combined&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=663&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-September-2018.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 720w&quot; alt=&quot;A woman drives a piece of farm equipment through a field&quot; data-caption=&quot;April Hemmes harvests a soybean field on her farm in Iowa in September 2018.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of April Hemmes and Joe Murphy&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;April Hemmes harvests a soybean field on her farm in Iowa in September 2018.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of April Hemmes and Joe Murphy&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A few years back, while building a fence on her farmland, Hemmes suffered her first bout of on-the-job heat exhaustion. Suddenly, her heart started to race and her body felt as if it began to boil from within, forcing her to abandon her task and head indoors, away from the menacing heat. It was a wake-up call: Ever since, she’s been hyper-cautious with how she feels when tending to her fields.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This past summer, the heat index repeatedly soared past 100 degrees in Hemmes’ corner of Iowa. She found herself needing to be extra careful, not only pacing herself while working and taking more frequent breaks, but also making sure to get the bulk of the day’s work done in the morning. She even began starting her day in the fields an hour or so earlier to avoid searing temperatures compounding with brutal humidity throughout the afternoon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This [farm] has been in my family for over 125 years,” she said. “I do everything from banking to planting to spraying, everything. So it’s all on me, and it’s my family farm. I’m very proud of that.” In 1993, her dad and grandfather both retired, and she took over operations. She’s been more or less “a one-woman show” since. Keeping her farm well-managed is a responsibility she doesn’t take lightly. “You do what’s best for the soil. Because that’s the inheritance of future generations,” she said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1161 1161w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/April-Hemmes-Iowa-planting-covercrop-September-2024-min-e1733875903542.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A point-of-view photo of a piece of farm equipment moving over green rows of crops&quot; data-caption=&quot;April Hemmes’ view as she plants cover crops on one of her fields in May 2024.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of April Hemmes&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;April Hemmes’ view as she plants cover crops on one of her fields in May 2024.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of April Hemmes&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When Hemmes looks at how to prepare for a future with hotter working conditions, she knows one thing: Nighttime work is out of the question.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Not only are summertime mosquitoes in Iowa “terrible after dark,” but Hemmes says some of the chemicals she uses are regulated, restricting her from spraying them during the nighttime. In addition, she would need to get lights installed throughout the fields to alleviate the risk of injury when she uses equipment, and she would be even more fearful of that equipment breaking down.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It would take more energy to work at night,” said Hemmes. “I think it would be far more dangerous … to work after the daylight was gone.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Like Pinto da Costa and Rabari, Hemmes is involved in advocacy for her community. With the United Soybean Board, Hemmes advocates for women in agriculture. With more resources at her disposal than Pinto da Costa and Rabari, Hemmes is focused on how to ensure solo-farming operations like hers have access to the technology they need to overcome heat spells —&amp;nbsp;and never have to seriously consider an overnight harvest schedule.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/extreme-heat-protection-florida-law-athletes-workers/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/florida-heat-merged216x9-final.gif?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/extreme-heat-protection-florida-law-athletes-workers/&quot;&gt;As heat becomes a national threat, who will be protected?&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/nate-rosenfield/&quot;&gt;Nate Rosenfield&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On her own farm, she’s invested in “expensive” autonomous agriculture technology that allows her to take breaks when she needs to from the blistering sun. And she would like to see more precision technology and autonomous agriculture tools readily applied and accessible for farmers. She currently uses a tractor with an automatic steering system &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/more-farms-are-turning-to-automation-amid-labor-shortages/&quot;&gt;that improves planting and plowing efficiency and requires much less work&lt;/a&gt;, which she credits as one of the pivotal reasons she’s able to successfully manage her hundreds of acres of fields on her own.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;She also hopes to see farmers tapping into their inherent flexibility. “What farmers are is adaptable,” she said. “I don’t have an orchard on my farm, but if I did, and I saw this thing [climate change] coming, you know, maybe you look at tearing the trees out and starting to plant what I can in those fields. Maybe the Corn Belt will move up to North Dakota. Who knows, if this keeps progressing?”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Gujarat, Rabari and the Maldhari Mahila Sangathan are working to secure better representation for pastoralists in policymakers’ decisions about land use. The hope is for these communities to inform policies that would allow pastoralists job security and financial safety nets as climbing temperatures make it difficult to work and turn a profit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Women pastoralists in particular are entirely left out of these policy spaces, said Rabari, which isn’t just an issue of exclusion but means their unique ecological knowledge is lost, too. “We have a traditional knowledge of which grass is good for our animals, which grass they need to eat so we get the most meals, how [they] can be used for medical treatment,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;h=300&amp;amp;crop=1 300w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;h=400&amp;amp;crop=1 400w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;h=600&amp;amp;crop=1 600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Madhuben-pictured-Gir-Forest-Gujarat-India-January-2021.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A woman kneels in a dry field with pots and pans strewn on the ground&quot; data-caption=&quot;A woman named Madhuben boils camel milk in Gir Forest, Gujarat, India, in January 2021. Madhuben is a nomadic pastoralist who walks at least 10 miles a day, herding her cattle from region to region in the hunt for pastureland.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Bhavana Rabari&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A woman named Madhuben boils camel milk in Gir Forest, Gujarat, India, in January 2021. Madhuben is a nomadic pastoralist who walks at least 10 miles a day, herding her cattle from region to region in the hunt for pastureland.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Bhavana Rabari&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Pinto da Costa and the Movimento de Pescadores e Pescadoras Artesanais do Brasil are also advocating for monetary relief from the Brazilian government to offset the losses her fisherfolk community has faced from climate change and shifting work hours. In addition, she is looking for technical support to improve fisherfolk’s resources and equipment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I have maintained my energy and motivation to continue to fight for our rights,” said Pinto da Costa.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For all, it’s a race against time. Eventually, even working at night may not be enough to keep outdoor agricultural work viable. The Boulder researchers found that an overnight working schedule will not significantly alleviate dangerous heat stress exposure risk in key agricultural regions of the world — particularly across India. After all, heat waves don’t only happen during the day, but also take place at night, with&lt;a href=&quot;https://ehp.niehs.nih.gov/doi/full/10.1289/EHP13206#:~:text=The%20team%20reviewed%2011%20causes,with%20all%2011%20causes%20reviewed.&quot;&gt; overnight minimum temperatures rising even more rapidly than daytime highs&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Zachary Zobel, a scientist at the Woodwell Climate Research Center who has separately researched the impact of overnight work adaptations on global agricultural productivity levels, said the Boulder team’s analysis has a “novel” result, and lines up with what his team has found. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Warming past 2 degrees C, which we will experience over the next 30 years, would mean that even overnight shifts wouldn’t recover productivity,” said Zobel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“How do you solve a problem like that?” Mehrabi said. “The reality is that the workers most at risk are the people contributing least to the climate change problem. That’s not to say that we can’t have better policies around hydration, shading, health. But it’s just kind of trying to put a BandAid on a problem. It doesn’t actually deal with the problem at its root cause, which comes down to this trajectory of fossil fuel consumption and emissions.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/overnight-work-extreme-heat-adaptation-agriculture/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/overnight-work-extreme-heat-adaptation-agriculture/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 09:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Ayurella Horn-Muller</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cruel-summer-agriculte-worker-farm-night-heat.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Heat</category><category>Food and Agriculture</category><category>International</category><category>Labor</category></item><item><title>Chronic health problems amplify heat risk in the Rio Grande Valley</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Something seemed amiss when police officer Oscar Lizarraga arrived at the Conquistador Apartments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Maria Ester Singh hadn’t yet paid that month’s rent, and the apartment manager said that was unusual. Singh’s daughter, who lives outside Houston, hadn’t heard from her since April. She asked a cousin in Brownsville to check in on her. Now it was May 8, and no one answered a knock at the door of unit 1012, which was latched from the inside.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Joaquin Galvan, 82, Maria Trinidad Galvan, 78, and Singh, 60, lived in the apartment complex on Billy Mitchell Boulevard with three small dogs. Singh was the personal care attendant for Joaquin, her father, and Maria Trinidad, her aunt.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lizarraga checked the windows and doors for signs of forced entry. Finding none, he pried the door open. He saw a body slumped on the floor. He asked Maria’s cousin and the apartment manager to wait outside.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The three family members had been dead for days. A pathologist attributed the deaths to complications of diabetes and extreme heat. “Multiple floor fans were in operation,” according to the autopsy report. “The air conditioner was reportedly not in operation and the inside thermostat displayed a reading of 88 F.” Temperatures had been in the 90s recently, and on the day the bodies were found, the mercury would hit 104.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Police said the AC was turned on when they entered the apartment. “Whether or not it was functioning properly is something that was undetermined,” a Brownsville Police Department spokeswoman said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-6-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Crime scene tape hangs from the doorway of unit 1012 at the Conquistador Apartments, where three family members were found dead on May 8. 
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Crime scene tape hangs from the doorway of unit 1012 at the Conquistador Apartments, where three family members were found dead on May 8. 
 &lt;cite&gt;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Either way, the pathologist’s conclusion was clear: the heat, along with their chronic medical conditions, was enough to kill all three family members.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The case illustrates the latent threat of extreme heat in deep south Texas and the disproportionate impact of climate change and high temperatures on the elderly. It also shines a light on the outsized role isolation plays in heat-related deaths, especially among the elderly in America,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK557972/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;one-quarter of whom are considered “socially isolated&lt;/a&gt;,” according to the National Academy of Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Rio Grande Valley has elevated rates of diabetes, heart failure and other chronic conditions. Now the population faces an additional threat: hotter days and nights, and more of them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Poverty and lack of health insurance magnify the risk of heat illnesses and deaths. Other aggravating factors: jobs that require people to withstand long hours in the hot sun and electric bills too high for low-income families to pay.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s 104 degrees and frequently one of the hottest parts of the United States,” said Dr. Ivan Melendez, the health authority for Hidalgo County, part of the Rio Grande Valley. “It’s a tremendous amount of cofactors coming together… It’s just a total nightmare. It’s a perfect storm.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Danielle Arigoni, an urban planner and author of “&lt;a href=&quot;https://islandpress.org/books/climate-resilience-aging-nation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Climate Resilience for an Aging Nation&lt;/a&gt;,” said the elderly are often left out of climate change and disaster planning, even though they die at disproportionate rates during natural disasters.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“How many more times do we have to see these headlines before we do things differently?” she said. “This is a tragedy. Our older adults deserve better.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-completely-preventable&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Completely preventable”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Maria Trinidad and her brother Joaquin had spent their whole lives in Brownsville.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Their first home was just a few miles from the Conquistador Apartments. The Galvan family lived at 1054 Roosevelt Avenue in 1950 when interviewed for that year’s census. Their father, Alberto, was born in Brownsville and worked as a longshoreman at the port. His wife, Maria Trinidad, was from the town of Cuero, southeast of San Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;By 1950 they had seven children. Joaquin was the third, born in 1941, and Maria Trinidad the fifth, born in 1945.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Joaquin wed Minerva Cervantes in 1964 when he was 22. The couple continued to live at the house on Roosevelt, where they had four children of their own. The Brownsville Herald reported the death of a “baby Alberto” in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It’s unclear how Joaquin and Maria Trinidad wound up at the Conquistador Apartments or how long they had been there.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=2048 2048w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-30-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A gray apartment building on a street lined with palm trees&quot; data-caption=&quot;Their neighbors in the Conquistador Apartments in Brownsville rarely saw Joaquin Galvan, 82, his 78-year-old sister and his 60-year-old daughter.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Their neighbors in the Conquistador Apartments in Brownsville rarely saw Joaquin Galvan, 82, his 78-year-old sister and his 60-year-old daughter.
 &lt;cite&gt;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Family members did not respond to requests for interviews. But publicly available records paint a picture of a family that scattered across Texas and beyond, likely leaving few relatives in Brownsville to help the aging siblings. The cousin who called the police told them she had not spoken with them in more than two years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Investigators have not determined the exact sequence of events leading up to the deaths. Months later, crime scene tape still hung from the doorway of the apartment. Brownsville police said their investigation is ongoing, and added, without elaborating, that they are looking into the possibility of elder abuse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Conquistador Apartments, a cluster of unremarkable two-story buildings painted blue and light orange, is managed by an Austin company. Rents for one-bedroom apartments start at $699. The unit where the three family members died is a two-bedroom and is currently listed for rent at $879 a month. The apartments at Conquistador have central air conditioning, and the walkways are shaded by trees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When officer Lizarraga entered unit 1012 on the morning of May 8, he found Singh’s body in a front room and the bodies of Joaquin and his sister in two back bedrooms. The siblings both appeared to have fallen out of bed. All three bodies were in a state of decay.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lizarraga called animal control to take control of the three small dogs barking at his feet. He called a Justice of the Peace, detectives and crime scene investigators. Employees of two funeral homes arrived by midday. The bodies were transported for autopsies. Investigators started interviewing neighbors and family members.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The autopsy report said the outdoor temperature was 85 degrees and the heat index was 96.8 when the family was found at about 9 a.m. that day. Heat index combines relative humidity and air temperature to capture how hot it feels under certain weather conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The pathologist determined that heat contributed to all three deaths. Singh died of diabetes ketoacidosis (DKA), complicated by heat exposure. DKA develops when the body doesn’t produce enough insulin, and acids known as ketones build up in the bloodstream. Without insulin, Singh would have declined rapidly until she entered a diabetic coma. The combination of high blood sugar and heat were fatal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Maria Trinidad died of diabetes mellitus, hypertension and hypothyroidism complicated by heat exposure. Joaquin died of diabetes mellitus, hypertension and elevated cholesterol, complicated by heat exposure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This family’s death was completely preventable,” said Jeff Goodell, an Austin-based journalist and author of “The Heat Will Kill You First.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;He pointed out that Texas has made no statewide effort to map vulnerable communities or reach the populations most endangered by excessive heat. He drew a contrast to the extensive governmental warnings and preparations that precede the arrival of a tropical storm or hurricane.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This is what happens when you have a government, local and state, that is not taking this risk seriously,” Goodell said of the Brownsville deaths.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-numbers-that-we-have-not-seen-before&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Numbers that we have not seen before”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As diabetics, Joaquin, Maria Trinidad and Singh were at greater risk from the heat. The damage diabetes does to nerves and blood vessels inhibits the body’s cooling mechanisms. When a person’s blood sugar spikes, they are also at risk of dehydration because they will urinate excessively to expel the blood sugar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Jose Vazquez, an internist in the Rio Grande Valley, explained that a diabetic’s “temperature regulation system is already impaired.” He said medications to treat diabetes can further blunt the body’s response to heat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We are exposed to high temperatures all year round,” Vazquez said. “However, over the last few years we have reached numbers that we have not seen before – 110, 112 degrees at the peak.”&lt;/p&gt;







  &lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-gallery alignwide is-cropped&quot;&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&quot;blocks-gallery-grid&quot;&gt;
              &lt;li class=&quot;blocks-gallery-item&quot;&gt;
          &lt;figure&gt;
            
&lt;div class=&quot;article-asset-mod&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&quot;article-asset &quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A bald man with a gray beard wears a doctor coat and stethescope&quot; data-caption=&quot;Dr. Jose Vasquez, former health authority for Starr County, poses for a portrait outside of his practice on Wednesday, September 4, 2024, in Brownsville, Texas.&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1463w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C1680&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=330%2C462&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=768%2C1075&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=1097%2C1536&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1097w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-2-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=150%2C210&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;2048&quot; width=&quot;1463&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li class=&quot;blocks-gallery-item&quot;&gt;
          &lt;figure&gt;
            
&lt;div class=&quot;article-asset-mod&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img class=&quot;article-asset &quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A man in green scrubs stands in a hospital hallway&quot; data-caption=&quot;Dr. James Castillo, heath authority for Cameron County, poses for a portrait on Friday, September 6, 2024, in Edinburg, Texas.&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1463w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=1200%2C1680&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=330%2C462&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=768%2C1075&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=1097%2C1536&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1097w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-21-1463x2048-1.jpg?resize=150%2C210&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;2048&quot; width=&quot;1463&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;

    

          &lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt; &lt;p&gt;Left: Jose Vezquez, an internist in the Rio Grande Valley. Right: Dr. James Castillo, the health authority for Cameron County. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Lee/San Antonio Express-News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;One in three Rio Grande Valley residents has diabetes, about double&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/php/data-research/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;the national rate&lt;/a&gt;, according to&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7002264/pdf/nihms-1546271.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;recent research&lt;/a&gt;. Many Valley residents with diabetes never receive a diagnosis and the disease goes unmanaged.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Many people with diabetes, especially those without health insurance, don’t seek treatment until the disease is already advanced. Brownsville is the seat of Cameron County, where 29% of residents are uninsured and another 26% are on Medicaid or other income-based public insurance. Without treatment, otherwise preventable wounds and infections lead to amputations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Rio Grande Valley, which encompasses Cameron, Hidalgo, Starr and Willacy counties, has&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texasobserver.org/life-and-limb/?src=longreads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;higher rates of diabetic amputations&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;than the rest of the state.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Joaquin Galvan was a below-the-knee amputee, although it could not be determined whether his diabetes was the reason. He used a wheelchair and was functionally immobile. His sister Maria Trinidad had congestive heart failure and hyperthyroidism in addition to diabetes. The siblings required round-the-clock care.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Singh was employed by two home health care agencies as a personal care attendant for her father and aunt. She also was managing her own diabetes. Once Singh was incapacitated, the elder siblings may have been unable to seek help.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Dr. James Castillo, a hospice doctor and health authority for Cameron County, said many of his patients with complex health problems prefer to be treated at home. He often has to consider whether home is a safe environment. Does the AC work? Is there a heat wave? Will the electricity stay on to keep medical equipment running?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“You have a very large population of medically fragile people,” he said of the Rio Grande Valley. “And in a crisis, fragility shows.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-don-t-really-know-who-they-were&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Don’t really know who they were”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Arigoni found that in disasters such as Hurricane Katrina, Texas’ Winter Storm Uri in 2021 and the Oregon heat dome the same year, elderly people die in disproportionate numbers. She said emergency management plans often account for elderly people at nursing homes but overlook those who are socially isolated and living at home, as the Galvans were.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“You see it time and time and time again, predictably, that older adults are dying at double, triple, quadruple the rate of other people in disasters,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Joaquin, Maria Trinidad and Maria Ester seemed to have made few impressions on their neighbors. Oralia Favata, 68, who lives a few doors down from their apartment, said she had never met them but would notice flyers and mail piling up outside the door.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-11-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Oralia Favata, 68, lives a few doors down from unit 1012 at the Conquistador Apartments but she knew nothing about the people who lived there.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Oralia Favata, 68, lives a few doors down from unit 1012 at the Conquistador Apartments but she knew nothing about the people who lived there.
 &lt;cite&gt;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I never saw anybody come in or out or visit them,” she said. “I don’t really know who they were.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On May 8, she watched a woman break down in tears outside the Galvans’ apartment. Favata said a relative of the Galvans gave her a bag of left-over dog food from the apartment before driving back to Houston.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Other neighbors repeated similar stories. Several said they learned only after the fact who the Galvans were.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Sunset Memorial Funeral Home took care of the family’s remains but no funeral services were held. One relative wrote on an online memorial page for Maria Trinidad that she would miss watching telenovelas with her. “I will miss you forever Tia Trine.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-you-can-t-live-here-without-ac-period&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“You can’t live here (without AC) … period”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Brownsville has always been hot and humid. But temperatures rarely reached 100 degrees in the 1940s and 1950s, when the Galvans were growing up. Air conditioning was not yet widespread in the Rio Grande Valley. In old adobe houses, people would open the doors at night and let cross-ventilation cool their homes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Over the span of the Galvan siblings’ lifetimes, that changed. As temperatures creeped up, air conditioning became ubiquitous.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The five hottest summers in Brownsville since record keeping began in 1878 have all been since 2018. 2023 was the hottest year on record. The 40 days of 100-degree heat in 2023 shattered the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weather.gov/media/bro/wxevents/2023/pdf/AutumnSeasonSummary.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;previous record&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of 12 days. So far in 2024, there have been&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.extremeweatherwatch.com/cities/brownsville/yearly-days-of-100-degrees&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;7 days of 100 degree heat&lt;/a&gt;, the fifth highest annual total.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=2048 2048w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-19-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Dr. Ivan Melendez, the Hidalgo County health authority, grew up in the Rio Grande Valley in the 1960s and ’70s, when air conditioning was a luxury. 
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Dr. Ivan Melendez, the Hidalgo County health authority, grew up in the Rio Grande Valley in the 1960s and ’70s, when air conditioning was a luxury. 
 &lt;cite&gt;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I remember when we were kids in the 1960s, 1970s, hardly anybody had air conditioning,” said Dr. Ivan Melendez, the Hidalgo County health authority. “We couldn’t afford it. It was really more of a privilege.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Now if you don’t have air conditioning in the Valley, you can’t live here,” he said. “You cannot survive the summer here without air conditioning. Period.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Extreme heat is starting earlier in the year. May 2024 was the hottest May on record in the city. Overnight, the heat index often stayed above 90 degrees during May. High nighttime temperatures prevent the body from cooling off and recovering from daytime heat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As of early September, Brownsville EMS had responded to 42 heat-related emergencies during summer 2024. Paramedic Hector Martinez estimated about 100 additional calls were most likely heat-related.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;South Texas Health System’s acute care and emergency departments in the Rio Grande Valley saw a spike in heat-related illnesses last year. From 2020 to 2022, the system recorded fewer than 200 heat-related illnesses a year. In 2023, they treated 325. By the end of August this year, the network had surpassed last year’s total of heat-related illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Texas Department of State Health Services uses death certificates to determine the number of deaths attributed to heat in Texas by county. When 10 or fewer heat deaths are recorded in a county, the exact number is withheld to protect confidentiality. Most years in Cameron County, the number has been below 10, according to data obtained by the Texas Tribune. In 2023, the total jumped to 11, including deaths where heat was a contributing factor. Two were migrants—a 44-year-old Mexican and a 32-year-old Guatemalan who succumbed to “environmental heat exposure” after crossing the border. The 2023 total included a 43-year-old man with Down syndrome who died in a house without air conditioning. Data for 2024 is not yet available.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Medical professionals say death certificates present an incomplete picture of heat-related fatalities. Physicians list the direct cause of death—a heart attack, a drug overdose—but often do not know about contributing factors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Autopsies can yield more information. In Cameron and Hidalgo Counties, Justices of the Peace determine when to have a forensic pathologist conduct an autopsy. (In more populous counties, a medical examiner’s office makes that decision.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Melendez said that under this system, a death certificate may be completed by a doctor, or a Justice of the Peace, or a coroner. The role of heat is not always considered.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Everyone has a different opinion,” he said. “And a different level of expertise.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-alone-in-their-moment-of-crisis&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alone in their moment of crisis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As a community paramedic in Brownsville, Hector Martinez keeps a close eye on the number of 911 calls and where they are coming from. Community paramedics provide preventive as well as routine medical care to minimize repeat hospital admissions in under-served populations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;There’s a clear pattern to heat-related emergencies, he said. Most of those calls come from low-income neighborhoods. Martinez said the most common such emergency involves a man who works outdoors, or in a confined space such as a restaurant kitchen, and underestimates the toll of the heat. “They work landscaping. They work in restaurants—cooks, waiters, waitresses,” he said. “They do manual labor, they’re builders.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On a September afternoon, Martinez drove the backstreets of Brownsville’s Southmost neighborhood with the familiarity of a taxi driver. More than three in 10 residents in this ZIP code (78521) live in poverty, according to census data. The median household income is $38,000.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_CL-29-2048x1366-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;The entrance to an apartment is adorned with Halloween decorations while crime scene tape hangs next to the door&quot; data-caption=&quot;More than five months after three family members were found dead inside unit 1012 at the Conquistador Apartments in Brownsville, crime scene tape still hangs from the doorway.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;More than five months after three family members were found dead inside unit 1012 at the Conquistador Apartments in Brownsville, crime scene tape still hangs from the doorway.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Chris Lee / San Antonio Express-News&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A $100 repair to an air conditioner could help keep a low-income resident out of the emergency room. Martinez will find a charity, church or nonprofit to help.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We don’t have a budget for it,” he said. “So we try and find people.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Area Agency on Aging and Rotary Clubs are some of his most reliable partners. But their funds run out every year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The federally funded Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program helps people below the poverty line pay for heating and cooling. But in states such as Texas, with large low-income populations and extended periods of extreme heat, the funds&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://insideclimatenews.org/news/19072024/low-income-families-electric-bills-federal-funds-stretched-thin/&quot;&gt;cover a small fraction&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of those eligible. The Hidalgo County agency that disburses utility assistance funds is&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hidalgocsa.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;closed to applications&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;because of high demand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Christopher Basaldú, a co-founder of the South Texas Environmental Justice Network, said Brownsville should open more cooling centers. The organization hands out bottled water at its downtown Brownsville office, which an overtaxed window unit struggles to keep cool during the summer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Climate change is happening. The heat is going up and it’s becoming more relentless,” he said. “People are choosing to not run their air conditioners as part of ways of saving money.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The City of Brownsville did not respond to questions about its preparedness for extreme heat. Nor did city commissioner Bryan Martinez, who represents the area of the Conquistador Apartments, or Cameron&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;County Judge Eddie Treviño.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.togethernola.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Community Lighthouses&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in New Orleans have been held up as a model for protecting vulnerable populations from the heat. These are churches and other community spaces equipped with solar power to keep the lights and air conditioning running during natural disasters or heat waves. The Lighthouses are dispersed throughout neighborhoods within walking distance of vulnerable populations. Staff knock on doors to inform residents about their services before disaster strikes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Ailing and isolated, the Galvans were alone in their moment of crisis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;After they died, there was no official response from the city or county. There was no public remembrance or reckoning. No obituaries were published. Neighbors were left to puzzle over how the family’s suffering went unnoticed. The Galvans’ surviving relatives mourned in private.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Another hot summer ran its course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat/chronic-health-problems-amplify-heat-risk-in-the-rio-grande-valley/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-heat/chronic-health-problems-amplify-heat-risk-in-the-rio-grande-valley/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Martha Pskowski, Inside Climate News</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/HeatDeath_resized.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Heat</category></item><item><title>Water challenges — made worse by rising temperatures — are threatening the world’s crops</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wri.org/insights/growing-water-risks-food-crops&quot;&gt;new report&lt;/a&gt; finds that one-quarter of the world’s crops are grown in places facing high levels of water stress, water unreliability, or both. The analysis comes from the research nonprofit World Resources Institute, or WRI, and highlights the difficulty of growing enough food to meet rising demand on a warming planet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/one-in-11-people-went-hungry-last-year-climate-change-is-a-big-reason-why/&quot;&gt;One out of every 11 people in the world are hungry&lt;/a&gt;, meaning they don’t get enough food to maintain basic health, according to a recent United Nations report. The water challenges outlined in WRI’s latest research could potentially contribute to increased levels of food insecurity, especially as global temperatures continue to rise.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The report looks at both irrigated crops, in which water is transferred from reservoirs to cropland, and rain-fed crops, which receive water through precipitation. The authors relied on WRI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wri.org/aqueduct/tools&quot;&gt;existing global water risk data&lt;/a&gt; and compared it to crop production data from the International Food Policy Research Institute.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Analyzing both sets of data, the report authors found that both irrigated and rain-fed crops face complications when it comes to water access. For example, about 60 percent of irrigated crops by weight come from regions of the world facing high or extremely high levels of water stress. Water stress refers to heightened competition over water resources; it is considered high when 40 percent or more of an area’s local water supply is spoken for by agriculture, energy, industry, and household use.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Areas facing high levels of water stress require robust water management and governance, said Sam Kuzma, one of the report authors. The problem, she said, stems partly from a common tendency to take water for granted and treat it like an endlessly renewable, on-demand resource. “Because we don’t put a value on water, you can irrigate and not pay much at all for the water that you’re using,” said Kuzma, who runs the water data program at WRI. “That means we can be pretty reckless with how we’re growing and in what environments. That’s why you see alfalfa being grown in the desert.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The majority of the world’s irrigated crops — 72 percent — are grown in just 10 countries, including Brazil, China, India, and the United States, according to WRI. These crops include staples like rice, wheat, and corn that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2018/10/once-neglected-these-traditional-crops-are-our-new-rising-stars/&quot;&gt;make up a good chunk of the world’s calories&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The high rate of water stress in areas that grow irrigated crops spells trouble for global food security. India, for example, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/india/fao-in-india/india-at-a-glance/en/&quot;&gt;a major agricultural producer&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/9/20/how-reliant-is-the-world-on-indian-rice-exports&quot;&gt;world’s largest exporter of rice&lt;/a&gt;. The country faces significant water risks; about one-fourth of its total crop production comes from areas using more water than can be naturally replenished, according to WRI’s analysis. Kuzma noted that this can lead to &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.umich.edu/groundwater-depletion-rates-in-india-could-triple-in-coming-decades-as-climate-warms-study-shows/&quot;&gt;groundwater depletion&lt;/a&gt; in parts of the country that rely on a source of water that “just isn’t going to be there forever” if current usage rates continue. “If that’s a key part of our global food supply chain and we no longer have the water to create those commodities, then sorry, everyone is impacted,” she added.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A farmer wearing a beige polo shirt and grey shorts bend overs as he waters crops with a hose&quot; data-caption=&quot;A farmer waters peanut crops using an irrigation system with solar pumps in Madagascar.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Sarah Tetaud / Contributor / Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A farmer waters peanut crops using an irrigation system with solar pumps in Madagascar.
 &lt;cite&gt;Sarah Tetaud / Contributor / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;WRI also looked at water unreliability facing rain-fed crops, which make up two-thirds of the world’s food supply. Its analysis found that 8 percent of rain-fed crops by weight face high to extremely high levels of water unreliability, which refers to fluctuations in the annual water supply such as periods of drought and extreme precipitation events &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nasa.gov/centers-and-facilities/goddard/warming-makes-droughts-extreme-wet-events-more-frequent-intense/&quot;&gt;caused by climate change&lt;/a&gt;. As the planet continues to warm, the amount of rain-fed crops affected by these conditions could jump 40 percent by 2050, compared to 2020 levels. Warming temperatures are also likely to impact irrigated crops, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/feature/2022/10/17/what-you-need-to-know-about-food-security-and-climate-change&quot;&gt;crops need more water to survive in hotter climates&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Nicole Silk, the global director of freshwater outcomes at the environmental nonprofit The Nature Conservancy, noted that these challenges are having a dire impact on people and communities. Floods and droughts are just as likely to put both “people and crop production in jeopardy,” she said. “We’re increasingly moving towards a world where both people and food production are going to be in places that are particularly water stressed,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As a sector, agriculture is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwater.org/water-facts/water-food-and-energy&quot;&gt;number one consumer of freshwater globally&lt;/a&gt;, accounting for &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/opendata/chart-globally-70-freshwater-used-agriculture&quot;&gt;70 percent of freshwater withdrawals&lt;/a&gt; — the process of removing freshwater from surface-water sources, like rivers and lakes, as well as groundwater sources like underground aquifers. In its latest report, WRI refers to agriculture as the largest driver of water stress. And yet, food has to be grown somewhere, somehow, by someone. Indeed, all signs point to more food needing to be grown, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wri.org/insights/how-sustainably-feed-10-billion-people-2050-21-charts&quot;&gt;the global population is projected to reach 10 billion by 2050&lt;/a&gt;. The challenge, then, becomes how to grow crops without exacerbating water resources.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We have to be smarter about what we grow, and we can be smarter about how we grow what we’re growing,” said Silk. She endorsed some of the interventions proposed by WRI as potential solutions — particularly, paying more attention to soil health (because the more moisture soil can retain, the less water farmers need to add to crops). WRI also recommends shifting diets away from meat, which requires &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/heres-how-much-cropland-could-be-freed-up-if-americans-ate-half-as-much-meat/&quot;&gt;a tremendous amount of land&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/heres-how-much-water-it-takes-to-make-a-serving-of-beef-and-why-where-it-comes-from-is-so-important-208155&quot;&gt;and water&lt;/a&gt; to produce, towards less water-intensive foods.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Silk also mentioned incorporating more nature-based solutions, “green” strategies that attempt to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.undp.org/publications/nature-based-solutions-water&quot;&gt;replicate an ecosystem’s natural rhythms&lt;/a&gt;, as opposed to “gray” interventions that involve humans building new infrastructure. The most effective nature-based solutions for managing water on cropland will vary from place to place, depending on geography as well as what’s being grown. Silk observed that “because water is always on the move,” finding the best management strategies will require taking a step back to see the full picture — for instance, reforestation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wri.org/insights/3-surprising-ways-water-depends-healthy-forests&quot;&gt;can improve water quality and regulate the water cycle&lt;/a&gt; within a landscape. “I think ultimately it becomes a really interesting opportunity for conservationists to meet with farmers and ranchers, to meet with local water regulators and utilities, and also with Indigenous peoples and populations,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Kuzma noted that farmers know better than anyone — and typically before anyone else —&amp;nbsp;about the water challenges they face, and that WRI’s analysis is really meant to communicate those risks to a broader audience. And she recognized that these management shifts and policy recommendations involve asking farmers to “change how they operate,” which usually requires them to shoulder the financial burden of climate adaptation alone. “We also need to be thinking about what type of financial policies and corporate sponsorship we can be providing” to make those shifts possible, she said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Silk agreed. “Sometimes farmers and ranchers are willing to change their practices, but they don’t necessarily have the financial resources to do so,” she said. “So if they’re incentivized to change those practices or somebody else can come in and help them, it makes a big difference.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/water-availability-farmers-crops-food-agriculture/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/water-availability-farmers-crops-food-agriculture/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Frida Garza</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/water-risks.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Heat</category><category>Food and Agriculture</category></item><item><title>In Montana, 911 calls reveal impact of heat waves on rural seniors</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Missoula is one of Montana’s largest cities but is surrounded by rural mountain communities where cattle ranching is king. Despite the latitude and altitude, in recent years this region has experienced punishing summer heat waves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It has been difficult for residents to adapt to the warming climate and new seasonal swings. Many don’t have air conditioning and are unprepared for the new pattern of daytime temperatures hovering in the 90s — for days or even weeks on end. Dehydration, heat exhaustion, heatstroke, and abnormalities in heart rate and blood pressure are among the many health complications that can develop from excessive exposure to high temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It can happen anywhere and to anyone, said Missoula firefighter Andrew Drobeck. He remembers a recent 911 call. The temperature that day had risen to over 90 degrees and a worker at a local dollar store had fainted. “She’s sensitive to the heat. Their AC wasn’t working super good,” Drobeck said. “I guess they only get a 15-minute break.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Drobeck said many of the heat calls his department receives are from seniors who struggle to stay cool inside their older homes. Montana’s population is among the oldest in the country.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dphhs.mt.gov/assets/sltc/AgingReports/MontanaStatePlanonAging.pdf&quot;&gt;About 1 in 4 residents&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;are over 60. Those over 65 are&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/extreme-heat/risk-factors/extreme-heat-and-older-adults-aged-65.html&quot;&gt;especially vulnerable&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to heat-related illness, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. As people age, their bodies don’t acclimate to heat as well as they did when they were younger, including not producing as much sweat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In July, a heat dome that settled over much of the western U.S. baked the region and shattered two types of temperature records: daily highs, and the number of consecutive days over 90 degrees. Although the Northwest, including western Montana, is typically cooler, the region experienced record-breaking heat this summer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Emergency responders like Drobeck have noticed. Drobeck says 911 calls during heat waves have ticked up over the last few summers. But Missoula County officials wanted to know more: They wanted better data on the residents who were calling and the communities that had been hardest hit by the heat. So the county teamed up with researchers at the University of Montana to comb through the data and create a map of 911 calls during heat waves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The team paired call data from 2020 with census data to see who lived in the areas generating high rates of emergency calls when it was hot. The analysis found that for every 1 degree Celsius (1.8 degree Fahrenheit) increase in the average daily temperature, 911 calls increased by 1 percent, according to researcher&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/dr-christina-barsky&quot;&gt;Christina Barsky&lt;/a&gt;, who co-authored&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hazards.colorado.edu/public-health-disaster-research/public-health-implications-of-911-calls-during-heat-and-smoke-events&quot;&gt;the study.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Though that may sound like a small increase, Barsky explained that a 5-degree jump in the daily average temperature can prompt hundreds of additional calls to 911 over the course of a month. Those call loads can be taxing on ambulance crews and local hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Missoula study also found that some of the highest rates of emergency calls during extreme heat events came from rural areas, outside Missoula’s urban core. That shows that rural communities are struggling with heat, even if they get less media attention, Barsky said. “What about those people, right? What about those places that are experiencing heat at a rate that we’ve never been prepared for?” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Barsky’s work showed that communities with more residents over 65 tend to generate more 911 calls during heat waves. That could be one reason so many 911 calls are coming from rural residents in Missoula County: Barsky said people living in Montana’s countryside and its small towns tend to be older and more vulnerable to serious heat-related illness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;And aging in rural communities can pose extra problems during heat waves. Even if it cools off at night, an older person living without air conditioning might not be able to cope with hours of high temperatures inside their home during the day. It’s not uncommon for rural residents to have to drive an hour or more to reach a library that might have air conditioning, a community center with a cooling-off room, or medical care. Such isolation and scattered resources are not unique to Montana. “I grew up in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan,” Barsky said. “There are no air-conditioned spaces in at least 50 miles. The hospital is 100 miles away.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Heat research like the Missoula study has focused mostly on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kingcounty.gov/en/legacy/elected/executive/constantine/news/release/2021/june/23-heat-mapping-results&quot;&gt;large cities&lt;/a&gt;, which are often hotter than outlying areas, due to the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/heatislands&quot;&gt;heat island&lt;/a&gt;” effect. This phenomenon explains why cities tend to get hotter during the day and cool off less at night: It’s because pavement, buildings, and other structures absorb and retain heat. Urban residents may experience higher temperatures during the day and get less relief at night.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;By contrast, researchers are only just beginning to investigate and understand the impacts of heat waves in rural areas. The impacts of extreme heat on rural communities have largely been ignored, said&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uvm.edu/cems/cee/profiles/elizabeth-m-b-doran&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Doran&lt;/a&gt;, an environmental engineering professor at the University of Vermont. Doran is leading an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uvm.edu/news/cems/cee/noaa-funds-uvm-extreme-heat-project&quot;&gt;ongoing study&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Vermont that is revealing that towns as small as 5,000 people can stay hotter at night than surrounding rural areas due to heat radiating off hot pavement. “If we as a society are only focused on large urban centers, we’re missing a huge portion of the population and our strategies are going to be limiting in how effective they can be,” Doran said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Brock Slabach, with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruralhealth.us/&quot;&gt;National Rural Health Association&lt;/a&gt;, agrees that rural residents desperately need help adapting to extreme heat. They need support installing air conditioning or getting to air-conditioned places to cool off during the day. Many rural residents have mobility issues or don’t drive much due to age or disability. And because they often have to travel farther to access health care services, extra delays in care during a heat-related emergency could lead to more severe health outcomes. “It’s not unreasonable at all to suggest that people will be harmed from not having access to those kinds of services,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Helping rural populations adapt will be a challenge. People in rural places need help where they live, inside their homes, said&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.missoulacounty.us/Home/Components/StaffDirectory/StaffDirectory/3522/&quot;&gt;Adriane Beck&lt;/a&gt;, director of Missoula County’s Office of Emergency Management. Starting a cooling center in a small community may help people living in town, but it’s unrealistic to expect people to drive an hour or more to cool off. Beck said the Missoula County Disaster and Emergency Services Department plans to use data from the 911 study to better understand why people are calling in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the coming years, the department plans to talk directly with people living in rural communities about what they need to adapt to rising temperatures. “It might be as simple as knocking on their door and saying, ‘Would you benefit from an air conditioner? How can we connect you with resources to make that happen?’” Beck said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But that won’t be possible for every rural household because there simply isn’t enough money at the county and state level to pay for that many air-conditioning units, Missoula County officials said. That’s why the county wants to plan ahead for heat waves and have specific protocols for contacting and assisting vulnerable rural residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Ideally, we’d be in a situation where maybe we have community paramedics that can be deployed into those areas when we know that these events are going to happen so they can check on them and avoid that hospital admission,” Beck explained. She added that preventing heat-related hospitalizations among rural residents can ultimately save lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is from a partnership that includes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mtpr.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;MTPR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://npr.org/shots&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://kffhealthnews.org/news/article/montana-west-heat-waves-rural-seniors-air-conditioning-911&quot;&gt;KFF Health News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;a national newsroom that produces in-depth journalism about health issues.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kffhealthnews.org/morning-briefing/&quot;&gt;Subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to KFF Health News’ free Morning Briefing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat/in-montana-911-calls-reveal-impact-of-heat-waves-on-rural-seniors/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-heat/in-montana-911-calls-reveal-impact-of-heat-waves-on-rural-seniors/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Aaron Bolton, MTPR</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/ElderlyHeat.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Heat</category><category>Health</category></item><item><title>An unlikely line of defense during heat waves: Food banks</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On a Tuesday morning in mid-August, Mary Hynes was blasting her air conditioning. Hynes has walking problems, and she said she’s passed out “a couple of times” in the past. The issue went away after having her pacemaker adjusted, but it was enough to make her nervous about leaving her apartment in the Chelsea neighborhood of Manhattan. And then New York experienced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnewyork.com/weather/nyc-forecast-heat-wave-again/5594504/&quot;&gt;a particularly hot summer&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/newyork/news/nyc-3rd-heat-wave-weather-forecast/&quot;&gt;multiple heat waves&lt;/a&gt;, making her even less likely to go outside.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Thank God for these guys,” she said, referring to the volunteer dropping off her weekly meals. Hynes is one of more than 20,000 New Yorkers 60 and older who receive meal deliveries from Citymeals on Wheels, a nonprofit organization founded in 1981 to fill the gaps in the city’s public meal assistance program for older, homebound New Yorkers. Her experience is an example of how, during heat emergencies, food assistance can provide a lifeline to vulnerable communities. “I didn’t think they were going to do deliveries because of the heat” at one point this summer, she said, “and I would’ve understood.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For older adults living with disabilities or mobility issues, heat can compound the challenges of getting outside, getting groceries, and cooking for oneself. By delivering meals during bouts of extreme weather, including heat waves, food distribution organizations like Citymeals serve as a line of defense against the worst of climate impacts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Emergencies have become a sweet spot for us,” said Beth Shapiro, the CEO of Citymeals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;New York City’s Department for the Aging facilitates home-delivered meals for older New Yorkers who aren’t able to prepare their own meals, but only on weekdays. “The city funds meals Monday through Friday, and our founder believed that people should eat every day of the week, as we still do,” said Shapiro. In addition to weekend and holiday service, Citymeals, which partners with 30 senior centers in all five boroughs of New York City, also delivers food to older adults during localized emergencies. To qualify for Citymeals, recipients must be 60 or older and have a physical or mental health condition that prevents them from shopping for food or cooking regularly for themselves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Citymeals volunteers and staff have delivered meals during major disasters — for example, 2012’s Hurricane Sandy, which flooded lower Manhattan, damaged buildings, and left hundreds of thousands without power. But extreme heat acts on vulnerable populations in ways that are more subtle, but just as dangerous. For adults 65 and older, living with certain illnesses, or taking certain medications, may &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/extreme-heat/risk-factors/extreme-heat-and-older-adults-aged-65.html&quot;&gt;impact the body’s ability to tolerate increases in temperature&lt;/a&gt;. Older adults with cardiovascular problems and other illnesses that can cause weakness are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nia.nih.gov/health/safety/hot-weather-safety-older-adults&quot;&gt;more susceptible to heat-related illness&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, the social isolation that many older adults experience can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8583294/&quot;&gt;become life-threatening during a heat wave&lt;/a&gt;. Home meal deliveries are one way to check in on older folks during heat emergencies — and as climate change makes summers hotter and hotter, the need for such high-touch services is growing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“One of the things we talk about during heat events is checking on your neighbor,” said Heidi Brown, professor and program director of epidemiology at the University of Arizona’s college of public health. Volunteers bringing food to homebound people can help to break up the social isolation that they face. For example, volunteers can observe how a meal recipient appears on a hot day, check for signs of heat-related illness, and ask if they have enough water or any trouble cooling their home. (Citymeals instructs volunteers who observe serious problems to contact the meal recipient’s case manager.) Checking in may not be the explicit “mandate” of meal on wheels organizations, said Brown, “but that is a piece of what they’re doing. They’re bringing resources, making sure that that person is OK. And if not, reaching out and getting them to medical resources, getting them to a cooling station, or making sure they know where cooling stations are.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/a-crisis-of-isolation-is-making-heat-waves-more-deadly/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of older man sitting beside empty chair within bright orange circle&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/0808_HeatIsolation.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/a-crisis-of-isolation-is-making-heat-waves-more-deadly/&quot;&gt;A crisis of isolation is making heat waves more deadly&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/akielly-hu/&quot;&gt;Akielly Hu&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The volunteer serving Hynes’ building said one thing he might pay attention to is whether a meal recipient has AC running or not. Even during a heat wave, it isn’t a given: Citymeals recently partnered with the City University of New York’s Urban Food Policy Institute to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citymeals.org/sites/default/files/inline-files/Citymeals%20on%20Wheels_Aging%20Without%20Hunger_2024.pdf&quot;&gt;survey recipients of meal assistance services for older adults&lt;/a&gt;, including Citymeals. Almost half of the respondents reported experiencing food insecurity in the last 12 months, and over 60 percent were living on less than $15,000 a year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“If I’m living on that, am I able to buy food, pay for medicine, turn on an air conditioner if I have it?” said Shapiro.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In addition to exacerbating financial burdens, extreme heat can complicate mobility issues for older people facing hunger. “Which makes sense,” said Michael Flood, the president and CEO of the Los Angeles Regional Food Bank. “None of us want to go out when it’s 98 degrees.” Across California, the heat in July shattered records and became &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2024-08-08/record-heat-in-july&quot;&gt;the state’s hottest month on record&lt;/a&gt;. For Los Angeles, the most brutal heat of the summer is yet to come: This week, Southern California is expecting its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2024-09-03/the-hottest-temperatures-of-the-summer-are-coming-to-socal-this-week-how-hot-will-it-be-where-you-are&quot;&gt;longest and hottest heat wave of the summer&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic made the Southern California food bank more aware of how public health crises impact older adults’ mobility and ability to access food distribution hubs. Now, the organization &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lafoodbank.org/programs/commodity-supplemental-food-program/&quot;&gt;delivers groceries&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fns.usda.gov/csfp/commodity-supplemental-food-program&quot;&gt;low-income people 60 or older&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Citymeals-heat-delivery.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A man in a purple shirt stands in front of a van with its doors open, revealing a shelf of bread&quot; data-caption=&quot;A meal deliverer for one of Citymeals&#39; partner agencies gets ready to deliver meals to recipients&#39; homes.&quot; data-credit=&quot;Citymeals on Wheels&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A meal deliverer for one of Citymeals’ partner agencies gets ready to deliver meals to recipients’ homes. &lt;cite&gt;Citymeals on Wheels&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Older adults aren’t the only population who experience heightened need for food banks and meal delivery services during extreme weather events. Unhoused people and families with children may also come to rely on food assistance programs more when there is a heat wave.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Silver Lake Community Church in L.A. has a food pantry program that was designed with the needs of homeless folks in mind. When it’s really hot outside, unhoused people may decide not to come to the church for food assistance, said office administrator Stephanie Young. But volunteers will also pick up folks from wherever they’re staying and bring them to the church for programming, whether that’s the food pantry or the church’s shower program.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Homeless individuals who attend a free breakfast program at the St. Francis Center in downtown L.A.&amp;nbsp; might stay and chat with other community members on particularly hot days, enjoying the center’s AC, according to programs director Cesar Argueta.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The summer also presents a twofold challenge for food-insecure families, especially those with children. “We see hunger spike a lot in the summer,” said Celia Cole, the CEO of Feeding Texas, a nonprofit dedicated to fighting hunger in the country’s second-largest state by population, “because what happens is those kids get out of school where they would have access to free breakfast and free lunch.” During the COVID-19 pandemic, Congress &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2022/jun/04/us-school-hunger-crisis-federal-waivers-end&quot;&gt;granted waivers that expanded schools’ and community groups’ ability to offer free meals&lt;/a&gt; to young people during the summer months, but those waivers expired in 2022. There are currently no sites in Texas offering free meals and snacks to children via the U.S. Agriculture Department’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fns.usda.gov/summer/sunmeals&quot;&gt;Summer Food Service Program&lt;/a&gt;, according to the latest data listed on the program’s website.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“At the same time,” Cole added, “people’s utility bills are soaring,” which reduces the income they have available for groceries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/farmworker-hunger-crisis-climate-inflation-grocery-costs/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Collage of farmworkers carrying produce, snippets of a dollar bill, and tomatoes —&amp;nbsp;all centered around an empty dinner plate&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/farmworker-hunger.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/farmworker-hunger-crisis-climate-inflation-grocery-costs/&quot;&gt;The people who feed America are going hungry&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/ayurella-horn-muller/&quot;&gt;Ayurella Horn-Muller&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Cole pointed out that there can be many barriers to food access —&amp;nbsp;for example, many people don’t apply for food stamps because they don’t realize they’re eligible, or because they may feel a sense of stigma around accepting government benefits.&amp;nbsp;However, Cole said the root cause of hunger is most often wealth inequality and the high cost of living. “Getting people connected to all the benefits they’re eligible for is the first step in dealing with the food part of the problem,” she said. “But at the end of the day, the underlying problem is the money problem.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In practice, disability, financial need, and climate impacts can all strike unexpectedly or all at once —&amp;nbsp;and they can all make it harder for people to get the nutrition they need. Rubem Dasilva, a New Yorker who started receiving deliveries from Citymeals during the pandemic, said the service has helped him a lot. The 79-year-old, who lives not far from the theater district in Manhattan, has trouble affording groceries. And he avoids the matinee crowds on Wednesdays and Sundays for fear of getting jostled by pedestrians, making it harder to go to the grocery store. “I’ve been bumped like three or four times,” he said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;So the food program has been a lifesaver. “The meals are just great,” he said. “I am so grateful.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For Dasilva, his mobility concerns do not prevent him from attempting to live life to the fullest. “I am very adventurous,” he said. “When the weather is great, I go to Central Park. I take my favorite form of travel, which is the Staten Island Ferry.” But even he has his limits. “When it’s too hot outside? I stay home.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat/an-unlikely-first-line-of-defense-during-heatwaves-food-banks/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-heat/an-unlikely-first-line-of-defense-during-heatwaves-food-banks/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Frida Garza</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/GettyImages-1229897645.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Heat</category><category>Food and Agriculture</category><category>Solutions</category></item><item><title>As climate change worsens, deadly prison heat is increasingly an everywhere problem</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On June 19, Michael Broadway struggled to breathe inside his cell at Stateville Correctional Center, a dilapidated Illinois state prison about 40 miles southwest of Chicago.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Outside, temperatures hovered in the 90s, with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/video/investigation-continues-after-man-dies-in-idoc-custody-exmpzn/&quot;&gt;heat index&lt;/a&gt; — what the temperature feels like — of nearly 100. Just days earlier, a punishing heat wave had brought a string of days topping out in the mid-90s. With no air conditioning or ventilation, Broadway’s unit on the fifth floor of the prison had become a furnace.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We live on the highest gallery in the cellhouse,” Mark, who lived next door to Broadway, told The Appeal over the prison’s messaging service. “It never cools off. Personal fans blow hot air. You have to sit still. Move and you are sweaty.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;(We are using an alias to protect Mark from retaliation.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Mark and others on Broadway’s cellblock &lt;a href=&quot;https://truthout.org/articles/i-watched-my-neighbor-die-a-preventable-death-due-to-scorching-heat-in-prison/&quot;&gt;yelled for help&lt;/a&gt;, but a nurse didn’t come until more than 15 minutes later, according to a statement Broadway’s neighbor, Anthony Ehlers, provided to the law firm representing Broadway’s family.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=724&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Michael_60534A98-61EF-4829-9B87-179524310929_1_105_c.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A smiling man with a gray beard wears a green cap and gown, and sits next to other graduates.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Michael Broadway in his graduation regalia.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Photo courtesy of Monika Wnuk&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Michael Broadway in his graduation regalia.
 &lt;cite&gt;Photo courtesy of Monika Wnuk&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s too hot,” the nurse said, according to Ehlers. “I’m not going up there. Tell him to come down here.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Broadway was “holding his neck, gasping for breath,” said Ehlers. An officer radioed that Broadway couldn’t walk. By the time the nurse entered his cell, he had already lost consciousness, said Ehlers. She administered Narcan, and officers began chest compressions. Ehlers yelled out repeatedly that Broadway had asthma and did not use drugs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The stretcher was broken, so Mark used his bed sheet to carry Broadway down five flights of stairs with the assistance of three staff members. Broadway was taken to a nearby hospital, where he was pronounced dead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At the time of his death, Broadway was 51 years old. While incarcerated, he battled cancer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/ONE-FOOT-Michael-Broadway/dp/B0CH2D7PTJ&quot;&gt;wrote a novel&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2023/11/northwestern-prison-education-program-students-first-incarcerated-people-to-graduate-from-a-top-10-university/&quot;&gt;earned his undergraduate degree&lt;/a&gt; from Northwestern University. An IDOC spokesperson said in an email that an investigation is ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Mike was really special and he deserved better than to die from something so easily avoidable,” Ehlers wrote to The Appeal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As summers get hotter, conditions are becoming increasingly dangerous for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prisonpolicy.org/reports/pie2024.html&quot;&gt;more than 1 million people locked up in state prisons&lt;/a&gt;, most of which do not have universal air conditioning. Even prisons in some of the hottest states, like Louisiana, Texas, and Georgia, are only partially air-conditioned, according to a survey of state corrections agencies conducted by The Appeal. For the six states that did not respond to the survey — Florida, Tennessee, Michigan, Nevada, Kansas, and West Virginia — we gathered information from news reports, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kansascity.com/news/local/article264192226.html&quot;&gt;local reporting&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2022/09/12/prisons-air-conditioning-climate-change-heat-waves/10158499002/?gnt-cfr=1&amp;amp;gca-cat=p&quot;&gt;USA Today analysis&lt;/a&gt; of prison air conditioning published in 2022.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to our investigation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just over 80 percent of federal prisons have universal air conditioning.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Only five states provide air conditioning in all prison housing units.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;In 22 states, most people are housed in air-conditioned units, which means more than 50 percent of state prisoners live in air-conditioned housing units;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;In 17 states, some prison housing units are air-conditioned across multiple facilities.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;In five states, few housing units are air-conditioned — only a single facility and/or specialized units, like infirmaries, are cooled.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Only one state, Alaska, has no air-conditioned housing units.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed flourish-map&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/19112110&quot;&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/visualisation/19112110/thumbnail&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;map visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Research has found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prisonpolicy.org/blog/2023/07/19/climate_change/&quot;&gt;higher temperatures&lt;/a&gt; — and especially prolonged periods of extreme heat — are &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0281389&quot;&gt;associated with higher death rates&lt;/a&gt; in prison. Despite the correlation between heat and mortality, the exact number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/09/california-heat-wave-prison-inmate-death&quot;&gt;heat-related deaths&lt;/a&gt; remains unknown, as many prisons do not properly track or report them, prompting concern from advocates that officials are effectively &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kut.org/crime-justice/2024-07-29/investigation-texas-prison-heat-inmate-deaths-ac-autopsy-lawsuit&quot;&gt;hiding these fatalities&lt;/a&gt; behind other causes of death.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In one &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sacbee.com/news/california/article289867299.html&quot;&gt;high-profile case in California&lt;/a&gt; this July, Adrienne “Twin” Boulware died after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/jul/09/california-heat-wave-prison-inmate-death&quot;&gt;collapsing at the Central California Women’s Facility&lt;/a&gt; during &lt;a href=&quot;https://weather.com/weather/monthly/l/6bfc89209291354ff67cd54c1da76f3e845eadd7d3cd723b37d5730828282391&quot;&gt;a heat wave&lt;/a&gt;, according to advocates. Boulware’s family has said prison staff told them she died from heat stroke, but a spokesperson for the state corrections agency said in an email that Boulware’s cause of death “appears to be an ongoing medical condition and not heat related.” The county coroner’s office will make the final determination, the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For years, incarcerated people and advocates have demanded &lt;a href=&quot;https://theappeal.org/heat-prison-deaths-air-conditioning/&quot;&gt;universal air conditioning and increased access to ice, cold water, and showers&lt;/a&gt; to help protect against the heat. But many prison systems continue to deny prisoners even the most basic accommodations, while lawmakers have offered, at most, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/04/22/texas-prisons-inmates-air-conditioning-lawsuit/73419881007/&quot;&gt;piecemeal investments&lt;/a&gt; in AC installation. Incarcerated people often rely on small, personal fans to provide some degree of comfort, but previous &lt;a href=&quot;https://theappeal.org/locked-in-priced-out-how-much-prison-commissary-prices/&quot;&gt;reporting by The Appeal&lt;/a&gt; has revealed that these devices can be too expensive for many to afford, especially on paltry wages — if they’re paid at all.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Without a radical departure from the status quo, the human-made crises of climate change and mass incarceration are on a collision course that will put more and more prisoners’ lives at risk. As extreme temperatures sweep across the country, the problem is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/weather/2021/06/18/heat-dome-western-us-temperatures/&quot;&gt;expanding&lt;/a&gt; beyond historic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/09/texas-heat-prisons-lawsuit&quot;&gt;hotbeds in the South and Southwest&lt;/a&gt;, bringing more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/21/us/heat-wave-forecast-washington-oregon-idaho.html&quot;&gt;intense and frequent heat waves&lt;/a&gt; to states with &lt;a href=&quot;https://stateline.org/2023/08/14/stifling-prison-heat-used-to-be-just-a-southern-problem-not-anymore/&quot;&gt;traditionally milder climates&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Heat waves this summer have hit much of the country, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/record-breaking-heat-blankets-west-end-sight/story?id=111777019&quot;&gt;Washington State&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.syracuse.com/weather/2024/06/unprecedented-heat-wave-in-upstate-ny-will-ease-today-but-not-much.html&quot;&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/boston/news/when-will-the-heat-wave-end-boston-massachusetts/&quot;&gt;Massachusetts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vermontpublic.org/local-news/2024-06-26/last-weeks-heat-wave-saw-a-spike-in-emergency-room-visits&quot;&gt;Vermont&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stateimpact.npr.org/pennsylvania/2024/07/18/pa-heat-advisories-are-outpacing-the-average-rate-this-summer-climate-change-plays-a-role/&quot;&gt;Pennsylvania&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nj.com/weather/2024/06/nj-weather-newark-hits-100-as-brutal-heat-wave-continues-to-sizzle.html&quot;&gt;New Jersey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipmnewsroom.org/heat-wave-over-central-illinois-to-peak-this-weekend/&quot;&gt;Illinois&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wmur.com/article/new-hampshire-heat-waves-records-history/61648520&quot;&gt;New Hampshire&lt;/a&gt;, all states that lack universal air conditioning in their prisons, according to our survey. Research suggests extreme heat can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0281389&quot;&gt;particularly dangerous&lt;/a&gt; for people who are not acclimated to such high temperatures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/equity/corcoran-prison-levee-climate-flood-justice/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 2000w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/HARM-header-no-title-min.png?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1125&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/equity/corcoran-prison-levee-climate-flood-justice/&quot;&gt;In California, climate chaos looms over prisons — and thousands of prisoners — in a lake bed&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/susie-cagle/&quot;&gt;Susie Cagle&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In New York, most of the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prisonpolicy.org/graphs/correctional_control2023/NY_incarceration_2023.html&quot;&gt;approximately 30,000 prisoners&lt;/a&gt; are confined to housing units without air conditioning. This summer, the heat index &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/NYSDHSES/status/1802678139891429603?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1802678139891429603%7Ctwgr%5E8372fa8f8499da1524ce702735115e2506e64ae2%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.lohud.com%2Fstory%2Fnews%2Flocal%2F2024%2F06%2F17%2Fhudson-valley-ny-heat-wave-on-the-way-what-to-expect-what-to-do%2F74121964007%2F&quot;&gt;hovered around 100 degrees&lt;/a&gt; for several days back-to-back in areas where some state prisons are located. In New Hampshire, only one of the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.corrections.nh.gov/locations&quot;&gt;three prisons&lt;/a&gt;, the New Hampshire Correctional Facility for Women, has air conditioning. Temperatures in Concord, where the New Hampshire State Prison for Men is located, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wmur.com/article/new-hampshire-heat-waves-records-history/61648520#:~:text=WMUR-,Rochester%20saw%20a%20whopping%2015%20days%20in%20a%20row%20where,back%20of%2090%2Ddegree%20heat.&quot;&gt;broke records in July&lt;/a&gt; with 12 consecutive days that reached 90 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In New Jersey, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/03/nyregion/new-jersey-warming-climate-change.html&quot;&gt;third-fastest warming U.S. state&lt;/a&gt; and the fastest in the Northeast, about 65 percent of housing units are air-conditioned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Marsha’s son is incarcerated at Bayside State Prison, where most housing units are not air-conditioned. The prison is “suffocatingly hot,” she said. (We are using an alias for Marsha to protect her son from retaliation.) Last month, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accuweather.com/en/us/leesburg/08327/july-weather/2192000?year=2024&quot;&gt;temperatures&lt;/a&gt; around Bayside hit the 90s on nine separate days. Marsha’s son told her they receive ice twice daily, but it “melts right away,” she said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;To combat the heat, Marsha said her son bought a couple of fans from the commissary; one was sold at a discounted price. According to a state prison &lt;a href=&quot;https://theappeal.org/commissary-database/&quot;&gt;commissary list&lt;/a&gt; obtained by The Appeal last year, a 9-inch fan costs about $16.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A Department of Corrections spokesperson said in an email that people assigned to housing units without air conditioning may purchase one fan and one 28-quart cooler at a discounted price if they have not previously been provided one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Like much of the Northeast, Vermont is heating up at a troubling pace, making it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.climatecentral.org/climate-matters/earth-day-fastest-warming-cities&quot;&gt;one of the fastest-warming states&lt;/a&gt; in the country, according to the research group Climate Central.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/indigenous/tribal-jail-climate-change-extreme-heat/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;a collage with heat graphs, chain link fence, and a police car photo&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Grist_Hero.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/indigenous/tribal-jail-climate-change-extreme-heat/&quot;&gt;Extreme heat will take an unequal toll on tribal jails&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/joseph-lee/&quot;&gt;Joseph Lee&lt;/a&gt;,      &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/jessie-blaeser/&quot;&gt;Jessie Blaeser&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;amp;       &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/chad-small/&quot;&gt;Chad Small&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In June, the Vermont State Employees’ Association &lt;a href=&quot;https://vtdigger.org/2024/07/01/employees-union-files-workforce-safety-complaint-over-excessive-heat-at-springfield-prison/&quot;&gt;filed a complaint with the state&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of members who work at Southern State Correctional Facility. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25051679-sscf-vsea-complaint-redacted-1?responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1&quot;&gt;complaint&lt;/a&gt;, an officer had developed heat stroke while he was working in the prison’s infirmary. Although this is the only unit in the facility with air conditioning, the complaint alleges it was not working properly at the time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A spokesperson for the Vermont DOC told The Appeal in an email that Southern State is the next prison slated to receive universal air conditioning, a project that is set to be completed by 2027. Earlier this year, lawmakers approved funding for a fraction of what it will likely cost to install air conditioning in all of the state’s prisons, according to local news outlet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vermontpublic.org/local-news/2024-07-02/state-employees-union-files-safety-complaint-hot-conditions-southern-state-correctional-facility-springfield&quot;&gt;Vermont Public&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The State is actively working to install HVAC across all correctional facilities,” a Vermont DOC spokesperson said in an email. “Investing in the physical infrastructure of our facilities, to include installing air conditioning, is a considerable priority for the Department to ensure a dignified and comfortable experience for those who live and work in Vermont correctional facilities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Only two out of Vermont’s six prisons are fully air-conditioned, which amounts to 29 percent of the state’s housing units, according to the DOC. The DOC spokesperson said that depending on the facility, staff may distribute free ice twice a day, place fans in common areas, use water misters, distribute popsicles, or set up water and shade stations in the yard. Prisoners can purchase a 6-inch desk fan for about $13 and an 8-inch fan for $42, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lowes.com/pd/Utilitech-8-in-3-Speed-Indoor-Desk-Fan/5013827613?cm_mmc=shp-_-c-_-prd-_-app-_-ggl-_-LIA_APP_235_Seasonal-_-5013827613-_-local-_-0-_-0&amp;amp;ds_rl=1286890&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwoJa2BhBPEiwA0l0ImB1XYeMmcW2V09ec18kyomSxXJ90V5s1ccvFKke30iK93EWEXnq3wBoCk_cQAvD_BwE&amp;amp;gclsrc=aw.ds&quot;&gt;almost twice as much&lt;/a&gt; as it costs at a local Lowe’s.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Prisoners’ rights advocate Timothy Burgess said he’s received reports from inside Southern State about the excessive heat.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“People are cooking,” said Burgess, who is executive director of the Vermont chapter of Citizens United for the Rehabilitation of Errants, an advocacy group known as CURE. “This summer, like last summer, is absolutely brutal.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/texas-inmates-are-being-cooked-to-death-in-extreme-heat-complaint-alleges/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A long corridor of dry grass between metal fences, as seen through a metal fence.&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1550w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?resize=1200%2C804&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?resize=330%2C221&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?resize=768%2C514&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?resize=1536%2C1029&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/TelfordPrison.webp?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1038&quot; width=&quot;1550&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/texas-inmates-are-being-cooked-to-death-in-extreme-heat-complaint-alleges/&quot;&gt;Texas inmates are being ‘cooked to death’ in extreme heat, complaint alleges&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/pooja-salhotra-the-texas-tribune/&quot;&gt;Pooja Salhotra, The Texas Tribune&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;       &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/william-melhado-texas-tribune/&quot;&gt;William Melhado, The Texas Tribune&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Prisoners are often denied the most basic protections from the heat when they’re taken outside, like shade, water misters, and cold water. The stakes are particularly high for prisoners in the South and Southwest, where climate change is threatening to make notoriously blistering summers even more dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Richard, who’s incarcerated in Arizona’s Lewis Complex, said there’s little shade in the recreation yard, and jugs of provided ice water are finished quickly. (We are only using Richard’s first name to protect him from retaliation.) According to the state Department of Corrections’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25057290-adcrr-facilities-hvac-conversion-plan-2024-r7-1-24?responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1&quot;&gt;HVAC Conversion Plan&lt;/a&gt;, air conditioning has been installed in five of the prison’s units, but installation in the remaining three is on hold pending funding. Richard says many prisoners rely on small, personal fans, which they can &lt;a href=&quot;https://theappeal.org/commissary-database/&quot;&gt;purchase from the commissary&lt;/a&gt; for about $23.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Temperatures around Lewis have reached &lt;a href=&quot;https://weather.com/weather/monthly/l/Buckeye+AZ+85326:4:US&quot;&gt;at least 100 degrees&lt;/a&gt; every day since the end of May. The unrelenting heat takes a toll on people’s physical and mental health, said Richard.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We’ve had several people fall out, pass out in the chow hall, which has no fans or ventilation of any sort,” he said. “I personally have seen probably about five or six people pass out from heat exhaustion or heat stroke.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Heat stroke &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2023/07/23/1189506023/heres-what-happens-to-the-body-in-extreme-temperatures-and-how-heat-becomes-dead&quot;&gt;can be deadly&lt;/a&gt;. Last July in Georgia, 27-year-old Juan Carlos Ramirez Bibiano died after being left outside in a cage at Telfair State Prison for approximately five hours without water, ice, or shade, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25051680-2024-07-22-de-001-complaint-1?responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; filed by his family. A spokesperson for the Georgia Department of Corrections said in an email that the agency does not comment on pending litigation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On the day of Ramirez’s death, the heat index — what the temperature feels like accounting for humidity — had reached over 105 degrees. That morning, the warden warned staff about the dangerous temperatures and told them not to keep anyone on the recreation yard for extended periods, according to the complaint.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/equity/new-study-people-dying-extreme-heat-in-prisons-us/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A view down a prison corridor, showing bars and cell doors.&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1598w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?resize=1200%2C676&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?resize=768%2C433&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?resize=1536%2C865&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Prison-heat.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1598&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/equity/new-study-people-dying-extreme-heat-in-prisons-us/&quot;&gt;Study: Extreme heat is driving deaths in US prisons&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/alleen-brown/&quot;&gt;Alleen Brown&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At about 3:00 pm, security staff called for medical help. When the nurses arrived, Ramirez was lying naked on the concrete and had vomited and defecated. He was taken to the hospital, where he was found to have a body temperature of 107 degrees. DOC reported that Ramirez died of “natural causes,” according to the family’s legal team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Louisiana, prisoners are engaged in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://theappeal.org/angola-prison-farm-line-ruling-louisiana/&quot;&gt;legal battle&lt;/a&gt; to temporarily halt work on the “Farm Line” when the heat index exceeds 88 degrees. In a July ruling, a federal judge stopped short of shutting down the program but ordered corrections officials to make changes to their heat-related policies. In response, the DOC told the court they now offer workers sunscreen, access to a pop-up tent to provide shade on breaks, and other protective measures. On Aug. 15, the judge &lt;a href=&quot;https://thelensnola.org/2024/08/16/grossly-insufficient-judge-blasts-doc-suggested-fixes-to-ongoing-conditions-for-angolas-farm-line/&quot;&gt;lambasted the agency’s actions&lt;/a&gt; as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25078712-govuscourtslamd635001090_1?responsive=1&amp;amp;title=1&quot;&gt;grossly insufficient&lt;/a&gt;.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Few protections exist for incarcerated people who are often forced to toil in extreme heat. This month, the U.S. Department of Labor has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/osha/osha20240702&quot;&gt;proposed a rule&lt;/a&gt; that would require employers to implement certain protections for people working in high temperatures. An agency spokesperson said in an email that the rule does not “explicitly mention incarcerated laborers” and that “as a general rule, prisoners are not regarded as employees under federal labor and employment laws.” The spokesperson said the proposed rule would soon be available for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osha.gov/laws-regs/rulemakingprocess#v-nav-tab2&quot;&gt;public comment&lt;/a&gt; and encouraged “people with serious concerns” to “participate in the rule-making process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;If the rule is adopted, individual states may choose to include incarcerated workers, according to the spokesperson. But there is little reason to believe they would. In California, the state’s safety board &lt;a href=&quot;https://calmatters.org/california-divide/2024/06/extreme-heat-california-workplace-rules/&quot;&gt;explicitly excluded &lt;/a&gt;prisons and jails from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nelp.org/california-finally-approved-indoor-heat-rules-why-were-prison-workers-excluded/&quot;&gt;newly approved heat-related protections&lt;/a&gt; for people who work indoors, meaning both incarcerated laborers and prison staff are not covered. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;With the onset of climate change, outdoor conditions are also becoming harsher for incarcerated people in other parts of the country. A woman incarcerated in a Pennsylvania prison wrote to The Appeal that during yard time, they have “to take our water bottles outside,” leaving them to drink “hot-as-piss water.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;From Stateville prison in Illinois, Ehlers said there is no shade when they go out for recreation, and they’re not provided sunscreen. He said staff give prisoners a “small water cooler full of ice water, but it’s gone pretty quickly.” During the summer, Ehlers usually opts to skip recreation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“You’re stuck out there,” he wrote. “I’ve seen plenty of guys go down with heat stroke on the yard.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Whether inside or outside, Ehlers said incarcerated people are given little protection against the heat.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The earth is getting hotter, and IDOC, and corrections, in general, is not adjusting, not doing anything to make sure that prisoners are safe,” he wrote. “We don’t have the ability to take care of ourselves, if we could, we would. We have to depend on the prison staff to take care of us, and they don’t care.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat/as-climate-change-worsens-deadly-prison-heat-is-increasingly-an-everywhere-problem/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-heat/as-climate-change-worsens-deadly-prison-heat-is-increasingly-an-everywhere-problem/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Elizabeth Weill-Greenberg, The Appeal</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/PrisonHallway.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Heat</category></item><item><title>Extreme weather 101: Your guide to staying prepared and informed</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;No matter where you live, extreme weather can hit your area, causing damage to homes, power outages, and dangerous or deadly conditions. If you’re on the coast, it &lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/hurricanes/&quot;&gt;may be a hurricane&lt;/a&gt;; in the Midwest or South, &lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/tornadoes/&quot;&gt;a tornado&lt;/a&gt;; in the West, &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.fema.gov/ProtectiveActions/s/article/Wildfire&quot;&gt;wildfires&lt;/a&gt;; and as we’ve seen in recent years, anywhere can experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/excessive-heat/&quot;&gt;heat waves&lt;/a&gt; or flash &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.fema.gov/ProtectiveActions/s/article/Flood&quot;&gt;flooding&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Living through a disaster and its aftermath can be both traumatic and chaotic, from the immediate losses of life and belongings to conflicting information around where to access aid. The weeks and months after may be even more difficult, as the attention on your community is gone but civic services and events have stalled or changed drastically.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Grist compiled this resource guide to help you stay prepared and informed. It looks at everything from how to find the most accurate forecasts to signing up for emergency alerts to the roles that different agencies play in disaster aid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wp-block-button__link wp-element-button&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/#h-where-to-find-the-facts-on-disasters-nbsp&quot;&gt;STAYING INFORMED &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wp-block-button__link wp-element-button&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/#h-how-to-pack-an-emergency-kit&quot;&gt;EMERGENCY KIT &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wp-block-button__link wp-element-button&quot;&gt;DISASTER AID &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wp-block-button__link wp-element-button&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/#h-fema&quot;&gt;FEMA &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wp-block-button__link wp-element-button&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/#h-what-to-expect-after-a-disaster&quot;&gt;POST-DISASTER &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-button&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;wp-block-button__link wp-element-button&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/#h-what-to-keep-in-mind-before-during-and-after-a-disaster&quot;&gt;WHAT NOT TO FORGET&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1246133174_cropped_Merced-California-flooding-bomb-cyclone.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;An aerial view shows flooding in Merced, California following a “bomb cyclone” in January 2023.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Josh Edelson / AFP via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;An aerial view shows flooding in Merced, California following a “bomb cyclone” in January 2023.
 &lt;cite&gt;Josh Edelson / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-where-to-find-the-facts-on-disasters-nbsp&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where to find the facts on disasters&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;These days, many people find out about disasters in their area via social media. But it’s important to make sure the information you’re receiving is accurate. Here’s where to find the facts on extreme weather and the most reliable places to check for emergency alerts and updates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your local emergency manager: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Your city or county will have an emergency management department, which is part of the local government. In larger cities, it’s often a separate agency; in smaller communities, fire chiefs or sheriff’s offices may manage emergency response and alerts. Emergency managers are responsible for communicating with the public about disasters, managing rescue and response efforts, and coordinating between different agencies. They usually have an SMS-based emergency alert system, so sign up for those via your local website (Note: Some cities have multiple languages available, but most emergency alerts are only in English.) Many emergency management agencies are active on Facebook, so check there for updates as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local news: &lt;/strong&gt;The local television news and social media accounts from verified news sources will have live updates during and after a storm. Follow your local newspaper and television station on Facebook or other social media, or check their websites regularly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather stations and apps: &lt;/strong&gt;The Weather Channel, Apple Weather, and Google will have information on major storms, but that may not be the case for smaller-scale weather events, and you shouldn’t rely on these apps to tell you if you need to evacuate or move to higher ground.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Weather Service: &lt;/strong&gt;This agency, also known as NWS, is part of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and offers information and updates on everything from wildfires to hurricanes to air quality. You can enter your zip code on &lt;a href=&quot;http://weather.gov/&quot;&gt;weather.gov&lt;/a&gt; and customize your homepage. The NWS also has regional and local branches where you can sign up for SMS alerts. If you’re in a rural area or somewhere that isn’t highlighted on its maps, keep an eye out for local alerts and evacuation orders, as NWS may not have as much information ahead of time.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-2163954446_cropped_Cal-Fire-monitoring-California.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Cal Fire firefighters livestream images and data from efforts to control and contain the Park Fire on July 29 near Chico, California.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;David McNew/Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Cal Fire firefighters livestream images and data from efforts to control and contain the Park Fire on July 29 near Chico, California.
 &lt;cite&gt;David McNew/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-how-to-pack-an-emergency-kit&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to pack an emergency kit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As you prepare for a storm, it’s important to have an emergency kit ready in case you lose power or need to leave your home. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ready.gov/sites/default/files/2021-02/ready_checklist.pdf&quot;&gt;Review this checklist from the Federal Emergency Management Agency, or FEMA&lt;/a&gt;, for what to pack so you can stay safe, hydrated, and healthy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;These can often be expensive to create, so contact your local disaster aid organizations, houses of worship, or charities to see if there are free or affordable kits available. Try to gather as much as you can ahead of time in case shelves are empty when a storm is on the way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Some of the most important things to have:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water (one gallon per person per day for several days)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Food (at least a several-day supply of non-perishable food) and a can opener&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Medicines and documentation of your medical needs&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Identification and proof of residency documents (see a more detailed list below)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Battery-powered or hand crank radio, batteries, flashlight&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;First aid kit&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Masks, hand sanitizer, and trash bags&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Wrench or pliers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Cell phone with chargers and a backup battery&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Diapers, wipes, and food or formula for babies and children&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Food and medicines for any household pets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget: Documents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;One of the most important things to have in your emergency kit is documents you may need to prove your residence, demonstrate extent of damage, and vote. FEMA often requires you to provide these documents in order to receive financial assistance after a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government issued ID, such as a drivers’ license for for each member of your household&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Proof of citizenship or legal residency for each member of your household (passport, green card, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Social Security card for each member of your household&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Documentation of your medical needs, such as medications or special equipment including oxygen tanks, wheelchairs, etc.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Health insurance card&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Car title and registration documents&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Pre-disaster photos of the inside and outside of your house and belongings&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Copy of your homeowners’ or renters’ insurance policy&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;For homeowners: copies of your deed, mortgage information, and flood insurance policy, if applicable&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;For renters: a copy of your lease&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Financial documents such as a checkbook or voided check&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;You can find more details about why you may need these documents &lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/2022/06/06/make-copies-of-everything-documents-to-have-in-case-of-a-hurricane/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1595195587_cropped_Lahaina-wildfire-ashes-volunteer.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;A volunteer assesses the remains of a charred apartment complex in the aftermath of a wildfire in Lahaina, western Maui, Hawaiʻi in 2023. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Yuki Iwamura/AFP via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A volunteer assesses the remains of a charred apartment complex in the aftermath of a wildfire in Lahaina, western Maui, Hawaiʻi in 2023. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Yuki Iwamura/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-disaster-aid-101&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaster aid 101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It can be hard to know who to lean on or trust when it comes to natural disasters. Where do official evacuation orders come from, for example, or who do you call if you need to be rescued? And where can you get money to help pay for emergency housing or to rebuild your home or community. Here’s a breakdown of the government officials and agencies in charge of delivering aid before, during, and after a disaster:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emergency management agencies: &lt;/strong&gt;Almost all cities and counties have local emergency management departments, which are part of the local government. Sometimes they’re agencies all their own, but in smaller communities, fire chiefs or sheriff’s offices may manage emergency response and alerts. These departments are the first line of defense during a weather disaster. They’re responsible for communicating with the public about incoming disasters, managing rescue and response efforts during an extreme weather event, and coordinating between different agencies. Many emergency management agencies, however, have a small staff and are under-resourced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Much of the work that emergency managers do happens before a disaster: They develop response plans that lay out evacuation routes and communication procedures, and they also delegate responsibility to different government agencies like the police, fire, and public health departments. Most counties and cities publish these plans online.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In most cases, they are the most trustworthy resource in the days just before and just after a hurricane or other big weather event. They’ll send out alerts and warnings, coordinate evacuation efforts, and direct survivors and victims to resources and shelter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;You can find your state emergency management agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usa.gov/state-emergency-management&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There isn’t a comprehensive list by county or city, but if you search your location online you’ll likely find a website, a page on the county or city website, or a Facebook page that posts updates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Law enforcement: &lt;/strong&gt;County sheriffs and city police departments are often the largest and best-staffed agencies in a given community, so they play a key role during disasters. Sheriff’s departments often enforce mandatory evacuation orders, going door-to-door to ensure that people vacate an area. They manage traffic flow during evacuations and help conduct search and rescue operations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Law enforcement agencies may restrict access to disaster areas for the first few days after a flood or fire. In most states, city and county governments also have the power to issue curfew orders, and law enforcement officers can enforce these curfews with fines or even arrests. In some rural counties, the sheriff’s department may serve as the emergency management department.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1242178982_cropped_Kentucky-floodwater-rescues.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Lexington Firefighters’ swift water teams rescue people stranded by extreme rain in Lost Creek, Kentucky in 2022.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Michael Swensen/Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Lexington Firefighters’ swift water teams rescue people stranded by extreme rain in Lost Creek, Kentucky in 2022.
 &lt;cite&gt;Michael Swensen/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governor: &lt;/strong&gt;State governors control several key aspects of disaster response. They have the power to declare a state of emergency, which allows them to deploy rescue and repair workers, distribute financial assistance to local governments, and activate the state National Guard. The governor has a key role in the immediate response to a disaster, but a smaller role in distributing aid and assistance to individual disaster victims.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In almost all U.S. states, and all hurricane-prone states along the Gulf of Mexico, the governor also has the power to announce mandatory evacuation orders. The penalty for not following these orders differs, but is most often a cash fine. (Though states seldom enforce these penalties.) The state government also decides whether to implement other transportation procedures such as contraflow, where officials reverse traffic flow on one side of a highway to allow larger amounts of people to evacuate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HUD: &lt;/strong&gt;The Department of Housing and Urban Development, or HUD, also spends billions of dollars to help communities recover after disasters, building new housing and public buildings such as schools — but this money takes much longer to arrive. Unlike FEMA, HUD must wait for Congress to approve its post-disaster work, and then it must dole out grants to states for specific projects. In some cases, such as the aftermaths of Hurricane Laura in Louisiana or Hurricane Florence in North Carolina, it took years for projects to get off the ground. States and local governments, not individual people, apply for money from HUD, but the agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hud.gov/disaster_resources&quot;&gt;can direct you&lt;/a&gt; to FEMA or housing counselors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1052197240_cropped_FEMA-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;A homeowner hangs a sign that reads “FEMA please help make Mexico Beach great again” on a house damaged by Hurricane Michael in Florida in 2018.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Hector Retamal/AFP via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A homeowner hangs a sign that reads “FEMA please help make Mexico Beach great again” on a house damaged by Hurricane Michael in Florida in 2018.
 &lt;cite&gt;Hector Retamal/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-fema&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEMA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Federal Emergency Management Agency, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fema.gov/&quot;&gt;FEMA&lt;/a&gt;, is the federal government’s main disaster response agency. It provides assistance to states and local governments during large events like hurricanes, wildfires, and floods. FEMA is part of the Department of Homeland Security.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;FEMA is almost never the first resource on the ground after a disaster strikes. In order for the agency to send resources to a disaster area, the state’s governor must first request a &lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/2022/02/18/heres-how-disaster-declarations-work-and-why-aid-takes-so-long/&quot;&gt;disaster declaration&lt;/a&gt; from the president, and the president must approve it. For large disasters such as Category 4 or 5 hurricanes, this typically happens fast. For smaller disasters, like severe rain or flooding events, it can take weeks or even months for the president to grant a declaration and activate the agency. FEMA has historically &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/record-high/fema-heat-waves-stafford-act/&quot;&gt;not responded&lt;/a&gt; to heat waves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;FEMA is broken into regional offices and offers specific contacts and information for each of those, as well as for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fema.gov/about/organization/tribal-affairs&quot;&gt;tribal nations&lt;/a&gt;. You can find your FEMA region &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fema.gov/locations&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;FEMA has two primary roles after a federally declared disaster:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributing to community rebuilding costs: &lt;/strong&gt;The agency helps states and local governments pay for the cost of removing debris and rebuilding public infrastructure. During only the most extreme events, the agency also deploys its own teams of firefighters and rescue workers to help locate missing people, clear roadways, and restore public services. For the most part, states and local law enforcement conduct on-the-ground recovery work. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/your-guide-to-fema/&quot;&gt;Read more about FEMA’s responsibilities and programs here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual financial assistance&lt;/strong&gt;: FEMA gives out&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;financial assistance&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to individual people who have lost their homes and belongings. This assistance can take several forms. FEMA gives out pre-loaded debit cards to help people buy food and fuel in the first days after a disaster, and may also provide cash payments for home repairs that your insurance doesn’t cover. The agency also provides up to 18 months of housing assistance for people who lose their homes in a disaster, and sometimes houses disaster survivors in its own manufactured housing units or “FEMA trailers.” FEMA also sometimes covers funeral and grieving expenses as well as medical and dental treatment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the aftermath of a disaster, FEMA offers survivors:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one-time payment of $750 for emergency needs&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Temporary housing assistance equivalent to 14 nights’ stay in a hotel in your area&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Up to 18 months of rental assistance&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Payments for lost property that isn’t covered by your homeowner’s insurance&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;And other forms of assistance, depending on your needs and losses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;If you are a U.S. citizen or meet certain qualifications as a non-citizen and live in a federal disaster declaration area, you are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fema.gov/assistance/individual/program/eligibility&quot;&gt;eligible for financial assistance&lt;/a&gt;. Regardless of citizenship or immigration status, if you are affected by a disaster you may be eligible for crisis counseling, disaster legal services, disaster case management, medical care, shelter, food, and water.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1243760210_cropped_FEMA-aid-sign-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;FEMA representatives take information from people displaced by Hurricane Ian in Estero, Florida in 2022.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Thomas Simonetti for The Washington Post via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;FEMA representatives take information from people displaced by Hurricane Ian in Estero, Florida in 2022.
 &lt;cite&gt;Thomas Simonetti for The Washington Post via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;FEMA also runs the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.floodsmart.gov/&quot;&gt;National Flood Insurance Program&lt;/a&gt;, which provides insurance coverage of up to $350,000 for home flood damage. The agency recommends that everyone who lives in a flood zone purchase this coverage — and most mortgage lenders require it for borrowers in flood zones — though many homes outside the zones are also vulnerable. You must begin paying for flood insurance at least 30 days before a disaster in order to be eligible for a payout. You can check if your home is in a flood zone by &lt;a href=&quot;https://msc.fema.gov/portal/search&quot;&gt;using this FEMA website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to get FEMA aid: &lt;/strong&gt;The easiest way to apply for individual assistance from FEMA is to fill out the application form on&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://disasterassistance.gov/&quot;&gt;disasterassistance.gov&lt;/a&gt;. This is easiest to do from a personal computer over Wi-Fi, but you can do it from a smartphone with cellular data if necessary. This website does not become active until the president issues a disaster declaration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Some important things to know:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FEMA will require you to create an account on the secure website &lt;a href=&quot;http://login.gov/&quot;&gt;Login.gov&lt;/a&gt;. Use this account to submit your aid application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;You can track the status of your aid application and receive notifications if FEMA needs more documents from you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;If FEMA denies your application for aid, you can appeal, but the process is lengthy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visiting a FEMA site in your area after a disaster: &lt;/strong&gt;FEMA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.disasterassistance.gov/get-assistance/forms-of-assistance/4627&quot;&gt;disaster recovery centers&lt;/a&gt; are facilities and mobile units where you can find information about the agency’s programs as well as other state and local resources. FEMA representatives can help you navigate the aid application process or direct you to nonprofits, shelters, or state and local resources. &lt;a href=&quot;https://egateway.fema.gov/ESF6/DRCLocator&quot;&gt;Visit this website&lt;/a&gt; to locate a recovery center in your area or text DRC and a ZIP Code to 43362. Example: DRC 01234.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1428698188_cropped_Hurricane-Ian-Florida-flood-clean-up.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;A woman looks over her apartment in Fort Myers, Florida, after Hurricane Ian inundated it with floodwaters in 2022.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Joe Raedle/Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A woman looks over her apartment in Fort Myers, Florida, after Hurricane Ian inundated it with floodwaters in 2022.
 &lt;cite&gt;Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-what-to-expect-after-a-disaster&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to expect after a disaster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Disasters affect people in many different ways, and it’s normal to grieve your losses — personal, professional, community — in your own time. Here are a few resources if you need mental health support after experiencing an extreme weather event.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ptsd.va.gov/understand/types/disaster_help.asp&quot;&gt;National Center for PTSD&lt;/a&gt;, or post-traumatic stress disorder, on what to expect after experiencing a disaster.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redcross.org/about-us/our-work/disaster-relief/disaster-mental-health.html&quot;&gt;American Red Cross&lt;/a&gt; has disaster mental health volunteers they often dispatch to areas hit by a disaster.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, or SAMHSA, has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.samhsa.gov/product/tips-survivors-disaster-or-other-traumatic-event-managing-stress/sma13-4776&quot;&gt;fact sheet&lt;/a&gt; on managing stress after a disaster. The agency has a Disaster Distress Helpline that provides 24/7 crisis counseling and support. Call or text: 1-800-985-5990&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/elections/your-guide-to-voting-after-a-disaster/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1058164786_cropped_voting-booth.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/elections/your-guide-to-voting-after-a-disaster/&quot;&gt;Your guide to voting after a disaster&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/lgilpin/&quot;&gt;Lyndsey Gilpin&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;       &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/jake-bittle/&quot;&gt;Jake Bittle&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After a disaster is an especially vulnerable time. Beware of scams and make sure to know your rights.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be wary of solicitors who arrive at your home after a disaster claiming to represent FEMA or another agency. FEMA will never ask you for money. The safest way to apply for aid is through FEMA’s official website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://disasterassistance.gov/&quot;&gt;disasterassistance.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Be cautious about hiring contractors or construction workers in the days after a disaster. Many cities require permits for rebuilding work, and it’s common for scammers to pose as contractors after a disaster.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/legal-aid/&quot;&gt;Renters&lt;/a&gt; can often face evictions after a disaster, so familiarize yourself with tenant rights in your state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1298811787_cropped_Paradise-California-wildfire-rebuilding.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Residents of Paradise, California visit the town’s planning department to file permitting applications to re-build homes and other structures after the devastating 2018 Camp Fire.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Gabrielle Lurie/San Francisco Chronicle via Getty Image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Residents of Paradise, California visit the town’s planning department to file permitting applications to re-build homes and other structures after the devastating 2018 Camp Fire.
 &lt;cite&gt;Gabrielle Lurie/San Francisco Chronicle via Getty Image&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-what-to-keep-in-mind-before-during-and-after-a-disaster&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to keep in mind before, during, and after a disaster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The most important thing to consider during a disaster is your own, your family’s, and your community’s safety. The National Weather Service has a guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weather.gov/media/owlie/HurricaneSafety-OnePager-07-03-18.pdf&quot;&gt;hurricanes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weather.gov/media/owlie/FloodSafety-OnePager-11-29-2018.pdf&quot;&gt;floods&lt;/a&gt;; FEMA has a guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ready.gov/wildfires&quot;&gt;wildfires&lt;/a&gt;; the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdc.gov/climate-health/php/resources/protect-yourself-from-the-dangers-of-extreme-heat.html&quot;&gt;has a guide for extreme heat safety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A few potentially life-saving things to remember:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never wade in floodwaters. They often contain harmful runoff from sewer systems and can cause serious illness and health issues.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;If it’s safe to do so, turn off electricity at the main breaker or fuse box in your home or business before a hurricane to prevent electric shock.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;If you lose power, never operate a generator inside your home. &lt;a href=&quot;https://southerlymag.org/generators/&quot;&gt;Generators&lt;/a&gt; emit carbon monoxide, a colorless and odorless gas that can be fatal if inhaled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did we miss something? Please let us know by emailing community@grist.org.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-weather-101-your-guide-to-staying-prepared-and-informed/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Lyndsey Gilpin, Jake Bittle</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GettyImages-1251790214_cropped_Fort-Lauderdale-flooding.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Climate</category><category>Drought</category><category>Elections</category><category>Equity</category><category>Extreme Heat</category><category>Extreme Weather</category><category>Justice</category><category>Politics</category><category>Uncategorized</category><category>Wildfires</category></item><item><title>Workers across the US rally after string of heat-related deaths</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For the last two years, Cecilia Ortiz has worked as a passenger service agent at Phoenix Sky Harbor International Airport. She typically has to walk 10 to 15 miles a day, up and down ramps, pushing heavy wheelchairs and carrying passengers’ luggage. This summer, temperatures have reached over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fox10phoenix.com/news/phoenix-heat-experts-expect-2024-break-record-hottest-summer-history&quot;&gt;110 degrees Fahrenheit&lt;/a&gt; on the airport’s jet bridges, and yet she says she’s been denied breaks and water by her supervisors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I have heart failure myself, and it is especially dangerous for me to work in extreme temperatures,” said Ortiz at a press briefing. “I shouldn’t have to work in these conditions. Nobody should.” Accessible drinking water, a cool place to rest, breaks as needed, and training to understand the signs of heat exhaustion are what Ortiz sees as a “very simple” way to make her workplace more safe during &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-weather/extreme-heat/&quot;&gt;searing temperatures&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Airport workers like Ortiz are being joined by laborers in fast food, retail, and the farm sector this week to demand on-the-job heat protections from employers and the federal government. From Atlanta to Los Angeles, a string of rallies, town halls, and delegations are taking place in 13 cities as laborers and coalitions escalate their demands to elected officials.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On Tuesday, service workers rallied at major airports in Charlotte, North Carolina, and Phoenix. They called for immediate action from employers to ensure their safety in the workplace, including adequate breaks and access to drinking water during periods of extreme heat.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Phoenix, where earlier this year &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/27/phoenix-workers-heat-protection-law&quot;&gt;local officials enacted a heat ordinance&lt;/a&gt; mandating many of these protections, workers and legislators sounded the alarm that the ordinance has led to inadequate improvements, and questioned how the protections are being enforced. “Why is it after passing an ordinance we’re still asking for the basics? Water. Breaks. These are humans rights,” said City of Phoenix Councilwoman Betty Guardado &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/GoodAirports/status/1823419795875983828&quot;&gt;at the rally&lt;/a&gt;. Later this week, laborers across the country will be taking a coordinated water break to signify the need for access to drinking water at work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As human-caused climate change continues to make the planet hotter, extreme heat in the workplace is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanprogress.org/article/extreme-heat-is-more-dangerous-for-workers-every-year/&quot;&gt;increasingly becoming&lt;/a&gt; a lethal threat. Organizers say “Heat Week” is also spurred by the recent sudden deaths of Wednesday “Wendy” Johnson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/07/15/usps-worker-heat-stroke-death-wendy-johnson/74414304007/&quot;&gt;a postal worker in North Carolina&lt;/a&gt;, and Ronald Silver II, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/08/06/baltimore-city-worker-ronald-silver-heat-death/74687692007/&quot;&gt;a sanitation worker in Maryland&lt;/a&gt;. Both Johnson and Silver are believed to have died, in part, because of on-the-job heat exposure, which kills &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climate-indicators/closer-look-heat-related-workplace-deaths#:~:text=Feature%20%7C%20Technical%20Documentation-,Key%20Points,reported%20data%20(Figure%201).&quot;&gt;dozens of workers&lt;/a&gt; every year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Service Employees International Union President April Verrett, whose organization is one of the groups helming Heat Week, said that these deaths could have been prevented by safer working conditions, before calling on the Biden administration to strengthen, finalize, and implement a federal heat rule. “Dying on the job is just simply out of the question, and it should never be a part of anyone’s routine. Yet employers are failing to act, and in doing so, they are failing to protect workers’ lives and their health,” said Verrett.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Heat is a silent killer. It is the biggest weather-related killer in our community,” said Representative Greg Casar, a Democrat from Texas, at the briefing. “I was born and raised in Texas. We know it’s hot, but it’s never been this hot, this early, for this long. So, as the climate crisis worsens, we need to come together and take federal action at the national level, guaranteeing everybody the right to these rest and water breaks.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/81d1ec15-32ce-41f6-93f8-dcded5d69499.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A group of people rally outside of an airport&quot; data-caption=&quot;At a rally on August 13, outside of Charlotte Douglas International Airport in North Carolina, service workers call on lawmakers to hold corporations accountable for putting their health and lives at risk. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Service Employees International Union&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;At a rally on August 13, outside of Charlotte Douglas International Airport in North Carolina, service workers call on lawmakers to hold corporations accountable for putting their health and lives at risk. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Service Employees International Union&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In July, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, or OSHA, &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/labor/biden-admin-unveils-first-ever-heat-protections-for-workers-heres-what-to-know/&quot;&gt;proposed a federal rule that would mandate employers provide indoor and outdoor workers&lt;/a&gt; with cool rest areas, drinking water, and breaks once temperatures approach 80 degrees. But that rule hasn’t yet been finalized, and it still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osha.gov/sites/default/files/OSHA_FlowChart.pdf&quot;&gt;faces a likely lengthy review&lt;/a&gt;, additional revisions, potential legal challenges, and an upcoming presidential election that could derail the political will to get it done. Casar said elected officials on every level need to do more to ramp up the urgent push for heat protections.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This is particularly important given that some policymakers are pursuing legislation that goes in the other direction, noted Casar —&amp;nbsp;referring to a law &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2023/06/16/texas-heat-wave-water-break-construction-workers/&quot;&gt;signed last summer&lt;/a&gt; by Texas Governor Greg Abbott that barred Texas cities from enacting local worker heat protections. A similar law went into effect in Florida &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2024/04/15/1244762307/florida-bans-local-heat-protections-for-outdoor-workers-in-extreme-heat&quot;&gt;this year&lt;/a&gt;. The proposed OSHA rule, he stressed, if finalized, would “override laws like Governor Abbott’s that get rid of heat protections.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We could have these heat protections codified in federal law this month, if the Republican Speaker of the House would put this up for a vote … but we can’t hold our breath,” said Casar. (In fact, House Republicans have &lt;a href=&quot;https://michiganindependent.com/politics/house-republicans-attempt-eliminate-osha-worker-safety/&quot;&gt;put forward spending bills&lt;/a&gt; that would hamper OSHA’s ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.safetyandhealthmagazine.com/articles/25624-house-proposes-budget-cuts-for-osha-and-other-safety-agencies-in-fy-2025&quot;&gt;enforce existing rules&lt;/a&gt;.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The offices of Governor Abbott and Congressman Mike Johnson, the Republican speaker of the House of Representatives, did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last week, Representative Ruben Gallego, a Democrat from Arizona, blasted the Biden administration for not doing enough to address the impacts of extreme heat. Beyond advocating for an OSHA standard, Gallego has also put forward legislation that would add extreme heat to the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s list of major disasters, The Hill &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/policy/energy-environment/4818894-ruben-gallego-biden-administration-extreme-heat-protections/#:~:text=The%20Arizona%20Democrat%20is%20a,Health%20Administration%20(OSHA)%20standard.&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. “Once again, the administration is all talk, no action when it comes to extreme heat in Arizona,” Gallego &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubengallego.house.gov/media-center/press-releases/gallego-calls-out-administration-for-insufficient-extreme-heat-response&quot;&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt; following a speech made by Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra, who deigned extreme heat in Phoenix a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/policy/energy-environment/4818193-xavier-becerra-extreme-heat-public-health-crisis/&quot;&gt;public health crisis&lt;/a&gt;.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/fema-disaster-response-florida-farmworkers/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A mobile home lays flipped on its side after a hurricane&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-1635280917.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/fema-disaster-response-florida-farmworkers/&quot;&gt;‘A matter of life and death’: How disaster response endangers US farmworkers&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/ayurella-horn-muller/&quot;&gt;Ayurella Horn-Muller&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“When hurricanes or tornadoes hit, federal officials offer resources, but with heat they just offer advice,” said Gallego. Others, like Senator Alex Padilla, a Democrat from California, have also pressed the administration to implement the proposed OSHA rule. “With climate change shattering heat records every summer, holding employers accountable to provide commonsense heat-stress protections has only become more critical,” Padilla told Grist. California is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kff.org/racial-equity-and-health-policy/issue-brief/floridas-recent-heat-protection-preemption-law-could-disproportionately-affect-hispanic-and-noncitizen-immigrant-workers/&quot;&gt;one of six states&lt;/a&gt; that have enacted heat-protection rules for outdoor workers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In June, Shae Parker was working at a convenience store in Columbia, South Carolina, when she suffered from extreme heat exhaustion because of brutal temperatures and a lack of access to free water. “I had to leave work on a gurney. I was vomiting. I was profusely sweating, light-headed, nauseous. It was unbearable,” said Parker. “We only get one body … we want to go home to our families at the end of the day.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lourdes Cardenas, a farmworker in Fresno, California, has also grappled with the consequences of sweltering heat. This summer, she has endured &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.extremeweatherwatch.com/cities/fresno/yearly-days-of-110-degrees&quot;&gt;multiple 110-degrees days&lt;/a&gt; in the fields — which, compounded by a lack of water, shade, and not enough breaks, led her to experience dizziness and dehydration on numerous occasions. Despite raising the alarm to her supervisors, water still isn’t easily accessible, and she and her coworkers work nowhere near shaded areas. “The heat has been really difficult, and every year it gets worse,” said Cardenas in Spanish.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We ought to be able to have the right to have water, the right to have shade, the right to have rest from the heat. But that’s not the case,” she said. “I know that one job is not worth my life.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat/heat-week-workers-rally-extreme-heat-protection/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-heat/heat-week-workers-rally-extreme-heat-protection/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Ayurella Horn-Muller</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Workers-rally-Phoenix-airport-image-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Equity</category><category>Extreme Heat</category><category>Labor</category></item><item><title>How the 2024 Paris Olympics handled the heat — and didn’t</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Curled up on a small, white rectangle of fabric on the grass by a park bench in Paris, Italian swimmer Thomas Ceccon inadvertently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.today.com/health/sleep/thomas-ceccon-sleeping-outside-olympics-village-rcna165183&quot;&gt;took the internet by storm&lt;/a&gt; simply by sleeping outside. The moment, posted to social media on Monday by a fellow Olympic athlete, came a week after Ceccon failed to qualify for the men’s 200-meter backstroke finals, despite having just won gold in the 100-meter event.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rainews.it/video/2024/07/olimpiadi-parigi-2024-nuoto-thomas-ceccon-200-dorso-semifinale-fuori-dalla-finale-88b55f46-6309-488a-bc5f-ffd7afdb8673.html&quot;&gt;an interview&lt;/a&gt; with an Italian broadcaster, Ceccon blamed his performance gap on subpar sleeping conditions in the Olympic Village — namely, heat. This week, media speculation that the uncomfortable temperatures were also behind his alfresco nap stirred an already roiling pot of concerns around the impact of extreme weather on this year’s summer games. (The Italian Swimming Federation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansa.it/english/news/2024/08/04/video-of-ceccon-napping-outdoors-in-paris-goes-viral_ed99e440-7d9e-4316-b195-754fed8b7a8b.html&quot;&gt;denied&lt;/a&gt; that Ceccon’s nap was related to conditions in the Olympic village.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the weeks leading up to the Paris Olympics, &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldathletics.org/athletics-better-world/news/report-athletes-researchers-warn-extreme-heat-paris-olympic-games&quot;&gt;weather forecasters and athletes alike&lt;/a&gt; feared that the games could become the hottest on record, surpassing the 2021 Tokyo events, where high humidity and 90-degree-Fahrenheit days led &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37055080/&quot;&gt;100 athletes to seek medical attention&lt;/a&gt; for heat illnesses; even more nonathletes followed suit. Although it’s too soon to know how this year’s games will stack up, a punishing heat dome settled over Paris on July 29, lasting for four days and spiking temperatures to highs of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/91165265/paris-olympics-heat-wave-athletes-organizers-climate-change&quot;&gt;97 degrees F&lt;/a&gt; as the first week of the games were underway.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;During the scorching weather, national teams rushed to keep their athletes in tip-top shape, renting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/article/2024/jul/30/hot-air-con-paris-2024-denies-claims-of-two-tier-games-in-searing-olympic-village-rooms&quot;&gt;air conditioners&lt;/a&gt; for their bedrooms in the Olympic Village and offering them &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/clairepoolesp/2024/07/30/paris-2024-heat-ice-vests-fans-and-longer-breaks-for-athletes/&quot;&gt;ice vests&lt;/a&gt;. The Australian Olympic Committee even invested in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miragenews.com/aussie-tech-aids-olympians-against-paris-heat-1291925/&quot;&gt;state-of-the-art monitors&lt;/a&gt; to record on-the-ground temperature, radiation, humidity, and wind speed, resulting in personalized recommendations to help their athletes manage heat risks. For some outdoor sports, like tennis and soccer, new protocols for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/sports/olympics/water-breaks-fans-ice-paris-heatwave-forces-tweaks-games-2024-07-30/&quot;&gt;additional rest breaks&lt;/a&gt; were triggered as temperatures surpassed predetermined safety thresholds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline1.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Japan’s Kaito Kawabata lies down after competing in the men’s 4x400-meter relay at the 2024 Paris Olympics. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Antonin Thuillier / AFP via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Japan’s Kaito Kawabata lies down after competing in the men’s 4×400-meter relay at the 2024 Paris Olympics. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Antonin Thuillier / AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Climate change is &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/how-climate-change-drives-hotter-more-frequent-heat-waves/&quot;&gt;driving up the frequency&lt;/a&gt; of extreme and deadly heat waves. &lt;a href=&quot;https://basis.org.uk/resource/rings-of-fire-2/&quot;&gt;Rings of Fire II&lt;/a&gt;, a report on Olympic heat released before this year’s games began on July 26, found that average summer temperatures in Paris have warmed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://basis.org.uk/resource/rings-of-fire-2/&quot;&gt;3.1 degrees Celsius&lt;/a&gt;, or about 5.6 degrees F, since 1924, the last time the City of Light hosted the games.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Yesterday, climate change crashed the Olympics,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WWAttribution/status/1818644784161943874&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; climatologist Friederike Otto of World Weather Attribution, an academic project that studies climate change impacts on meteorology, on July 31.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;“If the atmosphere wasn’t overloaded with emissions from burning fossil fuel, Paris would have been about 3 degrees C cooler and much safer for sport.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Just a few degrees can make a big difference for athletes. In warm temperatures, the body is less able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK331/&quot;&gt;shed the heat&lt;/a&gt; it generates, which can impact performance and health: A 2023 study of marathon and racewalking athletes found that a 2.7 degrees F increase in core body temperature could result in up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.physiology.org/doi/full/10.1152/japplphysiol.00348.2022&quot;&gt;20 percent slower&lt;/a&gt; performance times. And as the body tries to cool down, it sweats and dilates blood vessels. When these mechanisms are pushed too hard, they lead to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gavi.org/vaccineswork/deadly-heatwaves-how-high-temperatures-affect-body&quot;&gt;dangerous health risks&lt;/a&gt; — such as dehydration, organ failure, and heart attacks. And the longer a heat wave drags on, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/18/climate/long-heat-waves-health-risk.html&quot;&gt;more deadly the impacts become&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Extreme heat affects a wide range of sports. The Rings of Fire report, a collaboration between the British Association for Sustainable Sport and the Australian climate advocacy group Frontrunners, documented stories from elite athletes across 15 sports on how extreme temperatures had impacted their careers and health. In the report, British swimmer Hector Pardoe said he was “practically paralytic” after a heat stroke that left him vomiting and motionless during a competition in Budapest. For Yusuke Suzuki, a Japanese racewalker, heatstroke was a torturous ordeal that took two years to recover from.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/climate/lessons-from-the-world-cup-how-a-changing-climate-is-changing-sports/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;France Olivier Giroud Qatar 2022 World Cup&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/GettyImages-1244854117_worldcup_france_qatar.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/climate/lessons-from-the-world-cup-how-a-changing-climate-is-changing-sports/&quot;&gt;Lessons from the World Cup: How a changing climate is changing sports&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/lois-parshley/&quot;&gt;Lois Parshley&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Going forward, I don’t see this being any less of a problem,” said Mike Tipton, a human physiology researcher at the University of Portsmouth in the U.K. who contributed to the report. While Tipton is encouraged by the changes he sees taking place across sports to protect athletes and fans from extreme heat — such as water breaks and cooling stations — he also cautions against losing sight of the importance of mitigating the direct cause of climate change: humans burning fossil fuels.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The organizers of the Paris Olympics would seem to agree. In the years leading up to the games, the committee made unprecedented &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/16/climate/paris-olympics-climate.html&quot;&gt;sustainability promises&lt;/a&gt; like slashing the greenhouse gas emissions of recent Olympics in half. But, along with a 60 percent plant-based menu, the decision to cut energy use by building Olympic Village dorms with geothermal cooling, rather than air conditioning, has become a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/olympic-village-social-media-complaints-beds-food-heat-1932064&quot;&gt;main source&lt;/a&gt; of athletes’ complaints about the accommodations. Bernadette Szocs, a Romanian table tennis player, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/article/2024/jul/30/hot-air-con-paris-2024-denies-claims-of-two-tier-games-in-searing-olympic-village-rooms&quot;&gt;told The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; that the fans offered in dorm rooms weren’t enough. “You can feel it is too hot in the room,” she said.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I have a lot of respect for the comfort of athletes, but I think a lot more about the survival of humanity,” Paris Mayor Anne Hidalgo told a French radio station in 2023 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20240702-no-ac-ambition-for-paris-olympic-village-melts-away&quot;&gt;about the decision&lt;/a&gt; to eschew air-conditioning. But as temperature projections and concerns climbed, eventually, the organizers caved and ordered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.euronews.com/green/2024/07/04/green-dreams-of-the-paris-olympics-in-meltdown-as-organisers-u-turn-on-air-conditioning&quot;&gt;2,500 air-conditioning units&lt;/a&gt; for teams willing to pay for them. Some, like the Korean swim team, have opted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/sports/olympics/swimming-s-korea-swimmers-leave-athletes-village-due-long-commute-hot-buses-2024-07-26/#:~:text=PARIS%2C%20July%2026%20(Reuters),president%20said%20according%20to%20Yonhap.&quot;&gt;stay in hotels&lt;/a&gt;. Unequal access to such comforts have raised concerns of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/article/2024/jul/30/hot-air-con-paris-2024-denies-claims-of-two-tier-games-in-searing-olympic-village-rooms&quot;&gt;two-tier&lt;/a&gt; games.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1024 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/OlympicHeat_Inline2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Britain’s Jack Draper cools himself with a bag of ice during a break at a tennis event in the Paris 2024 Olympic Games.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Martin Bernetti / AFP via Getty&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Britain’s Jack Draper cools himself with a bag of ice during a break at a tennis event in the Paris 2024 Olympic Games.
 &lt;cite&gt;Martin Bernetti / AFP via Getty&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Experts agree that air-conditioning can create a competitive advantage. “Being able to cool down at night is a significant part of managing heat risk,” said Richard Franklin, a professor of public health and tropical medicine at James Cook University, in Queensland, Australia. Franklin added that heat waves often come with higher nighttime temperatures that prevent the body from fully recovering, and that lack of sleep and the physical strain of competition can increase risks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;There are other ways that athletes can mitigate the dangers of competing in high temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The best thing you can do is prepare ahead of the games by acclimatizing your body to the conditions,” said Madeleine Orr, an assistant professor of sport ecology at the University of Toronto and author of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.madeleineorr.com/book&quot;&gt;a book&lt;/a&gt; on how global warming is changing sports. She says that each sport comes with unique risk factors, such as time spent on exposed pavement, or duration of play. But for any athlete to properly sync their body before competition, she says, exercising in the heat is crucial. “It doesn’t eliminate risk, but it pushes the boundaries of when they feel the impacts. It makes a big, big difference.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Hannah Mason, a public health lecturer at James Cook University and lead author of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://portfolio.jcu.edu.au/Publications/JCU182183&quot;&gt;2024 paper&lt;/a&gt; analyzing the impacts of extreme heat on mass sporting events, said that other factors —&amp;nbsp;including the availability of shade and existing health conditions — should be considered in athletes’ heat preparedness plans. For example, Paralympic athletes often use equipment, like wheelchairs, that can trap more heat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Tipton, Orr, and Mason all agreed that, eventually, the escalating dangers of climate change will leave Olympics organizers with no option but to change the timing of summer games to happen during months with cooler weather. The good news, Tipton says, is that teams and athletic federations have started taking the risk of heat more seriously. “We’re seeing the nature of sports change in terms of the rules, regulations, and permissible cooling strategies,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;According to Mason, more top-down rulemaking on safety limits will be crucial for managing risk. With the high stakes and pressure of competition, she says athletes are often unwilling to back out even when conditions become dangerously hot.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“If it’s a few degrees too hot, they’re not going to back out,” she said. “We need policies to fall back on so that we don’t put these decisions in the hands of athletes that have spent their whole life training for that event.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-heat/paris-olympics-2024-extreme-heat/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-heat/paris-olympics-2024-extreme-heat/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:38:39 GMT</pubDate><author>Sachi Kitajima Mulkey</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/olympics-heat.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Climate</category><category>Culture</category><category>Extreme Heat</category></item></channel></rss>