<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>NL Times -- Top Stories</title><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/top-stories</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/nltimes/news/top-stories" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>NL Times -- Top Stories - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:09:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Only 16% of voters still have confidence in Dutch Cabinet</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Confidence in the Dutch government is at an all-time low. Only 16 percent of voters still have confidence in the Schoof I Cabinet. Half of VVD voters think the liberal party should team up with the left-wing next time, forming a centrist Cabinet with GroenLinks-PvdA instead of working with Geert Wilders’ PVV again, RTL Nieuws &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rtl.nl/nieuws/politiek/artikel/5499860/vertrouwen-kabinet-naar-dieptepunt-ook-wilders-minder-populair&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; after surveying over 23,000 members of its news panel. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;When the Schoof I Cabinet took office last summer it had the support of 37 percent of voters - a typical figure for a new Cabinet. That has now more than halved. Among people who voted for one of the coalition parties - PVV, VVD, NSC, and BBB - a large majority had confidence in this Cabinet when it took office. Now that’s only a quarter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“I see that voters mainly think that the parties bicker and argue too much among themselves,” said RTL pollster Gijs Rademaker. “They lack unity. Many also think that too few results have been achieved, and there is too little knowledge and experience in the coalition.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;VVD voters, in particular, seem to be done with this Cabinet. “I dare say that many VVD voters now have serious reservations about this coalition,” Rademaker said. “Last year, we saw that a large majority wanted to govern with Wilders’ PVV. That seems to be over now. If we ask them whether they would prefer to work with the PVV or with GL-PvdA in a next Cabinet, half choose Timmermans’ party, and only a fifth choose Wilders.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;VVD leader Dilan Yeşilgöz is the only coalition leader who has not lost support among her voters. 78 percent of VVD voters have confidence in her. The other coalition party leaders are less lucky, even PVV leader Geert Wilders, who seemed untouchable for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“For years, Wilders received confidence figures from his voters of around 100 percent. But since October, we have seen that confidence falling. First to 90 percent in October and now to 70 percent. I cannot remember ever seeing such figures for Wilders before,” Rademaker said. Critical PVV voters think that Wilders is not fulfilling his promises and blame him for harsh confrontations with the Cabinet. They also struggle with his positive attitude towards Donald Trump and his reluctance to invest in defense and Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Confidence in BBB leader Caroline van der Plas fell from 85 percent in December to 66 percent now. Pieter Omtzigt only has the confidence of 23 percent of NSC voters. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;At the same time, the leaders of the opposition parties are gaining support. Henri Botenbal scores the highest of the party leaders with the support of 93 percent of CDA voters. “The CDA is clearly on the way back and has also risen in all seat polls in recent months. Right-wing voters who say goodbye to BBB, NSC, and PVV regularly end up with CDA.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Frans Timmermans enjoys the support of 72 percent of GroenLinks-PvdA voters. And Rob Jetten has the confidence of 86 percent of D66 voters. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/19/16-voters-still-confidence-dutch-cabinet</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/19/16-voters-still-confidence-dutch-cabinet</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 07:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>House fires: One person killed in Drachten, another hospitalized in Delft</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Firefighters in the Netherlands had their hands full on Tuesday night. A house fire in Drachten killed one person. Another housefire in the historic center of Delft sent one person to the hospital and spread quickly. Firefighters are still working on extinguishing that blaze. There was also a large fire in a commercial property in Nijmegen, and a fire at a scrap yard in Amsterdam caused a stench in the capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drachten&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The fire Drachten, Friesland, started in a terraced house on Schuttersveld at around 00:15 a.m. on Wednesday. Firefighters found the deceased victim inside the home while fighting the blaze.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-entity-type=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;979a7337-3684-4e2d-bb8b-56ea71066e5c&quot; data-embed-button=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-embed-display=&quot;view_mode:node.full&quot; data-langcode=&quot;en&quot; data-entity-embed-display-settings=&quot;[]&quot; class=&quot;embedded-entity&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field field-node--field-embed-code field-name-field-embed-code field-type-string field-label-hidden has-single&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;837&quot; height=&quot;471&quot; src=&quot;https://embed.kijk.nl/?width=837&amp;amp;height=471&amp;amp;video=NrDtBTmigNwUMs&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;token=xxxxxx&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;sbsEmbed&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The fire brigade evacuated several homes on the street due to the blaze. The home where the fire started was badly damaged. Adjacent buildings suffered smoke and water damage, the local office for the emergency services, Veiligheidsregio Fryslan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fryslanveilig.nl/meldingen/grote-brand-schuttersveld-drachten&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;By 7:00 a.m. on Wednesday, the fire brigade had the fire under control but was still working on extinguishing it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delft&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The fire in Delft started in a home on Nieuwstraat at around 8:30 p.m. on Tuesday and spread to several upstairs apartments in that street and two houses on Wijnhaven. The emergency services took one person to hospital with unknown injuries. Firefighters also rescued two cats from different homes while fighting the fire. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-entity-type=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;31e3a33a-5c89-4d4f-a7b5-6f029efa7f3d&quot; data-embed-button=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-embed-display=&quot;view_mode:node.full&quot; data-langcode=&quot;en&quot; data-entity-embed-display-settings=&quot;[]&quot; class=&quot;embedded-entity&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field field-node--field-embed-code field-name-field-embed-code field-type-string field-label-hidden has-single&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;837&quot; height=&quot;471&quot; src=&quot;https://embed.kijk.nl/?width=837&amp;amp;height=471&amp;amp;video=BttWabaRPCjaYU&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;token=xxxxxx&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;sbsEmbed&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The large fire in the center of Delft is now “largely under control,” but extinguishing it completely will still take several hours, the fire brigade reported on Wednesday morning. The affected homes were badly damaged and are uninhabitable, the Veiligheidsregio Haaglanden &lt;a href=&quot;https://haaglandenveilig.nl/zeer-grote-brand-nieuwstraat-delft&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. The fire department expects that one of the buildings will collapse and has therefore cordoned off Nieuwstraat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nijmegen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;A large fire destroyed a commercial building on an industrial estate in Nijmegen overnight. The blaze on Vlotkampweg was first reported at around 10:00 p.m. The fire brigade responded with eight fire engines and three aerial platforms. They prevented the blaze from spreading to other buildings, but the building where it started was lost. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-entity-type=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-uuid=&quot;1f0c4c62-75f3-4904-b141-374b498400d7&quot; data-embed-button=&quot;node&quot; data-entity-embed-display=&quot;view_mode:node.full&quot; data-langcode=&quot;en&quot; data-entity-embed-display-settings=&quot;[]&quot; class=&quot;embedded-entity&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;field field-node--field-embed-code field-name-field-embed-code field-type-string field-label-hidden has-single&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;837&quot; height=&quot;471&quot; src=&quot;https://embed.kijk.nl/?width=837&amp;amp;height=471&amp;amp;video=MyrJfYgrKMoMvG&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;token=xxxxxx&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; class=&quot;sbsEmbed&quot; allow=&quot;encrypted-media; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Several explosions were heard while the fire brigade fought the blaze. According to the fire brigade, vehicles, gas bottles, and barrels in the building exploded due to the heat. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to De Gelderlander, two garages and a wholesaler of car parts were located in the building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amsterdam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In Amsterdam, a fire raged in a scrap yard in the Westelijk Havengebied, causing a lot of smoke and a stench in the area. Veiligheidsregio Kennemerland reported that the fire could be smelled as far as Haarlem. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The fire department used cranes to take apart the scrap yard and extinguish the fire on Vlothavenweg. A fireboat was also deployed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/19/house-fires-one-person-killed-drachten-another-hospitalized-delft</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/19/house-fires-one-person-killed-drachten-another-hospitalized-delft</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 07:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 7,000 people per year get cancer from their work; Trade union shocked</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Every year, some 7,000 Dutch people get cancer because they come into contact with harmful substances at work or are insufficiently protected against UV radiation from the sun while working in the open air, TNO found in a study on behalf of KWF Kankerbestrijding. Trade union FNV is shocked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;TNO identified 3,900 work-related cancer cases in the reference year, 2021. There were also at least 3,100 diagnoses of basal cell carcinoma - a less severe form of skin cancer. The study mentions these cases separately because basal cell carcinoma is “often treated in primary care, is rarely life-threatening, and is therefore not fully registered.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;KWF includes basal cell carcinomas in the figures because the cause is the same as that of more serious forms of skin cancer. “It also puts extra pressure on healthcare,” said a spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Lung cancer remains a common occupational disease, often caused by asbestos. The use of this pathogenic material has been prohibited since 1993, but it is still present in many older buildings and installations. According to the study, over 1,400 people developed cancer in the reference year 2021 due to exposure to asbestos at work. In most cases, it was lung cancer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to KWF, this estimate of the number of people who develop cancer due to exposure at work is the “most accurate to date.” The estimate is probably on the low side because only the most common risk factors were examined. “Nobody should get cancer from work. These figures show that we are still a long way from that,” said KWF director Dorine Manson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to Manson, the fact that skin cancer stands out so much emphasizes the importance of good protection against UV radiation. According to her, it is important to comply with the strict rules for demolition and renovation work to prevent asbestos-related cancer. KWF also concludes that it is important “not to wait too long to take measures if you know that a substance is carcinogenic.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to TNO, 5.4 percent of all new cancer diagnoses in men are related to their work. In women, this is a smaller share at 0.5 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;FNV was shocked by the results. “Never before has the relationship between the work you do and cancer been made so explicitly in the Netherlands,” said FNV director David van de Geer. He advocates better compliance with regulations, better checks, and better regulations. He also criticized recent motions in parliament that are intended to reduce the regulatory burden surrounding the registration of hazardous substances. The trade union believes this is &quot;ill-considered and irresponsible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“The realization that employees should be able to work in a healthy way should be much more ingrained in politicians, and in large and small employers. The Labor Inspectorate should be able to enforce better and the current regulations should therefore be tightened rather than weakened. Loosening the reins is a huge blow to the right to healthy and safe work.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/19/7000-people-per-year-get-cancer-work-trade-union-shocked</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/19/7000-people-per-year-get-cancer-work-trade-union-shocked</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 06:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Power outage in The Hague city center affecting 45,000 households; Chaotic rush hour</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A power outage affecting the city center and other parts of The Hague left tens of thousands of people without electricity at the end of Tuesday afternoon. There were many problems on the city’s public transport network as a result, creating a difficult rush hour situation for many even though trains were largely running on time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Please only call the emergency services for real emergencies,&quot; local authorities wrote on citizen alert system Burgernet just before 4:30 p.m. A total of 45,200 households and businesses were without power, according to grid operator Stedin. Aside from the city center, people reported problems in the coastal areas of Duindorp and Scheveningen, as well as the Archipelbuurt, Kompasbuurt, and other nearby neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stedin said it was hoping to have the issue resolved between 6:45 p.m. and 7:45 p.m. “Our technicians are on their way to determine the cause and resolve the outage as quickly as possible,” the company said on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First responders were answering multiple calls of people trapped in elevators, records show. Several national government buildings were evacuated because of the electricity outage. Among them are the Ministry of Social Affairs and Employment, the Ministry of Health Welfare and Sport, and the Ministry of Education, Culture and Science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But with the trouble extending through the end of the afternoon, the expectation is that commuters trying to get home will continue to have difficulty doing so. Public transport system HTM reported cancellations, delays and detours on each of the city’s tram routes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I was just driving and suddenly poof! Power gone,&quot; one tram operator in The Hague told Omroep West. &quot;Then the job is to come to a halt as safely as possible by letting the tram roll as far as possible and then letting the passengers out. And now we have to wait until we have power again, that&#39;s all we can do,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;HTM said it was unlikely for normal service to be restored before 5:30 p.m., but disrupted service could be extended by at least an hour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Haaglanden security office declared a Grip 2 regional emergency because of the incident. This ensured that a Regional Operational Team would be set up to coordinate the emergency response from a central location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They can then provide advice, and help collect and disseminate information as needed. They are also responsible for briefing the mayor’s office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/power-outage-hague-city-center-affecting-45000-households-chaotic-rush-hour</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/power-outage-hague-city-center-affecting-45000-households-chaotic-rush-hour</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Amsterdam alderman Reinier van Dantzig stepping down after MS diagnosis</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam Alderman Reinier van Dantzig (39) is quitting his position immediately. After being diagnosed with MS, he said that he does not feel fit enough to “fill the position of alderman as I deem necessary,” he wrote to the city council on Tuesday. At first, the alderman of Housing and Spatial Planning felt well enough to finish his term. A few weeks and an initial hearing later, he has to conclude that he cannot &quot;give his all every day for Mokum and its residents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Van Dantzig was a part of the Amsterdam city council since 2014. He was a council member at first before becoming the party chairman of D66 and becoming an alderman in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It was an honor and a privilege to dedicate so much of my life to Amsterdam,” he wrote about his time in the city’s politics. Van Dantzig will now focus on his recovery. “To hopefully be able to once again contribute to Amsterdam or society at some stage.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a bar owner with three catering establishments in the capital city, Van Dantzig often fought for the Amsterdam catering sector during his time as member of the city council and chairman of D66. As an alderman he often pushed for more affordable housing and expansion of mid-range rental homes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He announced his MS diagnosis in January. “This is a serious diagnosis that brings uncertainty. There is a good chance that I will no longer be able to walk independently in ten years,&quot; he said at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his farewell letter, he made an appeal to Amsterdammers to fight against nonsense, injustice and intolerance. “Amsterdam is a dream, an idea. If you make a contribution then you are an Amsterdammer,” said Van Dantzig. “Let’s do everything in our power to ensure that our DNA remains in these times of rising xenophobia and rising fascism.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam’s Mayor, Femke Halsema, has said that she thinks it is very sad that the alderman has had to quit his position. “We will miss him greatly in the municipal executive.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Halsema added that Van Dantzig has used his “typical Amsterdam intelligence” to help the city. “In his characteristic way- fast, sharp, and with a large sense of humor- he made his mark on the urban development of Amsterdam.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/amsterdam-alderman-reinier-van-dantzig-stepping-ms-diagnosis</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/amsterdam-alderman-reinier-van-dantzig-stepping-ms-diagnosis</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>One dead in Netherlands after taking fake Oxycodone laced with deadly opioid</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A person in the Netherlands has died after taking counterfeit oxycodone pills containing isotonitazepyne, a powerful synthetic opioid far more potent than fentanyl, authorities warn. The drug may be circulating in Dutch markets, posing a serious public health risk, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.trimbos.nl/actueel/nieuws/waarschuwing-namaak-oxycodonpillen-met-het-levensgevaarlijke-isotonitazepyne-in-omloop/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trimbos Institute&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The victim had purchased the pills online as pain medication without a prescription. Testing by the Netherlands Forensic Institute confirmed the pills contained no oxycodone but instead the deadly nitazene-class opioid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health experts say nitazenes dramatically increase the risk of fatal overdose, even in small doses. &quot;These substances can cause severe respiratory failure, leading to death,&quot; officials warn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authorities urge people to avoid online pain medication and seek immediate medical help if someone becomes unwell after taking suspected oxycodone. In an overdose situation, responders should request naloxone, a life-saving antidote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Drugs Information and Monitoring System (DIMS) is tracking the spread of these pills. For concerns about drug safety, users can get substances tested at designated facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/one-dead-netherlands-taking-fake-oxycodone-laced-deadly-opioid</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/one-dead-netherlands-taking-fake-oxycodone-laced-deadly-opioid</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dutch PM urges Israel, Hamas to maintain ceasefire; Pro-Gaza protests in various cities</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Prime Minister Dick Schoof called on all parties to adhere to the ceasefire in Gaza after &lt;a href=&quot;https://nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-min-urges-parties-hold-ceasefire-israeli-attack-kills-330-gaza&quot;&gt;Israeli airstrikes killed over 330 people in Gaza&lt;/a&gt;. According to Schoof, it is in the interest of the Palestinian and Israeli populations that the agreements are held. Pro-Palestinian protests have been announced in Nijmegen, Utrecht, Rotterdam, Amsterdam, Gouda, and Wageningen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Disturbing and sad news from Gaza, where many more fatalities can be deplored,” the Prime Minister wrote on X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Israel began airstrikes on the Gaza Strip overnight, ending the ceasefire that has been in effect since January 19. The Palestinian movement Hamas has said it wants to resume the ceasefire. Hamas government leader Essam al-Daalis was killed in the Israeli attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Protests have been announced in several cities in the country after the new Israeli attacks on Gaza. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;In Wageningen, there will be a demonstration at Forum at 12:30 p.m., Wageningenforpalestine reported on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Utrecht4 Palestine announced an “emergency protest” for Tuesday at 5:00 p.m. at the city office in Utrecht under the name Enough is Enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The Instagram account amsterdam.encampment said that there will be a demonstration at the station in Rotterdam on Tuesday at 4:00 p.m. and on Dam Square in Amsterdam on Wednesday at 4:00 p.m. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Activists will also take action in Gouda on Tuesday at 5:30 p.m., according to free.palestine.nl, and in Amsterdam, a sit-in is planned at Central Station for Tuesday at 7:30 p.m. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;At Radboud University in Nijmegen, there will be an “emergency demonstration” on Tuesday afternoon. The protest is at 3:30 p.m., nijmegenencampment reported on Instagram. “We cannot sit still while the Israeli genocidal massacres in Gaza continue: Last night’s massacre is further proof that a ‘ceasefire’ means nothing,” they wrote in the call to protest. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The pro-Palestinian student activists of the University of Amsterdam (UvA) are shocked by the intensity of the attacks. &quot;We are unfortunately not surprised,&quot; said a spokesperson. &quot;It was already clear from the negotiations that Israel did not want a definitive end to the war. We are now seeing that again, together with the starvation of Gaza.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-pm-urges-israel-hamas-maintain-ceasefire-pro-gaza-protests-various-cities</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-pm-urges-israel-hamas-maintain-ceasefire-pro-gaza-protests-various-cities</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 11:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Discount stores taking over Dutch shopping streets</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;With inflation driving consumers to cheaper options and major retail chains going bankrupt, the Dutch shopping streets are being taken over by discount chains. Nearly 120 discount drugstores and textile supermarkets have opened in the Netherlands in the past five years, the Volkskrant &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.volkskrant.nl/binnenland/de-discounter-verovert-de-winkelstraat-hoe-hoger-het-deal-gehalte-hoe-eerder-de-consument-koopt~bdbc06d7/&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; based on research by Locatus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Wibra and Action are doing well in the Netherlands, opening 34 and 31 new branches respectively between 2020 and 2025. But two relative newcomers stand out: Medikamente die Grenze opened a massive 50 stores in the Netherlands in the past five years, and Kik opened 30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Zeeman closed 49 branches in the past five years but is still the biggest discount chain in the Netherlands. According to the Volkskrant, the closing stores doesn’t mean that Zeeman is struggling. The textile supermarket is focusing more on growth in Southern Europe and online sales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to sector manager Olaf Zwijnenburg of Rabobank, discount chains are flourishing under economic uncertainty. High inflation is driving more and more Dutch consumers to cheaper options. “The higher the deal content, the sooner the consumer comes and buys,” he told the newspaper. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The bankruptcy of Blokker also contributed to the growth. Due to the department store chain’s downfall, around 350 relatively large retail spaces became available at the end of last year. Wibra, Kik, Normal, TerStal, and kruidvat jumped into that gap. Wibra added 33 stores, Kik is planning to take over around 20 Blokker stores, Takko at least 15, and Van Haren at least nine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/discount-stores-taking-dutch-shopping-streets</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/discount-stores-taking-dutch-shopping-streets</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dutch intelligence services mining more and more data in secret</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The Dutch intelligence services AIVD and MIVD made more use of their special powers to secretly gather information last year, NOS &lt;a href=&quot;https://nos.nl/artikel/2560145-aivd-en-mivd-vergaren-steeds-vaker-informatie-in-het-geheim&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; from the Review Committee for the Use of Powers’ (TIB) annual report. According to the TIB, the increase in secret data mining was due to international tensions, like the wars in Ukraine and the Gaza Strip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The secret information gathering included tapping phones, installing cameras, or tapping internet traffic. Last year, the TIB received 4,445 requests from the two services, an increase of 30 percent compared to a year earlier. In 2023, the number of requests increased by almost 17 percent. The TIB granted almost all requests, only rejecting 4 percent last year. This is comparable to 2023. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Geopolitically, a lot happened in 2024,” the TIB said in its report, referring to the war in Ukraine and Gaza and the “increasing threat” from China and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The general intelligence service AIVD and its military counterpart MIVD have to request permission from the TIB every time they want to use their special powers. The TIB then assesses whether the request is lawful and justified because the special powers are a violation of fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;According to the TIB, this violation is sometimes necessary “to protect national security against terrorism, cyber threats, espionage, criminal undermining, or threats to our economic security.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, the TIB and the other supervisor on the intelligence services, CTIVD, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nltimes.nl/2025/03/14/intelligence-service-regulators-reprimand-aivd-organized-crime-investigations&quot;&gt;reprimanded the AIVD for going beyond its scope&lt;/a&gt;. The AIVD is responsible for intelligence relating to national security. However, according to the supervisory bodies, it is increasingly common for the AIVD to want to investigate someone for criminal activities that do not pose a threat to national security. That is the purview of the police, FIOD, and Koninklijke Marechaussee. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-intelligence-services-mining-data-secret</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-intelligence-services-mining-data-secret</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 07:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dutch gov&#39;t taking over 4 times longer than allowed to answer requests for information</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item&quot;&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;It took the Dutch Ministries an average of 188 days to respond to a request for information last year, the Open State Foundation, the Institute for Social Innovation, and the University of Amsterdam reported in an annual study into the Open Government Act (Woo). The maximum response time under the law is 42 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Since May 2022, citizens have been able to appeal to the Woo to request government documents. Until then, the similar Government Information (Public Access) Act (Wob) applied. Journalists and lawyers, among others, use the law to obtain information about the state of affairs at Ministries, water boards, and municipalities, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The waiting time for a response from the government has only increased since 2022, according to the study. In that year, an information request took an average of 161 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Last year, the Ministry of Education was the fastest on average, responding within 99 days on average - still over double the statutory time. The Ministry of Justice and Security was the slowest with 299 days. According to the governments, requests take a long time because they are very difficult. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Ministries responded to more Woo requests last year than the year before, the researchers wrote. In 2023, it involved 1,752 responses. Last year, there were over 2,000. However, according to the research, these are “still relatively few information requests compared to surrounding countries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The government recently published its own “dashboard” with figures on the handling of information requests. It currently states that the Ministries take an average of 143 days to respond to Woo requests. The difference is that requests are sometimes temporarily suspended, the researchers write. The government does not count those days, but the researchers do. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    </description><link>https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-govt-taking-4-times-longer-allowed-answer-requests-information</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nltimes.nl/2025/03/18/dutch-govt-taking-4-times-longer-allowed-answer-requests-information</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 06:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>