<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>The world in brief | The Economist</title><link>https://www.economist.com/the-world-in-brief</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.rssforever.com/economist/espresso" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Catch up quickly on the global stories that matter - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-gb</language><image><url>https://www.economist.com/engassets/World-OG-image.png</url><title>The world in brief | The Economist</title><link>https://www.economist.com/the-world-in-brief</link></image><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:30:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Russian strikes hit a children’s hospital in northern Ukraine, local officials said, injuring 28 people including four children. The attack occurred ...</title><description>&lt;b&gt;Russian strikes &lt;/b&gt;hit a children’s hospital in northern Ukraine, local officials said, injuring 28 people including four children. The attack occurred as &lt;b&gt;American&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/03/18/putin-woos-trump-with-a-partial-ceasefire-and-big-geopolitical-deal&quot;&gt;Russian&lt;/a&gt; officials met in Saudi Arabia to discuss a plan to pause strikes on Ukrainian energy infrastructure and a potential ceasefire in the Black Sea to allow the resumption of grain and fuel exports.</description><link>https://www.economist.com/the-world-in-brief</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.economist.com/the-world-in-brief#9f9e30a53e18bc33</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:08:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkish authorities said they arrested more than 1,100 people during five days of mass protests over the jailing of Ekrem Imamoglu, the mayor of Istan...</title><description>&lt;b&gt;Turkish&lt;/b&gt; authorities said they arrested more than 1,100 people during five days of mass protests over the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/europe/2025/03/23/president-erdogan-jails-his-rival-and-endangers-turkeys-democracy&quot;&gt;jailing&lt;/a&gt; of&amp;nbsp;Ekrem Imamoglu, the mayor of Istanbul and opposition leader. The government banned public gatherings in many cities, but hundreds of thousands joined demonstrations. Those detained included ten journalists. The opposition says Mr Imamoglu’s arrest was politically motivated.</description><link>https://www.economist.com/the-world-in-brief</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.economist.com/the-world-in-brief#1641e240992cca61</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:08:57 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>