<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Today&#39;s News - Cybercrime Magazine</title><link>https://cybersecurityventures.com//today</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.pseudoyu.com/cybersecurityventures/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Today&#39;s News - Cybercrime Magazine - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:28:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Hacker claims responsibility for replacing NYU’s website with apparent test scores, racial epithet</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: New York Post&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;A dark web user claimed responsibility for briefly hacking New York University’s website Mar. 22, and replacing it with what appeared to be student test scores and an apparent racial epithet. Instead of the usual images of college athletes and the Greenwich Village campus, the site featured a black background with green writing showing a message along with charts of what were purported to be SAT and ACT scores and GPAs for students in 2024, divided by race. The site was reclaimed after approximately two hours, and back to normal &lt;a href=&quot;https://nypost.com/2025/03/22/us-news/nyus-website-seemingly-hacked-and-replaced-by-apparent-test-scores-racial-epithet/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://nypost.com/2025/03/22/us-news/nyus-website-seemingly-hacked-and-replaced-by-apparent-test-scores-racial-epithet/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67e12d01e9e9af030657fe62</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacker steals $8.4M from RWA restaking protocol Zoth</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Cointelegraph&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Real-world asset (RWA) re-staking protocol Zoth suffered an exploit leading to over $8.4 million in losses, leading the platform to put its site on maintenance mode. On Mar. 21, blockchain security firm Cyvers &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/CyversAlerts/status/1903021017460600885&quot;&gt;flagged&lt;/a&gt; a suspicious Zoth transaction. The security firm said that the protocol’s deployer wallet was compromised and that the attacker withdrew over $8.4 million in crypto assets. The blockchain security firm said that within minutes, the stolen assets were converted into the DAI stablecoin and were transferred to a different address.  Since the hack, the attackers have moved the funds and &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/PeckShieldAlert/status/1903040662829768994&quot;&gt;swapped&lt;/a&gt; the assets into Ether. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cointelegraph.com/news/zoth-exploit-admin-leak-causes-8m-losses&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://x.com/CyversAlerts/status/1903021017460600885</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67e12dc15a6bd2033d7cdaae</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Oracle Cloud says it&#39;s not true someone broke into its login servers and stole data</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Register&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oracle has straight up denied claims by a miscreant that its public cloud offering has been compromised and information stolen. A crook late last week advertised on an online cyber-crime forum what was alleged to be Oracle Cloud customer security keys and other sensitive data swiped from the IT giant. This material was said to have been obtained by the hacker from at least one of the cloud provider&#39;s single-sign-on (SSO) login servers by exploiting a security vulnerability. Oracle says that&#39;s not true. Bleeping Computer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/oracle-denies-data-breach-after-hacker-claims-theft-of-6-million-data-records/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; the hacker boasted of creating a text file on an Oracle Cloud login server at login.us2.oraclecloud.com, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20250301161517/https://login.us2.oraclecloud.com/oamfed/x.txt?x&quot;&gt;captured here&lt;/a&gt; by the Internet Archive&#39;s Wayback Machine earlier this month, as proof that systems were compromised. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2025/03/23/oracle_cloud_customers_keys_credentials/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/oracle-denies-data-breach-after-hacker-claims-theft-of-6-million-data-records/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67e12ed100e0f802d77b99f1</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukrainian railways system failure caused by large-scale cyberattack, recovery ongoing</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Ukrainska Pravda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;A systems failure experienced by Ukrzaliznytsia (Ukrainian railways) on Mar. 23 was the result of a large-scale targeted cyberattack. The restoration of all systems is ongoing. The attack was described as highly systemic, sophisticated and multi-layered. Before fully restoring from backups, specialists from Ukrzaliznytsia, various partner organisations and the cyber department of Ukraine’s Security Service are conducting thorough testing of services to identify any potential vulnerabilities. Online ticket sales remain unavailable as of Mar. 24, and the company plans to continue operating in offline mode until further notice. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2025/03/24/7504239/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2025/03/24/7504239/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67e133e20f123d032b44d9ef</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Youtube account of Costa Rica&#39;s presidency back online after cyberattack</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Reuters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The official YouTube account of Costa Rican President Rodrigo Chaves came back under government control late on Mar. 21 after the platform suffered an hours-long cyberattack earlier in the day. Experts from the president&#39;s office, the science and technology ministry as well as Google, worked to resolve the hack. No details were provided on who or what entity was behind the attack, or if any sensitive information had been breached. On the day of the hack, the YouTube presidential profile showed a logo with the word &quot;Strategy&quot; followed by a bitcoin symbol. The most recent videos uploaded to the profile had contained information related to the cryptocurrency, which the presidential office assured had not come from them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/costa-rica-governments-youtube-account-suffers-cyber-attack-2025-03-21/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/costa-rica-governments-youtube-account-suffers-cyber-attack-2025-03-21/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67e13652e7f9d002bd1e96b2</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>South Africa&#39;s Astral Foods flags sharp profit fall, reports cyberattack</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: MSN&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astral Foods said Mar. 24 it expects its half-year profit to decline by as much as 60 percent, with a recent cybersecurity incident compounding the impact of lower chicken prices and higher input costs. South Africa&#39;s top poultry producer said its flagship division was negatively affected by downtime in processing and deliveries to customers following a cybersecurity incident on Mar. 16, which impacted its half-year profit by about 20 million rand ($1.10 million). This was due to revenue losses and the added costs of clearing the production backlog, Astral said in an initial trading update. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/s-africa-s-astral-foods-flags-sharp-profit-fall-reports-cyber-attack/ar-AA1BwZKi?ocid=finance-verthp-feeds&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/companies/s-africa-s-astral-foods-flags-sharp-profit-fall-reports-cyber-attack/ar-AA1BwZKi?ocid=finance-verthp-feeds</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67e137ab673ccd03155d9bc6</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Former NFL and University of Michigan assistant football coach charged with identity theft</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: ESPN&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;A former NFL and University of Michigan assistant football coach allegedly hacked into the computer accounts of thousands of college athletes seeking intimate photos and videos, according to an indictment filed Mar. 20. Matt Weiss, who worked for the Baltimore Ravens before joining the University of Michigan in 2021, was charged with 14 counts of unauthorized computer access and 10 counts of identity theft. Weiss was fired in 2023 as Michigan&#39;s co-offensive coordinator after failing to cooperate with the school&#39;s investigation of his access to computers. From 2015 to 2023, Weiss gained access to the databases of more than 100 colleges and universities, and then downloaded personal information and medical data of more than 150,000 athletes, the indictment states. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.espn.com/college-football/story/_/id/44331637/ex-michigan-assistant-charged-hacking-computer-accounts&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.espn.com/college-football/story/_/id/44331637/ex-michigan-assistant-charged-hacking-computer-accounts</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dd44cc554db902cfffb9fa</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea launches new unit with a focus on AI hacking, per report</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TechCrunch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The North Korean government is reportedly establishing a new hacking group within the intelligence agency Reconnaissance General Bureau (RGB). Daily NK, a news outlet that focuses on North Korea, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dailynk.com/english/n-korea-ramps-up-cyber-offensive-new-research-center-to-focus-on-ai-powered-hacking/&quot;&gt;reported last week&lt;/a&gt; that the new hacking unit, called Research Center 227, will focus on research to develop “offensive hacking technologies and programs,” citing a source inside the regime. The source said, per the report, Research Center 227 will research Western cybersecurity systems and computer networks, strengthening the regime’s capabilities to steal digital assets; develop AI-based techniques for information theft; and work to respond to information from North Korean overseas hacking units. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/20/north-korea-launches-new-unit-with-a-focus-on-ai-hacking-per-report/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.dailynk.com/english/n-korea-ramps-up-cyber-offensive-new-research-center-to-focus-on-ai-powered-hacking/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dd4686972ca00361d751e9</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hospital system in Hidalgo County, Texas hit by cyberattack</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: MyRGV.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edinburg, Texas-based DHR Health has been hit with a cyberattack affecting its information systems, the local hospital system said in a statement Mar. 20. “Our dedicated IT teams are actively working to restore full functionality as quickly as possible,” the statement read. The hospital system, which has healthcare facilities stretching from Hidalgo to Cameron counties, did not say whether patients’ or staff’s sensitive information was compromised. In its statement, DHR Health only referred to IT functions. &quot;We have well-established backup protocols in place to ensure seamless operations, and our staff is fully equipped to manage the situation effectively,” DHR Health said. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cybersecurityventures.com//We%20have%20well-established%20backup%20protocols%20in%20place%20to%20ensure%20seamless%20operations,%20and%20our%20staff%20is%20fully%20equipped%20to%20manage%20the%20situation%20effectively,%E2%80%9D%20DHR%20Health%20said.&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://cybersecurityventures.com//We%20have%20well-established%20backup%20protocols%20in%20place%20to%20ensure%20seamless%20operations,%20and%20our%20staff%20is%20fully%20equipped%20to%20manage%20the%20situation%20effectively,%E2%80%9D%20DHR%20Health%20said.</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dd48bf554db902cfffd201</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Data breach at SpyX stalkerware exposes millions of Apple phone users</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Android Headlines&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; has recently uncovered a data breach that exposed records on nearly two million people linked to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://spyx.com/&quot;&gt;SpyX&lt;/a&gt; iPhone stalkerware. According to TechCrunch, the Jun. 2024 breach remained unreported until now. There is also no indication that SpyX’s operators ever notified affected customers or their spyware targets. Security researcher Troy Hunt, who runs the data breach notification service &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt;, confirmed the leak. Hunt said the vast majority of the email addresses are associated with SpyX. The cache also includes less than 300,000 email addresses associated with two near-identical clones of the SpyX app called Msafely and SpyPhone. London-based SpyX calls itself the best phone monitoring software for parental controls, and claims it protects more than 110,000 families. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidheadlines.com/2025/03/spyx-stalkerware-data-breach-exposes-millions-iphone-users.html&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dd4b994f974002e81df453</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>FBI warns of possible Outlook, Gmail cyberattacks</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Hill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FBI is warning users of popular email services such as Outlook and Gmail that they could be subject to cyberattacks by ransomware called Medusa, which has impacted more than 300 victims from a number of sectors, including technology, legal, medical and manufacturing. Medusa, a ransomware-as-a-service that was first identified in June, was spotted as recently last month, according to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa25-071a&quot;&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt; released last week by the FBI, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) and the Multi-State Information Sharing and Analysis Center (MS-ISAC). &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/policy/technology/5203914-medusa-ransomware-fbi-warning-outlook-gmail/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/cybersecurity-advisories/aa25-071a</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dd52dd9d0ad702d6117d65</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Mac phishing attack causes fake freezes to nab your Apple ID password</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Macworld&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;LayerX Labs on Mar. 18 &lt;a href=&quot;https://layerxsecurity.com/blog/layerx-identifies-new-phishing-campaign-targeted-at-mac-users/&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; its finding on a new phishing attack that originally targeted Windows users, but now can be found on Macs. The phishing attack attempts to get a user’s username and password by making the user think their Mac is compromised. The attack involves fake security warnings that appear while browsing the web. Alerts appear stating that the Mac has been “compromised” and “locked” and the webpage appears frozen to heighten the sense of a compromise. A window appears prompting the user to enter their Mac’s username and password, along with a phone number to contact for “support.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macworld.com/article/2642938/new-mac-phishing-attack-causes-fake-freezes-to-nab-your-apple-id-password.html&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://layerxsecurity.com/blog/layerx-identifies-new-phishing-campaign-targeted-at-mac-users/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dd53ff1f917803046ca5a7</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dogequest Website Exposes Tesla Owners&#39; Personal Data</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Newsweek&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;A website known as &quot;Dogequest&quot; has allegedly published personal details of Tesla owners across the U.S., sparking concerns over privacy and security. The site, which appears in the wake of anti-Elon Musk protests across the country, displays names, addresses, and phone numbers of Tesla owners on an interactive map and uses an image of a Molotov cocktail as its cursor. The website&#39;s operators claim they will only remove Tesla owners&#39; information if they provide proof that they have sold their vehicles. The accuracy of Dogequest&#39;s data is unclear. Some individuals listed on the website reportedly are Tesla owners, but not all data could be verified. Some plotted locations on the map do not correspond correctly to real-world addresses. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsweek.com/dogequest-tesla-elon-musk-doxxing-website-2046920&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.newsweek.com/dogequest-tesla-elon-musk-doxxing-website-2046920</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dbf90b972ca00361d116a0</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UK cybersecurity agency warns over risk of quantum hackers</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Guardian&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK’s cybersecurity agency is urging organisations to guard their systems against quantum hackers by 2035, as the prospect of breakthroughs in powerful computing threaten digital encryption. The National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) has issued new guidance recommending large entities including energy and transport providers introduce “post-quantum cryptography” in order to prevent quantum technology being deployed to break into their systems. The NCSC warned that quantum computers will be able to solve the hard mathematical problems that underpin asymmetric public key cryptography – a common encryption method used in a range of everyday situations from mobile phone use to online banking. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/mar/20/uk-cybersecurity-agency-quantum-hackers&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/mar/20/uk-cybersecurity-agency-quantum-hackers</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dbf987d7b8be02cb52911a</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pennsylvania teachers’ union says hackers stole sensitive personal data on 500K+ members</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TechCrunch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pennsylvania State Education Association (PSEA), a labor union representing educators across the state, says hackers stole the sensitive personal information of more than half a million of its members. PSEA is the largest organization for educators in Pennsylvania, representing current and former teachers, counselors, healthcare workers, and school social workers. In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e44266ce-8099-4d3c-8635-2c5cdb41f24a.html&quot;&gt;filing&lt;/a&gt; on Mar. 18, PSEA said it experienced a cyberattack in Jul. 2024 that saw an unauthorized actor access its network to steal a trove of data belonging to more than 517,000 individuals. The stolen data includes members’ government-issued identification documents, Social Security numbers, passport numbers, medical information, and financial information containing card numbers, and their associated PINs and expiration dates. &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/us-teachers-union-says-hackers-stole-sensitive-personal-data-on-over-500000-members/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e44266ce-8099-4d3c-8635-2c5cdb41f24a.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dbfaa70d6f3c03072a0336</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia&#39;s Notre Dame University students say outage creating mayhem</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: ABC News&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;A cyberattack on Australia&#39;s Notre Dame University IT systems seven weeks ago is still playing havoc on campus with students reporting uncertainty with graduations, finding classes, and submitting assignments. About three weeks out from the start of first semester the Perth-based university was hit by a ransomware attack which knocked out a number of IT systems including direct communication channels between students and staff. In a written statement, the university acknowledged the impact the ongoing IT problems were having on staff and students but said manual workaround were in place. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-20/notre-dame-uni-students-says-cyber-attack-playing-havoc/105075278&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-20/notre-dame-uni-students-says-cyber-attack-playing-havoc/105075278</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dbfe8bec911c02d8053747</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lab Dookhtegan cyberattack on Iranian oil tankers</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Industrial Cyber&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cydome’s maritime cyber research team just &lt;a href=&quot;https://cydome.io/lab-dookhtegan-cyber-attack-on-iranian-oil-tankers-disrupts-operations/&quot;&gt;published an analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the recent cyberattack by Lab Dookhtegan on Iranian oil tankers that &lt;a href=&quot;https://industrialcyber.co/transport/gao-report-flags-gaps-in-maritime-cybersecurity-urges-coast-guard-to-boost-defenses-against-global-threats/&quot;&gt;claimed to disrupt&lt;/a&gt; the operation of 116 oil vessels. These oil tanker ships are said to belong to two Iranian companies associated with the government and allegedly operating against international sanctions. The group claims that the attack prevented communications both on the ship and ship-to-shore (Satcom). The researchers noted that while Lab Dookhtegan has not publicly disclosed the exact Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures (TTPs) used, open-source reporting indicates the group likely exploited vulnerabilities in the maritime satellite communication systems that these ships rely on. &lt;a href=&quot;https://industrialcyber.co/news/cydome-analyzes-lab-dookhtegan-cyber-attack-on-iranian-oil-tankers-provides-mitigation-action/&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://cydome.io/lab-dookhtegan-cyber-attack-on-iranian-oil-tankers-disrupts-operations/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dbffbd11f910032e0523a7</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hokkaido Jalan Website Shut Down Amid Suspected Cyberattack</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Pinnacle Gazette&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Mar. 19, reports emerged that the official homepage of Hokkaido Jalan, a popular Japan-based travel information site operated by Recruit, was inaccessible, leading many to suspect a significant cyberattack. Since the morning of the same day, users attempting to access the site encountered a blank page, with alarming indications of a potential hack. It was reported that the site displayed messages indicating a cyberattack had occurred. Some individuals have reported receiving emails purportedly from someone posing as a security researcher, containing sensitive information such as names, addresses, and phone numbers linked to their Jalan accounts. &lt;a href=&quot;https://evrimagaci.org/tpg/hokkaido-jalan-website-shut-down-amid-suspected-cyber-attack-273495&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://evrimagaci.org/tpg/hokkaido-jalan-website-shut-down-amid-suspected-cyber-attack-273495</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67dc01a0eb62430322546cf8</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>California Cryobank confirms year-old cyberattack</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: cyberdaily.au&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Major U.S. sperm donation and cryopreservation firm California Cryobank (CCB) has confirmed a 2024 cyber incident that resulted in threat actors accessing customer data. According to a notice sent to customers Mar. 14, 2025, CCB identified unauthorized activity on some of the computers on its network on Apr 21, 2024. It quickly locked down the devices from the network and launched an investigation.The company, which is the largest sperm bank in the U,S, and has operations in all 50 states as well as 30 countries, including Australia, has not disclosed how many people were affected, nor whether or not operations overseas have been impacted. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyberdaily.au/security/11870-california-cryobank-confirms-year-old-cyber-attack&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.cyberdaily.au/security/11870-california-cryobank-confirms-year-old-cyber-attack</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67daa826cadd0c032e70bce8</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China identifies Taiwanese hackers allegedly behind cyberattacks and espionage</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Source: The Record&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s state security ministry (MSS) has accused four individuals allegedly linked to Taiwan’s military of carrying out cyberattacks and espionage against the mainland. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://eng.mod.gov.cn/xb/News_213114/TopStories/16375392.html&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; Mar. 17, the MSS identified the suspects as members of Taiwan’s Information, Communications, and Electronic Force Command (ICEFCOM) within the defense ministry. It released their names, headshots, birthdates and job titles. Beijing claims that ICEFCOM has been conducting cyber operations since 2023, targeting key infrastructure in China, including power grids, water supplies and telecommunications networks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://therecord.media/china-taiwan-hacks-identify-cyber&quot;&gt;Full Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://eng.mod.gov.cn/xb/News_213114/TopStories/16375392.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cybersecurityventures:67daa8a0cadd0c032e70bf11</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>