<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Latest News | KBS WORLD</title><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_today.htm?lang=e</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.thzu.xyz/kbs/today" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Latest News | KBS WORLD - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:25:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>US Fed Keeps Key Interest Rate Unchanged</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250320070054_81_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;US Fed Keeps Key Interest Rate Unchanged&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The U.S. Federal Reserve has decided to keep its key interest rate unchanged citing uncertainties around economic conditions.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
After a two-day meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee(FOMC), the Fed said in a statement Wednesday that it decided to maintain its key lending rate at the current range of four-point-25 percent to four-point-five percent.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The move comes after the Fed left rates at that level at its previous meeting in January.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Fed appears to have frozen the rates as it weighs growing uncertainty from U.S. President Donald Trump’s tariff and fiscal policy and stubborn inflation data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
According to the FOMC’s latest economic projections, central bank policymakers are forecasting two 25-basis-point interest rate cuts this year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The latest move kept the one-point-75 percentage point gap between the Fed’s rate and that of the Bank of Korea.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191745</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191745</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:12:36 GMT</pubDate><category></category></item><item><title>State Dept.: US Looks Forward Continued, Robust Cooperation with S. Korea on Scientific Research</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250320070225_97_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;State Dept.: US Looks Forward Continued, Robust Cooperation with S. Korea on Scientific Research&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The U.S. State Department says that the U.S. looks forward to &quot;continued and robust&quot; scientific research cooperation with South Korea amid concerns that the Energy Department&#39;s designation of South Korea as a &quot;sensitive country&quot; will undermine bilateral cooperation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Tammy Bruce, the spokesperson for the State Department, issued the position in a press briefing on Wednesday when asked why the Energy Department put South Korea on the &quot;Sensitive and Other Designated Countries List.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Bruce referred the matter to the Energy Department, saying that that’s the department’s designation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The spokesperson then reiterated that the United States greatly values its close relationship with South on scientific research collaboration, and it looks forward to “continued, robust cooperation.”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Energy Department recently announced that the previous Biden administration added South Korea to the list in early January, with the designation set to take effect April 15.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Countries on the list should acquire prior approval from the department to visit facilities or affiliated research institutions under the department, or to conduct joint research with these institutions.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191744</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191744</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:09:46 GMT</pubDate><category></category></item></channel></rss>