<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All - KBS WORLD</title><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_list.htm?lang=e</link><atom:link href="http://rss.owo.nz/kbs/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>All - KBS WORLD - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Gov&#39;t to Look into Exempting Fatal Malpractice Punishment for Medical Professionals following Settlement with Family</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319073644_33_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gov&#39;t to Look into Exempting Fatal Malpractice Punishment for Medical Professionals following Settlement with Family  &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The government will look into exempting medical professionals from criminal punishment over fatal malpractice in essential medicine if they settle with the bereaved family.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Such a review was included in the government&#39;s second-phase health care reform plan approved by the special reform committee on Wednesday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The government plans to set up a special judicial system for medical malpractice, under which medical professionals who complete mediation or reach settlement with the patient or the family could be exempt from punishment.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The government will also establish a medical malpractice review committee to reinforce judicial protection in essential medicine, comprising some 20 members representing the medical community, patients and the judiciary.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Medical institutions will be subject to mandatory insurance against malpractice, while the government is set to introduce insurance products with increased public compensation.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191743</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191743</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:36:31 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Court Yet to Announce Pres. Yoon&#39;s Impeachment Ruling Date, Ruling Unlikely to be Made This Week</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319072721_80_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Court Yet to Announce Pres. Yoon&#39;s Impeachment Ruling Date, Ruling Unlikely to be Made This Week&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The Constitutional Court did not announce the ruling date in President Yoon Suk Yeol&#39;s impeachment trial on Wednesday, raising speculation that its decision will likely be made next week at the earliest.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An official at the court said while the eight justices on the bench deliberated on the case earlier in the day, no ruling date would be notified to Yoon and the National Assembly&#39;s respective legal teams on Wednesday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The ruling is not likely to come this week as the court customarily notifies the date two to three days in advance for adjustment of scheduling at nearby schools for safety reasons.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The court had completed argument procedures in Yoon&#39;s trial on February 25, with 22 days having passed since.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The impeachment rulings of former presidents Roh Moo-hyun and Park Geun-hye were made 14 and eleven days, respectively, after the end of argument hearings.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191742</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191742</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:26:12 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>FM Cho: US&#39; &#39;Sensitive Country&#39; Designation Not Linked to Calls for Nuclear Armament, DP Chief&#39;s Pro-China Views</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319070617_33_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FM Cho: US&#39; &#39;Sensitive Country&#39; Designation Not Linked to Calls for Nuclear Armament, DP Chief&#39;s Pro-China Views &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                Foreign Minister Cho Tae-yul said the U.S. has affirmed that the Energy Department&#39;s designation of South Korea as a &quot;sensitive country&quot; is not linked to calls within the country&#39;s ruling camp&amp;nbsp;for nuclear armament&amp;nbsp;or pro-China views held by main opposition leader Lee Jae-myung.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
At a session of the National Assembly&#39;s Legislation and Judiciary Committee on Wednesday, Cho said Washington publicly confirmed that the designation was part of its technical security concern, and that it would be the most appropriate to handle the matter likewise.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The minister added that he had not heard from the U.S. that the designation was decided because of an involvement by the South Korean government and that the details are expected to be revealed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
While acknowledging that he was sternly considering the designation, Cho said it was being taken in a more serious manner than its actuality.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The minister also said that Industry and Energy Minister Ahn Duk-geun&#39;s visit to the U.S. in the near future for talks with his American counterpart is expected to offer an important opportunity for a possible withdrawal.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191741</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191741</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:02:40 GMT</pubDate><category>International</category></item><item><title>S. Korea, EU to Seek Inaugural Session of Bilateral Security and Defense Dialogue in H1</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319065934_21_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;S. Korea, EU to Seek Inaugural Session of Bilateral Security and Defense Dialogue in H1&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                South Korea and the European Union(EU) will seek to hold an inaugural session of their bilateral security and defense dialogue in the first half of the year, following the establishment of their security and defense partnership last November.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
According to Seoul’s foreign ministry on Wednesday, First Vice Foreign Minister Kim Hong-kyun discussed the matter with Belén Martínez Carbonell, secretary general of the European External Action Service(EEAS), in Brussels.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
At the time, the two sides solidified the partnership and elevated the dialogue to involve director-general level officials from Seoul’s foreign and defense ministries, as well as managing director-level officials from the EU and agreed to hold talks on an annual basis.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
They agreed to bolster cooperation in the defense industry, disarmament, nonproliferation and space.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
During talks with the EEAS chief, the vice minister also expressed serious concerns over the illegal military cooperation between North Korea and Russia, as well as North Korea’s nuclear and missile development, stressing the importance of a unified and stern response from the international community.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191740</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191740</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 09:58:49 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Documentation of Jeju April 3 Uprising, S. Korea&#39;s Post-War Reconstruction Expected to be Included in UNESCO Memory of the World</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319065143_32_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Documentation of Jeju April 3 Uprising, S. Korea&#39;s Post-War Reconstruction Expected to be Included in UNESCO Memory of the World&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                Records of the April 3 Jeju Uprising and South Korea&#39;s post-Korean War reconstruction are expected to be included in UNESCO&#39;s Memory of the World program.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
According to UNESCO on Wednesday, the Memory of the World International Advisory Committee recently recommended the inclusion of records that document the April 3 Incident and post-war reforestation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The archives of the April 3 Uprising, including court documents, news reports and investigation findings, detail the massacre of Jeju islanders during the government&#39;s efforts to quell the armed conflict between March 1, 1947 and September 21, 1954.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The records on reforestation document the government and private sector efforts to restore the nation&#39;s forests and rebuild the nation after the Korean War.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A final decision on the inclusion is expected at next month&#39;s session of UNESCO&#39;s executive board.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If both sets of records are approved, South Korea will have 20 inscriptions on the UNESCO list.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191739</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191739</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 09:50:19 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Committee Passes Bills to Invoke 2014 Independent Prosecutor Act for Allegations on First Lady, Drug Probe Intervention</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319063620_63_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Committee Passes Bills to Invoke 2014 Independent Prosecutor Act for Allegations on First Lady, Drug Probe Intervention&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The National Assembly&#39;s Legislation and Judiciary Committee passed bills to invoke the 2014 Act on the Appointment of Independent Prosecutor for allegations surrounding first lady Kim Keon-hee and the top office&#39;s alleged intervention in a drug smuggling investigation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The opposition unilaterally passed the bills on Wednesday amid a boycott by the ruling People Power Party(PPP), with PPP Rep. Song Seog-jun saying any special prosecutor probe should be conducted only when the prosecution&#39;s investigation is carried out either abnormally or unfairly.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
DP Rep. Seo Young-kyo said the independent prosecutor probe should be conducted as it concerns those currently in power, claiming that President Yoon Suk Yeol illegally declared martial law in December to evade the investigation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The bill on the first lady includes her alleged involvement in stock manipulation at Deutsche Motors and Sambu Construction, alleged acceptance of a luxury bag, and allegations surrounding the relocation of the presidential office.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The other bill is about an incident in January 2023, when customs officials at Incheon International Airport were suspected of assisting members of a Malaysian drug ring smuggle&amp;nbsp;methamphetamine, after which the top office allegedly exercised undue influence in the police investigation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
While the opposition plans to put the bills to a plenary vote on Thursday, it could be turned down through a presidential veto.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191738</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191738</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:55:26 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Monetary Board Member: Housing Transaction Permit Revival Could Work in Favor of Future Monetary Policy</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319063603_71_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monetary Board Member: Housing Transaction Permit Revival Could Work in Favor of Future Monetary Policy&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                A member of the Bank of Korea&#39;s(BOK) monetary policy board mentioned the rising housing prices as a major economic variable, saying Seoul City&#39;s revival of a permit system for housing transactions in the city&#39;s four affluent districts could work in favor of future monetary policy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Meeting with local reporters on Wednesday, BOK monetary policy board member Chang Yong-sung said if the latest permit revival helps bring down household debt, it would facilitate future monetary policy decisions.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Chang said there have been concerns over the foreign exchange rate, housing prices and household debt, adding that related trends should continue to be monitored.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In response to criticism that the central bank had run late in cutting the interest rate last year, the board member said although the real economy had weakened, an early cut could have accelerated the rise in housing prices.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Projecting that the future rate cut would be made to the point where it does not affect price stability, if concerns over home prices and household debt escalate, the board would have no other choice but to return to considering a rate hike.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191737</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191737</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:47:57 GMT</pubDate><category>Economy</category></item><item><title>Science Ministry: ‘Sensitive Country’ Designation Won’t Affect Tech Cooperation with US</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319054056_21_e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Science Ministry: ‘Sensitive Country’ Designation Won’t Affect Tech Cooperation with US &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The Ministry of Science and ICT reaffirmed that the U.S. Energy Department’s designation of South Korea as a “sensitive country” has not sparked any issues in bilateral cooperation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Meeting with state-run research institutes on Wednesday, First Vice Science and ICT Minister Lee Chang-yune said the department has assured the ministry that the matter will not interfere with science and technology cooperation between the two countries.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The vice minister said the department has also expressed its intent to continue such cooperation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Lee said his ministry is actively consulting with the White House, the Energy Department and the State Department while remaining in constant communication with Seoul’s foreign, energy and finance ministries.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The vice minister said he expects Industry and Energy Minister Ahn Duk-geun to convey the opinions of relevant ministries when he meets with U.S. Secretary of Energy Chris Wright during Ahn’s second visit to Washington in less than a month.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191736</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191736</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:30:41 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Financial Watchdog Launches Investigation of Homeplus’ Major Shareholder</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250304025107_1_k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Financial Watchdog Launches Investigation of Homeplus’ Major Shareholder &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                The Financial Supervisory Service(FSS) is launching an investigation into MBK Partners, the major shareholder of Homeplus, in connection with the company’s decision to file for court rehabilitation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Lee Bok-hyun, governor of the FSS, told reporters on Wednesday that the investigation would begin the same day.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This marks the first time the financial watchdog has launched an investigation into a private equity fund in relation to a specific case.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Under the Capital Markets Act, the head of the FSS is authorized to inspect the operations and financial situation of institutional private collective investment vehicles if necessary to maintain the stability of the financial markets or to ensure sound trading practices.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
According to the FSS governor, the investigation will not be limited to the timing of Homeplus’ credit rating downgrade or its application for court-led rehabilitation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Lee added that the FSS will form a task force to focus on the matter during the first half of the year.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191735</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191735</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:17:41 GMT</pubDate><category>Economy</category></item><item><title>‘When Life Gives You Tangerines’ No. 2 on Netflix List of Non-English Shows</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;img_box top&quot; id=&quot;ele1&quot;&gt;&lt;!-- 상단 고정 이미지는 class &quot;top&quot;이 들어감 --&gt;
                    &lt;div class=&quot;photo no-print&quot;&gt;
                        &lt;img src=&quot;http://worldimg.kbs.co.kr/src/images/news/202503/250319024531_89_k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;‘When Life Gives You Tangerines’ No. 2 on Netflix List of Non-English Shows &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p class=&quot;cap no-print&quot;&gt;Photo : YONHAP News&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;

                
                                “When Life Gives You Tangerines” has ranked second on Netflix’s list of Global Top 10 Non-English Shows.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The streaming service announced on Wednesday that the romance saga, starring Park Bo-gum and IU, drew six million viewing hours since it first aired March 7.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The series also made Netflix’s list of the ten most watched shows in 41 countries, including Brazil, Chile, Mexico and Türkiye.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The drama depicts the lives of Ae-sun, a woman born on Jeju Island in the 1960s, and her husband, Gwan-sik.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The show has gained popularity for its strong dialogue and sets that recall the scenery of Jeju Island in the 1960s and Seoul in the 1980s.
                &lt;!-- Key word --&gt;
                                &lt;!-- //Key word --&gt;
            </description><link>http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191734</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://world.kbs.co.kr/service/news_view.htm?lang=e&amp;Seq_Code=191734</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:03:21 GMT</pubDate><category>Culture</category></item></channel></rss>