<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Fortnite News</title><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news?lang=en-US</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.pseudoyu.com/fortnite/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Fortnite News - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:20:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Not Clixbait: Clix Joins the Fortnite Icon Series!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You watched him qualify for the Fortnite World Cup at just 14 years old, and then evolve into one of the biggest Fortnite Twitch streamers in the world. Now, it’s time to witness &lt;strong&gt;Clix&lt;/strong&gt; make Fortnite history once more as he joins the Icon Series!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Clix Outfit&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-clix-outfit-1920x1080-2a4ed1482e81.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A range of Clix-inspired items hit the Shop on March 22, 2025, at 8 PM ET — including the &lt;strong&gt;Clix Outfit&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Clix Bear Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt;, and a sparky surprise…&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Can’t wait ‘til then? Prove you’ve got skills that rival Fortnite’s latest Icon in the &lt;strong&gt;Clix Icon Cup&lt;/strong&gt; on March 21 to unlock Clix’s items early!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Click on Clix’s New Island&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of his Icon Series debut, Clix brings an all-new island to Fortnite in partnership with Sloth Games:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Clix Tycoon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Clix Tycoon Island&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-clix-tycoon-island-1920x1080-6c0697866c69.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In this tycoon game, experience the life of a Fortnite Icon! Become a young aspiring content creator, earning followers and developing a streaming career.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
To help you out with this, practice your Fortnite skills! You can test your aim in the Aim Trainer, practice your mechanics in the Edit Course, take your talents to the in-game Box Fights Arena, and more.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
As you earn money, followers, and subscribers, you’ll be able to upgrade your house, acquire a vacation home, buy new cars, enhance your stream setup, and even create your own gaming org!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Ready to live like Clix? Jump in with island code &lt;strong&gt;9730-2169-8778&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;starting March 20 Eastern Time&lt;span style=&quot;color:#000000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:14.6667px; white-space-collapse:preserve&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You can also check out his new Red vs Blue island — made in partnership with Creator Corp — with island code &lt;strong&gt;1929-3496-7173 &lt;/strong&gt;starting March 21 Eastern Time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Refine Your Style with Clix’s Shop Items!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re going for casual comfort or pro-level professionalism, Clix’s Icon Series launch has a wardrobe option to suit. When it&#39;s time to make a statement, the&lt;strong&gt; Clix Outfit’s&lt;/strong&gt; default Style delivers effortless sophistication. And for when you’re going for chill rather than champion, opt for relaxation with the&lt;strong&gt; Gamer Clix Style&lt;/strong&gt;. Here&#39;s a look at both Styles:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Do Not Share&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/do-not-share-1920x1080-e87deecceb0f.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
oops wrong… renders&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Clix Outfit Gamer Clix Style And Default Style&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-clix-outfit-gamer-clix-style-and-default-style-1920x1080-5dbe50d3499e.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;clix getting ready for a family wedding vs. clix when there’s a new battle royale season&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Clix Outfit has additional customization options: toggle Clix’s glasses on or off, and even put a bunny-shaped mask on.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It’s not just Clix who has a highly-adaptable sense of style… The &lt;strong&gt;Clix Bear Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt; is both cuddly AND sharply dressed. But why should looking flashy be reserved for just your clothing? Bring some extra wow factor with the &lt;strong&gt;Chain Linx Wrap&lt;/strong&gt; which glows whenever you fire your weapon!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Looking for Emotes? Refuse to throw in the towel with the &lt;strong&gt;Soggy Snap Emote&lt;/strong&gt;, and show off some signature moves with the &lt;strong&gt;Clix Groove Emote&lt;/strong&gt;. Finally, when you’re &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wiping the floor with the competition, you’ll wanna swing the &lt;strong&gt;2-Ply TP Hammer Pickaxe&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Clix Bear Back Bling, 2-Ply TP Hammer Pickaxe, Soggy Snap Emote, Clix Groove Emote, and Chain Linx Wrap&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-clix-bear-back-bling-2-ply-tp-hammer-pickaxe-soggy-snap-emote-clix-groove-emote-and-chain-linx-wrap-1920x1080-bced96a7de92.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;nbsp;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ignite the Spark&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, there’s an extra surprise coming to the Shop! Clix’s debut into the Icon Series wouldn’t be complete without a remix of his favorite Outfit, Sparkplug. This sophisticated take on Sparkplug — the&lt;strong&gt; Sparx Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; — will be in the Shop at the same time as Clix! Scrap the competition, elegantly.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Sharp Sparx Outfit&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-sharp-sparx-outfit-1920x1080-8bd3b9071ea8.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Even when looking Fancy, Fs in the chat are never one’s goal. Take control of the keys with the &lt;strong&gt;Clixy Keys Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt; also in the Shop!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Clixy Keys Back Bling&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-clixy-keys-back-bling-1920x1080-a6aa41ee39a0.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
All of the Clix items mentioned above will be available individually or in the Clix Bundle. (This bundle also has an Emoticon!) Get ready to suit up.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Make It Look Easy in the Clix Icon Cup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clix has been making his mark in the Fortnite Competitive scene since 2019, but now it’s time for YOU to show off your skills in the Clix Icon Cup! Gather your most talented teammates and fight for one of the top spots in this Trios Battle Royale event on March 21.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The top points-earning trios in each region will be awarded the &lt;strong&gt;entire Clix Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; before it hits the Shop! Trios who place within the second-highest tier in each region will unlock the Sparx Outfit. In addition, all teams who earn at least eight points will unlock the &lt;strong&gt;Dr3amin Spray&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Dr3amin Spray&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-dr3amin-spray-1920x1080-8bc2b06c68dd.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Competitors can play up to ten matches within their region’s three-hour time window, and the specific event timing for each region can be found in the “Compete” tab in-game. Scoring will follow the format below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Match Placement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victory Royale: 65 points&lt;br&gt;
2nd: 54 points&lt;br&gt;
3rd: 48 points&lt;br&gt;
4th: 44 points&lt;br&gt;
5th: 40 points&lt;br&gt;
6th: 36 points&lt;br&gt;
7th: 33 points&lt;br&gt;
8th: 30 points&lt;br&gt;
9th: 27 points&lt;br&gt;
10th: 24 points&lt;br&gt;
11th: 21 points&lt;br&gt;
12th: 18 points&lt;br&gt;
13th: 15 points&lt;br&gt;
14th: 12 points&lt;br&gt;
15th: 9 points&lt;br&gt;
16th: 6 points&lt;br&gt;
17th: 3 points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Each Elimination&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 point&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Among other requirements, players must have Two-Factor Authentication enabled and verified on their Epic account, and be at Account Level 50 or above to participate. (You can find your Account Level in Fortnite Battle Royale’s “Career” tab.) Players with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/cabinedaccounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cabined Accounts&lt;/a&gt; are not eligible to take part in this tournament.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the full details and requirements, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/competitive/news/clix-icon-cup-official-rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clix Icon Cup Official Rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It all clicks together in the Icon Series this month. Jump into the Clix Icon Cup on March 21, and look out for his items entering the Shop on March 22!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/not-clixbait-clix-joins-the-fortnite-icon-series?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/not-clixbait-clix-joins-the-fortnite-icon-series?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 21:58:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Fortnite Party Up - Spring Raid: Unlock the Dupli-Kate Outfit!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Just like superheroes, it’s time to assemble.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Welcome to &lt;strong&gt;Fortnite Party Up - Spring Raid&lt;/strong&gt;, where you get to explore Fortnite experiences with friends AND earn Locker items. It takes the power of friendship to unlock a one-woman army: the final item is the &lt;strong&gt;Dupli-Kate Outfit&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Dupli-Kate Outfit&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-dupli-kate-outfit-1920x1080-d44026b5129d.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
The raid starts &lt;strong&gt;NOW&lt;/strong&gt; and ends March 31, 2025, at 9 AM ET. Prepare to spring into action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It’s Mad Out There&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Island full of heisters? A world full of brick monsters? Games made out of creators’ wildest dreams? Fortnite is in need of some heroes. Every day until March 22, a new &lt;strong&gt;Party Up - Spring Raid Quest&lt;/strong&gt; will unlock for you and your party to complete. The Quests will alternate between:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earning a certain amount of XP in creator-made experiences in a party with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earning a certain amount of XP in “By Epic” experiences in a party with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
The creator-made and “By Epic” experiences you play are up to you, so raid where you please! It may seem obvious, but a “By Epic” experience is a Fortnite experience published by Epic, while a “creator-made experience” is a Fortnite experience NOT published by Epic. There are tons of creator-made experiences you can explore in the Discover screen!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Party Up - Spring Raid Quests will be completable until March 31 at 9 AM ET.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Field of Dreamflowers Loading Screen&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-field-of-dreamflowers-loading-screen-1920x1080-acd233a692ed.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Field of Dreamflowers Loading Screen. It’s one of the Spring Raid rewards, man.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
All the Spring Raid Rewards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more Party Up - Spring Raid Quests you complete, the more rewards you and your party will unlock in Fortnite. These rewards also include matching accessories for Dupli-Kate!&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Shrinking Rae Back Bling, Duplicating Batons Pickaxe, and Duplikates Emote&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-shrinking-rae-back-bling-duplicating-batons-pickaxe-and-duplikates-emote-1920x1080-27ba0011c2be.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Matching accessories for Dupli-Kate: the Shrinking Rae Back Bling, Duplicating Batons Pickaxe, and Duplikates Emote.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
A little Axo goes axolotl way (wow that was a stretch), which is why Spring Raid has more rewards like the &lt;strong&gt;Axo’s Big Moment Spray&lt;/strong&gt; and other music-themed items.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Axo’s Big Moment Spray, Song Bubble Emoticon, and Party Beats Spray&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-axos-big-moment-spray-song-bubble-emoticon-and-party-beats-spray-1920x1080-6056b9f8f5e6.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Axo’s Big Moment Spray, Song Bubble Emoticon, and Party Beats Spray.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Here’s a breakdown of what you can unlock and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 1 Party Up - Spring Raid Quest: &lt;strong&gt;“Through the Fire and Flames” Jam Track by DragonForce&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 2 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Axo&#39;s Big Moment Spray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 3 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Shrinking Rae Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 4 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Party Beats Spray&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 5 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Field of Dreamflowers Loading Screen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 6 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Duplicating Batons Pickaxe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 7 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Song Bubble Emoticon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 8 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Duplikates Emote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete 9 Party Up - Spring Raid Quests: &lt;strong&gt;Dupli-Kate Outfit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Through the Fire and Flames Jam Track&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-through-the-fire-and-flames-jam-track-1920x1080-848f2c31a38b.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Through the Fire and Flames Jam Track. (this song’s super easy right?)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
As a heads-up, all the Party Up - Spring Raid rewards may be available for purchase in the Fortnite Shop at a later date. Also, the “Through the Fire and Flames” Jam Track contains vocals that may not be suitable in all experiences. In experiences below a certain rating threshold, you’ll only be able to use non-Vox loops when jamming.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Thanks for being one of the Guardians of Fortnite!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0k842g2Bq_I?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-party-up-spring-raid-unlock-the-dupli-kate-outfit?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-party-up-spring-raid-unlock-the-dupli-kate-outfit?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 12:59:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>The Getaway LTM and Outlaw Midas Come to Fortnite Battle Royale v34.10!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The gilded man with the golden touch is back and badder than ever! &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Midas&lt;/strong&gt; has arrived with v34.10 along with the updated Getaway LTM, a slew of new weapons in the Black Market, and the return of Siphon in Ranked. Let’s get down to &lt;s&gt;brass&lt;/s&gt; gold tacks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Make Out Like a Bandit in the Getaway LTM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Qh3D3rJ5Rkw?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Getaway limited-time mode&lt;/strong&gt; is returning from Chapter 1! From now until April 1 Eastern Time, retrieve one of four Crystal Llamas &lt;strong&gt;(Jewels)&lt;/strong&gt; on the map as a duo or 4-player squad, and successfully extract them in one of the Island’s three &lt;strong&gt;Getaway Vans&lt;/strong&gt;. The first three teams to make their way to a van win! You can also win in traditional Battle Royale style, by eliminating all other teams.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Holding a Jewel will cause you to move slower and show on the map for other players. But on the flip side, holding a Jewel will restore your Health and Shield over time! The Getaway LTM is live now with Build and Zero Build options — play Duos or Squads in unranked or… &lt;strong&gt;Ranked&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is our first Ranked LTM and there are a few differences from other Ranked experiences. Namely, each member of your team will receive a large bonus to their rank for extracting a Jewel, and rank progression from each match is increased. The progress you make in Ranked Getaway will not unlock Styles for existing Ranked rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Earn Your Place in the Outlaw Faction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baron Fletcher Kane is levying a hefty tax on all vending machines and paid porta-potties. It’s up to you all to put an end to his insatiable greed! v34.10 introduces a new Quest, where the community is tasked to collectively drain Fletcher Kane of his resources by stealing Bars from his banks and from stashes around the Island.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Once the Quest is complete, all players will earn a basic membership to the Outlaw faction, which comes with its own upgradable &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Keycard&lt;/strong&gt;. With your Outlaw Keycard, you’ll gain access to the backroom of Black Markets around the Island! Complete &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Keycard Quests&lt;/strong&gt; to upgrade your card and gain access to more services and Exotic new weaponry. Here’s what you get with each upgrade:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncommon Outlaw Keycard&lt;/strong&gt;: Gain access to Black Market backrooms, where you can purchase Exotic items. Some Black Market backrooms also have muscle for hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rare Outlaw Keycard&lt;/strong&gt;: You’ll be able to open an Outlaw Chest in Black Market backrooms for free Bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epic Outlaw Keycard&lt;/strong&gt;: You’ll be able to buy premium loadouts from each Black Market shopkeeper for a significant amount of Bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skillet’s Loadout&lt;/strong&gt; - Sticky Grenade Launcher, Mammoth Pistol, Kneecapper, Chug Jug, Gold Ammo Boon, and Greed Boon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keisha’s Loadout&lt;/strong&gt; - Falcon Eye Sniper, Outlaw Shotgun, Gold Splashes, Chug Jug, Gold Ammo Boon, and Greed Boon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joss’&amp;nbsp;Loadout&lt;/strong&gt; - Holo Twister AR, Pump &amp;amp; Dump, Rocket Drill, Chug Jug, Gold Ammo Boon, and Greed Boon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legendary Outlaw Keycard&lt;/strong&gt;: Outlaw Chests in Black Market backrooms will also drop a Legendary item and a Dill Bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Once you’ve got those Black Market backrooms open, you’ll find new Exotic Items for sale, hot off the back of a truck. The following weapons will be available in exchange for Dill Bits!&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawless Slap Cannon:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fire healing Slap at your allies to restore their Health and&amp;nbsp;Shield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawless Blink Pump &amp;amp; Dump:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Grants a few seconds of Zero Point Dash after reloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawless Stink Rifle:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Unleashes a stink cloud on impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawless Shockwave Rocket Launcher:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fires a projectile that explodes to impulse anyone nearby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawless Trinity Assault Rifle:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Fires four shots in a triangle pattern, at the cost of a decreased fire rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lawless Heavy Impact Tracking Rifle:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Briefly reveals the location of players and Chests around the impact point of your shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Slap Cannon Pump And Dump Stink Rifle Shockwave Rocket Launcher Trinity Assault Rifle Heavy Impact Tracking Rifle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-slap-cannon-pump-and-dump-stink-rifle-shockwave-rocket-launcher-trinity-assault-rifle-heavy-impact-tracking-rifle-1920x1080-df8fdf3a4373.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Dropping from Chests around the Island outside of Black Markets are the &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Shotgun&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Rocket Drill&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s also Big Dill’s fave — the regular &lt;strong&gt;Pump &amp;amp; Dump&lt;/strong&gt;. Occupying a single weapon slot, you can now hold a Shotgun in one hand and an SMG in the other!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Outlaw Shotgun Rocket Drill Pump And Dump&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-outlaw-shotgun-rocket-drill-pump-and-dump-1920x1080-e28710c2c0c3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Siphon Returns in Ranked&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siphon, which partially heals you when you eliminate an opponent, is returning to Ranked Battle Royale and Zero Build for the remainder of LAWLESS! Like current competitive tournaments — every time you eliminate an opponent in a Ranked Battle Royale or Zero Build match, you’ll now gain 75 Health over five seconds. Siphon is not enabled in Ranked OG, Reload, or Getaway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Unlock the Infamous Outlaw Midas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The glittering, SHADOWY gunslinger is here! Starting now, owners of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/battle-pass&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LAWLESS Battle Pass&lt;/a&gt; will be able to unlock the &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Midas Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; by earning 10 Account Levels. You can work towards this goal by earning XP from any experience!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lawless Outlaw Midas&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lawless-outlaw-midas-1920x1080-9cfce154cf20.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
By meeting other Account Level goals, you can unlock matching accessories like the &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw’s Knife Rack Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the Outlaw’s Whipknives Pickaxe, Bullet Rider Glider, Outlaw&#39;s Mugshot Emote, and more. Keep meeting the goals to unlock Outlaw Midas’ &lt;strong&gt;Gunslinger&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;SHADOW&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;GHOST&lt;/strong&gt; Styles! These goals will be completable until Fortnite Battle Royale Chapter 6 Season 2: LAWLESS ends May 2, 2025 Eastern Time.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lawless Outlaws Knife Rack Back Bling Outlaws Whipknives Pickaxe Bullet Rider Glider Outlaws Mugshot Emote&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lawless-outlaws-knife-rack-back-bling-outlaws-whipknives-pickaxe-bullet-rider-glider-outlaws-mugshot-emote-1920x1080-eb15a349bd66.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Get ready for the Getaway Van — v34.10 is dropping now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/the-getaway-ltm-and-outlaw-midas-come-to-fortnite-battle-royale-v34-10?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/the-getaway-ltm-and-outlaw-midas-come-to-fortnite-battle-royale-v34-10?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Fortnite Ballistic v34.10 - Early Access Development Update</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Ballistic players,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Today’s v34.10 update includes several improvements and fixes, with more to come in v34.20 later in March. We’ve also got an update on our near-future plans for Ballstic, which includes new maps, weapons, and gadgets dropping in April.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Early Access Development Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we shared recently, we want to get new updates for Ballistic into your hands faster. One way we’re planning to accomplish this is by adding new maps to Ballistic as &lt;strong&gt;shells &lt;/strong&gt;— fully designed layouts but without all the environmental details that you might expect. This will allow us to bring two new maps to Ballistic in April. Expect new weapons and gadgets in April as well!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the new maps, we’ll examine how players move, rotate, and use sightlines during matches to inform how we fine-tune each. We’re also continuing to iterate on the Skyline 10 map and are looking for more feedback there.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Speaking of feedback, send us your thoughts! You can share your input by completing an in-game post-match survey, or by posting on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/FortNiteBR/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Battle Royale subreddit&lt;/a&gt; (which we’re currently using for Ballistic) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/fortnite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;English Fortnite Discord&lt;/a&gt;. Right now, we’re specifically looking for feedback on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mode timings (Such as Round timer, Buy Phase timer, Detonation timer, Defuse timer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing weapons and gadgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movement and shooting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Skyline 10 map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credit economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI/UX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The time it takes for us to act on feedback depends on what we’re trying to change. Value changes, such as adjusting fire rate, magazine size, or the time it takes for the Rift Point Device to be planted or detonated, are all simple updates we can turn around rather quickly. Larger updates, such as changing a map&#39;s layout or how a gadget works, will take longer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In our next blog post later in March, we’ll discuss some of the feedback we received during this round and how we plan to address it. Until then, let us know how you’re feeling about the improvements and fixes below going live with v34.10 today. (You can use the in-game survey to let us know!)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Let&#39;s start with a major pain point. Matches starting with uneven teams are not fun — we know! Beginning with v34.10, we&#39;ve made an adjustment so that &lt;strong&gt;matches will no longer begin unless the lobby is full&lt;/strong&gt; (5v5). If the lobby is unable to fill, all players will return to the main menu and restart matchmaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Other Improvements and Fixes - v34.10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made improvements to server/client data exchange to prevent elim-trading (players can no longer eliminate each other at the same time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where players could lose control of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where sliding visual effects and sound effects would persist after sliding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where weapons with optics would appear as held higher up compared to those without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where the light reflection off of weapons would not appear correctly when going around corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed a visual issue where eliminated players would appear to have full HP in the top Player Bar when spectating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed a visual issue where weapon attachments disappeared when the weapon holder stood too close to a wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed a visual issue on mobile devices that would sometimes occur when throwing a flashbang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed a visual inconsistency related to weapon recoil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed a typo on the &quot;Time&#39;s Up&quot; message at the end of a round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polished some aspects of animation related to players moving left and right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implemented several technical performance improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-ballistic-v34-10-early-access-development-update?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-ballistic-v34-10-early-access-development-update?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Shohei Ohtani Plays Fastball in the Fortnite Icon Series!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Batter up!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Just in time for the beginning of the MLB season, &lt;strong&gt;Shohei Ohtani&lt;/strong&gt; is giving this whole Fortnite thing a swing as he joins the Icon Series. Take “#17” aboard your Locker when his Outfits and accessories enter the Shop at 8 PM ET on March… 17! Think you’re ready for the big leagues? Compete in the &lt;strong&gt;Shohei Ohtani Cup&lt;/strong&gt; on March 15 for an opportunity to unlock one of his Outfits early ⚾&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Open the Record Book with Shohei Ohtani Quests!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Shohei Ohtani Quests&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-shohei-ohtani-quests-1920x1080-a3c70453b99d.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
To celebrate Shohei’s Icon Series debut, the Week 4 Quests in Battle Royale will be all about baseball and Shohei&#39;s historic 50/50 season! These Quests will drop &lt;strong&gt;March 18 Eastern Time&lt;/strong&gt; and last until Chapter 6 Season 2 ends:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish 3 matches in the Top 17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eliminate 3 players beyond 50 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw 17 items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deal 54 damage to opponents with The Kneecapper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel 59 units of distance while sliding continuously.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these Quests award XP, helping you level up in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/battle-pass&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Battle Pass&lt;/a&gt; and any other Pass you may own! Get ready to step up to the plate in Week 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Shohei Slides into the Shop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Shohei Ohtani Outfit, Decoy Back Bling, and Trusty Two-Way Pickaxe&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-shohei-ohtani-outfit-decoy-back-bling-and-trusty-two-way-pickaxe-1920x1080-5003b629e068.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The bases are loaded, and so is your next Locker preset! Donning the Dodgers uniform, the &lt;strong&gt;Shohei Ohtani Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; has three Styles: white for home, grey for away, and a LEGO Style for LEGO Fortnite.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It’s good to have a good boy by your side whether you’re home or away, which is why there’s also the &lt;strong&gt;Decoy Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt; — a bobblehead based on Shohei’s dog Decoy! If you don’t think it gets more classic baseball than bobbleheads, the &lt;strong&gt;Trusty Two-Way Pickaxe&lt;/strong&gt; based on a pitching machine will hit different.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Shohei &lt;u&gt;Slices&lt;/u&gt; into the Shop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Samurai Shohei Outfit, Samurai Screamer Back Bling, and Baseball Batana Pickaxe&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-samurai-shohei-outfit-samurai-screamer-back-bling-and-baseball-batana-pickaxe-1920x1080-7682c1918237.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In the wind-up to the Tokyo Series, Shohei steals the show with a high heat samurai suit. Equip the reactive &lt;strong&gt;Samurai Shohei Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; and watch the pitching arm become fiery after you get elims in a match! Or, go past the outfield wall into a LEGO experience and use Samurai Shohei’s LEGO Style.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Speaking of fiery, there are two ways to make a baseball screamin’ hot: throwing it really fast (like physically impossible fast) and eliminating people in Fortnite. The reactive &lt;strong&gt;Samurai Screamer Back Bling&lt;/strong&gt; will turn fiery after you get eliminations in a match! Also in the Shop, pick up the &lt;strong&gt;Baseball Batana Pickaxe&lt;/strong&gt; and farm for mats like you’re uppin’ your batting average.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Emotes for the Seventh-Inning Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Doggy Dingers Emote and Hey Batter Batter Emote&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-doggy-dingers-emote-and-hey-batter-batter-emote-1920x1080-9ef6d44a24d3.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Whether in the heat of a Battle Royale match or halfway through your Festival performance, ya gotta take a break! With the &lt;strong&gt;Doggy Dingers Emote&lt;/strong&gt;, show off your form as a Decoy bobblehead throws you balls to hit. And with the &lt;strong&gt;Hey Batter Batter Emote&lt;/strong&gt;, make positive energy appear with Shohei’s “magic wand” routine!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Shohei Ohtani Outfit, Decoy Back Bling, Trusty Two-Way Pickaxe, Samurai Shohei Outfit, Samurai Screamer Back Bling, Baseball Batana Pickaxe, Doggy Dingers Emote, and Hey Batter Batter Emote will be available in the Shop individually or in the Shohei Ohtani Bundle. Aim for the clouds after adding these items to your collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Shohei Ohtani Cup: Strive to Be an MVP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Shohei Ohtani Cup&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-shohei-ohtani-cup-1920x1080-9dd4f759ccbd.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You’re up to bat with one strike left. The fate of the game depends on your next move — make it a home run! In March 15’s &lt;strong&gt;Shohei Ohtani Cup&lt;/strong&gt;, a Solo Battle Royale tournament, the top points-earning players in each region will unlock the Samurai Shohei Outfit early. Send your rivals back to the dugout!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In this event, go the extra inning by playing up to ten matches within your region’s three-hour time window. (The specific event timing for each region can be found in the “Compete” tab in-game.) Scoring will follow the format below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Match Placement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victory Royale: 60 points&lt;br&gt;
2nd: 53 points&lt;br&gt;
3rd: 49 points&lt;br&gt;
4th: 47 points&lt;br&gt;
5th: 46 points&lt;br&gt;
6th: 45 points&lt;br&gt;
7th: 44 points&lt;br&gt;
8th: 43 points&lt;br&gt;
9th: 42 points&lt;br&gt;
10th: 41 points&lt;br&gt;
11th: 40 points&lt;br&gt;
12th: 39 points&lt;br&gt;
13th: 38 points&lt;br&gt;
14th: 37 points&lt;br&gt;
15th: 36 points&lt;br&gt;
16th: 35 points&lt;br&gt;
17th: 34 points&lt;br&gt;
18th: 33 points&lt;br&gt;
19th: 32 points&lt;br&gt;
20th: 31 points&lt;br&gt;
21st: 30 points&lt;br&gt;
22nd: 29 points&lt;br&gt;
23rd: 28 points&lt;br&gt;
24th: 27 points&lt;br&gt;
25th: 26 points&lt;br&gt;
26th: 25 points&lt;br&gt;
27th: 24 points&lt;br&gt;
28th: 23 points&lt;br&gt;
29th: 22 points&lt;br&gt;
30th: 21 points&lt;br&gt;
31st: 20 points&lt;br&gt;
32nd: 19 points&lt;br&gt;
33rd: 18 points&lt;br&gt;
34th: 17 points&lt;br&gt;
35th: 16 points&lt;br&gt;
36th: 15 points&lt;br&gt;
37th: 14 points&lt;br&gt;
38th: 13 points&lt;br&gt;
39th: 12 points&lt;br&gt;
40th: 11 points&lt;br&gt;
41st: 10 points&lt;br&gt;
42nd: 9 points&lt;br&gt;
43rd: 8 points&lt;br&gt;
44th: 7 points&lt;br&gt;
45th: 6 points&lt;br&gt;
46th: 5 points&lt;br&gt;
47th: 4 points&lt;br&gt;
48th: 3 points&lt;br&gt;
49th: 2 points&lt;br&gt;
50th: 1 point&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Each Elimination&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 points&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Among other requirements, players must have Two-Factor Authentication enabled and verified on their Epic account, and be at Account Level 50 or above to participate. (You can find your Account Level in Fortnite Battle Royale’s “Career” tab.) Players with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/cabinedaccounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cabined Accounts&lt;/a&gt; are not eligible to take part in this tournament.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For the full details and requirements, please see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/competitive/news/shohei-ohtani-cup-official-rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shohei Ohtani Cup Official Rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Aaaaaaaand like a home run, we’re outta here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jpMd-9ZYuPY?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/shohei-ohtani-plays-fastball-in-the-fortnite-icon-series?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/shohei-ohtani-plays-fastball-in-the-fortnite-icon-series?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 21:59:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>LEGO® Fortnite Updates - What to Expect in March 2025!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The world of LEGO® Fortnite expands with new updates for both &lt;strong&gt;Brick Life&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt; this March! Hit the pitch as soccer comes to Brick Life on March 11, and keep up the fight against the Storm King as improvements come to Odyssey on March 25.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Without further ado, let’s dig in… but wait a minute, what did our shovel just hit? The &lt;strong&gt;Rebel Oro Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; and more rewards await in the &lt;strong&gt;Goldrush Gallery LEGO Pass&lt;/strong&gt; arriving March 11!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
LEGO Fortnite Brick Life Updates - March 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Get off the Sidelines in Soccer!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;LEGO Fortnite Brick Life Soccer Trophy&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/lego-fortnite-brick-life-soccer-trophy-1920x1080-1a68aacaca99.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Go for the goal and slide into &lt;strong&gt;soccer&lt;/strong&gt;, or commonly called “football” around the world! At the soccer field across from &lt;strong&gt;Bobom Milk Tea&lt;/strong&gt;, score more goals than other players in a 90 second time limit. The winning player gets &lt;strong&gt;1,000 Creds&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;and a&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;trophy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;for their home!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Soccer is not a “daily activity” like Litter Boxing or Vampire Experiment, so you can win the full rewards no matter what time of day it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
React to Homes!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;LEGO Fortnite Brick Life Mailbox&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/lego-fortnite-brick-life-mailbox-1920x1080-946b43283eb5.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
See a kickin’ brick pad and wanna give kudos? Interact with a home’s mailbox and leave reactions! Whether it’s a house made entirely of toilets that makes you laugh or a maxed-out mansion that leaves you in awe, reactions let you have an influence on your favorite homes.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Reactions are visible from afar too, so you’ll be able to see Brick Bay’s most conversation-starting homes without needing to interact with their mailbox. Earn 50 Creds every time you react to a home for the first time! (Remember to be a good guest — don’t just react and dash!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Can’t Carry It? Get Mailed It!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;LEGO Fortnite Brick Life Mail&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/lego-fortnite-brick-life-mail-1920x1080-d852df6a609a.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Got the Undisputed Gloves from Litter Boxing, but don’t have room in your inventory? You don’t have to go home feline sad! Items you earn or buy will be instantly sent to your mailbox if your inventory is full.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you weren’t planning to stop back at your house, you can also use public mailboxes to get your stuff!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Keep checking your mail to see other things that may be waiting for you ✉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
45-Degree Decoratin’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not everyone likes to decorate by the book. When placing decorations in your home, you can now place them at &lt;strong&gt;45-degree angles&lt;/strong&gt; like in Odyssey. Add a new &lt;em&gt;twist&lt;/em&gt; to your interior design!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
LEGO Fortnite Odyssey Updates - March 25&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s talk about the Odyssey improvements coming later in March!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Do Your World a Favor with the Recycler!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;LEGO Fortnite Odyssey Recycler&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/lego-fortnite-odyssey-recycler-1920x1080-13c10b3382c9.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
With the new &lt;strong&gt;Recycler&lt;/strong&gt; Station, recycle crafted items to gain a portion of the used materials back. This means you can break down old Charms and weapons into resources you can reuse. Unlock the Recycler recipe by building or using a Stone Breaker starting March 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Wall Mount Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;LEGO Fortnite Odyssey Wall Mount&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/lego-fortnite-odyssey-wall-mount-1920x1080-43917939c502.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Starting March 25, you’ll be able to put non-holdable items on Wall Mounts, like resources and Charms. Use these as labels for the chests you put below them!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
And if your Wall Mounts are hanging things that can turn on or off — like the Illuminator or a Lightsaber — you&#39;ll be able to turn them on or off on the Wall Mount.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For easier access, the Wall Mount will move to the Utility section of the Build menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Sprint Attack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a force with the new &lt;strong&gt;sprint attack&lt;/strong&gt;! Sprint to close the gap on enemies, delivering a powerful strike when you catch up.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Jump Attack Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jump attack will have clearer visuals so it&#39;s easier to see when you hit an enemy. Also, the issue that prevents the attack from doing damage when it looks like it &lt;em&gt;should have done damage&lt;/em&gt; will be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Sprint Jump&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap into the adventure like never before with the &lt;strong&gt;sprint jump&lt;/strong&gt;. This new jump adds an extra spring to your step and makes exploring your Odyssey world even smoother!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Advanced Weapons Journal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;strong&gt;Advanced Weapons Journal&lt;/strong&gt; will help remind you which weapons you can craft! Activate the journal in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li aria-level=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Try refining your raw materials to stone slabs, metal bars, cut crystals, etc.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Interact with Stations like a Gem Cutter or Metal Smelter and start crafting a weapon of the same rarity as the refined materials you previously crafted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Next-Level Small Talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Villagers might have some things to say to you, without you needing to talk to them first! If they do, you’ll see a little bubble above their head with a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Safety from the Storm (and… Rocks)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run out of time in the Storm, you’ll be teleported into the sky at a safe distance. This is to help prevent an issue that makes players sometimes get stuck in rocks and other things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Thunderclap Blade Updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landing hits with the Thunderclap Blade will charge up the projectile attack, making it simpler to get this attack ready. The spin animation before the projectile launches will be removed so it&#39;s easier to land attacks on distant enemies!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Also, the more you charge up, the more damage you&#39;ll do with both the normal and projectile attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A &lt;u&gt;Raise&lt;/u&gt; in Shield Usefulness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In skirmishes with enemies, raising your shield will be faster and more responsive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Goldrush Gallery LEGO Pass - Get it March 11!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revenge is best served gilded in gold, which is why the famous skeleton Oro is rising as &lt;strong&gt;Rebel Oro&lt;/strong&gt;! This Outfit is in the new &lt;strong&gt;Goldrush Gallery LEGO Pass &lt;/strong&gt;going live March 11.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Rebel Oro Outfit LEGO Style&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-rebel-oro-outfit-lego-style-1920x1080-0ecd1cb53dba.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Unlock free and premium rewards in the Goldrush Gallery LEGO Pass by earning XP in any Fortnite experience. To claim the premium rewards as you earn XP, purchase the Pass for only 1,400 V-Bucks or get it through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/fortnite-crew-subscription&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Crew&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
You’ll automatically get the Rebel Oro Outfit after purchasing the Pass or accessing it through Fortnite Crew. Here’s a surprise: this LEGO Pass has &lt;strong&gt;TWO&lt;/strong&gt; Outfits! Progress through the Pass to unlock the &lt;strong&gt;Carmine Rosso Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; as another premium reward.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Carmine Rosso Outfit LEGO Style&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-carmine-rosso-outfit-lego-style-1920x1080-b6b29b8cd55a.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
There’s a lot more to unlock too! For example, the &lt;strong&gt;Oro’s Abode Decor Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; is perfect for anyone looking to give their bedroom a glamorous golden makeover.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you’re an expert in metals, like gold, maybe you also appreciate the art of welding! Become a tradesperson with the &lt;strong&gt;Welding Essentials Decor Bundle&lt;/strong&gt;, or for a more traditional fusion of gold and art, turn your home into a museum with the &lt;strong&gt;Golden Peel Gallery Decor Bundle&lt;/strong&gt;. (Be careful — art collecting is a slippery slope!)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Struck gold, so to speak? If you’re feeling smug, celebrate your riches with the &lt;strong&gt;Loot Stash Emote&lt;/strong&gt;! Misfortune struck instead? Let it be known with the &lt;strong&gt;Tragedy! Emote&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Some of the Rewards in the LEGO Fortnite Goldrush Gallery Pass&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/some-of-the-rewards-in-the-lego-fortnite-goldrush-gallery-pass-1920x1080-453c21cf06bd.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the free and premium rewards in the Goldrush Gallery LEGO Pass.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
All the rewards mentioned above are just PART of what’s in the Pass. The Goldrush Gallery LEGO Pass will be available to progress in until May 2, 2025 Eastern Time. As a reminder, everything in a LEGO Pass may come to the Fortnite Shop at a later date.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Before we go — reminder that some fan-favorite LEGO Kits will return to the Shop on March 12 Eastern Time! Find them in the &lt;strong&gt;Durrr Burger Bundle&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Beachside Boulevard Bundle&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Mage&#39;s Favorites Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; all making a comeback.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;LEGO Fortnite Durrr Burger Bundle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/lego-fortnite-durrr-burger-bundle-1920x1080-52278d14126c.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Other fan favorites will return on March 19 Eastern Time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/lego-fortnite-updates-what-to-expect-in-march-2025?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/lego-fortnite-updates-what-to-expect-in-march-2025?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Creators and Competitors Team Up in the FNCS Pro-Am!</title><description></description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-creators-and-competitors-team-up-in-the-fncs-pro-am-in-los-angeles?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-creators-and-competitors-team-up-in-the-fncs-pro-am-in-los-angeles?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Competitive Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Enjoy Sun, Sand &amp; Celebration in Fortnite’s Lantern Fest 2025!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to light the lanterns again! Celebrate the spirit of &lt;strong&gt;Lantern Fest 2025&lt;/strong&gt; by visiting the new Desert vs Sea island, answering Fortnite-related riddles and trivia, and competing in the Lantern Fest Cup! Lantern Fest 2025 starts now, let the festivities begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Dive (or Dig) into Desert vs Sea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest Desert Vs Sea Island&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-desert-vs-sea-island-1920x1080-ae32032d91f4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The new &lt;strong&gt;Desert vs Sea - Lantern Fest 2025 island&lt;/strong&gt; will have you choose a side: Desert or… well, Sea. Compete in battles against each other to rack up more eliminations than the other team! There are powerful abilities to unlock on the way like &lt;strong&gt;Double HP&lt;/strong&gt; (200 HP total), &lt;strong&gt;Double Damage&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Invisibility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Afterwards, head to the second-floor area where different &lt;strong&gt;Sandstorm Riddles&lt;/strong&gt; await to test your Fortnite knowledge and wit!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest Sandstorm Riddles&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-sandstorm-riddles-1920x1080-306596182cd8.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Ready to jump in? The island code for Desert vs Sea is &lt;strong&gt;7286-4717-1963&lt;/strong&gt;! It’ll continue to be available after the conclusion of Lantern Fest 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Light the Torch for the Lantern Fest Cup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test your mettle in the &lt;strong&gt;Lantern Fest Cup&lt;/strong&gt;, a Solo Battle Royale tournament on March 8 where the top points-earning players in each region will unlock the returning Noorah Outfit, Anwar Outfit, Lunar Lantern Back Bling, and Moonlit Blades Back Bling. Players with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/cabinedaccounts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cabined Accounts&lt;/a&gt; are not eligible to take part in this tournament. Stay tuned for more information!&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Look Positively Glowing!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Radiant Moon Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest Radiant Moon Bundle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-radiant-moon-bundle-1920x1080-61437fbaac2f.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The moon rises once again! The &lt;strong&gt;Noorah Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; (+ Lunar Lantern Back Bling) and &lt;strong&gt;Anwar Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; (+ Moonlit Blades Back Bling) will be in the Shop individually and as part of the Radiant Moon Bundle starting March 6 at 7 PM ET.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
SpiderGamer Locker Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest 2025 SpiderGamer Bundle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-2025-spidergamer-bundle-1920x1080-5f889e148080.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Not too long after the Radiant Moon Bundle, the &lt;strong&gt;SpiderGamer Locker Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; will crawl into the Shop! For his Locker Bundle, SpiderGamer has hand-selected the &lt;strong&gt;Hunter Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the Swagger Strut Emote, Hatchling Glider, Web Breaker Pickaxe, and Widow’s Web Wrap. The Hunter Outfit has the built-in Hero’s Beacon Emote!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
BanderitaX Locker Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest 2025 BanderitaX Bundle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-2025-banderitax-bundle-1920x1080-ff2b599f85eb.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
BanderitaX joins the celebration! Later during Lantern Fest, check out the &lt;strong&gt;BanderitaX Locker Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; in the Shop featuring his curated items: the &lt;strong&gt;PJ Pepperoni Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; plus the Patty Whacker Pickaxe, Flying Saucer Glider, Cheesy Back Bling, and Rage Quit Emote.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Power Shong Locker Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest 2025 PowerShong Bundle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-2025-powershong-bundle-1920x1080-d2f25f2f6df0.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Power Shong is sharing the light with the community! The &lt;strong&gt;Power Shong Locker Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; will be in the Shop later during Lantern Fest, featuring his hand-picked &lt;strong&gt;Shadow Ops Outfit&lt;/strong&gt;, Astral Axe Pickaxe, Burning Beast Glider, Prospect Back Bling, and Daydream Emote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
SirSanX Locker Bundle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lantern Fest 2025 SirSanX Bundle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lantern-fest-2025-sirsanx-bundle-1920x1080-fa0f4d8b4c8c.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;strong&gt;SirSanX Locker Bundle&lt;/strong&gt; is returning to Lantern Fest! Arriving in the Shop later in the festivities, it includes his curated &lt;strong&gt;Potassius Peels Outfit&lt;/strong&gt;, Smolder Pickaxe, Graven’s Wings Glider, Cape of Potassius Back Bling, The El Durrrado Back Bling, and Golden Cloud Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/enjoy-sun-sand-and-celebration-in-fortnites-lantern-fest-2025?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/enjoy-sun-sand-and-celebration-in-fortnites-lantern-fest-2025?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Fortnite Anti-Cheat Update - February 27, 2025</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In November, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/competitive/news/fortnite-competitive-details-chapter-6-season-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;we shared an update&lt;/a&gt; on competitive integrity in Fortnite and promised that we’d share more about our continued efforts to fight cheating. Here’s another update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Taking Legal Action Against Cheaters and Other Rulebreakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epic continues to take legal action against those found cheating in Fortnite, helping others cheat, or breaking other rules. Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/2025-02-27-epic-v--strock-complaint-5a69b553b2a2.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;filed a new lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against an individual who stole Fortnite accounts and resold them.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/FNCompetitive/status/1869424463193796718&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against a player who cheated in our tournaments and &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/FNCompetitive/status/1891564240604999725&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;reached a settlement&lt;/a&gt; with another.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following legal action, the makers of the Cronus devices removed Fortnite and Rocket League gamepacks and scripts from their website that help people cheat. Additionally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/help/c-Category_Fortnite/c-Fortnite_PlayerBehavior/why-am-i-receiving-a-restricted-hardware-warning-in-fortnite-a000085371&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cronus hardware&lt;/a&gt; and any other device that offers a competitive advantage are restricted and will result in a cheating ban.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the consequence is a cheating ban at minimum, it may also include the loss of tournament winnings and other legal repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
New PC Requirements for Tournaments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also focused on combatting cheating in tournaments, where competitive integrity is the cornerstone. For tournaments like FNCS events that require an Account Level of 350 or higher to be eligible, Windows PC players will need to enable two Windows security features starting today: &lt;strong&gt;TPM&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Secure Boot&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is TPM?&lt;/em&gt; TPM is a secure hardware component. It can verify that other security settings, like Secure Boot, are enabled in a way that is very difficult for malware or cheats to tamper with. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/help/en-US/c-Category_Fortnite/c-Fortnite_Competitive/what-is-tpm-and-how-can-i-enable-it-a000093836&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instructions on how to enable TPM can be found here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is Secure Boot?&lt;/em&gt; Secure Boot is a security feature that helps prevent malware from being inserted into the PC’s boot process. It’s common for cheats to behave like bootkits and attempt to run very early into the system start. Secure boot helps to mitigate that threat by making sure that bootloaders come from a trusted source. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/help/en-US/c-Category_Fortnite/c-Fortnite_Competitive/what-is-secure-boot-and-how-can-i-enable-it-a000093837&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instructions on how to enable Secure Boot can be found here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Offering a Second Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While maintaining game integrity is our top priority, we also believe in allowing second chances for players who made a bad decision and have learned from it. Starting in April, we’ll be moving to a one-year matchmaking ban for first-time cheating offenses, allowing former cheaters to learn from their mistakes while still punishing and deterring cheating. A second offense will result in a lifetime ban.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means for the duration of their first ban, players will be able to log in and text/voice chat with other players, but won’t be able to matchmake into Epic- or creator-made experiences, or spectate other players.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of rolling out this policy, existing lifetime cheating bans that have been in effect for more than a year will be lifted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li aria-level=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Players who have &lt;em&gt;used &lt;/em&gt;cheats: One-year matchmaking ban for the first offense, lifetime ban for the second.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Players who have &lt;em&gt;used &lt;/em&gt;cheats and participate in tournaments: One-year matchmaking ban + immediate lifetime ban from tournaments + potential loss of past tournament winnings. A second offense of using cheats will result in a lifetime ban.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li aria-level=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Players who have &lt;em&gt;sold &lt;/em&gt;cheats, or broken other rules&amp;nbsp;resulting in a lifetime ban: Nothing changes. The lifetime ban is still in effect.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional consequences may include legal repercussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Other Ways We Fight Cheating&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fighting cheating inside Fortnite or any other large online platform is an ongoing effort with no single, simple solution. Once a specific cheat is detected, cheat developers and cheaters look for workarounds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We prevent game-breaking exploits, make game code harder for cheat creators to analyze, leverage &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.easy.ac/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Easy Anti-Cheat’s&lt;/a&gt; kernel driver to protect the game while it runs, and utilize statistical analysis and machine learning algorithms to identify suspicious activity. We’re continually developing detections to help us effectively identify and confirm instances of cheating.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ban accounts for cheating based on technical evidence — we do not ban accounts based on suspicion. &lt;strong&gt;Anyone found cheating will be banned, there are no exceptions.&lt;/strong&gt; As explained above, we may also pursue legal action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
How You Can Help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-game reports help us identify and action cheaters every day. Anyone who has received our “Suspect Apprehended” message knows this well. If you suspect someone may be cheating, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/help/c-Category_Fortnite/c-Fortnite_PlayerBehavior/how-to-report-bad-player-behavior-in-fortnite-a000086135&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;submit a report inside Fortnite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-anti-cheat-update-february-27-2025?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-anti-cheat-update-february-27-2025?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Run Amok in Fortnite Battle Royale Chapter 6 Season 2: LAWLESS!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Crime City, the hustle never stops.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Stick ‘em up! It’s time to blow that vault door wide open and make a… “withdrawal.” Ransack Fletcher Kane&#39;s banks, take over his armored cars, even pull off a train robbery! The outlaw Midas returns with a new motley crew including wannabe hip-hop icon Big Dill, Cassidy Quinn, and more. There’s no such thing as honor among thieves in Fortnite Battle Royale &lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6 Season 2: LAWLESS&lt;/strong&gt;!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/66eAN56g7D8?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Rendezvous Views&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Island has been infused with an abundance of &lt;strong&gt;Bars&lt;/strong&gt; 💰, and now every opportunist is out to hit the jackpot including the ruthless crime kingpin Fletcher Kane. It’s every bandit for themselves in the ultimate race to get rich!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:24px&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:Comic Sans MS,cursive&quot;&gt;*reCoRd ScRaTch* People still care about Bars? My boi Big Dill got off the gold standard MONTHS ago It’s all about Dill Bits THAT’S what you should be coppin instead bro&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So where to look first? Here are some ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Crime City&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re sure to find mayhem in the seedy underbelly of &lt;strong&gt;Crime City&lt;/strong&gt;, the ultimate stomping ground for all manner of corrupt and crooked misfits. Make sure to visit the Hostile Hotel, Wise Guys Bookstore, and the Launder Mat for a full criminal excursion.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Crime City&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-crime-city-1920x1080-8b038830629e.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Outlaw Oasis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unwind at the &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Oasis&lt;/strong&gt;, a high-end hangout luxury spa and resort where burglars typically relax and recover after a busy day of swiping huge hauls.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Outlaw Oasis Day&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-outlaw-oasis-day-1920x1080-d0f25a1d7774.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Shiny Shafts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could rob one of Fletcher Kane’s banks for Bars… or you could go right to the source. His mining operation, &lt;strong&gt;Shiny Shafts&lt;/strong&gt;, is a highly contested area above ground and below.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Shiny Shafts Outside&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-shiny-shafts-outside-1920x1080-fea33993dfc8.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Lonewolf Lair&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is tight around Fletcher’s mansion hideout, &lt;strong&gt;Lonewolf Lair&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyone bold enough to challenge his growing empire is in for a fight!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Lonewolf Lair Outside&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-lonewolf-lair-outside-1920x1080-c59e1057b126.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Public Enemy #1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baron &lt;strong&gt;Fletcher Kane&lt;/strong&gt; has set up shop as the Island’s mob don, and his paws are in every pocket in town. He’s been known only to appear at the most inopportune moments. Namely, while you’re mid-heist.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Fletcher Kane&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-fletcher-kane-1920x1080-46ab68c2eac0.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Survive Fletcher’s barrage of claw attacks and you’ll be awarded with the Mythic &lt;strong&gt;Fletcher Kane’s Double Down Pistol&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Unstoppable Medallion&lt;/strong&gt;. True to its name, this Medallion increases sprint speed and allows for bashing enemies while sprinting. As a reminder, Medallions make you visible on opponents’ mini-map. The more Medallions you have, the more precise the radius of your exact location — you’ve been warned!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The demon warrior Shogun X still wanders the Island, though his defeat now rewards the &lt;strong&gt;Super Shield Medallion&lt;/strong&gt;, which places down a Shield Bubble Jr. when using a self-healing item like a Med Kit or Shield Potion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Pickle on the Beat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Big Dill&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-big-dill-1920x1080-d5e590a47887.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Big Dill&lt;/strong&gt; is the newest rap artist on the scene in Fortnite. He’s a mean, green, hot-tempered outlaw aiming to be the grittiest gherkin in the jar. Big Dill &amp;amp; The Brat make up the dynamic duo known as the Tasty Bois. Their new single “Runamok” &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/bigdill&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;just dropped on Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; and is available as a Jam Track in the Battle Pass.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Big Dill is robbing banks, launching music, and creating his own shoddy currency in-game: Dill Bits (more on that in a second). Who knows what he’ll do next… maybe launch a podcast?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;In Broad Daylight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the best heisters appreciate a how-to, so here’s what to expect in your malicious mission:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Feel the Rush&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that glitters is yours. Swimming in gold-infused water will put you under the effect of &lt;strong&gt;Gold Rush&lt;/strong&gt;, which increases your speed, how fast your Pickaxe swings, and how much damage your Pickaxe does against structures. You can also gain Gold Rush by mining &lt;strong&gt;Gold Veins&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be excavated with your Pickaxe for Bars.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Big Dill is ballin&#39; out of control thanks to his &lt;strong&gt;Dill Bits&lt;/strong&gt; coin, which has become even more valuable than Bars*. Typically sealed behind lock and key in vaults around the Island, Dill Bits don’t carry over from match to match, so spend them quickly before your wallet goes to zero! But, uh, to the moon!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Gold Bars Dill Bits&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-gold-bars-dill-bits-1920x1080-b2eab277f2d6.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;*Big Dill has more arrest warrants than he does top 40 tracks, please do not take financial advice from a rapping pickle.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Money’s Meant to Be Spent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend your Dill Bits and Gold Bars at one of three &lt;strong&gt;Black Markets&lt;/strong&gt; around the map, offering a selection of Mythic and Legendary items obtained in a totally legit way. Black Markets also offer Boons that’ll make your next break-in a breeze.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;FNBR C6S2 BlackMarket Social 1920x1080&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fnbr-c6s2-blackmarket-social-1920x1080-1920x1080-5ea39a051468.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Kane, Train &amp;amp; Automobiles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be wary, if gold moves in this town, you’d better believe Fletcher Kane knows about it. His &lt;strong&gt;Armored Transport&lt;/strong&gt; convoys can be found transporting valuables around the map. Expect a fight with his henchmen if you’re planning to get inside one, but if you can wrestle control of the steering wheel, it’s yours to joyride in.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Armored Transport&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-armored-transport-1920x1080-a7bf112be3db.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Raiding Fletcher’s &lt;strong&gt;Armored Train&lt;/strong&gt; promises a lotta loot, though it’s well-known as the most dangerous job in town! Board the train and destroy its turrets to bring it to a screeching halt, then blow open the vault car with Thermite and you’ll be rewarded handsomely. Just, be careful — you’re likely to attract the attention of other players while carrying out this “transaction.”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Armored Train&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-armored-train-1920x1080-92d4d1a47731.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A Boon of Boons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new Season means a refreshed slate of Boons! Available only from Black Markets or Rare Chests this Season, Boons persist beyond elimination in the same match (meaning you’ll keep them if you get rebooted in the same match). Collect all five!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulture Boon&lt;/strong&gt;: Reveal where enemies are eliminated on the map for a short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Rush Boon&lt;/strong&gt;: Opening or destroying Chests grants Gold Rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adrenaline Rush Boon&lt;/strong&gt;: Gain the Slap effect (short-term unlimited Energy regen) upon mantling, hurdling, and wall jumping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Ammo Boon&lt;/strong&gt;: Gain ammo when picking up Bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greed Boon&lt;/strong&gt;: Find extra Bars from eliminations and opening containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fornite Battle Royale Lawless Boons&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fornite-battle-royale-lawless-boons-1920x1080-af0c8bfa1d5d.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
New, Nefarious Munitions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We haven’t gone over the new tools at your disposal yet. They’re great for getting into trouble… and staying there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Items for Vault Busting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ONLY way to crack a vault is with &lt;strong&gt;Thermite&lt;/strong&gt;, a powerful explosive found stashed away around the map. After you’ve planted some, you can set off the explosion faster by damaging the vault&#39;s weak points. The &lt;strong&gt;Plasma Burst Laser&lt;/strong&gt; works great for this, as does the &lt;strong&gt;Rocket Drill&lt;/strong&gt; arriving later this Season in v34.10.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Plasma Burst Laser Thermite Rocket Drill&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-plasma-burst-laser-thermite-rocket-drill-1900x600-6a583598e946.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Items for Mayhem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bars can’t buy the time needed to pull a heist, but the &lt;strong&gt;Collateral Damage Assault Rifle&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Falcon Eye Sniper&lt;/strong&gt; might. And keep an eye out for the formidable &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Shotgun&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;which&amp;nbsp;drops in v34.10.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Falcon Eye Sniper Collateral Damage Assault Rifle&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-falcon-eye-sniper-collateral-damage-assault-rifle-1900x600-c8e13253a958.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Fancy yourself ambidextrous? Big Dill’s fave combo, the dual-wield &lt;strong&gt;Pump &amp;amp; Dump&lt;/strong&gt;, arrives in v34.10 and will be your new close-to-mid-range best friend. Occupying a single weapon slot, hold a Pump Shotgun in one hand and an SMG in the other!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An Item for a Home Run Heist…&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A favorite of ne&#39;er-do-wells everywhere is &lt;strong&gt;The Kneecapper&lt;/strong&gt;, great for giving opponents a good ol’ fashioned whack. Wielding The Kneecapper reduces the Energy cost of sprinting and increases sprint speed and jump height.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless The Kneecapper&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-the-kneecapper-1900x600-4cf502e3450f.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Items for Watching Your Back&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find new utility items around the map, such as the protective &lt;strong&gt;Port-A-Cover&lt;/strong&gt; and enemy-detecting &lt;strong&gt;Pulse Scanner&lt;/strong&gt;. Both are tremendously useful for holding off henchmen while you grab all the Bars you can find.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Henchmen and enemy squads interrupting your heist-in-progress? The &lt;strong&gt;Med-Mist Grenade&lt;/strong&gt; helps heal in a pinch, and &lt;strong&gt;Gold Splash&lt;/strong&gt; grants Gold Rush and heals 20 Health (or 20 Shield if you’re at full Health already).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Port A Cover Pulse Scanner Med Mist Grenade Gold Splash&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-port-a-cover-pulse-scanner-med-mist-grenade-gold-splash-1900x600-aac0e28283a0.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Slay Frosty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your enemies are about to be on thin ice. The cold-blooded cryomancer Sub-Zero has arrived on the Island and can be recruited to your cause! Be sure to pick up &lt;strong&gt;Sub-Zero’s Kombat Kit&lt;/strong&gt;, which empowers you to ice slide into opponents and unleash a flurry of frosty fists 🧊❄️&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Roayle Lawless Sub Zeros Kombat Kit&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-roayle-lawless-sub-zeros-kombat-kit-1900x600-ace0eaedcc32.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
LAWLESS Battle Pass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get ready for a notorious new look! The LAWLESS Season brings the &lt;strong&gt;LAWLESS Battle Pass&lt;/strong&gt;, offering a wealth of Outfits and accessories.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Lawless Battle Pass&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-lawless-battle-pass-1920x1080-2d4fa1858dcb.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Like with the other Passes in Fortnite, unlock and claim rewards in the Battle Pass by earning XP in any Fortnite experience. The Battle Pass has both free and premium rewards. To claim the premium rewards as you earn XP, purchase the Pass for only 1,000 V-Bucks or get it through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/fortnite-crew-subscription&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Crew&lt;/a&gt;! Included as premium rewards, there are several Outfits in the Pass:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cassidy Quinn&lt;/strong&gt;: She&#39;s all in. &lt;em&gt;(Cassidy Quinn is claimable right away upon purchasing the Battle Pass!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joss&lt;/strong&gt;: It&#39;s not magic. It&#39;s chemistry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fletcher Kane&lt;/strong&gt;: What&#39;s yours is his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valentina&lt;/strong&gt;: Get in, get the goods, and get out with style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Dill&lt;/strong&gt;: The original Tasty Boi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keisha Cross&lt;/strong&gt;: She rules the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-Zero (MK3)&lt;/strong&gt;: The Lin Kuei cryomancer of legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The golden king finds his way back to the Island. The &lt;strong&gt;Outlaw Midas Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; will be unlockable from Battle Pass Quests in March, completable in any Fortnite experience! The Battle Pass will be available to progress in until Chapter 6 Season 2 ends on May 2, 2025 Eastern Time.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Outlaw Midas&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-outlaw-midas-1920x1080-615211e4279c.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Let’s Go, Space Cowboy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prefer &lt;em&gt;stopping&lt;/em&gt; criminals? Starting March 1 Eastern Time, complete &lt;strong&gt;COWBOY BEBOP Quests&lt;/strong&gt; for XP that can contribute towards COWBOY BEBOP Bonus Goals. Meeting these Bonus Goals will unlock the &lt;strong&gt;COWBOY BEBOP Wrap&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;BEBOP Legends Loading Screen&lt;/strong&gt;! The Quests and Bonus Goals will be available until March 18 Eastern Time.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless BEBOP Legends Loading Screen&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-bebop-legends-loading-screen-1920x1080-132cef5d72b9.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The BEBOP Legends Loading Screen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What if we said you can complete these objectives as the famed bounty hunters themselves? The &lt;strong&gt;Spike Spiegel Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Faye Valentine Outfit&lt;/strong&gt; will be in the Fortnite Shop starting February 28 Eastern Time!&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (February 26, 2025):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
All things COWBOY BEBOP are going live early! The Spike Spiegel and Faye Valentine Outfits are in the Shop now, and COWBOY BEBOP Quests and Bonus Goals will now go live February 27 at 9 AM ET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Introducing Moments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrate the start and end of a match with a music &lt;strong&gt;Moment&lt;/strong&gt;! In the Locker, players can now choose a Jam/Lobby Track to play when they drop out of the Battle Bus and one to play when they get a Victory Royale. Players will not hear each other&#39;s music, even when spectating, as the chosen Track will only play locally. In split-screen, Player 1’s chosen Track will be the one that plays.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:24px&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:Comic Sans MS,cursive&quot;&gt;*REcOrD sCRatch* Bro the only music moment in history that mattered is when my man big Dill dropped runamok WHO cares about any other jam truck?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tournament Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Crime City Night&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-crime-city-night-1920x1080-21ea45ddd8eb.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
All gameplay items included in Chapter 6 Season 2 are eligible for tournament play, though loot pool differentiations may be made in the coming weeks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Also, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortnite.com/competitive/news/fortnite-br-c6s2-competitive-details-new-and-improved-compete-tab&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chapter 6 Season 2 Competitive Details blog post&lt;/a&gt; to learn about the updated Compete tab, which gives you a better sense of upcoming tournament offerings and the info on each one!&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Breakin&#39; Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortnite Battle Royale: LAWLESS ends May 2. The first Victory Royale you bag this Season in Battle Royale or Zero Build will earn you&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Vaultbrella&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Fortnite Battle Royale Lawless Vaultbrella&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/fortnite-battle-royale-lawless-vaultbrella-1920x1080-e11090146617.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:auto; width:auto&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:24px&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:Comic Sans MS,cursive&quot;&gt;DILL with it!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/run-amok-in-fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-6-season-2-lawless?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/run-amok-in-fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-6-season-2-lawless?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 06:55:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>FNBR C6S2 Competitive Details - Updated Compete Tab!</title><description></description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-br-c6s2-competitive-details-new-and-improved-compete-tab?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-br-c6s2-competitive-details-new-and-improved-compete-tab?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 06:50:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Competitive Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Fortnite Island Creator Rules</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last updated: February 13, 2025&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE (February 13, 2025)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We have a policy update. You can now use text in parts of your lobby backgrounds.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates to rules &lt;strong&gt;1.10,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1.15.7&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;4.2&lt;/strong&gt;: Existing rules apply to lobby backgrounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed rule &lt;strong&gt;1.19.1&lt;/strong&gt; which was previously prohibiting text in lobby backgrounds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Please take the time to read through these updated rules and familiarize yourself with them.&amp;nbsp;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Welcome Fortnite Creator!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/creative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Creative&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/uefn/starting-out-in-unreal-editor-for-fortnite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unreal Editor for Fortnite&lt;/a&gt; tools allow you to create islands that can be published within Fortnite.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Fortnite aims to be a safe and fun place for people to play games or hang with their friends, as we say in our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/community-rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Community Rules&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
As you create new islands, games, and experiences within Fortnite, we need your help to keep Fortnite welcoming to everyone. We also want to make it easy for you to publish and be successful with your Fortnite island.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
These rules, along with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/fortnite-creative/fortnite-creative-documentation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Creator Documentation&lt;/a&gt;, outline the appropriate ways to create, promote, and monetize your Fortnite island, including some important dos and don’ts. Please take the time to read them carefully before you publish your first Fortnite island and best of luck!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Applicable Rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether built using Fortnite or Unreal Editor for Fortnite, your island is your responsibility, and you must comply with the following rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;strong&gt;islands and content&lt;/strong&gt; must comply with the rules below, and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/content-guidelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Epic Games Content Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;strong&gt;behavior and content &lt;/strong&gt;must comply with the rules below, and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/community-rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Epic Games Community Rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any &lt;strong&gt;promotion &lt;/strong&gt;of your island, both within and outside of Fortnite, must comply with the rules below, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://brand.epicgames.com/d/KCYRTaiFZuRz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Creative Branding Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you choose to use any third party IP, such as LEGO® or Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles (TMNT) Assets and Templates, you must comply with the IP Partner Licensing Agreement and the related Brand and Creator Rules (&lt;a href=&quot;https://fn.gg/LEGO-Brand-and-Creator-Rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LEGO Brand and Creator Rules&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/uefn/tmnt-brand-and-creator-rules-in-unreal-editor-for-fortnite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TMNT Brand and Creator Rules&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1. Content Rules &amp;amp; Guidelines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we work together to ensure Fortnite stays a safe and welcoming environment for everyone, your Fortnite content must follow these rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;1.1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;A Safe Environment &lt;/strong&gt;- Don’t create, upload, or publish content promoting illegal activities, including the promotion of known real-world gangs or gang violence, the promotion of known real-world terrorist organizations or terrorism, the promotion of real-world violent extremists or extremism, harassment, bullying, assault, doxing, swatting, gambling, illegal drugs, animal cruelty, fraud, hacking, and piracy. Content that depicts, condones, incites, or threatens real-world violence against others is prohibited.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.2&quot;&gt;1.2 &lt;strong&gt;Keep Personal Info Private&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;To respect privacy and help combat deceptive practices like phishing and buying/selling account information, do not disclose, gather, exploit, or request personal information of individuals or organizations anywhere in your island. You may not include a URL or QR code or a request for direct or private messages. Do not include videos or photographs of real-life people (yourself or others) anywhere in your island, or metadata (name, description, thumbnail, loading screen text, lobby background, and/or trailers). Epic&#39;s voice and text chat within Fortnite include protections like privacy settings, parental controls, and player reporting. So don&#39;t provide other chat methods on your island, like chat boxes or custom keyboards.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;1.3&quot;&gt;1.3 &lt;strong&gt;Intolerance and Discrimination &lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fortnite welcomes diversity in race, ethnicity, color, religion, gender identity, sexual orientation, disability, national origin, and other groups. Content should not demean, dehumanize, marginalize, use hateful language against, perpetuate negative stereotypes about, or belittle other users or groups. Islands that promote or encourage intolerance or discrimination will not be allowed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.4&quot;&gt;1.4 &lt;strong&gt;Love… Don’t Hate&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Don’t create content that includes hateful symbols or depictions or content that glorifies or incites violence.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.5&quot;&gt;1.5 &lt;strong&gt;Bullying and Harassment&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Respect others that participate in your creation. Publishing content that is predatory, threatening, intimidating, demeaning, derogatory, invasive of privacy, abusive, or that would cause real-world harm, including extortion, sextortion, and blackmail, is against the rules.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.6&quot;&gt;1.6 &lt;strong&gt;Be Original&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Keep your creations original. Don&#39;t duplicate, copy, or reproduce other creators’ promotional assets such as thumbnails, titles, and/or descriptions. Don’t pass off your creations as another creator’s work, including by using similar game titles or imagery. Don’t impersonate other players, creators, streamers, celebrities, companies, brands, government officials, Epic employees, or anyone else. Pretending to be someone else in order to deceive or defraud others is not okay.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.7&quot;&gt;1.7 &lt;strong&gt;Respect IP Ownership&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The content you create, publish, or use cannot infringe or violate someone else&#39;s rights, including their intellectual property rights (such as copyright or trademark). You must own or have obtained the necessary rights to share and publish the content, and any such license must be broad enough to grant Epic a license consistent with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/eula&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Fortnite EULA&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/unreal-editor-for-fortnite-supplemental-terms&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;UEFN Supplemental Terms&lt;/a&gt;. More information about copyright can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wipo.int/copyright/en/faq-copyright.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.8&quot;&gt;1.8 &lt;strong&gt;Give Credit Where It’s Required&lt;/strong&gt; - If you use content with a license that requires attribution, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Creative Commons 4.0 International&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;you must give any required credits, such as by using the &quot;Attributions&quot; section in the Creator Portal. Keep in mind that some licenses may not be compatible with our tools or with UEFN. If you&#39;re not sure that you can meet the license&#39;s attribution requirements, don&#39;t use the licensed content.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.9&quot;&gt;1.9 &lt;strong&gt;Play by the Rules&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Do not create islands that promote the use of cheats, exploits, glitched items, server crashes, and bugs. Do not scam players on your island.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.10&quot;&gt;1.10 &lt;strong&gt;Appropriate Language Only&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Don’t include obscene text or symbols in your island’s metadata (name, description, thumbnail, lobby background, loading screen text, or trailer), promotional materials, your display name, creator code, or elsewhere on your island. This includes spelling variations or visual depictions of text aimed at evading this rule.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.11&quot;&gt;1.11 &lt;strong&gt;All Bets Are Off&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Don’t implement playable gambling content, raffles, or casino-style games. These are prohibited whether or not they involve real money or virtual currency.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.12&quot;&gt;1.12 &lt;strong&gt;Keep It on the Island&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Do not include external links anywhere on your island.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.13&quot;&gt;1.13 &lt;strong&gt;Keep It Authentic&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The assets (such as thumbnail images, descriptions, titles) you use to promote your Fortnite island must accurately represent the content within your island.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.13.1. Do not imitate or supplement visual elements provided by Fortnite to indicate a feature to players (e.g. the ability to earn Fortnite XP in your island, or game ratings).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1.13.2. Do not mention V-Bucks, Battle Pass, real-world currency, or rewards.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1.13.3. Do not incorporate elements that promise or mislead players regarding XP gains, in-game items, or Quests. Do not use terms such as “AFK,” “XP,” “Coin farm,” or “Coin slide” in your name, description, thumbnail, loading screen text, or lobby background. Do not use images of Fortnite coins or similar coins in your thumbnails and lobby backgrounds. Do not use any other imagery or language that may mislead players.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1.13.4. Do not mislead players as to the sort of experience they will have.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.14&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Stay within Spec Requirements&lt;/strong&gt; - Make sure the islands you are creating do not cause server issues, intentionally or not. Frame rates should stay above 30 FPS.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15&quot;&gt;1.15&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Align with Fortnite’s Game Rating &lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fortnite is an ecosystem with a range of ratings and content must not exceed Fortnite’s maximum age rating. Please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/fortnite-creative/iarc-overview-and-faqs-in-fortnite-creative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IARC Overview&lt;/a&gt; for “Maximum Age Ratings in Fortnite”. We also don&#39;t accept content that targets children under 13 as its primary audience (no nursery rhymes). Images and text used to promote your island must be appropriate for a general audience (e.g. content that would merit a rating of ESRB Everyone 10+, or lower).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We require all creators to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/fortnite-creative/publishing-from-the-creator-portal-in-fortnite-creative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;obtain age ratings&lt;/a&gt; for your content via IARC (International Age Rating Coalition) upon publishing. When creating or publishing content for Fortnite, you must also follow these content rules:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;1.15.1&quot;&gt;1.15.1.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Violence &amp;amp; Gore&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Violence must never be realistic. Death animations and kill replays are not permitted. Realistic gore of any kind is not permitted, including any inclusion of or reference to real or fake blood. Your content may contain horror themes and/or “scary” content, but neither may be intense or sustained. You must avoid disturbing images.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15.2&quot;&gt;1.15.2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Use of mild profanity and innuendo is permitted, but must not be frequent. Hateful or discriminatory language of any kind is not permitted. Sexual expletives of any kind are not permitted.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15.3&quot;&gt;1.15.3.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Nudity &amp;amp; Sexually Suggestive Themes&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Romantic themes are permitted, but must not go as far as strong or frequent sexually suggestive themes and references. Depictions of full nudity or sexual activities are not permitted in any form.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15.4&quot;&gt;1.15.4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Alcohol &amp;amp; Drug References&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;References to alcohol, tobacco, illegal drugs, or drug-taking are not permitted in any form.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15.5&quot;&gt;1.15.5.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Gambling&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Islands that teach or prominently feature images or activities that are typically associated with real-world gambling, casino style games, or games of chance that offer a prize, even if they are not directly simulating a gambling experience, are not permitted in any form.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15.6&quot;&gt;1.15.6.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Obscenity&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Realistic depictions of bodily functions including excrement, defecation, urination, or vomit are not permitted in any form.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
1.15.7. &lt;strong&gt;Promotional Materials&lt;/strong&gt;: All island metadata (name, description, thumbnail, lobby background, and loading screen text) must be suitable for a general audience and cannot contain realistic violence, suggestive themes, crude humor, gore, references to gambling or use of strong language. Examples of prohibited content include:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 80px;&quot;&gt;Mildly sexualized depictions of a character’s body parts, such as breasts or buttocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 80px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Images that elicit a strong sense of threat, dread or terror (e.g. grotesque creatures)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 80px;&quot;&gt;Active gunfire from a visible weapon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 80px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Crosshairs shown over a face/head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 80px;&quot;&gt;Guns pointed at the viewer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 80px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guns pointed at head of character&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Learn more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esrb.org/ratings/principles-guidelines/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ESRB Ratings Principles and Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.15&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;1.16&quot;&gt;1.16&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Misuse of Epic Systems&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Epic maintains many systems to keep our users safe and their data secure. Do not attempt to bypass these protections to gain unauthorized access to any Epic systems or data. Do not attempt to gain sensitive information from players. Do not attempt to create or distribute malicious software via Epic systems.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.17&quot;&gt;1.17&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Educational Exceptions&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;We may permit exceptions at our discretion to our Island Creator Rules if the primary purpose of your island is to provide an educational, scientific, artistic, or historical experience.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18&quot;&gt;1.18&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Island Content Disclosures&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;When answering the IARC Age Rating Questionnaire, you are required to accurately disclose relevant content within your Island in order to receive the correct age ratings. Content that is relevant to age ratings includes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.18.1. Violence&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18.2&quot;&gt;1.18.2. Fear or Gore&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18.3&quot;&gt;1.18.3. Sexuality&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18.4&quot;&gt;1.18.4. Gambling themes&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18.5&quot;&gt;1.18.5. Languages&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18.6&quot;&gt;1.18.6. Controlled Substances&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.18.7&quot;&gt;1.18.7. Crude humor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;1.18&quot;&gt;1.19&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow Epic’s Style Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1.19.1. Metadata must adhere and follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/fortnite-creative/thumbnail-image-guidelines-for-discover&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thumbnail Image Guidelines for Discover&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/en-us/fortnite-creative/lobby-background-image-guidelines-in-fortnite-creative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lobby Background Image Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;1.20&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Creator Picks &lt;/strong&gt;- Paid promotions and collaborations are prohibited in islands featured in your &quot;Creator Picks&quot; section. You must not accept payment, in any form, to list an experience in the Creator Picks section of your Creator Page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
2. Working with Others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;2&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2.1. If you engage another island creator to help you build your island or, similarly, if you agree to help another creator create their island, it is an agreement between you and that person. Epic Games is in no way a party to your agreement and is not responsible for it in any way.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
2.2. Unreal Editor for Fortnite permits adult creators to work together in teams, which are managed using the Fortnite Creator Portal. As the owner of a team, you are responsible for ensuring the content created and published by that team adheres to these rules, even if another member of your team made or imported content that violates these rules.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;2.2&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3. Promoting Your Island&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;We want to make it easy for you to promote your Fortnite island to help it be successful. Promotion of your island, &lt;strong&gt;including marketing content outside of Fortnite&lt;/strong&gt;, must follow these rules:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.1&quot;&gt;3.1&lt;/span&gt; Promotional Use of Epic Games and Fortnite IP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.1&quot;&gt;3.1.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;When promoting your island, you must not represent it as developed in partnership with Epic Games or suggest that it is in any way an official Epic Games Fortnite island, existing or past.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.2&quot;&gt;3.1.2&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;nbsp;When promoting your island, you may use the “Created in Fortnite” logo as long as it follows our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brand.epicgames.com/d/KCYRTaiFZuRz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Creative Branding Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.3&quot;&gt;3.1.3&lt;/span&gt;. You must not use the Fortnite or Epic Games logos anywhere in your island or in the promotional materials for your island.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.4&quot;&gt;3.1.4&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;nbsp;When promoting your island, the assets you use to represent your island must look and feel like your island, and follow our &lt;a href=&quot;https://brand.epicgames.com/d/KCYRTaiFZuRz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Creative Branding Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;; they must not mislead players as to the sort of experience they will have. You may not incorporate photographs.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.5&quot;&gt;3.1.5&lt;/span&gt;. You must prominently include the following legal line on all promotional material: This is not sponsored, endorsed, or administered by Epic Games, Inc.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.1.6&quot;&gt;3.1.6&lt;/span&gt;. When creating promotional materials for your island, you must only show Outfits or other items that are owned by Epic Games (or content that you have express permission or rights to use). For example, don’t use Marvel or DC Outfits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;3.2&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 Marketing Activities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.1&quot;&gt;3.2.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;All marketing content you use to promote your island, regardless of channel or format, must comply with these rules, including the Content Rules &amp;amp; Guidelines described above in Rule 1 and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/content-guidelines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Epic Games Content Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Marketing content you use to promote your island should also be appropriate for the age rating you obtain for the island under Rule 1.16. Promotions that violate these rules may result in action being taken against the island(s) being promoted or actions against your Epic Account.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.2&quot;&gt;3.2.2.&lt;/span&gt; You must not run advertisements on television or digital ad networks to promote your island without express and prior consent from Epic Games. To seek this consent, please contact us at&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:CreatorAdRequests@epicgames.com&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CreatorAdRequests@epicgames.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.3&quot;&gt;3.2.3.&lt;/span&gt; You may promote your island digitally via advertisements and assets on your own websites, social channels, or platforms, as well as with text-based search ads, such as Google Search.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.4&quot;&gt;3.2.4.&lt;/span&gt; If you engage and pay influencers to promote your island, you must follow all applicable laws such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/ftcs-endorsement-guides-what-people-are-asking&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FTC Endorsement Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Influencers you engage to promote your island must be clearly and conspicuously disclosed.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.5&quot;&gt;3.2.5.&lt;/span&gt; You must not create and distribute Fortnite-branded physical promotional items of any kind to promote your island (for example, clothing, stickers, flyers, mugs, etc.) without express and prior consent from Epic Games.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.6&quot;&gt;3.2.6.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;When promoting your island via search advertisements, you must not purchase advertisements against keywords or search terms that are Epic Games trademarks, such as “Fortnite” or “Epic Games.”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.2.7&quot;&gt;3.2.7.&lt;/span&gt; Fortnite is rated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esrb.org/ratings-guide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ESRB Teen for Diverse Content&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pegi.info/search-pegi?q=Fortnite&amp;amp;op=Search&amp;amp;age%5B%5D=&amp;amp;descriptor%5B%5D=&amp;amp;publisher=&amp;amp;platform%5B%5D=&amp;amp;release_year%5B%5D=&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;form_build_id=form-GnpjAhS89Zgn4jhhXRik4UsriLrMWi8TxBv1ggZlmSE&amp;amp;form_id=pegi_search_form&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PEGI &lt;/a&gt;! rated game. All advertising, promotion, or communication related to your island must be age-appropriate and follow local rating body guidelines. You must not target under-13s with advertising, promotion, or communication of any kind for your island.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;3.3&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.3 Event Marketing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.3.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.3.1&quot;&gt;3.3.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;You may promote your island through physical and online events, as long as your event, competition, or tournament complies with all the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/epic---fortnite-event-license-terms-master-en-7ff978607be1.pdf&quot;&gt;Fortnite Event License Terms&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/Fortnite+Esports%2FFeaturing-Fortnite-Brand-Guidelines-849d062ab5a8738d6e119cf65aec81b088d203a2.pdf&quot;&gt;Fortnite Third Party Event Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;3.4&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.4 Contests and Sweepstakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.4.1&quot;&gt;3.4.1. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Your Fortnite island may not be used to conduct or promote a contest or sweepstakes promotion offering prizes (“Promotion”). This means that all aspects of a Promotion (including references to the Promotion, promotional materials, explanation of how to enter, entry methods, winner selection, and the awarded prizes) must be entirely &lt;u&gt;outside&lt;/u&gt; of your Fortnite island.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.4.2&quot;&gt;3.4.2. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you conduct or promote a Promotion outside of Fortnite in connection with your island, you must comply with the rules in this Section 3 and all applicable laws (including any registration requirements). Also, you must:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:120px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.4.2.1&quot;&gt;3.4.2.1. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not encourage or require entrants to make any purchase or payment in connection with the Promotion. For example, you may not restrict entry in the Promotion behind entry fees, paid subscriptions/follows, or any other purchase requirements, or otherwise imply that making a purchase will increase the odds of winning;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.4.2.2&quot;&gt;3.4.2.2. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Publish official Promotion rules (“Promotion Terms”), including all disclosures and terms required by law, and make them available wherever the Promotion is promoted or entries are accepted;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.4.2.3&quot;&gt;3.4.2.3. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the Promotion Terms and wherever the Promotion is promoted or entries are accepted, ensure that the Promotion’s sponsor(s) are clearly identified and include the following statement: “This promotion is not sponsored, endorsed, or administered by Epic Games, Inc.”; and&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;3.4.2.4&quot;&gt;3.4.2.4. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Include the following statements in the Promotion Terms:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
For all Promotions: “TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, PARTICIPANTS AGREE TO RELEASE AND HOLD HARMLESS EPIC GAMES, INC., ITS LICENSORS, ITS AND THEIR AFFILIATES, AND ITS AND THEIR EMPLOYEES, OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, AGENTS, CONTRACTORS, AND OTHER REPRESENTATIVES FROM ALL CLAIMS, DEMANDS, ACTIONS, LOSSES, LIABILITIES, AND EXPENSES RELATED TO THIS PROMOTION.”&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In addition, if entrants must submit any account or personal information: “THE INFORMATION PARTICIPANTS PROVIDE IN CONNECTION WITH THIS PROMOTION IS BEING PROVIDED TO SPONSOR AND NOT TO EPIC GAMES, INC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;3.5&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.5 Engaging with Press&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.5.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;3.5.1&quot;&gt;3.5.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Press release materials you create to promote your island must not state or suggest in any way that your island is an official Epic Games experience, or that you are in a partnership with Epic Games.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
3.5.2. All press release materials you create to promote your island should include the following: “This is an independently created Fortnite island and is not sponsored, endorsed, or administered by Epic Games, Inc.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
3.5.3. If you have any questions about promoting your island with the press or would like your press materials reviewed to ensure they comply with our policies, please reach out to Epic Games at FNCreativePR@epicgames.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4. Monetizing Your Island&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;We want to make it as easy as possible for you to monetize your Fortnite island while maintaining transparency for players. These rules outline what you can and cannot do to monetize your Fortnite island:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;4.1&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.1. Engagement Payouts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.1.1&quot;&gt;4.1.1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;As an island creator, you may monetize your islands via engagement payouts, if you are eligible. To participate in this program, please apply at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://create.fortnite.com/island-creator/signup&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Island Creator signup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;4.2&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.2 Support-A-Creator Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.2.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.2.2&quot;&gt;4.2.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you create media content on other platforms which promotes your Fortnite content or promotes Fortnite content created by others, you may participate in Epic’s Support-A-Creator program. To learn more and participate in this program, please apply at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sac.epicgames.com/overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Support-A-Creator FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.2.3&quot;&gt;4.2.2.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;As a member of the Support-A-Creator program, you are free to advertise your Creator Code anywhere &lt;u&gt;outside&lt;/u&gt; of Fortnite. If you are also an island creator, you must not solicit support for your Creator Code anywhere within your island, including a pre-game lobby, or in its metadata (name, description, thumbnail, loading screen text, or Discover video).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;4.3&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.3 Commercial Content and Sponsorships&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brands and creators are welcome to collaborate in Fortnite, as long as they follow these rules and any applicable laws. You cannot pay Epic Games to promote your content within Fortnite.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.1&quot;&gt;4.3.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Commercial content&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;is permitted in your Fortnite island. Commercial content is defined as any island that contains content which promotes or endorses a brand, product, service, or organization.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.2&quot;&gt;4.3.2.&lt;/span&gt; Commercial content is either “Paid,” which needs to be disclosed by the island creator, or “Owned,” which does not need to be disclosed by the island creator&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;paid&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paid&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;commercial content is an island that contains, either in the island itself or its metadata, content for which you have been compensated (i.e. received anything of value, including money, goods, and/or services) by others. This content may be in the form of sponsorship, endorsement, takeover, placement, or other actions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;owned&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owned&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;commercial content is an island that is built or controlled by a brand or other commercial entity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.3&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.3&quot;&gt;4.3.3.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;If you create Paid content, you are responsible for complying with any applicable laws around disclosing your relationship with the sponsor/brand.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.4&quot;&gt;4.3.4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Individual creators must be at least 18 to create or publish Paid commercial content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.5&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.5&quot;&gt;4.3.5.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Whether commercial content or not, your island and your island’s metadata must not include (a) calls to action outside Fortnite, (b) solicitation to join, participate in, or donate to a real-world religion, political organization or military organization, c) product claims, (d) dates of offer, or (e) pricing. Examples of things that aren’t allowed in your island’s metadata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.5&quot;&gt;“Go to onlinestore.com to learn more!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.5&quot;&gt;“Available now for only $19.99!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.5&quot;&gt;“This product works better than ever!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.5&quot;&gt;“See event at 9 PM on TV channel, on this day!”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;“Join the Green Party Today”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.6&quot;&gt;4.3.6.&lt;/span&gt; Commercial content and sponsors must follow all the content rules above, and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/site/content-guidelines&quot;&gt;Epic Content Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, and must not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Promote the purchase, sale, or trade of any medical, pharmaceutical, or supplemental products or services;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Promote the purchase, sale, or trade of real-world explosives, firearms, or ammunition;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Promote the purchase, sale, or trade of tobacco, alcohol, marijuana (regardless of legality), illegal drugs, and other illegal, contraband, or regulated goods;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Promote deceptive or harmful financial products and services;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;
&lt;li style=&quot;margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Promote real-world dating, romantic introductions, or hook-ups.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.7&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.3.7&quot;&gt;4.3.7.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;You may sell sponsorships for “in-person” events, tournaments, and competitions related to your island, provided your event complies with all the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/Fortnite+Esports%2FFortniteEventLicenseTerms%2FFortnite-Event-License-Terms_04.01.20-2f1b6cda1fccffce3ddb23f7a0b03fb6d3131946.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Event License Terms&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.unrealengine.com/Fortnite+Esports%2FFeaturing-Fortnite-Brand-Guidelines-849d062ab5a8738d6e119cf65aec81b088d203a2.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite Third Party Event Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p id=&quot;4.4&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:40px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.4&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.4 Monetization Practices to Avoid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:80px&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.4.1&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;4.4.1&quot;&gt;4.4.1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;You must not restrict access to specific content or items within an island via external sites; all content should be accessible in-game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.4.2&quot;&gt;4.4.2.&lt;/span&gt; You must not charge for access to your island; it must be freely accessible to all Fortnite players.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.4.3&quot;&gt;4.4.3.&lt;/span&gt; You must not create, distribute, or sell physical merchandise that features any Epic Games or Fortnite assets or logos, such as clothing, hats, or mugs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;4.4.3&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;other-terms&quot;&gt;Other Terms &amp;amp; Conditions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;other-terms&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;As a player of Fortnite, you are bound by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/fortnite/en-US/eula&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fortnite EULA&lt;/a&gt;. If you use Unreal Editor for Fortnite, you are additionally bound by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fortnite.com/unreal-editor-for-fortnite-supplemental-terms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UEFN Supplemental Terms&lt;/a&gt;. If you are an island creator who has been given the ability to publish content to Fortnite, you are additionally bound by the Engagement Program Payout Terms. If you are a media creator who promotes Fortnite content, you are bound by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/affiliate/en-US/eula?lang=en-US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Support-A-Creator Terms &amp;amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If Epic is made aware that the Creator Rules on this page, (including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fn.gg/LEGO-Brand-and-Creator-Rules&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LEGO Brand and Creator Rules&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.epicgames.com/documentation/uefn/tmnt-brand-and-creator-rules-in-unreal-editor-for-fortnite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the TMNT Brand and Creator Rules&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;and the terms in the IP Partner Licensing Agreement), are being violated, Epic will take action on a case-by-case basis. Enforcement actions can be anything; from a warning, changes in Discover visibility, disabled content, loss of publishing privileges, all the way up to a permanent account or monetization ban for more severe or repeated offenses.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If your Epic account is permanently banned, you may lose all rights to Epic games, virtual items, account balances, or other items that you may have earned or purchased.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;reporting&quot;&gt;Reporting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;reporting&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;We are all a part of this community, and it is up to us to keep it fun. If you encounter a player or creator who is not respecting the rules above, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicgames.com/help/en-US/fortnite-c75/battle-royale-c93/how-do-i-report-bad-player-behavior-in-fortnite-a3276&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report them&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://safety.epicgames.com/en-US/policies/reporting-misconduct/submit-report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;report their island&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;1.14&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;</description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-island-creator-rules?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-island-creator-rules?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Fortnite Team</author></item><item><title>Lyon - Décines, France to Host FN Globals 2025!</title><description></description><link>https://www.fortnite.com/news/lyon-decines-france-to-host-2025s-fortnite-global-championship?lang=en-US</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fortnite.com/news/lyon-decines-france-to-host-2025s-fortnite-global-championship?lang=en-US</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>The Competitive Fortnite Team</author></item></channel></rss>