<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>dn.com - The Latest</title><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.email-once.com/dn/en-us/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Dn domain name information channel brings together the latest domain name news and information platform to provide users with domain name industry-related knowledge points, the current popularity of domain name information, popularise a variety of domain name knowledge, to understand the domain name industry&#39;s most comprehensive and most professional information, the world&#39;s high-quality domain names for sale to buy management on Dn.com. - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://dn.com/assets/images/logo.png</url><title>dn.com - The Latest</title><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/</link></image><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:29:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Big news! Bitcoin ISO domain name xbt.com starts at nearly $2.8 million, blockchain domain name value soars</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Recently, the Bitcoin ISO 4217 currency code associated domain name &quot;xbt.com&quot; was auctioned at Lloyd&#39;s Auction House with a starting price of $2,798,917, and the latest bid has reached $2,799,495!&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Recently, the domain name trading market ushered in a focus event: Bitcoin ISO 4217 currency code associated domain name &quot;xbt.com&quot; started at $2,798,917 at Lloyd&#39;s Auction House, and the latest bid has reached $2,799,495! This operation not only ignited the enthusiasm of the domain name investment circle, but also released a strong signal-Bitcoin and blockchain-related scarce domain names are becoming the &quot;new favorite of digital assets&quot; pursued by the market!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Big news! Bitcoin ISO domain name xbt.com starts at nearly $2.8 million, blockchain domain name value soars&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-24/05153194478243459dec8ebd91b85cb4.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason why &quot;xbt.com&quot; has attracted attention is that it is deeply bound to Bitcoin&#39;s historical status in the traditional financial field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the ISO currency code used by Bitcoin, &quot;XBT&quot; has been used by well-known exchanges such as Kraken and BitMEX for URLs and API endpoints, carrying important memories of the development of cryptocurrency. This high price is not only a reflection of the value of a single domain name, but also reflects the potential explosion of blockchain and cryptocurrency-related domain names under the upgrading of industry cognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Big news! Bitcoin ISO domain name xbt.com starts at nearly $2.8 million, blockchain domain name value soars&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-24/e8607242c1cb4ae2b5cdc257cdc03780.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bidding enthusiasm of &quot;xbt.com&quot; reflects the core value of domain names in the blockchain field. In the blockchain ecosystem, high-quality domain names are not only the entrance to the Internet, but also the key carrier of project brand recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take &quot;xbt.com&quot; as an example. It has its own industry memory point due to its historical association with Bitcoin. Whether it is used for the construction of the official website of the blockchain project, the logo of the ecological platform, or as a cultural symbol of the brand story, it can enhance the uniqueness of the project in the industry. This domain name that combines historical significance, practical functions and brand value is becoming an important medium for blockchain projects to build differentiated advantages and investors to deploy digital assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domain names are scarce identifiers in the digital age, and blockchain-related domain names have both collection and practical value due to the particularity of the industry. If you want to grasp more high-quality domain name resources for Bitcoin and blockchain, please contact us. The DN.COM platform brings together a large number of scarce domain names to help you capture domain name investment opportunities in the digital economy era. Click to explore your &quot;digital identifier&quot;!&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2041.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2041.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 06:55:40 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN domain name editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>xbt.com</category></item><item><title>Bitcoin breaks through $87,000, and Trump has set the crypto market on fire again!</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;President Trump just made a high-profile statement on the social platform: &quot;I love TRUMP coin - so cool! The best of them all!&quot; This sentence directly pushed TRUMP coin and Bitcoin to the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;President Trump just made a high-profile statement on the social platform: &quot;I love TRUMP coin - so cool! The best of them!&quot; This sentence directly pushed TRUMP coin and Bitcoin to the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bitcoin breaks through $87,000, and Trump has set the crypto market on fire again!&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-24/972f1c20c3de4921ab94957286ba1f1a.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After his speech, market sentiment was completely ignited, and the prices of Bitcoin and TRUMP coin rose. TRUMP coin once soared by nearly 15%, and then the price fell back to $11.48, while Bitcoin just broke through $87,000!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bitcoin breaks through $87,000, and Trump has set the crypto market on fire again!&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-24/31b0bac8a76248e091b79a2443f1c6b8.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the price of Bitcoin soared, the market&#39;s attention to cryptocurrencies reached its peak again. At the same time, assets related to Bitcoin and artificial intelligence (AI) have also attracted more attention, further strengthening their popularity in the investment field. BTC.ai is currently listed for sale on the DN.com platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many industry insiders believe that Trump&#39;s influence and market sentiment may continue to drive fluctuations in the value of assets in cryptocurrencies and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2039.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2039.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 06:34:57 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN platform editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>Bitcoin</category><category> Trump</category></item><item><title>Nallis.com domain name dispute re-ruled, Indian complainant lost, WIPO maintains domain name ownership</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The WIPO Arbitration and Mediation Center recently issued a ruling on the second Uniform Domain Name Dispute Resolution Policy (UDRP) case filed by the Nalli Silks Sari Centre of India regarding the domain name Nallis.com&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Recently, the Arbitration and Mediation Center of the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO) ruled on the second Uniform Domain Name Dispute Resolution Policy (UDRP) case filed by Nalli&#39;s Silks Sari Centre in India against the domain name Nallis.com, dismissing the complainant&#39;s request to transfer the domain name. This case has attracted industry attention due to the complexity of family trademark disputes, domain name investment and UDRP procedures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Nallis.com domain name dispute re-ruled, Indian complainant lost, WIPO maintains domain name ownership&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-22/42a435e366344b35a02eaa3f83a1f4d4.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historical disputes and domain name transfers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The complainant Nalli&#39;s Silks Sari Centre has been operating a silk sari business in India since 1981 and owns the &quot;NALLI&#39;S&quot; trademark registered in 1993. The domain name Nallis.com was registered by the complainant in 1999, but was ruled to be transferred to another Indian family business, Chetty Group, in the first UDRP in 2009. After that, the complainant failed to renew the domain name, causing it to expire in 2019, and it was eventually purchased by Mira Holdings, a US domain name investor, through a Snapnames auction for US$1,174.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Nallis.com domain name dispute re-ruled, Indian complainant lost, WIPO maintains domain name ownership&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-22/c09f982905314bcfa1148613485326bb.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Focus of dispute: bad faith registration and legitimate rights and interests&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The complainant claimed that the defendant maliciously registered the domain name with the intention of reselling it at a high price. The reasons include: the domain name is highly similar to the complainant&#39;s trademark, the defendant has been found malicious in other UDRP cases, and the complainant has been using the &quot;NALLI&quot; trademark for a long time. However, the defendant argued that &quot;Nalli&quot; is a common surname (used by more than 900 people worldwide), and its acquisition of the domain name was based on investment value and was not targeted at the complainant. The defendant further pointed out that the complainant did not participate in the auction and did not provide evidence of actual use of the trademark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WIPO panel determined that although the complainant holds a trademark, it has not proved its international reputation, and the trademark registration category is relatively narrow (only textiles). In addition, the domain name transaction records provided by the defendant show that similar surname domain names are often sold at high prices. Therefore, the panel believes that the defendant&#39;s behavior is in line with reasonable investment logic and does not constitute bad faith.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruling results and procedural details&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel finally ruled that the complainant failed to meet the &quot;bad faith registration and use&quot; requirement of the three elements of the UDRP, and rejected the defendant&#39;s allegations of reverse domain name hijacking. During the case process, the defendant&#39;s reply was overdue due to email delays, but the panel still accepted his statement based on the complexity of the case.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2037.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2037.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 07:35:37 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN platform editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>Nallis.com Domain</category></item><item><title>Detroit.com domain name successfully sold, new opportunities for geographic domain name investment</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Detroit.com has recently been successfully sold. Detroit, a historic American city known as the &quot;Rock City&quot; and the &quot;Motor City&quot;, has seen the sale of its representative geographic domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Detroit.com has recently been successfully sold, becoming a hot topic in the domain name investment community. Detroit, a historic American city known as the &quot;Rock City&quot; and the &quot;Motor City&quot;, ushered in the sale of its representative geographic domain name. The transaction was planned by Grit Brokerage and GeoCentric Media and attracted widespread attention on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Detroit.com domain name successfully sold, new opportunities for geographic domain name investment&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-22/2a127cec0ad84ea7898ef43d54b72134.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detroit is not only famous for the classic song &quot;Detroit Rock City&quot; by the Kiss band, it is also regarded as the birthplace of the automobile industry and the center of industrial innovation. Today, the sale of Detroit.com has undoubtedly added new digital asset value to this important city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The success of this transaction once again proves the scarcity and high value of geographic domain names, especially when these domain names are deeply tied to history, culture and industry. As a domain name registered in 1996, Detroit.com not only represents the history and culture of this city, but also has strong market appeal and investment potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, do you have a geographic name .com domain name in your investment portfolio? With the sale of iconic domain names like Detroit.com, the investment value of geographic domain names has been increasingly valued by the market and has become a part that investors cannot ignore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information source: domaingang&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2035.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2035.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 07:07:11 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN domain name editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>Detroit.com</category></item><item><title>.com is stable at a high price, .ai transactions surge, and the recent domain name market shows a bipolar trend</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;The latest data shows that in the past two weeks, .com domain names still dominate with high prices, while .ai domain names have seen a significant increase in transaction volume due to the popularity of artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;According to the latest domain name transaction data released by dnjournal, from March 3, 2025 to March 16, 2025, the global domain name transaction market showed a distinct bipolar trend: .com domain names still dominate at high prices, while .ai domain names have become the new favorite of the market due to the popularity of artificial intelligence and a sharp increase in transaction volume.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;.com is stable at a high price, .ai transactions surge, and the recent domain name market shows a bipolar trend&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-21/26edfb68455848f6a92580f018acb9bf.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this transaction list, GX.com took the lead with a price of US$1.2 million, becoming the domain name with the highest transaction amount in the past two weeks. Double.com, which followed closely, also sold at a high price of US$980,000, further consolidating the dominance of .com domain names in the high-end market. Although .com domain names continue to maintain strong premium capabilities, in addition to the top two, only a few .com domain names such as WWWW.com and IRU.com are in the top 20, indicating that high-priced .com transactions are still scarce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;.com is stable at a high price, .ai transactions surge, and the recent domain name market shows a bipolar trend&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-21/a0e550cf4a4c48d193ba9c2cac32a18d.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that .ai domain names performed particularly well in this round of transactions. Among the top 20, 10 .ai domain names were on the list, accounting for half of the list, fully demonstrating the driving effect of the artificial intelligence craze on the domain name market. Among them, Ace.ai became the most expensive .ai domain name with a transaction price of US$205,000, followed by OS.ai and TP.ai, which were also sold for US$150,000 and US$90,000 respectively, reflecting the market&#39;s continued attention to brands and technologies related to artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;.com is stable at a high price, .ai transactions surge, and the recent domain name market shows a bipolar trend&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-21/0d9f3725c4774d70943618b69a4ae3d2.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, among other suffix domain names, Coches.es, which means &quot;car&quot; in Spanish, was sold for approximately US$130,800, showing the market value of domain names related to specific languages and industries. Borderless.xyz was sold for US$35,888, reflecting that some emerging suffixes still have investment potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the overall transaction trend, .com domain names are still the most valuable assets in the market, and high-end domain names can still attract large transactions. However, .ai domain names are rapidly expanding their market share with the booming development of the artificial intelligence industry, especially in the mid-to-high price range, becoming the focus of investors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the continuous advancement of artificial intelligence technology, the market demand for .ai domain names may continue to rise, and more high-quality .ai domain names may be sold at high prices in the future. As the core asset of the Internet, .com domain names still maintain an unshakable value position, especially short and clear-meaning high-quality domain names, which are expected to continue to dominate the top-level domain name market.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2033.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2033.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 06:02:20 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>.com</category><category>.ai</category><category>domain name transactions</category></item><item><title>$79,888! The domain name Codex.xyz was successfully sold</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Recently, Swetha announced on the social platform x that the domain name Codex.xyz was successfully sold for $79,888.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Recently, Swetha announced on the social platform x that the domain name Codex.xyz was successfully sold for $79,888. Swetha is known as the &quot;Queen of xyz&quot; in the industry. With her rich experience and keen vision, she has completed many influential domain name transactions. The domain name was registered in 2018 and has a history of several years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;$79,888! The domain name Codex.xyz was successfully sold&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-21/dcd9c220ac244488a2b0fcc34f9c934a.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Codex means &quot;code&quot; in English, which is rich in connotation and highly recognizable. With the new top-level domain suffix .xyz, its uniqueness and innovation are further highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an emerging top-level domain name, .xyz has been widely popular worldwide in recent years. It gives the domain name a fashionable and cutting-edge quality, breaking the limitations of traditional domain name suffixes and providing more diverse choices for various innovative projects and emerging companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;$79,888! The domain name Codex.xyz was successfully sold&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-21/892328da38b74c92888977cc55af7243.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For companies or projects in the fields of law, academia, and technology, Codex.xyz can not only show its profound heritage, but also demonstrate its attitude of keeping up with the times. It is undoubtedly an attractive brand identity and is expected to shine on the Internet stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The high price of Codex.xyz not only confirms the market value of high-quality domain names, but also reflects that the recognition of the .xyz suffix in the field of domain name investment is continuing to increase. With the continuous development of the Internet industry, this domain name combination with both cultural connotations and contemporary characteristics is expected to occupy a more important position in the future domain name trading market.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2030.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2030.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 02:57:59 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>Codex.xyz</category><category> .xua domain names</category></item><item><title>Amazon to launch three new top-level domains: .free, .hot, and .spot next month</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Amazon plans to launch three new top-level domains (TLDs) next month: .free, .hot and .spot.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Amazon plans to launch three new top-level domains (TLDs) next month: .free, .hot, and .spot. These domains were originally applied for in the new generic top-level domain (gTLD) expansion plan in 2012. After years of preparation, they are now ready for public registration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Amazon to launch three new top-level domains: .free, .hot, and .spot next month&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-20/85c83980bb10434b9822a57492db20b9.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Important dates:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Priority use period: Starting from April 2, 2025, Amazon will provide priority registration opportunities for trademark holders and specific user groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early experience period: From May 12 to 17, 2025, this stage adopts the Dutch auction model, and the registration fee decreases day by day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May 12: About $6,000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May 13: About $3,000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May 17: About $200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Prices may vary by registrar)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public registration: These new top-level domains will be available to all users starting May 19, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pricing information:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to domain registrar 101Domain, the registration fee for a .free domain is $44.99 per year, a .hot domain is $59.99 per year, and a .spot domain is $29.99 per year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source: domainnamewire&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2029.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2029.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 08:25:24 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN platform editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>New TLDs</category></item><item><title>Rare two-letter domain name IZ.com was auctioned due to expiration</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Among the approximately 350 million registered domain names in the world, there are only 676 two-letter .com domain names. However, IZ.com, which was sold for $625,000 in 2017, has entered the auction due to expiration.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Among the approximately 350 million registered domain names in the world, there are only 676 two-letter .com domain names, which are extremely rare and have long-term stable investment value. However, IZ.com, which was sold for $625,000 in 2017, entered the auction due to expiration, and the current bid has reached $290,500. This unexpected incident has attracted widespread attention in the domain name investment circle, and people can&#39;t help but feel sorry that such a precious digital asset has flowed into the market due to negligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rare two-letter domain name IZ.com was auctioned due to expiration&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-20/8d42b70a11f54a9ea19736b921e14f6f.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market value of IZ.com was revealed as early as 2017, when the domain name was publicly accepted for bids, and the original holder clearly hoped that the price would be in the seven-digit US dollar range (more than $1 million). However, in 2021, IZ.com was finally sold by QEIP.com for $625,000. Although it did not reach the expected seven-digit price, it was still one of the high-priced domain names of the year, demonstrating the hard-core value of the two-letter .com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rare two-letter domain name IZ.com was auctioned due to expiration&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-20/4103094853794ff7b9192c44302443ad.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly, in 2025, this precious asset expired unexpectedly due to failure to renew in time, and then entered the Namecheap platform for public auction. As one of the only 676 two-letter .com domain names in the world, the expired auction of IZ.com is undoubtedly a regrettable thing. After all, such domain names are not only scarce, but also have irreplaceable significance in brand building and digital asset preservation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two-letter .com domain names have always been the target of companies and investors because of their short and powerful, easy to remember and highly versatile. Such domain names are usually used for brand simplification, international expansion and marketing. Especially for companies pursuing a global layout, owning a two-letter domain name not only represents the unique identity of the brand, but also a symbol of business strength.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is precisely because of this scarcity and high value that two-letter .com domain names have repeatedly been sold at high prices in recent years. For example, TS.com was sold for US$1.4 million in 2022, and IT.com set a sales record of US$3.5 million in 2023. In contrast, the auction of IZ.com due to expiration not only caused huge losses to the original owner, but also made the market once again realize the importance of missed management of rare domain names.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2027.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2027.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 02:37:50 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN platform editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>Two letter domain names</category><category> .com domain names</category><category> domain name auctions</category></item><item><title>Breaking news! The two-letter domain name DF.com has changed hands, and the semiconductor giant has acquired it strongly</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Reliable sources indicate that the two-letter domain name DF.com, which was once used for cryptocurrency transactions, has been successfully acquired by Diamond Foundry (DF Semiconductor), a leading global semiconductor company.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;Reliable information shows that the two-letter domain name DF.com, which was once used for cryptocurrency transactions, has been successfully acquired by Diamond Foundry (DF Semiconductor), a world-leading single-crystal diamond technology research and manufacturing company. This transaction not only highlights the scarcity of high-quality domain names, but also reflects the volatility of the virtual currency market and the long-term value of domain names as stable Internet assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Breaking news! The two-letter domain name DF.com has changed hands, and the semiconductor giant has acquired it strongly&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-19/78c12790ad6d45378de1e2d28e42f794.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DF.com was originally acquired by Shentu Qingchun, the founder of Silver Chain Technology from China, in March 2018 and built into the &quot;DFEX Cryptocurrency Trading Platform&quot;, which was officially launched on October 22, 2018, mainly for the Southeast Asian market. However, with the tightening of global supervision, the DFEX platform could not escape the fate of withdrawal and quietly closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, DF.com completed the transaction transfer in April 2023. The buyer is Diamond Foundry (DF Semiconductor), headquartered in San Francisco, USA. Founded in 2012, the company focuses on cultivating high-quality single-crystal diamonds using semiconductor chemical vapor deposition (CVD) technology. Its products are widely used in cutting-edge technology fields such as 5G communications, cloud computing, artificial intelligence and electric vehicles, and have broad market prospects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Breaking news! The two-letter domain name DF.com has changed hands, and the semiconductor giant has acquired it strongly&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-19/08d68132ab884b4da7244d267f59ef4f.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the transaction amount has not been disclosed, as a rare two-letter .com domain name, DF.com has extremely high market value. The domain name perfectly matches the abbreviation of Diamond Foundry, strengthens its brand image, and enhances the company&#39;s professionalism and recognition in the global semiconductor market. For DF Semiconductor, which focuses on cutting-edge technology, this is undoubtedly a strategic investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Against the backdrop of increasing volatility in the virtual currency market, the successful sale of DF.com once again confirms the ability of high-quality domain names to maintain and increase value. Compared with the high risks and uncertainties of virtual currencies, domain names have become more stable digital assets due to their scarcity and long-term market demand.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2025.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2025.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:46:10 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>DF.com</category><category> two-letter domain name</category><category> domain name transaction</category></item><item><title>Dutch company Skytree BV loses UDRP case, domain name skytree.com remains owned</title><description>&lt;backquote&gt; 
          &lt;span&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;WIPO recently ruled on the domain name dispute between Dutch company Skytree BV and US entity Whiskytree, Inc., determining that the complainant constitutes RDNH and the disputed domain name belongs to the respondent.&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;/backquote&gt;   
            &lt;p&gt;The World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO) recently ruled on the domain name dispute between Dutch company Skytree BV (complainant) and US entity Whiskytree, Inc. (respondent), finding that the complainant filed the Uniform Domain Name Dispute Resolution Policy (UDRP) procedure in bad faith, constituting reverse domain name hijacking (RDNH), and the disputed domain name skytree.com continues to belong to the respondent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dutch company Skytree BV loses UDRP case, domain name skytree.com remains owned&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-19/09feb05aba6c47e3a900f88d816cc71b.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus of dispute: Domain name registered in 1998 vs. trademark rights in 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The respondent registered skytree.com in December 1998, while the complainant only began to use the SKYTREE trademark to provide carbon capture technology services in 2014. Although the complainant filed the UDRP procedure after unsuccessfully trying to acquire the domain name for $14,000 through GoDaddy brokerage services, accusing the respondent of holding the domain name in bad faith, the panel pointed out that according to UDRP policy precedent, if the domain name registration time is earlier than the trademark right (16 years in this case), there is no possibility of bad faith registration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dutch company Skytree BV loses UDRP case, domain name skytree.com remains owned&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-19/7f43000c467941eb9d63a448d1bf93a4.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel: Complainant abused the procedure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its ruling, the panel listed multiple violations by the complainant:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Ignoring policy precedents: The complaint clearly acknowledged that the respondent registered the trademark long before the trademark right, but still claimed bad faith registration, violating the principles established in Section 3.8.1 of WIPO Overview 3.0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. Fabricating legal basis: Equating the lack of active use of the domain name with &quot;deterioration&quot; as bad faith, attempting to replace the respondent&#39;s bad faith evidence with the complainant&#39;s needs;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3. Instrumentalization of procedures: Acknowledging that the complaint was filed because the domain name owner could not be contacted through the brokerage service, using the UDRP as a tool to reveal the identity or pressure the purchase;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4. Lack of good faith negotiation: After the respondent did not respond to the broker&#39;s request, the UDRP was directly initiated instead of resolving the dispute through other legal channels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dutch company Skytree BV loses UDRP case, domain name skytree.com remains owned&quot; src=&quot;https://static.loupan.com/dn/upload/image/2025-03-19/9ff8621174f44e88adb3189f42f3ffa5.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry warning: UDRP is not a shortcut to domain name acquisition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This case once again highlights the core principle of the UDRP procedure - protecting legitimate prior domain name rights. WIPO expert Adam Taylor stressed: &quot;The complainant misunderstood the UDRP as a negotiation tool to obtain other people&#39;s domain names, and this behavior seriously damaged the credibility of the dispute resolution mechanism.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, skytree.com is still held by the respondent, and its legitimate rights and interests as a visual effects company are protected. The case shows that when trademark holders assert their rights through UDRP, they must strictly follow the constituent elements of &quot;bad faith registration&quot;, otherwise they may face sanctions for procedural abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
         </description><link>https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2023.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dn.com/en-us/news/detail-2023.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 02:58:38 GMT</pubDate><author>By：DN editor</author><category>Industry Information</category><category>WIPO</category><category> UDRP</category><category> domain name transactions</category></item></channel></rss>