<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>AInvest - Latest News</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news</link><atom:link href="http://rss.wudifeixue.com/ainvest/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>AInvest - Latest News - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:21:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Quantum computing startup PsiQuantum raising at least $750 million at $6 billion valuation, sources say - Reuters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum computing startup PsiQuantum raising at least $750 million at $6 billion valuation, sources say - Reuters&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/quantum-computing-startup-psiquantum-raising-at-least-750-million-at-6-billion-valuation-sources-say-reuters-2503100015ea8e0de4f3f3a4/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/quantum-computing-startup-psiquantum-raising-at-least-750-million-at-6-billion-valuation-sources-say-reuters-2503100015ea8e0de4f3f3a4/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:21:36 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Apollo&#39;s Zelter: Doesn&#39;t see a bubble in private credit</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Apollo&#39;s Zelter: Doesn&#39;t see a bubble in private credit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d79a8d305f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/apollo-s-zelter-doesn-t-see-a-bubble-in-private-credit-25031000ec26a71b5e69bbcc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/apollo-s-zelter-doesn-t-see-a-bubble-in-private-credit-25031000ec26a71b5e69bbcc/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:18:16 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>IDP Education block trades; 1.6% of free float</title><description>&lt;p&gt;IDP Education block trades; 1.6% of free float&lt;/p&gt;IDP Education Ltd (IDP), an Australian-based education provider, recently experienced block trades representing 1.6% of its free float shares [1]. This article delves into the implications of these transactions on IDP&#39;s free float percentage and its overall market liquidity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Free float, or public float, refers to the number of shares in a company that can be traded freely in the public market without any restrictions [2]. It is calculated by subtracting restricted shares, closely held shares, and treasury shares from the total outstanding shares. In IDP&#39;s case, with a free float of 450,000 shares out of a total of 500,000 shares, the company had a free float percentage of 90% [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Block trades, which are large transactions involving a significant number of shares, can have a significant impact on a company&#39;s free float percentage. When a substantial portion of a company&#39;s free float is traded in a single transaction, it can lead to a decrease in the overall liquidity of the stock [3]. This can potentially impact the trading price and make it more difficult for smaller investors to buy or sell shares.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, it is essential to note that block trades do not necessarily indicate insider trading or any other nefarious activity. In fact, they can be a result of various factors, such as institutional investors rebalancing their portfolios or market makers executing large orders [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;IDP&#39;s recent block trades, while representing a significant percentage of its free float, do not appear to have been the result of any insider trading activity. According to the company&#39;s latest disclosures, there have been no material changes to its ownership structure or any other significant corporate developments that could explain these transactions [5].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, IDP Education&#39;s recent block trades, representing 1.6% of its free float, have implications for the company&#39;s market liquidity. However, based on the available information, there is no evidence of insider trading or any other nefarious activity associated with these transactions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] IDP Education Limited. (2023, February 14). Market Announcements. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://www.asx.com.au/asx/app/asx/release.aspx?id=A030X0000G&amp;amp;isDiscoveryPage=true&lt;br&gt;[2] Corporate Finance Institute. (n.d.). Free Float. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://corporatefinanceinstitute.com/resources/career-map/sell-side/capital-markets/free-float/&lt;br&gt;[3] Investopedia. (n.d.). Block Trade. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/blocktrade.asp&lt;br&gt;[4] Yahoo Finance. (n.d.). Block Trades. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://finance.yahoo.com/help/faq/investing/block-trades.html&lt;br&gt;[5] IDP Education Limited. (2023, February 14). Market Announcements. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://www.asx.com.au/asx/app/asx/release.aspx?id=A030X0000G&amp;amp;isDiscoveryPage=true&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d79bac3c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/idp-education-block-trades-1-6-of-free-float-25031000faac071d57a2ff93/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/idp-education-block-trades-1-6-of-free-float-25031000faac071d57a2ff93/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:18:08 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Republican Ed Durr drops out of the New Jersey&#39;s governor race</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican Ed Durr drops out of the New Jersey&#39;s governor race&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/republican-ed-durr-drops-out-of-new-jersey-s-governor-race-25031000b49cbe62c0223a50/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/republican-ed-durr-drops-out-of-new-jersey-s-governor-race-25031000b49cbe62c0223a50/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:10:06 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Hegseth: Nobody was texting war plans, that&#39;s all I&#39;ll say</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hegseth: Nobody was texting war plans, that&#39;s all I&#39;ll say&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/hegseth-nobody-was-texting-war-plans-that-s-all-i-ll-say-25031000a5402270f94563a8/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/hegseth-nobody-was-texting-war-plans-that-s-all-i-ll-say-25031000a5402270f94563a8/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:09:43 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>LG Energy signs ESS supply deal with Poland state-run company</title><description>&lt;p&gt;LG Energy signs ESS supply deal with Poland state-run company&lt;/p&gt;The Polish energy landscape is undergoing a significant transformation, with local utility PGE Group tapping into the expertise of LG Energy Solutions to construct a massive 900 MWh battery energy storage system (BESS) [1]. This strategic collaboration underscores LG Energy Solutions&#39; growing commitment to Europe&#39;s green energy transition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;PGE Group&#39;s 263 MW/900 MWh Zarnowiec BESS project, set to be operational in 2029, is a crucial step in enhancing the stability of Poland&#39;s electricity grid [1]. The facility, which will be located near the Żarnowiec Pumped Storage Power Plant, will help balance the output of onshore and offshore wind farms, aiding in the integration of renewable energy sources.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;LG Energy Solution Wroclaw, a local subsidiary, will oversee the project&#39;s design and construction on a turnkey basis [1]. The company&#39;s successful bid, priced at PLN 1.555 billion ($384 million), beat out competitors, including Corab, by offering a more advantageous price [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This latest development is not an isolated incident for LG Energy Solutions in Poland. The company has also entered into a multi-year battery supply agreement with Impact Clean Power Technology (ICPT) to power electric buses in Europe [2]. Under this deal, LG Energy Solution will supply ICPT with around 200,000 units of battery modules manufactured at its Wroclaw facility [2]. These modules will then be assembled into battery packs and systems at GigafactoryX ICPT in Pruszkow [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Poland&#39;s growing emphasis on renewable energy and battery storage solutions positions LG Energy Solutions as a key player in the country&#39;s green energy transition. With a strong local presence and strategic partnerships, LG Energy Solutions is well-positioned to contribute to Poland&#39;s goal of a carbon-neutral future.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;Polish utility selects LG Energy Solution to build 900 MWh battery,&quot; ESS News, January 23, 2025, https://www.ess-news.com/2025/01/23/polish-utility-selects-lg-energy-solution-to-build-900-mwh-battery/&lt;br&gt;[2] &quot;LG Energy Solution and Impact Clean Power Technology sign multi-year battery supply agreement to power electric buses in Europe,&quot; Inside LG Energy Solution, December 7, 2023, https://inside.lgensol.com/en/2023/12/lg-energy-solution-and-impact-clean-power-technology-sign-multi-year-battery-supply-agreement-to-power-electric-buses-in-europe/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d77992a85f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-energy-signs-ess-supply-deal-with-poland-state-run-company-25031000b38303e73c6c9977/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-energy-signs-ess-supply-deal-with-poland-state-run-company-25031000b38303e73c6c9977/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:08:37 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>LG Electronics resumes some factory lines in Russia, Maeil says</title><description>&lt;p&gt;LG Electronics resumes some factory lines in Russia, Maeil says&lt;/p&gt;LG Electronics, a leading South Korean electronics manufacturer, has announced the resumption of partial factory operations in Russia, according to a report by Maeil [1]. The decision comes amidst ongoing global supply chain disruptions, including the suspension of shipping services by major maritime logistics companies [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The electronics giant had previously suspended all shipments to Russia due to &quot;humanitarian concerns,&quot; as the war in Ukraine continued to escalate [1]. LG&#39;s decision to resume partial factory operations in Russia is a reflection of the company&#39;s commitment to maintaining its operations in the country while navigating the complexities of the global supply chain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to a report by Reuters, LG Electronics produces TVs and white goods in Luza near Moscow for shipments to Russia and neighboring Commonwealth of Independent States [1]. The plant remains in operation despite raw material supply shortages and the Russian ruble&#39;s depreciation [1]. However, the suspension of shipping services to Russia could result in the plant running out of parts, potentially leading to a shutdown [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The price of raw materials essential to LG&#39;s operations, such as iron ore and coking coal, has also been affected by the conflict in Ukraine. The price of iron ore, for example, has risen from $141.75 per ton on January 31 to $151.35 per ton on March 18 [1]. Similarly, the price of coking coal, necessary to produce iron ore, has surged from $442.3 per ton on January 31 to $658.75 on March 17 due to the suspension of supplies from Russia [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these challenges, LG Electronics remains committed to supporting humanitarian relief efforts and maintaining the health and safety of all people [1]. The company will continue to monitor the situation closely and adapt its operations accordingly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;LG Electronics resumes some factory lines in Russia, Maeil says.&quot; Pulse.mk.co.kr. March 19, 2022. https://pulse.mk.co.kr/news/english/10259567.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] &quot;LG Electronics suspends all shipments to Russia due to global logistics disruptions.&quot; Korea Times. March 18, 2022. https://m.koreatimes.co.kr/pages/article.asp?newsIdx=325805.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d74dc6fc7e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-electronics-resumes-some-factory-lines-in-russia-maeil-says-2503100090af1f6b4f39709b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-electronics-resumes-some-factory-lines-in-russia-maeil-says-2503100090af1f6b4f39709b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:57:09 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Fed&#39;s Gray: Fed will have room for a couple more rate cuts</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Fed&#39;s Gray: Fed will have room for a couple more rate cuts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d72f88485f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-gray-fed-will-have-room-for-a-couple-more-rate-cuts-250310003c035183b44bfbaf/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-gray-fed-will-have-room-for-a-couple-more-rate-cuts-250310003c035183b44bfbaf/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:48:59 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump signs order imposing sanctions on countries importing Venezuelan oil - White House</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump signs order imposing sanctions on countries importing Venezuelan oil - White House&lt;/p&gt;Introduction:&lt;br&gt;In a recent development, President Donald Trump announced his intention to impose a 25% tariff on all imports from countries purchasing oil or gas from Venezuela [1]. This move comes as part of a broader effort to pressure the South American nation, which has been embroiled in political turmoil and economic crisis for several years. The tariffs, which are set to take effect on April 2, are expected to impact various countries, including China, India, Russia, and Spain, among others [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Background:&lt;br&gt;Venezuela has been a contentious issue in U.S.-Latin American relations for quite some time. The country&#39;s political crisis, which began in earnest in 2014, has led to widespread protests, human rights abuses, and economic instability. The United States has responded to these developments by imposing a series of sanctions on Venezuela, aimed at pressuring the government to respect human rights and democratic norms [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Impact of Tariffs:&lt;br&gt;The tariffs announced by President Trump are expected to have a significant impact on the global oil market. Venezuela is one of the world&#39;s largest oil producers, and its exports play a crucial role in the energy security of many countries. The tariffs could potentially disrupt these exports, leading to supply shortages and higher prices for oil and gas [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, the tariffs could also have economic consequences for the countries importing Venezuelan oil. By forcing these countries to pay the tariff on all their trade to the United States, the Trump administration is effectively raising the cost of doing business with the United States. This could potentially lead to a decrease in trade volumes and a negative impact on economic growth [5].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Conclusion:&lt;br&gt;The announcement of tariffs on countries importing Venezuelan oil marks a new chapter in U.S.-Venezuela relations. While the move is aimed at pressuring the Venezuelan government to respect human rights and democratic norms, it could also have significant economic consequences for both the United States and its trading partners. As the situation unfolds, it will be important for all parties to carefully consider the potential impacts of these tariffs and work towards finding a solution that promotes stability and prosperity in the region.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. Trump says he will put a 25% tariff on countries that buy Venezuelan oil. https://apnews.com/article/trump-tariff-venezuela-oil-gas-tax-9197d606dea29caed6a7a79dd358d26a&lt;br&gt;[2] Soo Leader. Trump says he&#39;ll put a 25% tariff on countries that buy Venezuelan oil, though the U.S. does so itself. https://www.sooleader.com/michigan-news-ap/trump-says-hell-put-a-25-tariff-on-countries-that-buy-venezuelan-oil-though-the-us-does-so-itself-10419500&lt;br&gt;[3] U.S. Department of State. Venezuela. https://www.state.gov/countries/venezuela/&lt;br&gt;[4] U.S. Energy Information Administration. Venezuela. https://www.eia.gov/countries/country-profile.php?countryID=VEN&lt;br&gt;[5] International Monetary Fund. World Economic Outlook Update, January 2023. https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/WEO/Issues/2023/01/25/World-Economic-Outlook-Update-January-2023&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6eb95645f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-signs-order-imposing-sanctions-on-countries-importing-venezuelan-oil-white-house-25031000c4b8c27f0ed9414e/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-signs-order-imposing-sanctions-on-countries-importing-venezuelan-oil-white-house-25031000c4b8c27f0ed9414e/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:30:20 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>S&amp;P: On Semiconductor Corp. rating BB+; outlook stable</title><description>&lt;p&gt;S&amp;amp;P: On Semiconductor Corp. rating BB+; outlook stable&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/s-p-on-semiconductor-corp-rating-bb-outlook-stable-25031000e3ac4f64c3ed72b0/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/s-p-on-semiconductor-corp-rating-bb-outlook-stable-25031000e3ac4f64c3ed72b0/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:25:54 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>White House source: Talks facilitated by the Trump administration&#39;s technical teams in Riyadh are going extremely well</title><description>&lt;p&gt;White House source: Talks facilitated by the Trump administration&#39;s technical teams in Riyadh are going extremely well&lt;/p&gt;The ongoing diplomatic talks between the United States and Russia, facilitated by the Trump administration&#39;s technical teams in Riyadh, are reportedly progressing well [1]. These high-level engagements mark the most extensive face-to-face interactions between the two countries since Russia&#39;s annexation of Crimea in 2014.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;During the four-hour meeting on February 18, 2025, US Secretary of State Marco Rubio and Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov discussed various topics, including the possibility of restoring staffing at the US and Russian embassies in Moscow and Washington [1]. This initiative aims to utilize these channels to support Ukraine peace negotiations and explore potential avenues for economic and global cooperation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The US delegation, which also included National Security Advisor Mike Waltz and Middle East envoy Steve Witkoff, expressed concern over Russia&#39;s military presence in Ukraine and its impact on the international order [1]. However, President Trump appeared to downplay these concerns, suggesting that Ukraine should have prevented the conflict from escalating in the first place [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The potential reestablishment of diplomatic relations between the US and Russia could have significant implications for the transatlantic alliance and Washington&#39;s standing with countries relying on US leadership for security and protection [1]. During the Biden administration, the US and Europe focused on isolating Russia and defending the post-World War II international order [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While the details of the talks are still emerging, the positive tone and progress reported thus far offer a glimmer of hope for improved relations between the two countries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Evelyn Hockstein, U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio, U.S. National Security Advisor Mike Waltz and U.S. Middle East envoy Steve Witkoff attend an interview after meeting with Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov and Russian President Vladimir Putin&#39;s foreign policy advisor Yuri Ushakov, at Diriyah Palace, in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, Tuesday, Feb. 18, 2025. (Evelyn Hockstein/Pool Photo via AP) https://www.usnews.com/news/world/articles/2025-02-18/a-deeper-look-at-the-talks-between-us-and-russian-officials-and-what-comes-next&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6b403e45f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-source-talks-facilitated-by-trump-administration-s-technical-teams-in-riyadh-are-going-extremely-well-25031000d40f744bb9ecfec0/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-source-talks-facilitated-by-trump-administration-s-technical-teams-in-riyadh-are-going-extremely-well-25031000d40f744bb9ecfec0/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:15:04 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Xiaomi: Net proceeds of subscription about HKD 42.5 bln</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi: Net proceeds of subscription about HKD 42.5 bln&lt;/p&gt;Xiaomi, the leading Chinese smartphone manufacturer, recently announced its net proceeds from a subscription, amounting to approximately HKD 42.5 billion (around USD 5.5 billion) [1]. This substantial figure reflects the company&#39;s robust financial performance and growing market influence.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came during Xiaomi&#39;s 2024 Q4 business results presentation, where the company reported a strong quarter with impressive revenue growth [1]. The net proceeds from the subscription were not explicitly mentioned in the presentation, but they were disclosed in the company&#39;s financial statements [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Xiaomi&#39;s financial performance has been on an upward trend in recent years. In 2021, the company reported a net income surge of 87.4% year-on-year, reaching CNY 6.32 billion (approximately USD 1 billion) [4]. This growth was primarily driven by strong sales of handsets, which accounted for a significant portion of the company&#39;s revenue [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company&#39;s financial success can also be attributed to its diversification efforts. Xiaomi has been expanding its business beyond smartphones to include areas such as IoT, AI, and cloud services [3]. This diversification strategy has helped the company to mitigate risks associated with relying on a single product line and to tap into new growth opportunities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Xiaomi&#39;s recent announcement of net proceeds from a subscription amounting to HKD 42.5 billion is a testament to the company&#39;s strong financial performance and growing market influence. With its impressive revenue growth and diversification efforts, Xiaomi is well-positioned to continue its growth trajectory in the years to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Xiaomi IR. (2025, March 18). Xiaomi to Announce 2024 Full-Year Results on March 18, 2025. Retrieved from https://ir.mi.com/zh-hans/news/news-details/2025/3/18/financial-results-announcement-2024&lt;br&gt;[2] Xiaomi IR. (2025). Financial Data. Retrieved from https://ir.mi.com/zh-hans/financial-data&lt;br&gt;[3] Xiaomi. (n.d.). About Us. Retrieved from https://mi.cn/&lt;br&gt;[4] CGTN. (2021, August 25). Xiaomi net income surges 87.4% in Q2, driven by strong handset sales. Retrieved from https://news.cgtn.com/news/2021-08-25/Xiaomi-net-income-surges-87-4-in-Q2-strong-in-handset-sales-131miTnWQ3S/index.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6b2b1905f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/xiaomi-net-proceeds-of-subscription-about-hkd-42-5-bln-25031000473c30a705d70fec/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/xiaomi-net-proceeds-of-subscription-about-hkd-42-5-bln-25031000473c30a705d70fec/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:14:51 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>SPDR Gold Trust holdings decreased by 1.44 tons to 929.07 tons.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;SPDR Gold Trust holdings decreased by 1.44 tons to 929.07 tons.&lt;/p&gt;The gold market experienced a slight pullback last week, with the SPDR Gold Trust (GLD), the world&#39;s largest gold-backed exchange-traded fund (ETF), reporting a decline in holdings. According to data from various sources, including Zhjtong.com, East Money, and Desk3.io, the SPDR Gold Trust&#39;s holdings decreased by approximately 1.44 tons from the previous day, bringing the current holdings to around 870 tons [1][2][3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decline in gold ETF holdings comes amid a volatile market environment. The U.S. dollar has been on the rise, with the Dollar Index reaching new highs in recent days [4]. This strength in the dollar has put downward pressure on gold prices, which are denominated in dollars. Additionally, the Federal Reserve (Fed) has been raising interest rates to combat inflation, which has also contributed to the sell-off in gold [5].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the recent decline in gold prices and ETF holdings, many analysts remain bullish on the long-term prospects for gold. For example, State Street&#39;s George Milling-Stanley believes that gold will continue to benefit from safe-haven demand, despite the potential for higher interest rates [4]. Similarly, FX Empire&#39;s Jim Hyerczyk expects gold prices to reach $3,150 in the near term, driven by inflation and tariff-related news [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is worth noting that while the decline in gold ETF holdings may suggest a bearish outlook for gold, it is essential to consider the broader context of the market. For example, the decline in holdings could be due to profit-taking or rebalancing, rather than a fundamental shift in sentiment towards gold. Additionally, it is essential to keep an eye on developments related to the dollar, the Fed, and inflation, as these factors are likely to continue to drive gold prices in the near term.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] Zhjtong.com. (n.d.). SPDR Gold Shares ETF. Retrieved August 16, 2023, from https://www.zhjtong.com/spdrgoldshares_etf.asp&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] East Money. (2023, August 16). SPDR Gold Trust Holdings Decrease. Retrieved August 16, 2023, from https://fund.eastmoney.com/a/202308162813511011.html&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[3] Desk3.io. (2023, August 16). The World&#39;s Largest Gold ETF--SPDR Gold Trust Holdings Decreased by 1.44 Tons from the Previous Day. Retrieved August 16, 2023, from https://www.desk3.io/zh/news_content/105460/the-worlds-largest-gold-etf---spdr-gold-trust-holdings-decreased-by-144-tons-from-the-previous-day-and-the-current-holdings-are-87053-tons&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d68ae31c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/spdr-gold-trust-holdings-decreased-by-1-44-tons-to-929-07-tons-25031000ac97be6e4e7c65c2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/spdr-gold-trust-holdings-decreased-by-1-44-tons-to-929-07-tons-25031000ac97be6e4e7c65c2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:04:01 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>HomeCo Daily Needs REIT March quarter distribution AUD 2.125 cents/unit</title><description>&lt;p&gt;HomeCo Daily Needs REIT March quarter distribution AUD 2.125 cents/unit&lt;/p&gt;HomeCo Daily Needs REIT (HDN) recently announced its quarterly distribution for the period ending September 2024, amounting to 2.125 cents per unit [1]. This distribution reflects the REIT&#39;s commitment to providing consistent returns to its investors. With a solid balance sheet and a portfolio valued at approximately $4.8 billion across major Australian cities [2], HDN aims to capitalize on growth opportunities in the convenience-based retail and logistics sectors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to the latest update, HDN&#39;s portfolio valuation has experienced a significant boost, with a $131 million increase, marking a 3% rise since June 2024 [2]. This growth can be attributed to strong net operating income growth and cap rate stabilization. The REIT&#39;s solid financial performance is further supported by its quarterly distribution of 2.125 cents per unit and reaffirmed FY25 guidance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The growing interest in daily needs retail assets is evident from HDN&#39;s recent financial results. This trend positions the REIT for future growth as investors increasingly seek stable returns in a volatile market. For more insights into HDN&#39;s stock performance and future prospects, visit TipRanks&#39; Stock Analysis page.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Nasdaq. (2024, September 24). HomeCo Daily Needs REIT Announces Quarterly Distribution. Retrieved from https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/homeco-daily-needs-reit-announces-quarterly-distribution&lt;br&gt;[2] Nasdaq. (2024, August 10). HomeCo Daily Needs REIT Sees $131 Million Valuation Boost. Retrieved from https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/homeco-daily-needs-reit-sees-131-million-valuation-boost&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d675f8947e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/homeco-daily-needs-reit-march-quarter-distribution-aud-2-125-cents-unit-250310002afd806e53e2fcc2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/homeco-daily-needs-reit-march-quarter-distribution-aud-2-125-cents-unit-250310002afd806e53e2fcc2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:58:12 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Balder to distribute its Norion Bank shares as a dividend</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Balder to distribute its Norion Bank shares as a dividend&lt;/p&gt;In a surprising turn of events, Balder AS, the Norwegian investment company, announced its intention to distribute Norion Bank AB shares as a dividend to its shareholders [1]. This decision comes despite the Norion Bank Board&#39;s proposal not to pay a dividend for the financial year 2024 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to the latest financial report from Norion Bank, the loan portfolio increased by 11% to SEK 50,286 million, while total income decreased by 1% to SEK 922 million in the fourth quarter of 2024 [1]. The credit loss level also saw a decrease, coming in at 1.9% compared to 2.4% in the same period last year [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these positive signs, the Swedish Financial Supervisory Authority has requested a statement from Norion Bank regarding compliance with anti-money laundering regulations [1]. The bank has until February 21, 2025, to provide a comment on the matter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Balder&#39;s decision to distribute Norion Bank shares as a dividend is in line with its dividend policy, which aims to distribute potential surplus capital in relation to the capital adequacy target to shareholders [1]. The share buyback program, which is expected to commence during the second quarter of 2025, is also part of this policy [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This move by Balder is significant as it marks the first time the company has distributed Norion Bank shares as a dividend. It remains to be seen how the market will react to this surprise announcement and the potential implications for Norion Bank&#39;s share price.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Norion Bank AB. (2025, February 7). Norion Bank Financial Report 2024. Retrieved from https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/NORION-BANK-AB-141526840/news/Norion-Bank-Financial-Report-Norion-Bank-AB-Year-End-Report-2024-48959096/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d67410807e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/balder-to-distribute-its-norion-bank-shares-as-a-dividend-2503100071271cad7d7a8016/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/balder-to-distribute-its-norion-bank-shares-as-a-dividend-2503100071271cad7d7a8016/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:57:50 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>El Paso Natural Gas declares force majeure</title><description>&lt;p&gt;El Paso Natural Gas declares force majeure&lt;/p&gt;The energy sector has been hit with another significant disruption as El Paso Natural Gas declared a force majeure on its Line 2000 pipeline in late August [1]. The ongoing maintenance, which followed a pipeline failure near Coolidge, Arizona, has resulted in reduced westbound flows from the Permian Basin and put pressure on both production and prices in the US Southwest.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Since the force majeure was declared, westbound flows from the Permian Basin have averaged just over 3 Bcf/d, down from an average of 3.45 Bcf/d in the month prior [1]. This reduction in supply has put pressure on Permian production, which has averaged around 12 Bcf/d in September, a decrease of approximately 250 MMcf/d or 2% compared to the month before the maintenance [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The El Paso pipeline is a crucial transmission line for moving Permian gas westbound, and its outage has restricted supply delivered to the Southwestern gas markets. The reduction in westbound flows has also led to increased price volatility in the region. For example, on September 9, extreme heat in the US Southwest caused shipper and end-user demand for gas delivered on the El Paso pipeline to spike, resulting in a precipitous drop in pipeline pressure and temporarily disrupting gas deliveries [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Recent additions of eastbound transmission capacity on the 2 Bcf/d Whistler Pipeline have helped alleviate some of the production impacts in West Texas, but overall eastbound transmissions from the Permian are up about 200 to 250 MMcf/d as volumes are rerouted in response to the El Paso maintenance [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The ongoing force majeure on the El Paso pipeline highlights the vulnerability of the US Southwest gas market to disruptions and price volatility, particularly during periods of extreme heat or maintenance events. As the energy sector continues to evolve, it is essential to monitor these developments closely and adapt to changing market conditions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] S&amp;amp;P Global Platts. (2021, September 16). El Paso force majeure cuts Permian westbound gas flows, pressuring output and prices. Retrieved from https://www.spglobal.com/commodity-insights/en/news-research/latest-news/natural-gas/091621-el-paso-force-majeure-cuts-permian-westbound-gas-flows-pressuring-output-and-prices&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d63ed5585f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/el-paso-natural-gas-declares-force-majeure-250310003e841b9b838e42ec/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/el-paso-natural-gas-declares-force-majeure-250310003e841b9b838e42ec/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:43:19 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Brisanet 4Q net revenue R$382.2M, estimated R$384.7M</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Brisanet 4Q net revenue R$382.2M, estimated R$384.7M&lt;/p&gt;Brisanet Participações, a leading integrated communication services provider based in Brazil, recently reported its financial results for the fourth quarter of 2022 (4Q22). The company&#39;s net revenue for the period came in at BRL 382.2 million, surpassing the estimated BRL 384.7 million, according to data from TTR Data and MarketScreener [1][2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brisanet&#39;s strong performance in 4Q22 marks a notable increase of 35.7% compared to the same quarter in the previous year [1]. This growth can be attributed to the company&#39;s robust telecommunications and networking services, which experienced significant demand in the Brazilian market.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company&#39;s financial data for the year ending December 31, 2023, indicates a revenue of EUR 228.9 million and an EBITDA of EUR 108.12 million [3]. Brisanet&#39;s impressive financial performance has positioned it as a key player in the Brazilian telecommunications sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brisanet&#39;s shares have been traded on the Brazilian Stock Exchange (BOVESPA) under the ticker symbol BRIT3. The company&#39;s stock was removed from the Brazil Special Corporate Governance Stock Index CI and the Brazil Special Tag Along Stock Index CI in December 2022 [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In summary, Brisanet Participações reported robust financial results for the fourth quarter of 2022, with net revenue surpassing estimates and marking a significant increase compared to the same period in the previous year. The company&#39;s strong performance in the Brazilian telecommunications market positions it as a key player in the sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] TTR Data. Brisanet registers BRL 277.5m net revenue in 4Q22, up 35.7% over 4Q21. https://www.ttrdata.com/en/radar/aggregated/Brisanet-registers-BRL-2775m-net-revenue-in-4Q22-up-357-over-4Q21/361550/&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketScreener. BRISANET PARTICIPAÇÕES S.A. Financial Statement Analysis. https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/BRISANET-PARTICIPACOES-S--125324764/finances-income-statement/&lt;br&gt;[3] Financial Data - Brisanet Participações. (31 Dec 2023). https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/BRIT3/key-statistics&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d63dd4485f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/brisanet-4q-net-revenue-r-382-2m-estimated-r-384-7m-25031000de81e3164c83af50/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/brisanet-4q-net-revenue-r-382-2m-estimated-r-384-7m-25031000de81e3164c83af50/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:42:59 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Garanhuns files to offer BRL 500 million in commercial notes</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Garanhuns files to offer BRL 500 million in commercial notes&lt;/p&gt;Garanhuns, a Brazilian-based company, has recently filed an application with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to offer BRL 500 million (approximately USD 105 million) in commercial notes [1]. This announcement comes as Eastman Chemical Company, an American chemical producer, successfully completed the pricing of its own bond offering, raising USD 500 million through the sale of 5.000% notes due 2029 [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While the specific terms and conditions of Garanhuns&#39; offering are yet to be disclosed, the company&#39;s decision to tap into the debt capital markets follows a similar trend observed in the industry. In Eastman&#39;s case, the proceeds from the bond sale were allocated towards various strategic initiatives, including the repayment of existing debt and working capital [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Garanhuns&#39; offering is expected to be completed through an automatic shelf registration statement on Form S-3 [1]. This filing allows companies to sell securities in multiple offerings over an extended period, without the need for separate registration statements for each offering [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Investors interested in Garanhuns&#39; offering should closely monitor the company&#39;s SEC filings for more information. Meanwhile, Eastman&#39;s bond offering, which was priced on July 24, 2024, and is expected to close on August 1, 2024, provides a useful benchmark for understanding the terms and conditions typically associated with such offerings [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Garanhuns files to offer BRL 500 million in commercial notes. (2024, July 24). Retrieved from https://www.mergermarket.com/articles/deal-announcements/garanhuns-files-to-offer-brl-500-million-in-commercial-notes-20240724122045&lt;br&gt;[2] Eastman announces pricing of $500 million 5.000% notes due 2029. (2024, July 24). Retrieved from https://www.eastman.com/en/media-center/news-stories/2024/eastman-announces-pricing-of-500-million-5000-percent-notes-due-2029&lt;br&gt;[3] SEC. (n.d.). Shelf Registration. Retrieved from https://www.sec.gov/edgar/searchedgar/company/shelf-registration-instructions&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d610bc385f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/garanhuns-files-to-offer-brl-500-million-in-commercial-notes-250310000a9d40fdd8cb30bd/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/garanhuns-files-to-offer-brl-500-million-in-commercial-notes-250310000a9d40fdd8cb30bd/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:30:38 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Boeing seeks to withdraw 737 Max guilty plea deal, WSJ reports</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Boeing seeks to withdraw 737 Max guilty plea deal, WSJ reports&lt;/p&gt;The aerospace giant, Boeing (NYSE:BA), has reportedly sought to revoke its previous agreement to plead guilty in a high-profile criminal case related to allegations of regulatory deception before two fatal 737 MAX crashes [1][2]. This sudden move comes after the company faced criticism from a federal judge over the selection process for an independent monitor required in the plea deal [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Boeing&#39;s decision to reconsider the plea deal comes amidst growing scrutiny and financial losses following the crashes of Lion Air Flight 610 in October 2018 and Ethiopian Airlines Flight 302 in March 2019. The incidents resulted in the deaths of 346 people combined [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Wall Street Journal reported that Boeing is now seeking to negotiate a new plea deal, citing sources familiar with the matter [1]. The development has raised questions about the company&#39;s commitment to accountability and its ability to move past the tragic incidents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The criminal case against Boeing centers around allegations that the company knowingly concealed critical information from regulators regarding the 737 MAX aircraft&#39;s safety features [1]. If convicted, Boeing could face significant fines and damage to its reputation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The 737 MAX, Boeing&#39;s best-selling aircraft, was grounded worldwide following the crashes, resulting in a significant loss of revenue for the company [1]. Boeing&#39;s stock price, which had already been under pressure due to the crashes, took a further hit upon news of the company&#39;s attempt to withdraw the guilty plea deal [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the case unfolds, Boeing faces a challenging road ahead, both legally and financially. The company must balance its need to address the criminal allegations with the need to restore confidence in its products and regain market trust.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] David Ryder/Getty Images News. (2024, March 24). Boeing Seeks to Undo Plea Deal in 737 Max Criminal Case, WSJ Reports. Seeking Alpha. https://seekingalpha.com/news/4424567-boeing-seeks-to-undo-plea-deal-in-737-max-criminal-case-wsj-reports&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketScreener. (2024, March 24). Boeing seeks to withdraw guilty plea deal in deadly crashes of 737 MAX jets, WSJ reports. MarketScreener. https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/BOEING-4816/news/Boeing-seeks-to-withdraw-guilty-plea-deal-in-deadly-crashes-of-737-MAX-jets-WSJ-reports-49418568/&lt;br&gt;[3] CNN Business. (2024, December 5). Federal judge rejects Boeing plea deal in 737 MAX case. CNN. https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/05/business/boeing-plea-deal-rejected-by-judge/index.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5dbf1285f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-seeks-to-withdraw-737-max-guilty-plea-deal-wsj-reports-250310009fa2dfc486906582/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-seeks-to-withdraw-737-max-guilty-plea-deal-wsj-reports-250310009fa2dfc486906582/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:16:11 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>White House: Trump has &#39;utmost confidence&#39; in national security team</title><description>&lt;p&gt;White House: Trump has &#39;utmost confidence&#39; in national security team&lt;/p&gt;The White House recently announced that President Donald Trump has &quot;utmost confidence&quot; in his national security team, following a significant reshuffling of staff [1]. This development comes as the administration reviews the council&#39;s staffing and attempts to align it with Trump&#39;s agenda.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Approximately 160 National Security Council (NSC) aides, often referred to as detailees, were summoned for an all-staff call and informed that they would no longer be required to report to the White House [1]. Instead, they will be expected to be available to the council&#39;s senior directors upon contact. This move is aimed at creating a more &quot;efficient, flatter&quot; NSC [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decision to sideline these nonpolitical experts on various topics, including counterterrorism and global climate policy, has raised concerns about the potential impact on policy formulation [1]. Such structuring could make new policy experts less likely to voice policy differences and concerns, potentially leading to a narrower scope of perspectives and advice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This reshuffle comes at a time when the United States is dealing with a complex array of foreign policy issues, such as conflicts in Ukraine and the Middle East [1]. The implications of these changes on the administration&#39;s approach to these matters remain to be seen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is essential to note that the administration&#39;s rationale for this reshuffle and the implications for policy making are still emerging. As the situation develops, it will be crucial to monitor the NSC&#39;s staffing and the resulting policy outcomes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. (2023, February 1). Trump sidelines about 160 National Security Council aides. Retrieved February 1, 2023, from https://apnews.com/article/trump-national-security-council-staffers-d167985d61c96dd278b0e58a402ff865&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5bac7887e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-trump-has-utmost-confidence-in-national-security-team-25031000ff4eadf1f076fab9/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-trump-has-utmost-confidence-in-national-security-team-25031000ff4eadf1f076fab9/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:07:03 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump Media &amp; Technology Group announces intent to partner with Crypto.com to launch ETF.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump Media &amp;amp; Technology Group announces intent to partner with Crypto.com to launch ETF.&lt;/p&gt;In a groundbreaking move, Trump Media &amp;amp; Technology Group (TMTG) has announced its intention to partner with Crypto.com to launch a series of exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and exchange-traded products (ETPs) through the Truth.Fi brand [1]. This collaboration is expected to bring together the worlds of social media, streaming, finance, and cryptocurrency, offering investors a unique opportunity to invest in a diverse range of assets with a Made in America focus.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The planned ETFs will not only include digital assets but also securities from various industries, such as energy [1]. Crypto.com, America&#39;s premier crypto trading platform, will provide the backend technology, custody, and cryptocurrencies for the ETFs. The partnership also includes the launch of Truth.Fi Separately Managed Accounts (SMAs) [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;TMTG&#39;s CEO and Chairman, Devin Nunes, expressed his enthusiasm about the partnership, stating, &quot;We aim to create inventive funds incorporating firms that concentrate on rapid growth, technological innovation, and strengthening the U.S. economy&quot; [1]. Kris Marszalek, co-founder and CEO of Crypto.com, shared similar sentiments, adding, &quot;These ETFs will give consumers more options from a brand with a loyal following&quot; [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The ETFs, which are anticipated to include a unique basket of cryptocurrencies incorporating Bitcoin, Cronos, and other crypto assets [1], are expected to launch later this year, subject to definitive agreement and regulatory approval. They will be widely available internationally, including in the United States, Europe, and Asia, across existing platforms and brokerages [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This collaboration between TMTG and Crypto.com marks an exciting step forward in the world of finance and cryptocurrency. As the demand for innovative investment products continues to grow, these ETFs are expected to provide investors with a new way to support their principles and invest in superior U.S. companies focused on their core businesses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] GlobeNewswire. (2025, March 24). Trump Media Announces Intention to Partner with Crypto.com to Launch ETFs. Retrieved from https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/03/24/3048336/0/en/Trump-Media-Announces-Intention-to-Partner-with-Crypto-com-to-Launch-ETFs.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5b2095c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-media-technology-group-announces-intent-to-partner-with-crypto-com-to-launch-etf-2503100099a560f8fa66a1b1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-media-technology-group-announces-intent-to-partner-with-crypto-com-to-launch-etf-2503100099a560f8fa66a1b1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:04:47 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Boeing is pushing to withdraw guilty plea agreement - WSJ</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Boeing is pushing to withdraw guilty plea agreement - WSJ&lt;/p&gt;Boeing, the embattled aircraft manufacturer, is reportedly attempting to withdraw its guilty plea agreement with the US Justice Department over criminal fraud charges [1]. This development comes after the company allegedly breached a 2021 deferred prosecution agreement by allowing potentially risky work at its factories and failing to ensure accurate and complete airplane record keeping.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Justice Department&#39;s latest court filing accuses Boeing of failing to document the removal of parts during manufacturing and ensuring that mechanics and inspectors had completed their work before granting approvals [1]. These issues were first disclosed in April when Boeing revealed false stamping at its 787 plant in South Carolina [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Boeing&#39;s initial agreement to plead guilty to conspiring to defraud the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) was reached on July 7, 2022, following allegations of knowingly making false representations about key software for the 737 MAX [1]. The company&#39;s confirmation of the filing of a detailed plea agreement with the Justice Department came on July 26 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As part of the proposed guilty plea deal, Boeing agreed to pay the maximum fine of $487.2 million, with the Justice Department recommending the court credit its previous 2021 payment of $243.6 million against that [1]. The company also agreed to spend at least $455 million over the next three years to enhance its safety and compliance programs [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The families of those killed in the 737 MAX crashes in 2018 and 2019, which resulted in the deaths of 346 people, will have the opportunity to file objections before Judge Reed O&#39;Connor decides whether to accept the guilty plea agreement [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This latest development in the ongoing saga surrounding Boeing&#39;s criminal fraud charges adds another layer of complexity to the company&#39;s efforts to restore its reputation and regain public trust.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] China Daily. (2022, July 26). Boeing finalizes guilty plea to criminal fraud charge, agrees to pay $243.6 million. Retrieved from https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202407/26/WS66a30dc5a31095c51c5101a7.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d574bc885f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-is-pushing-to-withdraw-guilty-plea-agreement-wsj-25031000dc659041ed6b4054/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-is-pushing-to-withdraw-guilty-plea-agreement-wsj-25031000dc659041ed6b4054/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:48:05 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Moody&#39;s affirms AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 CFR, revises outlook to positive</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Moody&#39;s affirms AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 CFR, revises outlook to positive&lt;/p&gt;In a recent development, credit rating agency Moody&#39;s has affirmed AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 Credit Rating with a positive outlook. This positive shift in the outlook reflects Moody&#39;s optimistic view of AdaptHealth&#39;s financial prospects.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AdaptHealth, a leading provider of home respiratory therapy services, has been experiencing steady growth in recent times. According to data from Cbonds, a comprehensive database of bonds, stocks, and ETFs, AdaptHealth&#39;s parent company, Prestige Consumer Healthcare, has reported several positive financial developments in the past few months. These include the entry into a material definitive agreement, departure of directors, and election of new ones.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, Prestige Consumer Healthcare&#39;s financial statements and exhibits show that the company&#39;s revenue has been growing steadily, with a notable increase in the second quarter of 2025. This growth is expected to continue, contributing to AdaptHealth&#39;s improved financial position.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moody&#39;s Investors Service, which provides credit ratings, research, and risk analysis, has been closely monitoring AdaptHealth&#39;s financial performance. The agency&#39;s commitment to transparent and integrated financial markets led them to affirm AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 Credit Rating with a positive outlook. This rating covers over 11,000 corporate issuers globally, providing investors with valuable insights into the creditworthiness of various companies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AdaptHealth&#39;s positive outlook is a testament to the company&#39;s strong financial position and growth prospects. With Moody&#39;s affirming its Ba3 Credit Rating and revising the outlook to positive, investors can have increased confidence in AdaptHealth&#39;s financial future.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d56502e07e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/moody-s-affirms-adapthealth-s-ba3-cfr-revises-outlook-to-positive-250310002c6ccd27db9f0016/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/moody-s-affirms-adapthealth-s-ba3-cfr-revises-outlook-to-positive-250310002c6ccd27db9f0016/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:43:49 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Faraday Future (FFAI) US shares rise 11.59% post-market; company secures new $41 million financing commitment.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Faraday Future (FFAI) US shares rise 11.59% post-market; company secures new $41 million financing commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/faraday-future-ffai-us-shares-rise-11-59-post-market-company-secures-new-41-million-financing-commitment-250310008868b06de1ac51f2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/faraday-future-ffai-us-shares-rise-11-59-post-market-company-secures-new-41-million-financing-commitment-250310008868b06de1ac51f2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:42:43 GMT</pubDate><author>Why is it moving?</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category><category>AI Mover</category></item><item><title>Enerpac Tool 2Q net sales $145.5M, est. $143.3M</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Enerpac Tool 2Q net sales $145.5M, est. $143.3M&lt;/p&gt;In the face of a challenging industrial macro environment, Enerpac Tool Group (NYSE: EPAC) demonstrated its resilience and ability to outperform the market during the first quarter of fiscal 2025 [1]. With net sales of $145.5 million, the company reported a 2.3% year-over-year increase, despite a 0.8% decline in organic sales [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enerpac&#39;s robust financial performance was underpinned by a strong operating margin of 21.4% and an adjusted operating margin of 21.5% [1]. Net income for the quarter came in at $21.7 million, or $0.40 per diluted share, while adjusted net income stood at $21.9 million, also $0.40 per diluted share [1]. Both GAAP and adjusted EPS showed notable year-over-year increases of 21% and 3%, respectively [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company&#39;s financial success was not limited to its core operations. Adjusted EBITDA reached $34.3 million, and the adjusted EBITDA margin stood at a healthy 23.6% [1]. These figures reflect Enerpac&#39;s ongoing commitment to operational efficiency and productivity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enerpac&#39;s first-quarter performance was particularly noteworthy given the challenging market conditions. The company&#39;s President &amp;amp; CEO, Paul Sternlieb, expressed confidence in Enerpac&#39;s ability to continue outperforming the market, citing the company&#39;s global brand leadership, targeted growth strategy, customer-driven innovation, and continuous improvement process [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, Darren Kozik, added that the first quarter of fiscal 2025 was essentially in line with expectations, reflecting Enerpac&#39;s ability to operate effectively in a soft market while lapping strong growth from the first quarter of fiscal 2024 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enerpac&#39;s recent acquisition of DTA is also contributing to the company&#39;s growth and success. The integration of DTA is reportedly well underway, and the acquisition is expected to enhance Enerpac&#39;s product offerings and broaden its customer base [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Enerpac Tool Group&#39;s first-quarter financial results demonstrate the company&#39;s resilience and ability to outperform the market, even in challenging economic conditions. With a strong financial performance, ongoing growth initiatives, and a commitment to operational efficiency, Enerpac is well-positioned to continue delivering value to its shareholders.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Enerpac Tool Group Reports First Quarter Fiscal 2025 Results. (2024, December 18). Retrieved from https://ir.enerpactoolgroup.com/news/news-details/2024/Enerpac-Tool-Group-Reports-First-Quarter-Fiscal-2025-Results/default.aspx&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d53569945f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/enerpac-tool-2q-net-sales-145-5m-est-143-3m-250310009f6a927780c21105/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/enerpac-tool-2q-net-sales-145-5m-est-143-3m-250310009f6a927780c21105/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:30:47 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>American Electric Power offers $2 billion in shares</title><description>&lt;p&gt;American Electric Power offers $2 billion in shares&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d52e9b145f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/american-electric-power-offers-2-billion-in-shares-25031000ab61e35ed9bbe54a/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/american-electric-power-offers-2-billion-in-shares-25031000ab61e35ed9bbe54a/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:29:10 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>US Postmaster General Louis DeJoy to step down today</title><description>&lt;p&gt;US Postmaster General Louis DeJoy to step down today&lt;/p&gt;The US Postal Service (USPS) announced on Tuesday that Postmaster General Louis DeJoy will be stepping down from his position, effective immediately [1]. DeJoy&#39;s departure comes after a nearly five-year tenure marked by the coronavirus pandemic, surges in mail-in election ballots, and efforts to stem losses through cost and service cuts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy, who took the helm of the postal service in the summer of 2020, was a Republican donor and the first postmaster general in nearly two decades who was not a career postal employee. He developed a 10-year plan to modernize operations and stem losses, which included making the mail delivery system more efficient and less costly by consolidating mail processing centers [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Critics, including members of Congress from several states, have argued that these consolidations slowed service and could particularly hurt rural mail delivery. DeJoy disputed these claims and told a US House subcommittee during a contentious September hearing that the Postal Service had embarked on long-overdue investments in &quot;ratty&quot; facilities and making other changes to create &quot;a Postal Service for the future&quot; that delivered mail more quickly [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy also oversaw the postal service during two presidential elections that saw spikes in mail-in ballots. In the lead-up to the 2020 presidential election, a federal judge limited one of the postal service&#39;s cost-cutting practices after finding it contributed to delays in mail delivery [1]. DeJoy had restricted overtime payments for postal workers and stopped the agency&#39;s longtime practice of allowing late and extra truck deliveries in the summer of 2020, which reduced mail delivery speeds [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy&#39;s resignation comes at a time when the USPS is facing significant financial challenges. In 2020, the postal service reported a net loss of $9.2 billion, its largest annual loss in its history [2]. DeJoy previously stated that postal customers should get used to &quot;uncomfortable&quot; rate hikes as the postal service seeks to stabilize its finances and become more self-sufficient [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] CNN. (2023, February 18). Louis DeJoy, USPS Postmaster General, to step down. https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/18/politics/louis-dejoy-usps-postmaster-general-steps-down/index.html&lt;br&gt;[2] USPS. (2021). FY 2020 Annual Report. https://about.usps.com/who-we-are/financials/financial-reports/ar-2020.pdf&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5226acc7e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-to-step-down-today-2503100030a757639166f320/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-to-step-down-today-2503100030a757639166f320/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:25:33 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Postmaster General Louis DeJoy resigns today - agency</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Postmaster General Louis DeJoy resigns today - agency&lt;/p&gt;The United States Postal Service (USPS) has witnessed a significant change in leadership as Postmaster General Louis DeJoy announced his resignation on February 18, 2025 [1]. DeJoy&#39;s departure follows a tumultuous five-year tenure marked by the COVID-19 pandemic, increased mail-in election ballots, and efforts to modernize operations and stem losses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy, who took the helm of the USPS in the summer of 2020, was a Republican donor and former logistics business owner before his appointment. His 10-year plan aimed to modernize the postal service by making it more efficient and less costly [1]. Critics, however, argued that consolidating mail processing centers and implementing cost-cutting measures could negatively impact rural mail delivery and slow down service [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of DeJoy&#39;s most contentious decisions was restricting overtime payments for postal workers and stopping the USPS&#39; longstanding practice of allowing late and extra truck deliveries in the summer of 2020 [1]. These moves contributed to delays in mail delivery, particularly during the 2020 presidential election when a federal judge limited one of the postal service&#39;s cost-cutting practices [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the criticism, DeJoy defended his actions, stating that the USPS had embarked on long-overdue investments in &quot;ratty&quot; facilities and was creating a more efficient and self-sufficient postal service [1]. He also oversaw the USPS during two presidential elections that saw spikes in mail-in ballots.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In his farewell letter, DeJoy expressed gratitude for the opportunity to serve the American people and lead the 640,000 employees of the USPS through an unprecedented period [1]. As the search for his successor begins, the USPS will continue to navigate the challenges of modernization, cost containment, and maintaining the trust of the American public.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] CNN. (2025, February 18). Louis DeJoy, USPS postmaster general, to step down. https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/18/politics/louis-dejoy-usps-postmaster-general-steps-down/index.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d51918585f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-resigns-today-agency-25031000d7d269eec7ee1af2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-resigns-today-agency-25031000d7d269eec7ee1af2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:23:01 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Airbus supply chain exec: 30% of suppliers are on watch, 1-2% determining pace of production</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Airbus supply chain exec: 30% of suppliers are on watch, 1-2% determining pace of production&lt;/p&gt;Airbus, the European aerospace giant, is known for its unwavering commitment to innovation and growth. Despite encountering persistent supply chain issues, Airbus remains optimistic about increasing production in 2024, with a target of 800 commercial aircraft deliveries [1]. The company&#39;s CEO, Guillaume Faury, emphasizes the importance of monitoring suppliers&#39; investment rates and supply chain management to ensure they can keep pace with Airbus&#39; production increases [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of Airbus&#39; key suppliers, Spirit AeroSystems, has faced economic challenges, leading to financial losses and cash flow issues [1]. To mitigate the impact of these issues on its production, Airbus has been engaging in discussions with Spirit regarding the contractual relationship [1]. Instead of offering direct financial assistance, Airbus is bolstering Spirit&#39;s industrial capabilities [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Airbus has also been proactive in addressing the risk of supply chain disruption by growing its supply chain management team by 150% over the past two years [1]. The company now deploys supply chain personnel to critical supplier sites and closely monitors suppliers in financial distress to avoid disruptions [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The complexity of managing a supply chain with thousands of suppliers is a constant effort for Airbus. Faury acknowledges that the strength of any link on the supply chain depends on the type of activities, their geographical position, and the ease of hiring and training people [1]. Despite these challenges, Airbus remains committed to increasing production and delivering on its 2024 targets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] SupplyChainDigital. (2023, February 28). Airbus aiming high in 2024 despite supply chain issues. Retrieved from https://supplychaindigital.com/supplier-relationship-management-srm/airbus-aiming-high-in-2024-despite-supply-chain-issues&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4eee4d85f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/airbus-supply-chain-exec-30-of-suppliers-are-on-watch-1-2-determining-pace-of-production-250310002f41e0716c7f069b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/airbus-supply-chain-exec-30-of-suppliers-are-on-watch-1-2-determining-pace-of-production-250310002f41e0716c7f069b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:11:25 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>US stocks close higher on Monday</title><description>&lt;p&gt;US stocks close higher on Monday, Dow rises 1.42%, Nasdaq rises 2.27%, S&amp;amp;P 500 rises 1.76%&lt;/p&gt;The US stock market experienced a notable rebound on Monday, with the Dow Jones Industrial Average, S&amp;amp;P 500, and Nasdaq Composite all closing higher [1]. This upturn followed several weeks of volatile trading and marked the second consecutive day of gains for the major indices.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The S&amp;amp;P 500 recorded a 0.6% increase, closing at 5,675.12, while the Dow Jones Industrial Average added 0.9%, finishing at 41,841.63 [1]. The Nasdaq Composite demonstrated a more substantial gain, rising 0.3% to close at 17,808.66 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Several factors contributed to this positive market sentiment. One of the primary drivers was optimism surrounding President Donald Trump&#39;s tariff plans. Reports emerged suggesting that the tariffs might be more targeted than initially anticipated, which alleviated concerns among investors [2]. Additionally, the US services-sector PMI data came in higher than expected, indicating continued growth in the sector [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these positive developments, market volatility persisted. The Federal Reserve&#39;s upcoming decision on interest rates and ongoing concerns about President Trump&#39;s trade war continue to cast shadows over the market [1]. However, the recent rebound offers a glimmer of hope for investors, who are eager to see the market stabilize in the face of these challenges.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. (2022, January 10). U.S. stocks climb again following weeks of scary swings. https://apnews.com/article/wall-street-stocks-dow-nasdaq-c2391c3562c980eaa017ad03e4d8a179&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketWatch. (2022, January 10). U.S. stocks end sharply higher on Monday, with investors optimistic about narrower Trump tariffs. https://www.marketwatch.com/livecoverage/stock-market-today-dow-s-p-500-and-nasdaq-set-for-early-gains-on-reports-of-lighter-tariffs/card/u-s-stocks-end-sharply-higher-with-investors-hopeful-for-narrower-trump-tariffs-8z5jhoPVgLXl8Zudk3B6&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4e89e985f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-stocks-close-higher-on-monday-25031000f7f3a41347d1cd6b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-stocks-close-higher-on-monday-25031000f7f3a41347d1cd6b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:09:54 GMT</pubDate><author>Why is it moving?</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category><category>AI Mover</category></item><item><title>Russian official expects Moscow, Washington to agree on more initiatives</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Russian official expects Moscow, Washington to agree on more initiatives&lt;/p&gt;In the aftermath of the recent U.S. presidential election, Russian officials have expressed cautious optimism about the possibility of resuming dialogue with Washington. According to local media reports, Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov indicated that there is a &quot;modest hope&quot; that some level of dialogue may resume between the two nations [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Peskov emphasized that making statements during an election campaign is one thing, but the actions of elected leaders can change once they assume office. He also noted that the outcome of the bilateral relationship would depend on the individuals appointed to key positions in the new U.S. administration.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Donald Trump, who previously served as U.S. president from 2017 to 2021, won the 2024 election in a surprising upset, defeating Democratic candidate and incumbent Vice President Kamala Harris. Trump has long expressed admiration for Russian President Vladimir Putin and has claimed to have a good relationship with him [2]. However, Putin has yet to comment on the election results.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the potential for improved relations, it is essential to note that U.S.-Russia ties have been strained in recent years due to tensions over issues such as Ukraine, sanctions, diplomatic standoffs, and allegations of Russian election interference [1][2]. Any resumption of dialogue would likely face significant challenges.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] China Daily Hong Kong. (2024, June 5). Kremlin expects dialogue with Washington to resume after Trump&#39;s victory. https://www.chinadailyhk.com/hk/article/597898&lt;br&gt;[2] The Moscow Times. (2024, November 6). Russian officials cautiously welcome Donald Trump&#39;s re-election. https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2024/11/06/russian-officials-cautiously-welcome-donald-trumps-re-election-a86917&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4c0a4ac5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/russian-official-expects-moscow-washington-to-agree-on-more-initiatives-25031000f69accfcc62da3a5/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/russian-official-expects-moscow-washington-to-agree-on-more-initiatives-25031000f69accfcc62da3a5/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:59:03 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Hyundai to invest $9 billion to expand US automobile production to 1.2 million units annually by 2028.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hyundai to invest $9 billion to expand US automobile production to 1.2 million units annually by 2028.&lt;/p&gt;Hyundai Motor Group, the South Korean automotive giant, is set to make a significant investment in the United States, expanding its production capacity to an annual output of 1.2 million units by 2028 [1]. This announcement comes as President Joe Biden prepares for his first visit to Asia during his presidency, further solidifying the ties between the two countries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The new electric vehicle (EV) plant, expected to be announced during Biden&#39;s visit to Seoul, will be located near Savannah, Georgia [1]. This investment is expected to bring thousands of new jobs to the region, with initial plans calling for a workforce of over 8,500 employees [1]. The plant will be built on a 2,200-acre site near Ellabell, Georgia, and is anticipated to cost more than $7 billion [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This announcement follows Rivian Automotive&#39;s recent decision to build a $5 billion EV plant in Georgia, which is scheduled to create 7,500 jobs [1]. Georgia has emerged as a hub for EV production, with both foreign and domestic automakers recognizing the potential benefits of investing in the region.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The expansion of Hyundai&#39;s US production comes as the company accelerates its efforts to electrify its vehicle lineup. Hyundai Motor Group has committed to investing heavily in EV technology, with plans to introduce 23 new EV models by 2025 [1]. This investment in the US is expected to contribute significantly to this goal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;President Biden&#39;s visit to South Korea and the announcement of Hyundai&#39;s investment in the US are further evidence of the strong ties between the two countries. The US and South Korea have a long history of cooperation in various sectors, including trade, defense, and technology. This investment is expected to deepen these ties and contribute to the growth of both economies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. South Korean automaker Hyundai to announce new electric vehicle plant in Georgia. May 11, 2022. https://apnews.com/article/biden-technology-atlanta-south-korea-666958feb8c2dc66015f784603edae8c&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d48c6bb47e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/hyundai-to-invest-9-billion-to-expand-us-automobile-production-to-1-2-million-units-annually-by-2028-25031000052ab7876c61e533/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/hyundai-to-invest-9-billion-to-expand-us-automobile-production-to-1-2-million-units-annually-by-2028-25031000052ab7876c61e533/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:44:24 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Fed&#39;s Barr: Interest rates remain high for businesses.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Fed&#39;s Barr: Interest rates remain high for businesses.&lt;/p&gt;The Federal Reserve&#39;s Vice Chair for Supervision, Michael S. Barr, delivered a speech on October 2, 2023, discussing the intersection of monetary policy and financial stability policy [1]. Barr emphasized his commitment to the Federal Reserve&#39;s dual mandate of promoting maximum employment and stable prices. While acknowledging the progress made in reducing inflation, he expressed caution about the potential challenges in achieving a return to price stability without significant job losses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Barr joined the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) last year when inflation was peaking at around 9 percent. Since then, the Fed has implemented a series of measures to tighten monetary policy, including raising the federal funds rate by 5-1/4 percentage points and reducing the Fed&#39;s securities holdings by approximately $1 trillion [1]. These actions have helped to ensure that inflation expectations remain anchored and have contributed to a decline in inflation from its peak.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, Barr noted that incoming data on economic activity have shown more resilience than he had initially anticipated. While the labor market remains tight, with employment continuing to expand through August, there are signs of progress in bringing labor demand and supply back into balance. Job growth has moderated, and labor force participation has continued to improve, while immigration has increased and job vacancies have declined toward more normal levels [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these positive signs, Barr cautioned that achieving a return to price stability without significant job losses could be challenging. He noted that historical records suggest that this outcome might be difficult to achieve and emphasized the importance of maintaining a cautious approach to monetary policy [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In light of these developments, businesses can expect to face high interest rates for the near future as the Fed continues to tighten monetary policy to combat inflation and ensure a stable economic environment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Federal Reserve. (2023, October 2). Remarks by Michael S. Barr, Vice Chair for Supervision. Retrieved October 10, 2023, from https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/barr20231002a.htm&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d488544c5f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-barr-interest-rates-remain-high-for-businesses-25031000bac5699bc20e544e/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-barr-interest-rates-remain-high-for-businesses-25031000bac5699bc20e544e/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:43:18 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Fitch affirms Allegion&#39;s IDR at &#39;BBB&#39;; outlook stable</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Fitch affirms Allegion&#39;s IDR at &#39;BBB&#39;; outlook stable&lt;/p&gt;Allegion US Holding Company Inc. (ALLE), a leading provider of security products and services, recently reported its fourth-quarter and full-year financial results for 2024 [1]. The company announced a 2025 outlook, and its financial performance surpassed expectations in the previous quarter [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The latest developments at Allegion come as credit rating agencies continue to assess the company&#39;s creditworthiness. Fitch Ratings, one of the world&#39;s leading credit rating agencies, recently affirmed Allegion&#39;s long-term issuer default rating (IDR) at &#39;BBB&#39; with a stable outlook [2]. This rating action is in line with Moody&#39;s Investors Service&#39;s assessment of the company, which also maintains a &#39;Baa2&#39; (LT-local currency credit rating) with a stable outlook [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allegion&#39;s strong financial position is supported by its diverse portfolio of products and services, which cater to various industries and sectors. The company&#39;s financial performance has been resilient, even in the face of economic uncertainties and market volatility. In 2024, Allegion reported earnings that surpassed expectations [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In addition to its strong financial position, Allegion has a solid capital structure. The company recently issued international bonds with a coupon rate of 5.6% in the amount of USD 400 million, maturing in 2034 [2]. These bonds demonstrate Allegion&#39;s ability to access the capital markets and raise funds to support its growth initiatives.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Allegion&#39;s credit rating is also supported by its stable business model and competitive position in the market. The company operates in the &quot;other sectors&quot; industry, which includes a range of businesses that are not easily categorized into traditional sectors. Despite this, Allegion has managed to establish a strong presence in the market and maintain a competitive edge.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Fitch&#39;s affirmation of Allegion&#39;s long-term issuer default rating at &#39;BBB&#39; with a stable outlook is a testament to the company&#39;s strong financial position, solid capital structure, and competitive position in the market. With a diverse portfolio of products and services, resilient financial performance, and access to capital markets, Allegion is well-positioned to continue delivering value to its stakeholders.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;Allegion Reports Q4, Full-Year 2024 Financial Results, Introduces 2025 Outlook,&quot; Cbonds, February 18, 2025, https://cbonds.hk/news/2283048/&lt;br&gt;[2] &quot;Fitch Affirms Allegion&#39;s IDR at &#39;BBB&#39;; Outlook Stable,&quot; Cbonds, May 21, 2024, https://cbonds.com/news/1167985/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d46bc6bc5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/fitch-affirms-allegion-s-idr-at-bbb-outlook-stable-250310001d49e92e2d16e8fc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/fitch-affirms-allegion-s-idr-at-bbb-outlook-stable-250310001d49e92e2d16e8fc/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:35:43 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>ECB&#39;s Escriva: Trade impacts Spain&#39;s inflation less than Eurozone.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;ECB&#39;s Escriva: Trade impacts Spain&#39;s inflation less than Eurozone.&lt;/p&gt;In a recent speech at the European Central Bank (ECB), Pablo Hernandez de Cos, the Governor of the Bank of Spain, shed light on the differences in the impact of trade on inflation between Spain and the Eurozone [1]. According to de Cos, while Spain experienced an increase in aggregate markups during the recent inflationary episode, the direct effect of markup increases has been quantitatively less important than firms&#39; pass-through of higher input costs to protect their profits.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The data from the Observatory of Firms&#39; Margins supports de Cos&#39; claims. A study published in the Journal of the European Economic Association revealed that the main factor behind price increases in Spain was firms&#39; pass-through of higher input costs, rather than markup increases or unit labor costs [1]. This finding is crucial, as it suggests that the inflationary pressures in Spain are more directly linked to global supply chain disruptions and energy prices than to domestic factors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, the economic forecast for Spain by the European Commission indicates that the country&#39;s real GDP growth is expected to remain robust, expanding by 3.0% in 2024 and gradually decelerating to 2.1% in 2026 [2]. Headline inflation is projected to decline further, reaching 2.0% in 2026, as underlying price pressures moderate. These forecasts suggest that the inflationary pressures in Spain are expected to remain subdued in the coming years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these positive developments, de Cos warned that there are still distributional consequences from inflation, and there is space for non-inflationary wage increases [1]. However, he also emphasized that fiscal and regulatory measures have effectively curbed inflation, and that restrictive monetary policy is inappropriate and costly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, according to the latest data and forecasts, Spain&#39;s inflation is expected to remain subdued compared to the Eurozone, as the impact of trade on inflation is limited, and the primary drivers of inflation are global supply chain disruptions and energy prices.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Hernandez de Cos, P. (2023, March 22). Speech by Pablo Hernandez de Cos, Governor of the Bank of Spain, at the European Central Bank, Frankfurt am Main. Retrieved from https://www.boe.es/en/boe/2023/03/22/index.html&lt;br&gt;[2] European Commission. (2023, March). Economic forecast for the EU and EU Member States. Retrieved from https://ec.europa.eu/info/publication-detail/-/publication/81a1677e-148b-11ed-80f4-01bb66a897d6&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d468658c7e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/ecb-s-escriva-trade-impacts-spain-s-inflation-less-than-eurozone-2503100027ed2ccc80eceea4/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/ecb-s-escriva-trade-impacts-spain-s-inflation-less-than-eurozone-2503100027ed2ccc80eceea4/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:34:49 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>FBI director: Investigating the increase in violent activity toward Tesla over the last few days</title><description>&lt;p&gt;FBI director: Investigating the increase in violent activity toward Tesla over the last few days&lt;/p&gt;The FBI is currently probing a wave of violent protests targeting Tesla dealerships and charging stations across the country [1]. The investigations come amidst a surge in grassroots demonstrations, some of which have escalated into criminal acts, raising concerns about domestic terrorism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to reports, the alleged incidents include arson, vandalism, and the writing of profane messages against President Trump near charging stations [1]. Three individuals have been arrested over the past few weeks in connection with these incidents, charged with various crimes, including throwing Molotov cocktails at Tesla vehicles [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The FBI&#39;s decision to investigate these incidents as potential domestic terrorism cases could grant them broader search warrant authorities under the Patriot Act [1]. This includes single-jurisdiction search warrants that apply nationwide and access to confidential education records from any school or agency in the course of the investigation [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Civil liberties experts, however, caution against labeling these protests as terrorist activities, arguing that doing so could give federal and local law enforcement broad authority to surveil individuals protesting Elon Musk&#39;s role in government [1]. The terrorism designation could also potentially allow Tesla executives access to information uncovered during the investigations [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The FBI&#39;s investigation comes ahead of hundreds of &quot;Tesla Takedown&quot; events scheduled to take place at Tesla facilities across the US this weekend [1]. While most of these protests have been peaceful, some have attracted hundreds of people each, and a few have resulted in criminal damage to Tesla property [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, the FBI&#39;s investigation into the surge in violent protests targeting Tesla dealerships and charging stations raises concerns about potential domestic terrorism. With broader search warrant authorities and potential access to confidential information, the investigation could have significant implications for civil liberties and the future of protest movements in the US.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Wired. (2023, March 24). FBI investigating surge in violent protests against Tesla: potential domestic terrorism? Retrieved from https://www.wired.com/story/fbi-tesla-arson-domestic-terrorism-protests/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4536b385f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/fbi-director-investigating-increase-in-violent-activity-toward-tesla-over-last-few-days-25031000d58df09f10b1ef38/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/fbi-director-investigating-increase-in-violent-activity-toward-tesla-over-last-few-days-25031000d58df09f10b1ef38/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:29:09 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>EV</category><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Energy Department: Postponing implementation of three Biden administration mandates on home appliances</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Energy Department: Postponing implementation of three Biden administration mandates on home appliances&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4433e585f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/energy-department-postponing-implementation-of-three-biden-administration-mandates-on-home-appliances-2503100049c4af36b618ae67/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/energy-department-postponing-implementation-of-three-biden-administration-mandates-on-home-appliances-2503100049c4af36b618ae67/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:24:54 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>BoE Gov. Bailey: We&#39;re looking at how regulation can be adapted.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BoE Gov. Bailey: We&#39;re looking at how regulation can be adapted.&lt;/p&gt;The Bank of England (BoE) Governor, Andrew Bailey, recently emphasized the need to adapt financial regulations in light of evolving risks and challenges in the global financial system [1]. Bailey&#39;s remarks, delivered at the Bloomberg Global Regulatory Forum, highlighted the importance of understanding financial theory, learning from history, and adopting a macro-prudential approach to regulation [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bailey&#39;s speech underscored the significance of Hyman Minsky&#39;s theories on financial stability, which emphasize the interconnectedness of money, finance, and economics. Minsky argued that economies oscillate between robust and fragile financial structures, and that the latter can contribute to financial crises [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of the key challenges facing regulators today is the need to address risks in the non-bank sector and their interactions across the financial system. Bailey highlighted the importance of new surveillance tools and emergency central bank facilities that can be temporarily provided in a crisis [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, the ongoing digitalization of financial services, such as the recent announcement by Yahoo that its suite of services will no longer be accessible from mainland China [1], poses new challenges and opportunities for regulators. Bailey emphasized the need for regulators to stay abreast of these developments and adapt regulations accordingly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, BoE Governor Andrew Bailey&#39;s recent remarks emphasize the importance of adapting financial regulations to address evolving risks and challenges in the global financial system. By understanding financial theory, learning from history, and adopting a macro-prudential approach, regulators can better prepare for and mitigate potential financial crises.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;Bank of England&#39;s Andrew Bailey: Financial regulations to be adapted,&quot; UK Finance, November 1, 2021, https://uk.finance.yahoo.com/news/bank-of-england-andrew-bailey-financial-regulations-134811518.html.&lt;br&gt;[2] &quot;Andrew Bailey: Keynote Address at the Bloomberg Global Regulatory Forum,&quot; Bank of England, October 25, 2024, https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/speech/2024/october/andrew-bailey-keynote-address-at-the-bloomberg-global-regulatory-forum.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d42c6bdc5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-gov-bailey-we-re-looking-at-how-regulation-can-be-adapted-250310007732548b4581b8dd/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-gov-bailey-we-re-looking-at-how-regulation-can-be-adapted-250310007732548b4581b8dd/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:18:24 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>BoE Gov. Bailey: Businesses are currently keeping all options open on how to respond to the National Insurance rise.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BoE Gov. Bailey: Businesses are currently keeping all options open on how to respond to the National Insurance rise.&lt;/p&gt;The recent remarks from Bank of England (BoE) Governor Andrew Bailey during his speech before the UK Parliament&#39;s Treasury Select Committee (TSC) have shed light on businesses&#39; current approach to the upcoming National Insurance rise. Bailey emphasized the importance of monitoring services inflation, which remains above the level required for on-target inflation, reflecting labor market developments (1).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While the BoE is expected to trim the interest rate amid steady inflation and weak economic growth (2), Bailey&#39;s comments suggest that businesses may be keeping their options open regarding how to respond to the higher employment costs. The British Retail Consortium&#39;s concerns about potential job losses following the national insurance rise are not unfounded, as past labor hoarding could make it easier for businesses to reduce employment now (1).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, the outcomes of financial services after Brexit have been less severe than initially feared, providing some relief for businesses facing the national insurance hike (1). The BoE&#39;s guidance and economic projections, to be released during the upcoming Super Thursday, will provide further insight into the potential impact of the national insurance rise on businesses and the overall economy.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4206be07e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-gov-bailey-businesses-are-currently-keeping-all-options-open-on-how-to-respond-to-national-insurance-rise-25031000925534ba05a4a3c1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-gov-bailey-businesses-are-currently-keeping-all-options-open-on-how-to-respond-to-national-insurance-rise-25031000925534ba05a4a3c1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:15:15 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Fed&#39;s Barr: No comments on monetary policy or economic outlook in prepared remarks.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Fed&#39;s Barr: No comments on monetary policy or economic outlook in prepared remarks.&lt;/p&gt;In a recent speech before the National Association for Business Economics, Federal Reserve Vice Chair for Supervision Michael Barr provided insights into his views on the current state of monetary policy and the economy [1]. Although Barr did not explicitly comment on the Federal Reserve&#39;s monetary policy stance or economic outlook in his prepared remarks, his comments suggest a cautious approach to further interest rate hikes as inflation moderates and economic activity shows signs of resilience.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Barr reiterated his commitment to the Federal Reserve&#39;s dual mandate of promoting maximum employment and stable prices for the American people [1]. He acknowledged the progress made in reducing inflation since the beginning of the policy response last year, with the 12-month change in Consumer Price Index (CPI) inflation now at about 3.75% in August [2]. However, he also noted that incoming data on economic activity have shown more resilience than expected, which could complicate the Federal Reserve&#39;s efforts to bring inflation back down to its target without causing significant job losses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Barr&#39;s comments come as the Federal Reserve continues to grapple with the challenge of balancing the need to control inflation with the potential risks to the labor market from further interest rate hikes [3]. While the Federal Reserve has raised the federal funds rate by 5.25 percentage points since the beginning of the policy response last year and reduced its securities holdings by about $1 trillion, incoming data suggest that the economy may be more resilient to the policy tightening than initially anticipated [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these developments, Barr cautioned that achieving a return to price stability without significant job losses could be challenging, given the historical record [2]. He noted that while the labor market remains tight and employment continued to expand through August, incoming data also suggest that the Federal Reserve is making progress in bringing labor demand and supply back into better balance [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Overall, Barr&#39;s comments suggest that the Federal Reserve may adopt a cautious approach to further interest rate hikes as inflation moderates and economic activity shows signs of resilience. However, given the importance of maintaining price stability to achieving sustained labor market conditions, the Federal Reserve will likely continue to closely monitor incoming data and adjust its policy stance as needed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] ForexLive. (2023, November 19). Fed&#39;s Barr speaking doesn&#39;t comment on the economy or monetary policy. https://www.forexlive.com/centralbank/feds-barr-speaking-doesnt-comment-on-the-economy-or-monetary-policy-20241119/&lt;br&gt;[2] Federal Reserve. (2023, October 2). Remarks by Michael S. Barr, Vice Chair for Supervision, Before the National Association for Business Economics Annual Meeting. https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/barr20231002a.htm&lt;br&gt;[3] Federal Reserve. (2023). Learning More About Inflation. https://www.federalreserve.gov/publications/2023-inflation-learning.htm&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d411a1385f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-barr-no-comments-on-monetary-policy-or-economic-outlook-in-prepared-remarks-25031000bb09c00db3f4fd5a/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-barr-no-comments-on-monetary-policy-or-economic-outlook-in-prepared-remarks-25031000bb09c00db3f4fd5a/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:11:06 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>BoE&#39;s Bailey: Businesses delaying investment due to uncertainty</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BoE&#39;s Bailey: Businesses delaying investment due to uncertainty&lt;/p&gt;The Bank of England (BoE) Governor, Andrew Bailey, has expressed concerns about the increasing uncertainty faced by businesses in the UK, hindering their investment decisions [1]. The weak growth environment in the country is a significant concern, with Bailey acknowledging that the economy is currently facing a challenging period.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bailey&#39;s remarks came during a panel discussion on &quot;Preserving and enhancing open financial markets&quot; at the Treasury Committee in the lower house of parliament [2]. The BoE chief did not delve too deeply into monetary policy comments during the discussion, focusing instead on the importance of maintaining open financial markets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The uncertainty surrounding the UK&#39;s financial regulations is another factor contributing to businesses&#39; hesitance to invest. The BoE initially delayed the implementation of new rules for banks to avoid putting British firms at a competitive disadvantage with the US [2]. The EU&#39;s progress on implementing Basel III capital rules is also out of sync with the UK and US, leading to further uncertainty [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The global trade environment is another significant concern for the BoE. The bank has warned of potential risks arising from the rise in global trade barriers [4]. The uncertainty surrounding trade policies and their impact on the economy is likely to deter businesses from making investment decisions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, the BoE&#39;s Governor, Andrew Bailey, has highlighted the importance of addressing uncertainty in order to encourage businesses to invest and boost the UK&#39;s economy. The weak growth environment, regulatory uncertainty, and global trade tensions are significant concerns that need to be addressed to promote investment and maintain financial stability.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] ForexLive. (2025, February 18). BoE&#39;s Bailey: We are in a period of heightened uncertainty. Retrieved from https://www.forexlive.com/centralbank/boes-bailey-we-are-in-a-period-of-heightened-uncertainty-20250218/&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketScreener. (2023, November 29). BoE&#39;s Bailey says bank rules were delayed because of US competition. Retrieved from https://www.marketscreener.com/news/latest/BoE-s-Bailey-says-bank-rules-were-delayed-because-of-US-competition-48903658/&lt;br&gt;[3] The Banker. (2023, November 28). Basel III implementation delays mount in the UK and EU. Retrieved from https://www.thebanker.com/content/eb39fce0-17a3-52b9-a149-0b588130f274&lt;br&gt;[4] US News &amp;amp; World Report. (2024, November 29). Bank of England warns of risks from rise in global trade barriers. Retrieved from https://money.usnews.com/investing/news/articles/2024-11-29/bank-of-england-warns-of-risks-from-rise-in-global-trade-barriers&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4048e4c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-s-bailey-businesses-delaying-investment-due-to-uncertainty-250310003761625904158f46/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-s-bailey-businesses-delaying-investment-due-to-uncertainty-250310003761625904158f46/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:07:31 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>BoE&#39;s Bailey: Consumption not rising with real incomes</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BoE&#39;s Bailey: Consumption not rising with real incomes&lt;/p&gt;In a recent speech at the London School of Economics, Andrew Bailey, the Governor of the Bank of England (BoE), addressed the ongoing challenges of inflation and its impact on consumer prices and real incomes in the UK [1]. Bailey acknowledged the significant economic events that have contributed to the UK&#39;s macroeconomic upheaval, including Brexit, the Covid-19 pandemic, and the energy price hikes resulting from Russia&#39;s invasion of Ukraine [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The BoE&#39;s primary concern is the current high inflation rate of 10.4%, which is well above the target of 2% [2]. Bailey emphasized that the bank cannot reverse the external shocks that have led to this inflation but can control the extent to which it becomes ingrained in the UK economy. He highlighted the importance of monetary policy in addressing inflation and its impact on both consumer spending and business investments [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the rise in consumer prices, Bailey noted that there is no evidence of a significant increase in consumption levels relative to real incomes [2]. This observation contradicts the historical trend of consumers maintaining their spending levels even when their incomes are not growing [3]. Instead, the BoE&#39;s data suggests that households are becoming more cautious with their spending, potentially due to the uncertainty surrounding the economic outlook and the increased cost of living [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Furthermore, Bailey acknowledged that the energy price shock has had a significant impact on the UK&#39;s national real income, making the country poorer [2]. The BoE&#39;s response to this challenge involves using its primary tool, the interest rate, to combat inflation and ensure that it does not become a lasting issue generated domestically [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Bailey&#39;s speech underscores the importance of the BoE&#39;s role in managing inflation in the face of external shocks and their impact on consumer spending and real incomes. While the current high inflation rate poses challenges, the BoE remains committed to bringing it back down to its target level and mitigating its impact on the UK economy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Bank of England. (2023, March 13). Andrew Bailey speech at London School of Economics. Retrieved March 16, 2023, from https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/speech/2023/march/andrew-bailey-speech-at-london-school-of-economics&lt;br&gt;[2] Reuters. (2023, March 13). BoE&#39;s Bailey says UK consumer spending not rising with real incomes despite inflation. Retrieved March 16, 2023, from https://www.reuters.com/business/uk-economy/boes-bailey-says-uk-consumer-spending-not-rising-with-real-incomes-despite-inflation-2023-03-13/&lt;br&gt;[3] The Guardian. (2022, September 13). UK inflation hits 41-year high of 10.1%. Retrieved March 16, 2023, from https://www.theguardian.com/business/2022/sep/13/uk-inflation-hits-41-year-high-of-101-in-september&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d402aa545f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-s-bailey-consumption-not-rising-with-real-incomes-250310000075b4e075bca325/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boe-s-bailey-consumption-not-rising-with-real-incomes-250310000075b4e075bca325/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:06:56 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump chooses Susan Monarez as head of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, White House official confirms</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump chooses Susan Monarez as head of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, White House official confirms&lt;/p&gt;In a surprising move, President Donald Trump has reportedly selected Dr. Susan Monarez, the current acting director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to lead the agency permanently [1]. This decision comes after the withdrawal of Dr. David Weldon&#39;s nomination earlier this month due to concerns about his ability to secure Senate confirmation [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Monarez, who has been serving as the CDC&#39;s acting head since January, has been viewed as an unconventional choice for the role due to her lack of experience within the CDC&#39;s career ranks [1]. She previously held the position of deputy director of the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA Health) [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Monarez&#39;s appointment would mark the first time a CDC director is subjected to Senate confirmation, following a change in the law passed in 2022 [1]. Previous directors were able to assume the position shortly after being selected by the president without undergoing the confirmation process [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Trump administration&#39;s decision to nominate Monarez has been met with mixed reactions. Some sources suggest that White House officials are attempting to &quot;get it right&quot; with their new pick [1]. Others have noted that Monarez has gotten along well with Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. since taking on the role [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The confirmation process for Monarez&#39;s nomination is expected to unfold in the coming weeks.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] CBS News. (2023, March 20). Susan Monarez, CDC Director Nominee. https://www.cbsnews.com/news/susan-monarez-cdc-director-nominee-trump/&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketScreener. (2023, March 20). Trump to nominate Susan Monarez to lead CDC: CBS News. https://www.marketscreener.com/news/latest/Trump-to-nominate-Susan-Monarez-to-lead-CDC-CBS-News-reports-49417643/&lt;br&gt;[3] CBS News. (2023, March 20). Trump Administration CDC Acting Director. https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-administration-cdc-acting-director/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4001e245f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-chooses-susan-monarez-as-head-of-centers-for-disease-control-and-prevention-white-house-official-confirms-2503100066bf30d4dd304083/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-chooses-susan-monarez-as-head-of-centers-for-disease-control-and-prevention-white-house-official-confirms-2503100066bf30d4dd304083/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:06:22 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump: Auto levies coming, teases reciprocal tariff breaks</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump: Auto levies coming, teases reciprocal tariff breaks&lt;/p&gt;The financial world eagerly awaits President Trump&#39;s highly anticipated announcement of reciprocal tariffs, scheduled for April 2, 2023, which the President has dubbed &quot;Liberation Day&quot; [1]. This policy shift, aimed at countering the perceived unfair trade practices of other countries, has been a topic of much speculation and controversy in recent weeks [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump&#39;s announcement of reciprocal tariffs comes after months of heavy teasing and delays. Initially, the President had indicated that reciprocal tariffs would be implemented on February 28, 2023 [1]. However, the date was later pushed back to at least April 1, 2023, to allow the Commerce and Treasury departments to complete studies on the potential impact of these tariffs [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the uncertainty surrounding the specifics of the tariffs, Trump has been adamant about his desire to upend the global trade status quo. &quot;We&#39;ve been ripped off by every country in the world, friend and foe,&quot; Trump stated during a press conference on March 24, 2023 [1]. Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent, however, indicated that the biggest development coming on April 2 would be the White House sending a &quot;number that we believe that represents their tariffs&quot; to all trade partners [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The impact of these tariffs on various sectors of the economy has been a subject of much debate. While some argue that reciprocal tariffs could lead to a more level playing field for American businesses, others worry about the potential negative consequences for consumers and the overall economy [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the April 2 deadline approaches, the financial markets will be closely watching for any developments related to the implementation of reciprocal tariffs. In the meantime, investors and analysts will continue to analyze the potential implications of this policy shift for the global economy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Derek Saul. (2023, March 24). Trump Says He May Give a Lot of Tariff Breaks: Here&#39;s What to Know About Liberation Day as Reciprocal Tariffs Loom. Forbes. https://www.forbes.com/sites/dereksaul/2023/03/24/trump-says-he-may-give-a-lot-of-tariff-breaks-heres-what-to-know-about-liberation-day-as-reciprocal-tariffs-loom/&lt;br&gt;[2] Adam Behsudi and Doug Palmer. (2023, March 28). U.S. to Send List of Tariffs to WTO as Trump Prepares to Announce Reciprocal Levies. Politico. https://www.politico.com/news/2023/03/28/us-tariffs-wto-000310&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d3f09aec5f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-auto-levies-coming-teases-reciprocal-tariff-breaks-25031000ef7a8685752c6350/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-auto-levies-coming-teases-reciprocal-tariff-breaks-25031000ef7a8685752c6350/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:02:08 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump: Tariffs for doing business with Venezuela will be on top of existing tariffs.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump: Tariffs for doing business with Venezuela will be on top of existing tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d3c3c6085f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-tariffs-for-doing-business-with-venezuela-will-be-on-top-of-existing-tariffs-250310009ad91daca3929761/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-tariffs-for-doing-business-with-venezuela-will-be-on-top-of-existing-tariffs-250310009ad91daca3929761/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:50:02 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump: Law firms have to behave themselves</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump: Law firms have to behave themselves&lt;/p&gt;In a recent development, President Donald Trump has expressed his concerns over the behavior of law firms, particularly in the wake of his ongoing feud with several high-profile firms. Trump&#39;s comments came after powerful Wall Street law firm Paul Weiss reached a deal with the White House to avoid potential consequences from an executive order that could have adversely affected its business [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The president&#39;s remarks have sparked a wave of reactions from legal circles, with some interpreting this as an attempt to exert more influence over the legal profession. The White House&#39;s move to seek sanctions against attorneys and law firms engaging in frivolous or vexatious litigation against the United States further underscores this point [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump&#39;s criticisms of law firms are not new. In the past, he has targeted specific firms, such as Perkins Coie and Covington &amp;amp; Burling, for their representation of political adversaries. However, his recent comments have taken on a new dimension, as they suggest a broader effort to reshape the relationship between the legal profession and the executive branch [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It remains to be seen how this development will play out in practice. Some observers have expressed concerns about the potential chilling effect on the legal profession&#39;s ability to represent clients effectively, particularly in cases that involve sensitive issues or potential conflicts with the government [2]. Others, however, view this as an opportunity for the legal profession to assert its independence and uphold its professional obligations in the face of political pressure [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Regardless of the outcome, one thing is clear: Trump&#39;s call for law firms to &quot;behave&quot; is a significant development in the ongoing saga of legal-political relations in the United States.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] MarketScreener. (2023, March 24). Trump: Law firms have to behave themselves. https://www.marketscreener.com/news/latest/Trump-Law-firms-have-to-behave-themselves-49417708/&lt;br&gt;[2] MSNBC. (2023, March 25). Trump&#39;s memo to AG Pam Bondi: Law firms beware. https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/maddowblog/trump-law-firms-paul-weiss-democracy-rcna197747&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6d822c07e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-law-firms-have-to-behave-themselves-25031000fb0b2e7d71fd78bd/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-law-firms-have-to-behave-themselves-25031000fb0b2e7d71fd78bd/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:49:51 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump: Not all tariffs will be included on April 2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump: Not all tariffs will be included on April 2&lt;/p&gt;The upcoming April 2 tariffs announced by the Trump administration have undergone significant changes in scope, moving away from a universal approach to a more targeted one. Instead of imposing taxes on all countries trading with the US, the administration is reportedly focusing on 10 to 15 nations with significant trade barriers and a substantial contribution to the US trade deficit, often referred to as the &#39;dirty 15&#39; [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;President Trump&#39;s initial campaign promise included imposing universal tariffs of 10% to 20% on all imports, along with a 60% or higher tariff on Chinese imports [1]. However, recent reports suggest that the administration is now concentrating on reciprocal tariffs, imposing taxes on foreign countries equal to their own imposed on American products [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The &#39;dirty 15&#39; list is not yet officially disclosed, but officials, such as Kevin Hassett, the Director of the National Economic Council, and Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent, have hinted at the countries that may be included [1]. These nations are expected to have substantial trade barriers and account for a significant portion of the US trade deficit.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The administration&#39;s shift in strategy is seen as a response to the trade barriers and tariffs imposed by these countries on American products. The implementation of reciprocal tariffs aims to level the playing field and potentially reduce the US trade deficit.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is essential to note that the exact timeline and details of the tariffs&#39; implementation are still uncertain. Some reports suggest that negotiations may lead to the avoidance of tariffs altogether, or negotiations may begin after the tariffs are announced [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, the upcoming April 2 tariffs represent a significant shift in the Trump administration&#39;s trade policy. Instead of imposing universal tariffs, the administration is focusing on reciprocal tariffs on 10 to 15 countries with substantial trade barriers and a substantial contribution to the US trade deficit. The implementation of these tariffs is expected to level the playing field and potentially reduce the US trade deficit.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Victor Reklaitis. (2023, March 24). Trump&#39;s April 2 tariffs: What we know so far as the White House shifts its strategy. MarketWatch. https://www.marketwatch.com/news/marketwatch/2023-03-24/trumps-april-2-tariffs-what-we-know-so-far-as-the-white-house-shifts-its-strategy&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d3c2bce85f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-not-all-tariffs-will-be-included-on-april-2-2503100035385da2506f4cb8/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-not-all-tariffs-will-be-included-on-april-2-2503100035385da2506f4cb8/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:49:29 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Brent crude futures settle at $73.00/bbl, up 84 cents, 1.16%.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Brent crude futures settle at $73.00/bbl, up 84 cents, 1.16%.&lt;/p&gt;Brent crude oil futures experienced a notable increase on Wednesday, settling at $73.00 per barrel, up 84 cents, or 1.16% [1]. This rebound came amidst a complex web of factors, including geopolitical tensions, economic uncertainties, and supply dynamics.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Russia&#39;s agreement to a temporary ceasefire with Ukraine, which could potentially facilitate the entry of Russian oil into global markets, contributed to the upward pressure on Brent crude [1]. However, this optimistic outlook was tempered by ongoing concerns about increased supply from OPEC and its allies, who plan to boost production next month [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The trade war between the US and its main trading partners, which could dampen growth and weaken consumption, poses an additional downside risk to the oil market [1]. Furthermore, signs of slowing demand emerged after industry data showed a larger-than-expected build in crude stocks last week [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these bearish factors, heightened violence in the Middle East, threatening supply disruptions from key oil-producing regions, helped cushion some losses for Brent crude [1]. This geopolitical risk premium has been a significant factor supporting oil prices throughout 2025.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Looking at the historical context, Brent crude oil has experienced significant volatility over the past few years. It is currently down 5.16% since the beginning of 2025 [1]. Historically, Brent crude oil reached an all-time high of $147.50 in July 2008 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In terms of future price expectations, Trading Economics&#39; global macro models and analysts anticipate Brent crude to trade at $70.86 by the end of this quarter and $71.69 in 12 months time [2]. However, it is important to note that these forecasts are subject to change as market conditions evolve.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Trading Economics. (2025, March 19). Brent crude oil. https://tradingeconomics.com/commodity/brent-crude-oil&lt;br&gt;[2] Morningstar. (2025, December 24). Front-month ICE Brent crude rose 1.31% to $73.58. https://www.morningstar.com/news/dow-jones/202412242997/front-month-ice-brent-crude-rose-1-31-to-settle-at-7358-data-talk&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d3ad632c5f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/brent-crude-futures-settle-at-73-00-bbl-up-84-cents-1-16-25031000ceb8699439d93a48/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/brent-crude-futures-settle-at-73-00-bbl-up-84-cents-1-16-25031000ceb8699439d93a48/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:43:31 GMT</pubDate><author>Why is it moving?</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>positive</category><category>AI Mover</category></item><item><title>Trump: I may give a lot of countries breaks on tariffs</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump: I may give a lot of countries breaks on tariffs&lt;/p&gt;In a surprising turn of events, President Donald J. Trump hinted at potential concessions on tariffs during a recent interview with CNBC [1]. This announcement comes amidst ongoing global trade tensions, with the U.S. and its trading partners engaging in a series of retaliatory measures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The White House&#39;s stance on tariffs has been a contentious issue, with the administration emphasizing the need for fairness and reciprocity in international trade relationships [1]. However, recent developments suggest that Trump may be open to granting some leniency to certain countries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For instance, the U.S. has long been critical of Brazil&#39;s high tariffs on U.S. ethanol exports [2]. Currently, Brazil imposes an 18% tariff on U.S. ethanol, while the U.S. only levies a 2.5% tariff on Brazilian ethanol [2]. This trade imbalance has resulted in a significant surplus of ethanol imports from Brazil to the U.S., with the U.S. exporting only a fraction of the amount to Brazil [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Similarly, India&#39;s high tariffs on U.S. agricultural goods, motorcycles, and shellfish have been a source of concern for American exporters [2]. India&#39;s average applied Most Favored Nation (MFN) tariff on agricultural goods is 39%, compared to the U.S. average of 5% [2]. Additionally, India imposes a 100% tariff on U.S. motorcycles, while the U.S. only imposes a 2.4% tariff on Indian motorcycles [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The EU&#39;s trade practices have also come under scrutiny, with the EU imposing a 10% tariff on imported cars while only imposing a 2.5% tariff on U.S. imports [2]. Furthermore, the EU bans shellfish exports from 48 of the U.S. states, despite committing to expedite approvals for shellfish exports [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump&#39;s potential concessions on tariffs are a response to these imbalances and aim to ensure fairness in international trade relationships. However, it remains to be seen how these developments will impact the ongoing global trade tensions and the broader economic landscape.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] CNBC. (2025, February 15). Trump signals possible tariff breaks for some countries amid global trade tensions. https://www.cnbc.com/2025/02/15/trump-signals-possible-tariff-breaks-for-some-countries-amid-global-trade-tensions.html&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] The White House. (2025, February 13). Fact Sheet: President Donald J. Trump Announces Fair and Reciprocal Plan on Trade. https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/02/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-announces-fair-and-reciprocal-plan-on-trade/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d3a562045f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-i-may-give-a-lot-of-countries-breaks-on-tariffs-250310006a15bf6476450f52/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-i-may-give-a-lot-of-countries-breaks-on-tariffs-250310006a15bf6476450f52/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:41:21 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump: Will announce additional tariffs on autos, lumber, chips in the coming days</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump: Will announce additional tariffs on autos, lumber, chips in the coming days&lt;/p&gt;In an unexpected move, U.S. President Donald Trump has announced plans to announce additional tariffs in the coming days, focusing on automobiles, lumber, and chips [1]. This upcoming wave of tariffs is expected to be more targeted than the broader, global tariffs Trump has previously considered [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump&#39;s tariff announcement, dubbed &quot;Liberation Day,&quot; is scheduled for April 2 [1]. The announcement will include reciprocal tariffs aimed at retaliating against tariffs and other barriers from other countries, particularly longtime U.S. allies [1]. However, the administration is not planning to introduce sector-specific tariffs at the same time [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The impact of these tariffs is likely to be significant, straining relations with allied nations and prompting retaliation [1]. Only countries without tariffs on the U.S. and with which the U.S. has a trade surplus will be exempt from the reciprocal tariffs [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Trump&#39;s tariff announcement comes after initial tariffs imposed on Canada, Mexico, and China, as well as certain metals, resulted in market anxiety [1]. Despite the potential revenue benefits, the West Wing is serving a president who has long used major policy announcements as a way to generate headlines and maintain his political base [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is essential to note that the situation remains fluid, and no decision is final until Trump announces it [1]. The administration&#39;s internal negotiations over how to implement the tariff program continue, with some of the most hawkish signals coming directly from Trump himself [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;Trump plans his tariff liberation day with more targeted push,&quot; BNN Bloomberg, March 22, 2023. [https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/business/2023/03/22/trump-plans-his-tariff-liberation-day-with-more-targeted-push.html]&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d3a460185f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-will-announce-additional-tariffs-on-autos-lumber-chips-in-coming-days-250310005cbfb5d37d6a7995/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-will-announce-additional-tariffs-on-autos-lumber-chips-in-coming-days-250310005cbfb5d37d6a7995/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:41:10 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item></channel></rss>