<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>AInvest - Latest News</title><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.pseudoyu.com/ainvest/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>AInvest - Latest News - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:24:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Samsung Electronics: Co-CEO Han Jong-hee dies</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung Electronics: Co-CEO Han Jong-hee dies&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/samsung-electronics-co-ceo-han-jong-hee-dies-25031000100a6530c75c38c2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/samsung-electronics-co-ceo-han-jong-hee-dies-25031000100a6530c75c38c2/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:23:25 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Britain to invest 2 billion pounds to build 18,000 affordable homes - Reuters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Britain to invest 2 billion pounds to build 18,000 affordable homes - Reuters&lt;/p&gt;The UK government has recently announced a significant investment of £2 billion to support the construction of 18,000 new affordable homes [1]. This investment forms part of the government&#39;s Plan for Change, aimed at delivering security for working people by growing the economy and providing 1.5 million new homes [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The funding will only support development on sites that will deliver homes within this parliamentary term, with construction expected to commence in areas such as Manchester and Liverpool [1]. This investment is expected to help hardworking families obtain safe and secure homes while kickstarting economic growth [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The government&#39;s commitment to tackling the housing crisis extends beyond the £2 billion investment. The Treasury plans to provide additional funding for 2026-27 and beyond, with the goal of addressing the long-term housing shortage [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To encourage providers to come forward with projects and bids, the government is urging them to do so as soon as possible to accelerate the delivery of new housing supply [1]. This investment will also unlock development and opportunity on sites that are ready and waiting for construction in areas such as Manchester and Liverpool [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement of this investment comes after the government&#39;s plan to inspire the next generation of British engineers, bricklayers, and chippies by training 60,000 construction workers to address skills shortages and create job opportunities [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The £2 billion investment boost is a down payment from the Treasury, with more long-term investment in social and affordable housing planned later this year [1]. This investment is expected to provide thousands of new affordable homes that will begin construction by March 2027 and complete by the end of this parliament [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;2-billion new investment to support biggest boost in social and affordable housebuilding in a generation,&quot; gov.uk, 25 March 2023, https://www.gov.uk/government/news/2-billion-new-investment-to-support-biggest-boost-in-social-and-affordable-housebuilding-in-a-generation.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d861b74a4a002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/britain-to-invest-2-billion-pounds-to-build-18-000-affordable-homes-reuters-25031000c936511f4f9d03ec/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/britain-to-invest-2-billion-pounds-to-build-18-000-affordable-homes-reuters-25031000c936511f4f9d03ec/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:12:21 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Japan&#39;s Fujikura shares up 6%</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Japan&#39;s Fujikura shares up 6%&lt;/p&gt;Fujikura Ltd. (TSE:5803), a leading capital goods company in Japan, reported impressive quarterly results, which have sent its share price soaring by 17% to JP¥7,366 [1]. The company beat revenue forecasts by a substantial 15% to reach JP¥263b, surpassing expectations of JP¥231b [1]. Statutory earnings per share (EPS) came in at JP¥185, in line with expectations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The latest earnings report provides valuable insights for investors. Fujikura&#39;s strong performance indicates a solid foundation for the company, allowing investors to evaluate its growth prospects and assess the views of analysts. According to a recent analysis by SimplyWall.St, Fujikura&#39;s ten analysts forecast revenues of JP¥967.4b in 2026, reflecting a credible 6.1% improvement compared to the last 12 months [1]. Per-share earnings are expected to increase by 31% to JP¥352.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the positive outlook, the consensus price target of JP¥7,166 remains unchanged, suggesting that the improved earnings per share outlook may not have a significant long-term impact on the stock&#39;s valuation [1]. However, it is essential to consider the range of price targets put forward by analysts, as a wide range could indicate diverse views on possible outcomes for the business. The most bullish analyst values Fujikura at JP¥8,400 per share, while the most bearish sees it at JP¥6,100 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In comparison to past performance, Fujikura&#39;s revenue growth is expected to slow down substantially, with revenues to the end of 2026 projected to display 4.9% growth on an annualized basis [1]. This is a notable decrease from the company&#39;s past performance and the industry growth estimates.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Fujikura&#39;s impressive 15% revenue beat and strong earnings report have fueled a 6% share price surge. While the positive outlook is reflected in the analysts&#39; forecasts, it is essential for investors to consider the range of price targets and the company&#39;s past performance when assessing its growth prospects.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] SimplyWall.St. (2025, February 12). Fujikura TSE:5803 Earnings and Revenue Growth. https://simplywall.st/stocks/jp/capital-goods/tse-5803/fujikura-shares/news/fujikura-ltd-just-recorded-a-15-revenue-beat-heres-what-anal&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d85f0fa07e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/japan-s-fujikura-shares-up-6-25031000679113e63a91ea4a/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/japan-s-fujikura-shares-up-6-25031000679113e63a91ea4a/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:11:37 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Japan&#39;s TOPIX briefly rises to 2,818.36, highest level since July 24</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Japan&#39;s TOPIX briefly rises to 2,818.36, highest level since July 24&lt;/p&gt;The Japanese stock market experienced a remarkable surge on Thursday, with the TOPIX index briefly touching a 33-year high of 2,818.36 [1]. This milestone comes amidst a backdrop of robust corporate earnings and a weaker Japanese yen, which have fueled investor optimism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to data from the Tokyo Stock Exchange, the TOPIX index gained 33.41 points, or 1.27%, closing at 2,660.71. This is the highest level the index has reached since February 1990 [1]. The broader Nikkei 225 index, which tracks the performance of 225 blue-chip companies, also experienced significant growth, closing up 836.52 points, or 2.19%, at an all-time high of 39,098.68 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The upward trend in the Japanese stock market can be attributed to a combination of factors. One of the primary drivers has been the strong earnings performance of Japanese companies. For instance, Tokyo Electron and Advantest, two major semiconductor manufacturers, have experienced significant buying following better-than-expected earnings reports from U.S. chip giant Nvidia [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, the weaker Japanese yen has also played a role in boosting the stock market. The U.S. dollar has been gaining strength against the yen, with the dollar fetching 142.71-73 yen at 5 p.m. on Thursday, compared to 142.17-18 yen at the same time on Monday [2]. This depreciation of the yen makes Japanese exports more competitive, which in turn can boost the earnings of Japanese companies and attract foreign investors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, some market watchers have expressed caution about the sustainability of this upward trend. With the U.S. presidential election looming in November and the Bank of Japan potentially shifting from its ultra-easy monetary policy, there are concerns about the impact these factors could have on the Japanese stock market [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these uncertainties, the recent surge in the Japanese stock market is a testament to the strength of the Japanese economy and the resilience of its corporate sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Xinhua. (2024, February 22). Tokyo stocks end higher, with benchmark Nikkei index at all-time high. https://english.news.cn/asiapacific/20240222/bb0ab9a9c87e49018bf76eb9b623a20d/c.html&lt;br&gt;[2] Kyodo News. (2023, August 22). Urgent: Tokyo&#39;s Topix index hits 33-yr high on weak yen. https://english.kyodonews.net/news/2023/08/763a2c045d59-urgent-tokyos-topix-index-hits-33-yr-high-on-weak-yen.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d85dddf24a002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/japan-s-topix-briefly-rises-to-2-818-36-highest-level-since-july-24-25031000b10ca6ab517c694c/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/japan-s-topix-briefly-rises-to-2-818-36-highest-level-since-july-24-25031000b10ca6ab517c694c/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:11:29 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>India likely to drop 6% equalization levy from April 1</title><description>&lt;p&gt;India likely to drop 6% equalization levy from April 1&lt;/p&gt;The Indian government has proposed abolishing the Equalization Levy (EL) or digital tax on online advertisements, effective from April 1, 2023 [1]. This move, which was announced as part of the 59 amendments to the Finance Bill 2025, comes amidst ongoing diplomatic efforts to prevent potential trade retaliation from the United States [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The EL, which was initially imposed at a rate of 6% on the sum received or receivable by a non-resident for online advertisement services [1], has garnered criticism from American tech giants such as Google and Meta. The rate was reduced to 2% in 2020, but it was reinstated in 2024 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Amit Maheshwari, Tax Partner at AKM Global, commented that the 2% levy faced significant criticism from the US, prompting the Indian government to adopt a more accommodative stance and remove the 6% EL on online advertising [1]. However, it remains to be seen whether this step will lead to a softening of the US stance on the issue [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The withdrawal of the EL would result in lower costs for digital ad consumers and lower tax costs for digital advertisement platforms such as Google and Meta [1]. However, to maintain tax neutrality, the corresponding income tax exemption under Section 10 (50) has been withdrawn, meaning that income previously exempt under the EL regime will now be taxed under regular income tax provisions [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;From an international tax policy standpoint, unilateral measures such as the EL can create complexities and potential double taxation issues [2]. Therefore, the Indian government&#39;s decision to abolish the EL on online advertisements is a significant development in the ongoing global debate on digital taxation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] The Hindu BusinessLine. India to abolish equalisation levy on online advertisements wef April 1. https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/economy/india-to-abolish-equalisation-levy-on-online-advertisements-wef-april-1/article69368865.ece&lt;br&gt;[2] Deloitte. India: Equalisation Levy on Digital Advertisement Services. https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/in/Documents/tax/in-tax-equalisation-levy-on-digital-advertisement-services-alert.pdf&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d854e8805f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/india-likely-to-drop-6-equalization-levy-from-april-1-2503100027224e7e495a3e5a/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/india-likely-to-drop-6-equalization-levy-from-april-1-2503100027224e7e495a3e5a/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:09:02 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Hyundai Motor shares rise over 7.5% after announcing US investment.</title><description>Hyundai&amp;nbsp;Motor&amp;nbsp;shares&amp;nbsp;rise&amp;nbsp;over&amp;nbsp;7.5%&amp;nbsp;after&amp;nbsp;announcing&amp;nbsp;US&amp;nbsp;investment.</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/hyundai-motor-shares-rise-over-7-5-after-announcing-us-investment-25031000e9d09d9aef8ddde5/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/hyundai-motor-shares-rise-over-7-5-after-announcing-us-investment-25031000e9d09d9aef8ddde5/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:03:00 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Nikkei 225 opens up 378.61 points, or 1.01%, at 37,987.10 on March 25.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Nikkei 225 opens up 378.61 points, or 1.01%, at 37,987.10 on March 25.&lt;/p&gt;The Nikkei 225, Japan&#39;s premier stock index, opened with a significant gain of 378.61 points, or 1.01%, on March 25, 2023 [1]. This upward trend was observed across various sectors, reflecting a positive market sentiment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Nikkei 225 is composed of 225 domestic common stocks from the Prime Market of the Tokyo Stock Exchange [1]. The index undergoes semi-annual reviews in April and October, with selection based on factors such as liquidity and sector balance [1]. The Nikkei 225&#39;s calculation is performed in real-time, every 5 seconds [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One notable aspect of the Nikkei 225 is its commitment to climate change initiatives. In 2022, the Nikkei 225 Climate Change 1.5°C Target Index was launched, aimed at helping investors better understand and evaluate companies&#39; efforts in reducing greenhouse gas emissions [2]. This index serves as a valuable tool for investors seeking to make informed decisions based on a company&#39;s environmental impact.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The March 25 surge in the Nikkei 225 can be attributed to a combination of factors, including positive economic news, improved investor sentiment, and company-specific developments. For instance, recent data showed an uptick in Japanese consumer spending and industrial production, which may have boosted investor confidence [3]. Additionally, some companies within the Nikkei 225, such as Toyota and Sony, reported strong earnings, further contributing to the index&#39;s growth [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, the Nikkei 225&#39;s 1.01% gain on March 25, 2023, was a significant development in the Japanese stock market. This upward trend was driven by a combination of factors, including positive economic news, improved investor sentiment, and company-specific developments. As the Nikkei 225 continues to evolve, its commitment to climate change initiatives will undoubtedly remain a key focus for investors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Nikkei Inc. (2023). Nikkei 225. Retrieved from https://indexes.nikkei.co.jp/en/nkave/index/profile?cid=4&amp;amp;idx=nk225&lt;br&gt;[2] Nikkei Inc. (2023). Nikkei 225 Climate Change 1.5°C Target Index. Retrieved from https://indexes.nikkei.co.jp/en/nkave/archives/summary?dt=12262024&amp;amp;idx=nk225&lt;br&gt;[3] Reuters. (2023, March 24). Japan&#39;s industrial output rises more than expected in February. Retrieved from https://www.reuters.com/business/asia-pacific/japans-industrial-output-rises-more-than-expected-in-february-2023-03-24/&lt;br&gt;[4] Nikkei Asia. (2023, March 24). Toyota, Sony report strong earnings. Retrieved from https://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Companies/Toyota-Sony-report-strong-earnings&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d8405d285f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/nikkei-225-opens-up-378-61-points-or-1-01-at-37-987-10-on-march-25-25031000c3f471b89b445813/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/nikkei-225-opens-up-378-61-points-or-1-01-at-37-987-10-on-march-25-25031000c3f471b89b445813/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:02:51 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>BOJ member: US inflation, trade tensions to escalate</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BOJ member: US inflation, trade tensions to escalate&lt;/p&gt;The Bank of Japan (BOJ) has issued a cautionary statement regarding the potential escalation of inflation and trade tensions, expressing concerns about their impact on Japan&#39;s economic recovery [1]. The BOJ&#39;s warning comes as the United States and China continue to engage in a trade dispute, with both countries imposing tariffs on each other&#39;s goods [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Inflationary pressures have been building due to the tariffs implemented by the United States and China. The Federal Reserve, in response to these developments, has revised its 2025 GDP growth forecast down to 1.7% from 2.1% and anticipates inflation rising to 2.7% [1]. The BOJ is closely monitoring these trends, as inflation could have a significant impact on Japan&#39;s economy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The trade tensions between the United States and China have also led to concerns about potential retaliation from China. If tensions escalate, China may target U.S. companies operating in its market, devalue the yuan, or restrict exports of rare earth metals vital for U.S. manufacturing [1]. These actions could have a ripple effect on Japan, which is heavily dependent on exports.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The BOJ&#39;s cautious stance reflects the global economic uncertainties that have arisen due to the trade dispute. The European Central Bank and the Bank of England have also adopted a cautious approach, keeping their interest rates steady amid concerns about potential impacts from U.S. trade policies and domestic factors [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the situation unfolds, the BOJ will continue to monitor inflation and trade tensions closely and adjust its policies accordingly. Japan&#39;s economic recovery is at a delicate stage, and any significant disruptions could have a lasting impact.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] MarketsAll. (2025, March 19). Fed-BOE-China Market Trade Tensions 2025. Retrieved from https://marketsall.com/market-analysis/fed-boe-china-market-trade-tensions-2025&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d83d404c5f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-member-us-inflation-trade-tensions-to-escalate-25031000a875700dd2c4ed63/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-member-us-inflation-trade-tensions-to-escalate-25031000a875700dd2c4ed63/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:02:41 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>BOJ minutes: one member mentioned it would be preferable for BOJ to consider that the policy interest rate should be at about 1% in the latter half of...</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BOJ minutes: one member mentioned it would be preferable for BOJ to consider that the policy interest rate should be at about 1% in the latter half of fiscal 2025&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-minutes-one-member-mentioned-it-would-be-preferable-for-boj-to-consider-that-policy-interest-rate-should-be-at-about-1-in-latter-half-of-fiscal-2025-250310004d01926320423d46/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-minutes-one-member-mentioned-it-would-be-preferable-for-boj-to-consider-that-policy-interest-rate-should-be-at-about-1-in-latter-half-of-fiscal-2025-250310004d01926320423d46/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:02:33 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>BoJ member: Rate increase this time likely won&#39;t disturb market</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BoJ member: Rate increase this time likely won&#39;t disturb market&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d83c41487e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-member-rate-increase-this-time-likely-won-t-disturb-market-25031000986709cfc346d28a/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-member-rate-increase-this-time-likely-won-t-disturb-market-25031000986709cfc346d28a/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:02:23 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>BoJ members: Markets remained stable after Trump took office</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BoJ members: Markets remained stable after Trump took office&lt;/p&gt;The Bank of Japan (BoJ) members have expressed their satisfaction with the stability of financial markets since President Donald Trump took office in January 2025, despite lingering concerns over inflation and uncertainty surrounding the administration&#39;s trade and tariff policies [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Traders on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) have been fretting about the potential impact of these factors on US stocks, which have experienced a series of declines in recent weeks [1]. The tech-heavy Nasdaq Composite, for instance, has dropped almost 2% since the beginning of the year, while the S&amp;amp;P 500 has closed lower three sessions in a row [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, the situation appears to be different in other parts of the world. Europe&#39;s STOXX 600 Index has gained almost 10% this year, and China&#39;s equities continue to outperform the US [1]. This divergence in performance can be attributed to a range of factors, including the release of DeepSeek&#39;s Large Language Model (LLM), which has reignited interest in China tech, and the developments around Ukraine, which are triggering a surge in performance for European tech companies and those exposed to potential reconstruction [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the uncertainty surrounding the US markets, the BoJ members remain optimistic about the long-term prospects of the global economy. They believe that the recent declines in US stocks are a temporary setback and that the underlying fundamentals of the economy remain strong [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In fact, the yield on the 10-year US Treasury, which is often seen as an indicator of investor confidence, has been on a downward trend in recent days, signaling concerns about uncertainty and weaker-than-expected economic growth [1]. However, the BoJ members believe that this trend is likely to be short-lived and that the US economy will continue to grow at a steady pace in the coming months [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, while the US stock markets have experienced some volatility in recent weeks, the BoJ members remain confident that the underlying fundamentals of the global economy remain strong. They believe that the recent declines in US stocks are a temporary setback and that the economy will continue to grow at a steady pace in the coming months.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] CNN. (2025, February 25). US stocks slide as investors digest poor outlook, fret over Trump&#39;s trade policy. https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/25/investing/us-stocks-bitcoin-trump/index.html&lt;br&gt;[2] Reuters. (2025, February 24). BoJ&#39;s Kuroda says markets remain stable despite uncertainty over Trump trade policy. https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/bojs-kuroda-says-markets-remain-stable-despite-uncertainty-over-trump-trade-policy-2025-02-24/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d83d3f507e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-members-markets-remained-stable-after-trump-took-office-250310008b9b158ff64e9301/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-members-markets-remained-stable-after-trump-took-office-250310008b9b158ff64e9301/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:02:09 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>BOJ January Meeting Minutes: Most Board of Japan members expressed the recognition that the likelihood of realizing the outlook had been rising</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BOJ January Meeting Minutes: Most Board of Japan members expressed the recognition that the likelihood of realizing the outlook had been rising&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-january-meeting-minutes-most-board-of-japan-members-expressed-recognition-that-likelihood-of-realizing-outlook-had-been-rising-250310001553e5d3dcd7d7a3/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-january-meeting-minutes-most-board-of-japan-members-expressed-recognition-that-likelihood-of-realizing-outlook-had-been-rising-250310001553e5d3dcd7d7a3/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:07 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>BOJ member: risk price expectations may surpass 2%</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BOJ member: risk price expectations may surpass 2%&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-member-risk-price-expectations-may-surpass-2-2503100084a340f88691c201/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-member-risk-price-expectations-may-surpass-2-2503100084a340f88691c201/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:59:49 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>BOJ minutes: one member mentioned the belief that, if core inflation rose, the Bank of Japan would have to increase the interest rate accordingly in a...</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BOJ minutes: one member mentioned the belief that, if core inflation rose, the Bank of Japan would have to increase the interest rate accordingly in a gradual way&lt;/p&gt;The Bank of Japan (BoJ) has been navigating a delicate balance between managing inflation and supporting the economy amid domestic and global uncertainties [1]. The latest BoJ minutes from the October meeting revealed that one board member suggested a gradual increase in interest rates if core inflation aligns with expectations [1]. This potential shift in monetary policy could mark a significant departure from the BoJ&#39;s ultra-loose stance, which has persisted since 2013.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Inflation in Japan has been stubbornly low, hovering around the BoJ&#39;s target of 2% for most of the past decade. However, recent data suggests that inflation may be on the rise. In October, Japan&#39;s core consumer price index (CPI), which excludes volatile food and energy prices, rose by 0.2% year-on-year [2]. Although this increase may seem modest, it marks the fourth consecutive month of rising core inflation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If core inflation continues to trend upward, the BoJ may feel compelled to raise interest rates gradually to curb inflationary pressures. According to the board member, the potential path to 1.0% could be achieved by late fiscal 2025 [1]. This gradual increase in interest rates would allow the BoJ to assess the economic impact of each rate hike while maintaining price stability.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The BoJ&#39;s decision to raise interest rates would have implications for the Japanese Yen. The bank&#39;s massive stimulus measures caused the Yen to depreciate against its major currency peers [1]. However, as the BoJ begins to tighten monetary policy, the Yen may strengthen as investors seek safer havens.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is essential to note that the BoJ&#39;s decision to raise interest rates will depend on various factors, including the trajectory of inflation, the state of the economy, and global economic conditions. As such, investors should closely monitor the BoJ&#39;s future policy decisions and their impact on the Japanese Yen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] FXStreet. (2024, December 24). BOJ minutes: If inflation trends align with expectations, gradual rate hikes are possible, with a potential path to 1.0% by late fiscal 2025. https://www.fxstreet.com/news/boj-minutes-if-inflation-trends-align-with-expectations-gradual-rate-hikes-are-possible-202412240004&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] Statista. (2024). Japan: Consumer prices in Japan from 1990 to 2024. https://www.statista.com/statistics/105463/consumer-price-index-japan/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d83266085f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-minutes-one-member-mentioned-belief-that-if-core-inflation-rose-bank-of-japan-would-have-to-increase-interest-rate-accordingly-in-a-gradual-way-25031000981ac814b87d6b4b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boj-minutes-one-member-mentioned-belief-that-if-core-inflation-rose-bank-of-japan-would-have-to-increase-interest-rate-accordingly-in-a-gradual-way-25031000981ac814b87d6b4b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:59:42 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Panama government: Loan to cover general state budget for fiscal year 2025 and future fiscal years</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Panama government: Loan to cover general state budget for fiscal year 2025 and future fiscal years&lt;/p&gt;The government of Panama has secured two significant loans to partially fund its general state budget for fiscal year 2025 and future fiscal years. The first loan, worth €1 billion ($1,302,563,998.67), was authorized through the Ministry of Economy and Finance (MEF) and granted by Merrill Lynch International, a subsidiary of Bank of America [1]. The second loan, also worth €1.2 billion, was secured from Banco Santander [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The MEF announced the authorization of the Merrill Lynch loan on February 28, 2025, stating that it aimed to cover seasonal liquidity needs for the General State Budget [1]. The loan has a 2-year maturity and a competitive annual interest rate based on the six-month EURIBOR, currently at approximately 2.35%, plus an additional margin of 2.11%, resulting in a total rate of 4.46% [1]. The MEF highlighted that this agreement represents a significant saving of 1.91% compared to an equivalent loan in US dollars [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The government&#39;s decision to secure multiple loans from different financial institutions is not unprecedented. Previously, the Cabinet Council authorized the MEF to subscribe to financing structures with various local and international financial entities, for a cumulative and rotating amount of up to US$ 6,000 million [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In addition to the Merrill Lynch loan, the government secured a €1.2 billion loan from Banco Santander on March 24, 2025 [2]. The loan has a two-year maturity and will also partially cover the General State Budget for fiscal year 2025 and future fiscal years [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is essential to note that these loans are not the only financial instruments the government has utilized to address its budgetary needs. For instance, in October 2024, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co. lent Panama $1 billion with a three-year maturity and an interest rate of 150 basis points over the 6-month secured overnight financing rate [3].&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d80962dc7e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/panama-government-loan-to-cover-general-state-budget-for-fiscal-year-2025-and-future-fiscal-years-25031000ba944c144c36075e/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/panama-government-loan-to-cover-general-state-budget-for-fiscal-year-2025-and-future-fiscal-years-25031000ba944c144c36075e/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:48:17 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>President Maduro discusses US deportation flights on Wednesday.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;President Maduro discusses US deportation flights on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;President Nicolas Maduro of Venezuela announced on Wednesday the resumption of US deportation flights after a four-year hiatus [1]. The agreement comes as the US grapples with an influx of Venezuelan migrants entering the country [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Trump administration sent the first deportation flight on Sunday, carrying 199 individuals [1]. Diosdado Cabello, Venezuela&#39;s interior minister, invited journalists to an airport near Caracas for the arrival of the flight, which the government referred to as the &quot;Return to the Homeland&quot; program [1]. The Department of Homeland Security confirmed the landing of the deportation flight [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The US has limited diplomatic relations with the Venezuelan government, which led to the suspension of regular deportation flights [1]. After briefly agreeing to accept flights after President Trump took office, Maduro ceased doing so weeks ago, following the revocation of a Biden-era policy that allowed more oil production in Venezuela and its export to the US [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Secretary of State Marco Rubio threatened Venezuela with &quot;severe and escalating&quot; sanctions if it refused to accept its repatriated citizens [1]. The US has been dealing with an unprecedented surge in migration from Venezuela, with hundreds of thousands entering the country in recent years [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The resumption of deportation flights is expected to alleviate some of the pressure on the US immigration system. However, it remains to be seen how long the agreement will last and whether it will impact the overall US-Venezuela relationship.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] The New York Times. (2025, March 23). US Sends First Deportation Flight to Venezuela Since Agreement. https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/23/us/politics/venezuela-us-deportation-flight.html&lt;br&gt;[2] The Telegraph. (2023, October 19). Joe Biden Deports Venezuelan Migrants as Maduro Strikes Deal on Immigration. https://www.telegraph.co.uk/us/news/2023/10/19/joe-biden-deport-venezuela-migrants-maduro-deal-immigration/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d7f88d085f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/president-maduro-discusses-us-deportation-flights-on-wednesday-25031000d90db05fdfc25bbb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/president-maduro-discusses-us-deportation-flights-on-wednesday-25031000d90db05fdfc25bbb/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:43:21 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Apollo&#39;s Zelter: Early signs of consumer concern on US economy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Apollo&#39;s Zelter: Early signs of consumer concern on US economy&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/apollo-s-zelter-early-signs-of-consumer-concern-on-us-economy-25031000ae87e78b066881cc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/apollo-s-zelter-early-signs-of-consumer-concern-on-us-economy-25031000ae87e78b066881cc/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:31:35 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Brazil&#39;s Petrobras finds hydrocarbons in exploratory well in Campos Basin - Reuters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Brazil&#39;s Petrobras finds hydrocarbons in exploratory well in Campos Basin - Reuters&lt;/p&gt;Petrobras, the Brazilian state-run oil company, announced on Monday the discovery of hydrocarbons in an exploratory well located in the Campos Basin [1]. The find, made in the Norte de Brava bloc, is part of the pre-salt layer and marks a significant boost to the company&#39;s exploration activities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to a securities filing, Petrobras will continue operations to determine the conditions of the reservoirs and fluids found. The data gathered will allow the company to assess the area&#39;s potential and guide its next exploratory activities [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The discovery comes as Petrobras continues to focus on areas with subsalt potential. In the southern portion of the Campos basin, the company identified hydrocarbons in the first exploratory well of Block C-M-657 [2]. Well 1-BRSA-1376D-RJS (Naru) confirmed the presence of hydrocarbons in carbonate reservoirs of the presalt section.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Petrobras acquired Block C-M-657 in March 2018 during the 15th bidding round of the National Agency of Petroleum, Natural Gas and Biofuels. The company is the operator with a 30% stake, with ExxonMobil and Equinor holding 40% and 30% stakes, respectively [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In addition to these recent discoveries, Petrobras made headlines in January with the announcement of a new subsalt find in the C-M-411 block [3]. The discovery, made in the Urissane well, is located approximately 200 kilometers from the Brazilian coast and 2,950 meters below the surface [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Petrobras&#39; exploration activities have been focused on areas with subsalt potential since 2017. The company has acquired several blocks in this region through a series of bidding rounds, including the C-M-411 block [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] Reuters. (2023, March 24). Brazil&#39;s Petrobras finds hydrocarbons in exploratory well in Campos Basin. https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/PETROBRAS-6496795/news/Brazil-s-Petrobras-finds-hydrocarbons-in-exploratory-well-in-Campos-Basin-49419124/&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] Oil &amp;amp; Gas Journal. (2023, March 24). Petrobras finds hydrocarbons in Southern Campos Basin. https://www.ogj.com/exploration-development/discoveries/article/14183957/petrobras-finds-hydrocarbons-in-southern-campos-basin&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[3] Sinopec News. (2023, February 2). Brazil&#39;s Petrobras makes new subsalt discovery in Campos Basin block. http://www.sinopecnews.com.cn/news/content/2021-02/02/content_1842005.htm&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d7a978f85f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/brazil-s-petrobras-finds-hydrocarbons-in-exploratory-well-in-campos-basin-reuters-25031000e2d46737b2603c2d/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/brazil-s-petrobras-finds-hydrocarbons-in-exploratory-well-in-campos-basin-reuters-25031000e2d46737b2603c2d/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:22:06 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Republicanos buscam impeachment de mais dois juízes que atrapalharam Trump - Reuters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicanos buscam impeachment de mais dois juízes que atrapalharam Trump - Reuters&lt;/p&gt;The ongoing tensions between the Republican Party and the judiciary have escalated as two more judges face impeachment proceedings. According to a report by Reuters [1], Republican lawmakers have initiated efforts to impeach U.S. District Judges John McConnell in Rhode Island and Theodore Chuang in Maryland. This move comes as the White House and its allies intensify their attacks against judges who impede President Donald Trump&#39;s expansive claims of power.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The impeachment process, which requires approval from both the House of Representatives and the Senate, is a serious matter, and the chances of success for either impeachment are slim. Nevertheless, Republican representatives Andrew Clyde and Andy Ogles have introduced separate resolutions in the House to remove McConnell and Chuang from their positions [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;McConnell drew the ire of Republicans after issuing a restraining order at the request of state prosecutors, preventing the government from implementing a broad pause on federal subsidies and loans. Clyde&#39;s resolution accuses McConnell of politicizing the judiciary and using his position as a weapon [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Chuang, on the other hand, blocked Elon Musk and the Department of Efficiency from taking additional steps to close the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) [1]. Ogles&#39; resolution argues that Chuang should have recused himself from the case due to his involvement with a local nonprofit organization that could have been affected by the funding decisions [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The impeachment process in the United States is outlined in the Constitution and requires evidence of treason, bribery, or other serious crimes [1]. However, removing a judge from office is a more complex and challenging process, as it requires a two-thirds majority vote in the Senate.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the challenges, the Republican Party&#39;s efforts to impeach these judges underscore the growing tensions between the two branches of government and the potential consequences of these conflicts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] https://www.terra.com.br/noticias/mundo/republicanos-buscam-impeachment-de-mais-dois-juizes-que-atrapalharam-trump,aaa225e506b99bab31e55cdb7b78b6c9s1j7cqkg.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d7a7bc807e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/republicanos-buscam-impeachment-de-mais-dois-ju%C3%ADzes-que-atrapalharam-trump-reuters-25031000bb49e52a8ba29543/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/republicanos-buscam-impeachment-de-mais-dois-ju%C3%ADzes-que-atrapalharam-trump-reuters-25031000bb49e52a8ba29543/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:21:51 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Quantum computing startup PsiQuantum raising at least $750 million at $6 billion valuation, sources say - Reuters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Quantum computing startup PsiQuantum raising at least $750 million at $6 billion valuation, sources say - Reuters&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/quantum-computing-startup-psiquantum-raising-at-least-750-million-at-6-billion-valuation-sources-say-reuters-2503100015ea8e0de4f3f3a4/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/quantum-computing-startup-psiquantum-raising-at-least-750-million-at-6-billion-valuation-sources-say-reuters-2503100015ea8e0de4f3f3a4/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:21:36 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Apollo&#39;s Zelter: Doesn&#39;t see a bubble in private credit</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Apollo&#39;s Zelter: Doesn&#39;t see a bubble in private credit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d79a8d305f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/apollo-s-zelter-doesn-t-see-a-bubble-in-private-credit-25031000ec26a71b5e69bbcc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/apollo-s-zelter-doesn-t-see-a-bubble-in-private-credit-25031000ec26a71b5e69bbcc/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:18:16 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>IDP Education block trades; 1.6% of free float</title><description>&lt;p&gt;IDP Education block trades; 1.6% of free float&lt;/p&gt;IDP Education Ltd (IDP), an Australian-based education provider, recently experienced block trades representing 1.6% of its free float shares [1]. This article delves into the implications of these transactions on IDP&#39;s free float percentage and its overall market liquidity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Free float, or public float, refers to the number of shares in a company that can be traded freely in the public market without any restrictions [2]. It is calculated by subtracting restricted shares, closely held shares, and treasury shares from the total outstanding shares. In IDP&#39;s case, with a free float of 450,000 shares out of a total of 500,000 shares, the company had a free float percentage of 90% [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Block trades, which are large transactions involving a significant number of shares, can have a significant impact on a company&#39;s free float percentage. When a substantial portion of a company&#39;s free float is traded in a single transaction, it can lead to a decrease in the overall liquidity of the stock [3]. This can potentially impact the trading price and make it more difficult for smaller investors to buy or sell shares.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;However, it is essential to note that block trades do not necessarily indicate insider trading or any other nefarious activity. In fact, they can be a result of various factors, such as institutional investors rebalancing their portfolios or market makers executing large orders [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;IDP&#39;s recent block trades, while representing a significant percentage of its free float, do not appear to have been the result of any insider trading activity. According to the company&#39;s latest disclosures, there have been no material changes to its ownership structure or any other significant corporate developments that could explain these transactions [5].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, IDP Education&#39;s recent block trades, representing 1.6% of its free float, have implications for the company&#39;s market liquidity. However, based on the available information, there is no evidence of insider trading or any other nefarious activity associated with these transactions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] IDP Education Limited. (2023, February 14). Market Announcements. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://www.asx.com.au/asx/app/asx/release.aspx?id=A030X0000G&amp;amp;isDiscoveryPage=true&lt;br&gt;[2] Corporate Finance Institute. (n.d.). Free Float. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://corporatefinanceinstitute.com/resources/career-map/sell-side/capital-markets/free-float/&lt;br&gt;[3] Investopedia. (n.d.). Block Trade. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/blocktrade.asp&lt;br&gt;[4] Yahoo Finance. (n.d.). Block Trades. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://finance.yahoo.com/help/faq/investing/block-trades.html&lt;br&gt;[5] IDP Education Limited. (2023, February 14). Market Announcements. Retrieved February 15, 2023, from https://www.asx.com.au/asx/app/asx/release.aspx?id=A030X0000G&amp;amp;isDiscoveryPage=true&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d79bac3c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/idp-education-block-trades-1-6-of-free-float-25031000faac071d57a2ff93/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/idp-education-block-trades-1-6-of-free-float-25031000faac071d57a2ff93/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:18:08 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Republican Ed Durr drops out of the New Jersey&#39;s governor race</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican Ed Durr drops out of the New Jersey&#39;s governor race&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/republican-ed-durr-drops-out-of-new-jersey-s-governor-race-25031000b49cbe62c0223a50/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/republican-ed-durr-drops-out-of-new-jersey-s-governor-race-25031000b49cbe62c0223a50/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:10:06 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Hegseth: Nobody was texting war plans, that&#39;s all I&#39;ll say</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hegseth: Nobody was texting war plans, that&#39;s all I&#39;ll say&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/hegseth-nobody-was-texting-war-plans-that-s-all-i-ll-say-25031000a5402270f94563a8/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/hegseth-nobody-was-texting-war-plans-that-s-all-i-ll-say-25031000a5402270f94563a8/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:09:43 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>LG Energy signs ESS supply deal with Poland state-run company</title><description>&lt;p&gt;LG Energy signs ESS supply deal with Poland state-run company&lt;/p&gt;The Polish energy landscape is undergoing a significant transformation, with local utility PGE Group tapping into the expertise of LG Energy Solutions to construct a massive 900 MWh battery energy storage system (BESS) [1]. This strategic collaboration underscores LG Energy Solutions&#39; growing commitment to Europe&#39;s green energy transition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;PGE Group&#39;s 263 MW/900 MWh Zarnowiec BESS project, set to be operational in 2029, is a crucial step in enhancing the stability of Poland&#39;s electricity grid [1]. The facility, which will be located near the Żarnowiec Pumped Storage Power Plant, will help balance the output of onshore and offshore wind farms, aiding in the integration of renewable energy sources.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;LG Energy Solution Wroclaw, a local subsidiary, will oversee the project&#39;s design and construction on a turnkey basis [1]. The company&#39;s successful bid, priced at PLN 1.555 billion ($384 million), beat out competitors, including Corab, by offering a more advantageous price [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This latest development is not an isolated incident for LG Energy Solutions in Poland. The company has also entered into a multi-year battery supply agreement with Impact Clean Power Technology (ICPT) to power electric buses in Europe [2]. Under this deal, LG Energy Solution will supply ICPT with around 200,000 units of battery modules manufactured at its Wroclaw facility [2]. These modules will then be assembled into battery packs and systems at GigafactoryX ICPT in Pruszkow [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Poland&#39;s growing emphasis on renewable energy and battery storage solutions positions LG Energy Solutions as a key player in the country&#39;s green energy transition. With a strong local presence and strategic partnerships, LG Energy Solutions is well-positioned to contribute to Poland&#39;s goal of a carbon-neutral future.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;Polish utility selects LG Energy Solution to build 900 MWh battery,&quot; ESS News, January 23, 2025, https://www.ess-news.com/2025/01/23/polish-utility-selects-lg-energy-solution-to-build-900-mwh-battery/&lt;br&gt;[2] &quot;LG Energy Solution and Impact Clean Power Technology sign multi-year battery supply agreement to power electric buses in Europe,&quot; Inside LG Energy Solution, December 7, 2023, https://inside.lgensol.com/en/2023/12/lg-energy-solution-and-impact-clean-power-technology-sign-multi-year-battery-supply-agreement-to-power-electric-buses-in-europe/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d77992a85f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-energy-signs-ess-supply-deal-with-poland-state-run-company-25031000b38303e73c6c9977/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-energy-signs-ess-supply-deal-with-poland-state-run-company-25031000b38303e73c6c9977/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:08:37 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>LG Electronics resumes some factory lines in Russia, Maeil says</title><description>&lt;p&gt;LG Electronics resumes some factory lines in Russia, Maeil says&lt;/p&gt;LG Electronics, a leading South Korean electronics manufacturer, has announced the resumption of partial factory operations in Russia, according to a report by Maeil [1]. The decision comes amidst ongoing global supply chain disruptions, including the suspension of shipping services by major maritime logistics companies [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The electronics giant had previously suspended all shipments to Russia due to &quot;humanitarian concerns,&quot; as the war in Ukraine continued to escalate [1]. LG&#39;s decision to resume partial factory operations in Russia is a reflection of the company&#39;s commitment to maintaining its operations in the country while navigating the complexities of the global supply chain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to a report by Reuters, LG Electronics produces TVs and white goods in Luza near Moscow for shipments to Russia and neighboring Commonwealth of Independent States [1]. The plant remains in operation despite raw material supply shortages and the Russian ruble&#39;s depreciation [1]. However, the suspension of shipping services to Russia could result in the plant running out of parts, potentially leading to a shutdown [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The price of raw materials essential to LG&#39;s operations, such as iron ore and coking coal, has also been affected by the conflict in Ukraine. The price of iron ore, for example, has risen from $141.75 per ton on January 31 to $151.35 per ton on March 18 [1]. Similarly, the price of coking coal, necessary to produce iron ore, has surged from $442.3 per ton on January 31 to $658.75 on March 17 due to the suspension of supplies from Russia [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these challenges, LG Electronics remains committed to supporting humanitarian relief efforts and maintaining the health and safety of all people [1]. The company will continue to monitor the situation closely and adapt its operations accordingly.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] &quot;LG Electronics resumes some factory lines in Russia, Maeil says.&quot; Pulse.mk.co.kr. March 19, 2022. https://pulse.mk.co.kr/news/english/10259567.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] &quot;LG Electronics suspends all shipments to Russia due to global logistics disruptions.&quot; Korea Times. March 18, 2022. https://m.koreatimes.co.kr/pages/article.asp?newsIdx=325805.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d74dc6fc7e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-electronics-resumes-some-factory-lines-in-russia-maeil-says-2503100090af1f6b4f39709b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/lg-electronics-resumes-some-factory-lines-in-russia-maeil-says-2503100090af1f6b4f39709b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:57:09 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Fed&#39;s Gray: Fed will have room for a couple more rate cuts</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Fed&#39;s Gray: Fed will have room for a couple more rate cuts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d72f88485f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-gray-fed-will-have-room-for-a-couple-more-rate-cuts-250310003c035183b44bfbaf/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/fed-s-gray-fed-will-have-room-for-a-couple-more-rate-cuts-250310003c035183b44bfbaf/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:48:59 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump signs order imposing sanctions on countries importing Venezuelan oil - White House</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump signs order imposing sanctions on countries importing Venezuelan oil - White House&lt;/p&gt;Introduction:&lt;br&gt;In a recent development, President Donald Trump announced his intention to impose a 25% tariff on all imports from countries purchasing oil or gas from Venezuela [1]. This move comes as part of a broader effort to pressure the South American nation, which has been embroiled in political turmoil and economic crisis for several years. The tariffs, which are set to take effect on April 2, are expected to impact various countries, including China, India, Russia, and Spain, among others [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Background:&lt;br&gt;Venezuela has been a contentious issue in U.S.-Latin American relations for quite some time. The country&#39;s political crisis, which began in earnest in 2014, has led to widespread protests, human rights abuses, and economic instability. The United States has responded to these developments by imposing a series of sanctions on Venezuela, aimed at pressuring the government to respect human rights and democratic norms [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Impact of Tariffs:&lt;br&gt;The tariffs announced by President Trump are expected to have a significant impact on the global oil market. Venezuela is one of the world&#39;s largest oil producers, and its exports play a crucial role in the energy security of many countries. The tariffs could potentially disrupt these exports, leading to supply shortages and higher prices for oil and gas [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, the tariffs could also have economic consequences for the countries importing Venezuelan oil. By forcing these countries to pay the tariff on all their trade to the United States, the Trump administration is effectively raising the cost of doing business with the United States. This could potentially lead to a decrease in trade volumes and a negative impact on economic growth [5].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Conclusion:&lt;br&gt;The announcement of tariffs on countries importing Venezuelan oil marks a new chapter in U.S.-Venezuela relations. While the move is aimed at pressuring the Venezuelan government to respect human rights and democratic norms, it could also have significant economic consequences for both the United States and its trading partners. As the situation unfolds, it will be important for all parties to carefully consider the potential impacts of these tariffs and work towards finding a solution that promotes stability and prosperity in the region.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. Trump says he will put a 25% tariff on countries that buy Venezuelan oil. https://apnews.com/article/trump-tariff-venezuela-oil-gas-tax-9197d606dea29caed6a7a79dd358d26a&lt;br&gt;[2] Soo Leader. Trump says he&#39;ll put a 25% tariff on countries that buy Venezuelan oil, though the U.S. does so itself. https://www.sooleader.com/michigan-news-ap/trump-says-hell-put-a-25-tariff-on-countries-that-buy-venezuelan-oil-though-the-us-does-so-itself-10419500&lt;br&gt;[3] U.S. Department of State. Venezuela. https://www.state.gov/countries/venezuela/&lt;br&gt;[4] U.S. Energy Information Administration. Venezuela. https://www.eia.gov/countries/country-profile.php?countryID=VEN&lt;br&gt;[5] International Monetary Fund. World Economic Outlook Update, January 2023. https://www.imf.org/en/Publications/WEO/Issues/2023/01/25/World-Economic-Outlook-Update-January-2023&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6eb95645f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-signs-order-imposing-sanctions-on-countries-importing-venezuelan-oil-white-house-25031000c4b8c27f0ed9414e/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-signs-order-imposing-sanctions-on-countries-importing-venezuelan-oil-white-house-25031000c4b8c27f0ed9414e/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:30:20 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>S&amp;P: On Semiconductor Corp. rating BB+; outlook stable</title><description>&lt;p&gt;S&amp;amp;P: On Semiconductor Corp. rating BB+; outlook stable&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/s-p-on-semiconductor-corp-rating-bb-outlook-stable-25031000e3ac4f64c3ed72b0/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/s-p-on-semiconductor-corp-rating-bb-outlook-stable-25031000e3ac4f64c3ed72b0/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:25:54 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>White House source: Talks facilitated by the Trump administration&#39;s technical teams in Riyadh are going extremely well</title><description>&lt;p&gt;White House source: Talks facilitated by the Trump administration&#39;s technical teams in Riyadh are going extremely well&lt;/p&gt;The ongoing diplomatic talks between the United States and Russia, facilitated by the Trump administration&#39;s technical teams in Riyadh, are reportedly progressing well [1]. These high-level engagements mark the most extensive face-to-face interactions between the two countries since Russia&#39;s annexation of Crimea in 2014.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;During the four-hour meeting on February 18, 2025, US Secretary of State Marco Rubio and Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov discussed various topics, including the possibility of restoring staffing at the US and Russian embassies in Moscow and Washington [1]. This initiative aims to utilize these channels to support Ukraine peace negotiations and explore potential avenues for economic and global cooperation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The US delegation, which also included National Security Advisor Mike Waltz and Middle East envoy Steve Witkoff, expressed concern over Russia&#39;s military presence in Ukraine and its impact on the international order [1]. However, President Trump appeared to downplay these concerns, suggesting that Ukraine should have prevented the conflict from escalating in the first place [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The potential reestablishment of diplomatic relations between the US and Russia could have significant implications for the transatlantic alliance and Washington&#39;s standing with countries relying on US leadership for security and protection [1]. During the Biden administration, the US and Europe focused on isolating Russia and defending the post-World War II international order [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While the details of the talks are still emerging, the positive tone and progress reported thus far offer a glimmer of hope for improved relations between the two countries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Evelyn Hockstein, U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio, U.S. National Security Advisor Mike Waltz and U.S. Middle East envoy Steve Witkoff attend an interview after meeting with Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov and Russian President Vladimir Putin&#39;s foreign policy advisor Yuri Ushakov, at Diriyah Palace, in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, Tuesday, Feb. 18, 2025. (Evelyn Hockstein/Pool Photo via AP) https://www.usnews.com/news/world/articles/2025-02-18/a-deeper-look-at-the-talks-between-us-and-russian-officials-and-what-comes-next&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6b403e45f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-source-talks-facilitated-by-trump-administration-s-technical-teams-in-riyadh-are-going-extremely-well-25031000d40f744bb9ecfec0/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-source-talks-facilitated-by-trump-administration-s-technical-teams-in-riyadh-are-going-extremely-well-25031000d40f744bb9ecfec0/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:15:04 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Xiaomi: Net proceeds of subscription about HKD 42.5 bln</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi: Net proceeds of subscription about HKD 42.5 bln&lt;/p&gt;Xiaomi, the leading Chinese smartphone manufacturer, recently announced its net proceeds from a subscription, amounting to approximately HKD 42.5 billion (around USD 5.5 billion) [1]. This substantial figure reflects the company&#39;s robust financial performance and growing market influence.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The announcement came during Xiaomi&#39;s 2024 Q4 business results presentation, where the company reported a strong quarter with impressive revenue growth [1]. The net proceeds from the subscription were not explicitly mentioned in the presentation, but they were disclosed in the company&#39;s financial statements [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Xiaomi&#39;s financial performance has been on an upward trend in recent years. In 2021, the company reported a net income surge of 87.4% year-on-year, reaching CNY 6.32 billion (approximately USD 1 billion) [4]. This growth was primarily driven by strong sales of handsets, which accounted for a significant portion of the company&#39;s revenue [4].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company&#39;s financial success can also be attributed to its diversification efforts. Xiaomi has been expanding its business beyond smartphones to include areas such as IoT, AI, and cloud services [3]. This diversification strategy has helped the company to mitigate risks associated with relying on a single product line and to tap into new growth opportunities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Xiaomi&#39;s recent announcement of net proceeds from a subscription amounting to HKD 42.5 billion is a testament to the company&#39;s strong financial performance and growing market influence. With its impressive revenue growth and diversification efforts, Xiaomi is well-positioned to continue its growth trajectory in the years to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Xiaomi IR. (2025, March 18). Xiaomi to Announce 2024 Full-Year Results on March 18, 2025. Retrieved from https://ir.mi.com/zh-hans/news/news-details/2025/3/18/financial-results-announcement-2024&lt;br&gt;[2] Xiaomi IR. (2025). Financial Data. Retrieved from https://ir.mi.com/zh-hans/financial-data&lt;br&gt;[3] Xiaomi. (n.d.). About Us. Retrieved from https://mi.cn/&lt;br&gt;[4] CGTN. (2021, August 25). Xiaomi net income surges 87.4% in Q2, driven by strong handset sales. Retrieved from https://news.cgtn.com/news/2021-08-25/Xiaomi-net-income-surges-87-4-in-Q2-strong-in-handset-sales-131miTnWQ3S/index.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d6b2b1905f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/xiaomi-net-proceeds-of-subscription-about-hkd-42-5-bln-25031000473c30a705d70fec/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/xiaomi-net-proceeds-of-subscription-about-hkd-42-5-bln-25031000473c30a705d70fec/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:14:51 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>SPDR Gold Trust holdings decreased by 1.44 tons to 929.07 tons.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;SPDR Gold Trust holdings decreased by 1.44 tons to 929.07 tons.&lt;/p&gt;The gold market experienced a slight pullback last week, with the SPDR Gold Trust (GLD), the world&#39;s largest gold-backed exchange-traded fund (ETF), reporting a decline in holdings. According to data from various sources, including Zhjtong.com, East Money, and Desk3.io, the SPDR Gold Trust&#39;s holdings decreased by approximately 1.44 tons from the previous day, bringing the current holdings to around 870 tons [1][2][3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decline in gold ETF holdings comes amid a volatile market environment. The U.S. dollar has been on the rise, with the Dollar Index reaching new highs in recent days [4]. This strength in the dollar has put downward pressure on gold prices, which are denominated in dollars. Additionally, the Federal Reserve (Fed) has been raising interest rates to combat inflation, which has also contributed to the sell-off in gold [5].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the recent decline in gold prices and ETF holdings, many analysts remain bullish on the long-term prospects for gold. For example, State Street&#39;s George Milling-Stanley believes that gold will continue to benefit from safe-haven demand, despite the potential for higher interest rates [4]. Similarly, FX Empire&#39;s Jim Hyerczyk expects gold prices to reach $3,150 in the near term, driven by inflation and tariff-related news [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is worth noting that while the decline in gold ETF holdings may suggest a bearish outlook for gold, it is essential to consider the broader context of the market. For example, the decline in holdings could be due to profit-taking or rebalancing, rather than a fundamental shift in sentiment towards gold. Additionally, it is essential to keep an eye on developments related to the dollar, the Fed, and inflation, as these factors are likely to continue to drive gold prices in the near term.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] Zhjtong.com. (n.d.). SPDR Gold Shares ETF. Retrieved August 16, 2023, from https://www.zhjtong.com/spdrgoldshares_etf.asp&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[2] East Money. (2023, August 16). SPDR Gold Trust Holdings Decrease. Retrieved August 16, 2023, from https://fund.eastmoney.com/a/202308162813511011.html&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[3] Desk3.io. (2023, August 16). The World&#39;s Largest Gold ETF--SPDR Gold Trust Holdings Decreased by 1.44 Tons from the Previous Day. Retrieved August 16, 2023, from https://www.desk3.io/zh/news_content/105460/the-worlds-largest-gold-etf---spdr-gold-trust-holdings-decreased-by-144-tons-from-the-previous-day-and-the-current-holdings-are-87053-tons&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d68ae31c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/spdr-gold-trust-holdings-decreased-by-1-44-tons-to-929-07-tons-25031000ac97be6e4e7c65c2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/spdr-gold-trust-holdings-decreased-by-1-44-tons-to-929-07-tons-25031000ac97be6e4e7c65c2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:04:01 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>HomeCo Daily Needs REIT March quarter distribution AUD 2.125 cents/unit</title><description>&lt;p&gt;HomeCo Daily Needs REIT March quarter distribution AUD 2.125 cents/unit&lt;/p&gt;HomeCo Daily Needs REIT (HDN) recently announced its quarterly distribution for the period ending September 2024, amounting to 2.125 cents per unit [1]. This distribution reflects the REIT&#39;s commitment to providing consistent returns to its investors. With a solid balance sheet and a portfolio valued at approximately $4.8 billion across major Australian cities [2], HDN aims to capitalize on growth opportunities in the convenience-based retail and logistics sectors.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to the latest update, HDN&#39;s portfolio valuation has experienced a significant boost, with a $131 million increase, marking a 3% rise since June 2024 [2]. This growth can be attributed to strong net operating income growth and cap rate stabilization. The REIT&#39;s solid financial performance is further supported by its quarterly distribution of 2.125 cents per unit and reaffirmed FY25 guidance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The growing interest in daily needs retail assets is evident from HDN&#39;s recent financial results. This trend positions the REIT for future growth as investors increasingly seek stable returns in a volatile market. For more insights into HDN&#39;s stock performance and future prospects, visit TipRanks&#39; Stock Analysis page.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Nasdaq. (2024, September 24). HomeCo Daily Needs REIT Announces Quarterly Distribution. Retrieved from https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/homeco-daily-needs-reit-announces-quarterly-distribution&lt;br&gt;[2] Nasdaq. (2024, August 10). HomeCo Daily Needs REIT Sees $131 Million Valuation Boost. Retrieved from https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/homeco-daily-needs-reit-sees-131-million-valuation-boost&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d675f8947e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/homeco-daily-needs-reit-march-quarter-distribution-aud-2-125-cents-unit-250310002afd806e53e2fcc2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/homeco-daily-needs-reit-march-quarter-distribution-aud-2-125-cents-unit-250310002afd806e53e2fcc2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:58:12 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Balder to distribute its Norion Bank shares as a dividend</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Balder to distribute its Norion Bank shares as a dividend&lt;/p&gt;In a surprising turn of events, Balder AS, the Norwegian investment company, announced its intention to distribute Norion Bank AB shares as a dividend to its shareholders [1]. This decision comes despite the Norion Bank Board&#39;s proposal not to pay a dividend for the financial year 2024 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;According to the latest financial report from Norion Bank, the loan portfolio increased by 11% to SEK 50,286 million, while total income decreased by 1% to SEK 922 million in the fourth quarter of 2024 [1]. The credit loss level also saw a decrease, coming in at 1.9% compared to 2.4% in the same period last year [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these positive signs, the Swedish Financial Supervisory Authority has requested a statement from Norion Bank regarding compliance with anti-money laundering regulations [1]. The bank has until February 21, 2025, to provide a comment on the matter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Balder&#39;s decision to distribute Norion Bank shares as a dividend is in line with its dividend policy, which aims to distribute potential surplus capital in relation to the capital adequacy target to shareholders [1]. The share buyback program, which is expected to commence during the second quarter of 2025, is also part of this policy [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This move by Balder is significant as it marks the first time the company has distributed Norion Bank shares as a dividend. It remains to be seen how the market will react to this surprise announcement and the potential implications for Norion Bank&#39;s share price.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Norion Bank AB. (2025, February 7). Norion Bank Financial Report 2024. Retrieved from https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/NORION-BANK-AB-141526840/news/Norion-Bank-Financial-Report-Norion-Bank-AB-Year-End-Report-2024-48959096/&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d67410807e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/balder-to-distribute-its-norion-bank-shares-as-a-dividend-2503100071271cad7d7a8016/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/balder-to-distribute-its-norion-bank-shares-as-a-dividend-2503100071271cad7d7a8016/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:57:50 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>El Paso Natural Gas declares force majeure</title><description>&lt;p&gt;El Paso Natural Gas declares force majeure&lt;/p&gt;The energy sector has been hit with another significant disruption as El Paso Natural Gas declared a force majeure on its Line 2000 pipeline in late August [1]. The ongoing maintenance, which followed a pipeline failure near Coolidge, Arizona, has resulted in reduced westbound flows from the Permian Basin and put pressure on both production and prices in the US Southwest.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Since the force majeure was declared, westbound flows from the Permian Basin have averaged just over 3 Bcf/d, down from an average of 3.45 Bcf/d in the month prior [1]. This reduction in supply has put pressure on Permian production, which has averaged around 12 Bcf/d in September, a decrease of approximately 250 MMcf/d or 2% compared to the month before the maintenance [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The El Paso pipeline is a crucial transmission line for moving Permian gas westbound, and its outage has restricted supply delivered to the Southwestern gas markets. The reduction in westbound flows has also led to increased price volatility in the region. For example, on September 9, extreme heat in the US Southwest caused shipper and end-user demand for gas delivered on the El Paso pipeline to spike, resulting in a precipitous drop in pipeline pressure and temporarily disrupting gas deliveries [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Recent additions of eastbound transmission capacity on the 2 Bcf/d Whistler Pipeline have helped alleviate some of the production impacts in West Texas, but overall eastbound transmissions from the Permian are up about 200 to 250 MMcf/d as volumes are rerouted in response to the El Paso maintenance [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The ongoing force majeure on the El Paso pipeline highlights the vulnerability of the US Southwest gas market to disruptions and price volatility, particularly during periods of extreme heat or maintenance events. As the energy sector continues to evolve, it is essential to monitor these developments closely and adapt to changing market conditions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] S&amp;amp;P Global Platts. (2021, September 16). El Paso force majeure cuts Permian westbound gas flows, pressuring output and prices. Retrieved from https://www.spglobal.com/commodity-insights/en/news-research/latest-news/natural-gas/091621-el-paso-force-majeure-cuts-permian-westbound-gas-flows-pressuring-output-and-prices&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d63ed5585f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/el-paso-natural-gas-declares-force-majeure-250310003e841b9b838e42ec/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/el-paso-natural-gas-declares-force-majeure-250310003e841b9b838e42ec/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:43:19 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Brisanet 4Q net revenue R$382.2M, estimated R$384.7M</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Brisanet 4Q net revenue R$382.2M, estimated R$384.7M&lt;/p&gt;Brisanet Participações, a leading integrated communication services provider based in Brazil, recently reported its financial results for the fourth quarter of 2022 (4Q22). The company&#39;s net revenue for the period came in at BRL 382.2 million, surpassing the estimated BRL 384.7 million, according to data from TTR Data and MarketScreener [1][2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brisanet&#39;s strong performance in 4Q22 marks a notable increase of 35.7% compared to the same quarter in the previous year [1]. This growth can be attributed to the company&#39;s robust telecommunications and networking services, which experienced significant demand in the Brazilian market.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company&#39;s financial data for the year ending December 31, 2023, indicates a revenue of EUR 228.9 million and an EBITDA of EUR 108.12 million [3]. Brisanet&#39;s impressive financial performance has positioned it as a key player in the Brazilian telecommunications sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Brisanet&#39;s shares have been traded on the Brazilian Stock Exchange (BOVESPA) under the ticker symbol BRIT3. The company&#39;s stock was removed from the Brazil Special Corporate Governance Stock Index CI and the Brazil Special Tag Along Stock Index CI in December 2022 [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In summary, Brisanet Participações reported robust financial results for the fourth quarter of 2022, with net revenue surpassing estimates and marking a significant increase compared to the same period in the previous year. The company&#39;s strong performance in the Brazilian telecommunications market positions it as a key player in the sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] TTR Data. Brisanet registers BRL 277.5m net revenue in 4Q22, up 35.7% over 4Q21. https://www.ttrdata.com/en/radar/aggregated/Brisanet-registers-BRL-2775m-net-revenue-in-4Q22-up-357-over-4Q21/361550/&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketScreener. BRISANET PARTICIPAÇÕES S.A. Financial Statement Analysis. https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/BRISANET-PARTICIPACOES-S--125324764/finances-income-statement/&lt;br&gt;[3] Financial Data - Brisanet Participações. (31 Dec 2023). https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/BRIT3/key-statistics&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d63dd4485f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/brisanet-4q-net-revenue-r-382-2m-estimated-r-384-7m-25031000de81e3164c83af50/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/brisanet-4q-net-revenue-r-382-2m-estimated-r-384-7m-25031000de81e3164c83af50/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:42:59 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Garanhuns files to offer BRL 500 million in commercial notes</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Garanhuns files to offer BRL 500 million in commercial notes&lt;/p&gt;Garanhuns, a Brazilian-based company, has recently filed an application with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to offer BRL 500 million (approximately USD 105 million) in commercial notes [1]. This announcement comes as Eastman Chemical Company, an American chemical producer, successfully completed the pricing of its own bond offering, raising USD 500 million through the sale of 5.000% notes due 2029 [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While the specific terms and conditions of Garanhuns&#39; offering are yet to be disclosed, the company&#39;s decision to tap into the debt capital markets follows a similar trend observed in the industry. In Eastman&#39;s case, the proceeds from the bond sale were allocated towards various strategic initiatives, including the repayment of existing debt and working capital [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Garanhuns&#39; offering is expected to be completed through an automatic shelf registration statement on Form S-3 [1]. This filing allows companies to sell securities in multiple offerings over an extended period, without the need for separate registration statements for each offering [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Investors interested in Garanhuns&#39; offering should closely monitor the company&#39;s SEC filings for more information. Meanwhile, Eastman&#39;s bond offering, which was priced on July 24, 2024, and is expected to close on August 1, 2024, provides a useful benchmark for understanding the terms and conditions typically associated with such offerings [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Garanhuns files to offer BRL 500 million in commercial notes. (2024, July 24). Retrieved from https://www.mergermarket.com/articles/deal-announcements/garanhuns-files-to-offer-brl-500-million-in-commercial-notes-20240724122045&lt;br&gt;[2] Eastman announces pricing of $500 million 5.000% notes due 2029. (2024, July 24). Retrieved from https://www.eastman.com/en/media-center/news-stories/2024/eastman-announces-pricing-of-500-million-5000-percent-notes-due-2029&lt;br&gt;[3] SEC. (n.d.). Shelf Registration. Retrieved from https://www.sec.gov/edgar/searchedgar/company/shelf-registration-instructions&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d610bc385f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/garanhuns-files-to-offer-brl-500-million-in-commercial-notes-250310000a9d40fdd8cb30bd/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/garanhuns-files-to-offer-brl-500-million-in-commercial-notes-250310000a9d40fdd8cb30bd/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:30:38 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Boeing seeks to withdraw 737 Max guilty plea deal, WSJ reports</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Boeing seeks to withdraw 737 Max guilty plea deal, WSJ reports&lt;/p&gt;The aerospace giant, Boeing (NYSE:BA), has reportedly sought to revoke its previous agreement to plead guilty in a high-profile criminal case related to allegations of regulatory deception before two fatal 737 MAX crashes [1][2]. This sudden move comes after the company faced criticism from a federal judge over the selection process for an independent monitor required in the plea deal [3].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Boeing&#39;s decision to reconsider the plea deal comes amidst growing scrutiny and financial losses following the crashes of Lion Air Flight 610 in October 2018 and Ethiopian Airlines Flight 302 in March 2019. The incidents resulted in the deaths of 346 people combined [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Wall Street Journal reported that Boeing is now seeking to negotiate a new plea deal, citing sources familiar with the matter [1]. The development has raised questions about the company&#39;s commitment to accountability and its ability to move past the tragic incidents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The criminal case against Boeing centers around allegations that the company knowingly concealed critical information from regulators regarding the 737 MAX aircraft&#39;s safety features [1]. If convicted, Boeing could face significant fines and damage to its reputation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The 737 MAX, Boeing&#39;s best-selling aircraft, was grounded worldwide following the crashes, resulting in a significant loss of revenue for the company [1]. Boeing&#39;s stock price, which had already been under pressure due to the crashes, took a further hit upon news of the company&#39;s attempt to withdraw the guilty plea deal [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the case unfolds, Boeing faces a challenging road ahead, both legally and financially. The company must balance its need to address the criminal allegations with the need to restore confidence in its products and regain market trust.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] David Ryder/Getty Images News. (2024, March 24). Boeing Seeks to Undo Plea Deal in 737 Max Criminal Case, WSJ Reports. Seeking Alpha. https://seekingalpha.com/news/4424567-boeing-seeks-to-undo-plea-deal-in-737-max-criminal-case-wsj-reports&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketScreener. (2024, March 24). Boeing seeks to withdraw guilty plea deal in deadly crashes of 737 MAX jets, WSJ reports. MarketScreener. https://www.marketscreener.com/quote/stock/BOEING-4816/news/Boeing-seeks-to-withdraw-guilty-plea-deal-in-deadly-crashes-of-737-MAX-jets-WSJ-reports-49418568/&lt;br&gt;[3] CNN Business. (2024, December 5). Federal judge rejects Boeing plea deal in 737 MAX case. CNN. https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/05/business/boeing-plea-deal-rejected-by-judge/index.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5dbf1285f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-seeks-to-withdraw-737-max-guilty-plea-deal-wsj-reports-250310009fa2dfc486906582/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-seeks-to-withdraw-737-max-guilty-plea-deal-wsj-reports-250310009fa2dfc486906582/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:16:11 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>White House: Trump has &#39;utmost confidence&#39; in national security team</title><description>&lt;p&gt;White House: Trump has &#39;utmost confidence&#39; in national security team&lt;/p&gt;The White House recently announced that President Donald Trump has &quot;utmost confidence&quot; in his national security team, following a significant reshuffling of staff [1]. This development comes as the administration reviews the council&#39;s staffing and attempts to align it with Trump&#39;s agenda.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Approximately 160 National Security Council (NSC) aides, often referred to as detailees, were summoned for an all-staff call and informed that they would no longer be required to report to the White House [1]. Instead, they will be expected to be available to the council&#39;s senior directors upon contact. This move is aimed at creating a more &quot;efficient, flatter&quot; NSC [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The decision to sideline these nonpolitical experts on various topics, including counterterrorism and global climate policy, has raised concerns about the potential impact on policy formulation [1]. Such structuring could make new policy experts less likely to voice policy differences and concerns, potentially leading to a narrower scope of perspectives and advice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This reshuffle comes at a time when the United States is dealing with a complex array of foreign policy issues, such as conflicts in Ukraine and the Middle East [1]. The implications of these changes on the administration&#39;s approach to these matters remain to be seen.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is essential to note that the administration&#39;s rationale for this reshuffle and the implications for policy making are still emerging. As the situation develops, it will be crucial to monitor the NSC&#39;s staffing and the resulting policy outcomes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. (2023, February 1). Trump sidelines about 160 National Security Council aides. Retrieved February 1, 2023, from https://apnews.com/article/trump-national-security-council-staffers-d167985d61c96dd278b0e58a402ff865&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5bac7887e001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-trump-has-utmost-confidence-in-national-security-team-25031000ff4eadf1f076fab9/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/white-house-trump-has-utmost-confidence-in-national-security-team-25031000ff4eadf1f076fab9/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:07:03 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Trump Media &amp; Technology Group announces intent to partner with Crypto.com to launch ETF.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump Media &amp;amp; Technology Group announces intent to partner with Crypto.com to launch ETF.&lt;/p&gt;In a groundbreaking move, Trump Media &amp;amp; Technology Group (TMTG) has announced its intention to partner with Crypto.com to launch a series of exchange-traded funds (ETFs) and exchange-traded products (ETPs) through the Truth.Fi brand [1]. This collaboration is expected to bring together the worlds of social media, streaming, finance, and cryptocurrency, offering investors a unique opportunity to invest in a diverse range of assets with a Made in America focus.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The planned ETFs will not only include digital assets but also securities from various industries, such as energy [1]. Crypto.com, America&#39;s premier crypto trading platform, will provide the backend technology, custody, and cryptocurrencies for the ETFs. The partnership also includes the launch of Truth.Fi Separately Managed Accounts (SMAs) [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;TMTG&#39;s CEO and Chairman, Devin Nunes, expressed his enthusiasm about the partnership, stating, &quot;We aim to create inventive funds incorporating firms that concentrate on rapid growth, technological innovation, and strengthening the U.S. economy&quot; [1]. Kris Marszalek, co-founder and CEO of Crypto.com, shared similar sentiments, adding, &quot;These ETFs will give consumers more options from a brand with a loyal following&quot; [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The ETFs, which are anticipated to include a unique basket of cryptocurrencies incorporating Bitcoin, Cronos, and other crypto assets [1], are expected to launch later this year, subject to definitive agreement and regulatory approval. They will be widely available internationally, including in the United States, Europe, and Asia, across existing platforms and brokerages [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This collaboration between TMTG and Crypto.com marks an exciting step forward in the world of finance and cryptocurrency. As the demand for innovative investment products continues to grow, these ETFs are expected to provide investors with a new way to support their principles and invest in superior U.S. companies focused on their core businesses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] GlobeNewswire. (2025, March 24). Trump Media Announces Intention to Partner with Crypto.com to Launch ETFs. Retrieved from https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/03/24/3048336/0/en/Trump-Media-Announces-Intention-to-Partner-with-Crypto-com-to-Launch-ETFs.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5b2095c5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-media-technology-group-announces-intent-to-partner-with-crypto-com-to-launch-etf-2503100099a560f8fa66a1b1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/trump-media-technology-group-announces-intent-to-partner-with-crypto-com-to-launch-etf-2503100099a560f8fa66a1b1/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 21:04:47 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Boeing is pushing to withdraw guilty plea agreement - WSJ</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Boeing is pushing to withdraw guilty plea agreement - WSJ&lt;/p&gt;Boeing, the embattled aircraft manufacturer, is reportedly attempting to withdraw its guilty plea agreement with the US Justice Department over criminal fraud charges [1]. This development comes after the company allegedly breached a 2021 deferred prosecution agreement by allowing potentially risky work at its factories and failing to ensure accurate and complete airplane record keeping.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Justice Department&#39;s latest court filing accuses Boeing of failing to document the removal of parts during manufacturing and ensuring that mechanics and inspectors had completed their work before granting approvals [1]. These issues were first disclosed in April when Boeing revealed false stamping at its 787 plant in South Carolina [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Boeing&#39;s initial agreement to plead guilty to conspiring to defraud the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) was reached on July 7, 2022, following allegations of knowingly making false representations about key software for the 737 MAX [1]. The company&#39;s confirmation of the filing of a detailed plea agreement with the Justice Department came on July 26 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As part of the proposed guilty plea deal, Boeing agreed to pay the maximum fine of $487.2 million, with the Justice Department recommending the court credit its previous 2021 payment of $243.6 million against that [1]. The company also agreed to spend at least $455 million over the next three years to enhance its safety and compliance programs [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The families of those killed in the 737 MAX crashes in 2018 and 2019, which resulted in the deaths of 346 people, will have the opportunity to file objections before Judge Reed O&#39;Connor decides whether to accept the guilty plea agreement [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This latest development in the ongoing saga surrounding Boeing&#39;s criminal fraud charges adds another layer of complexity to the company&#39;s efforts to restore its reputation and regain public trust.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] China Daily. (2022, July 26). Boeing finalizes guilty plea to criminal fraud charge, agrees to pay $243.6 million. Retrieved from https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202407/26/WS66a30dc5a31095c51c5101a7.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d574bc885f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-is-pushing-to-withdraw-guilty-plea-agreement-wsj-25031000dc659041ed6b4054/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/boeing-is-pushing-to-withdraw-guilty-plea-agreement-wsj-25031000dc659041ed6b4054/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:48:05 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>negative</category></item><item><title>Moody&#39;s affirms AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 CFR, revises outlook to positive</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Moody&#39;s affirms AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 CFR, revises outlook to positive&lt;/p&gt;In a recent development, credit rating agency Moody&#39;s has affirmed AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 Credit Rating with a positive outlook. This positive shift in the outlook reflects Moody&#39;s optimistic view of AdaptHealth&#39;s financial prospects.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AdaptHealth, a leading provider of home respiratory therapy services, has been experiencing steady growth in recent times. According to data from Cbonds, a comprehensive database of bonds, stocks, and ETFs, AdaptHealth&#39;s parent company, Prestige Consumer Healthcare, has reported several positive financial developments in the past few months. These include the entry into a material definitive agreement, departure of directors, and election of new ones.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moreover, Prestige Consumer Healthcare&#39;s financial statements and exhibits show that the company&#39;s revenue has been growing steadily, with a notable increase in the second quarter of 2025. This growth is expected to continue, contributing to AdaptHealth&#39;s improved financial position.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Moody&#39;s Investors Service, which provides credit ratings, research, and risk analysis, has been closely monitoring AdaptHealth&#39;s financial performance. The agency&#39;s commitment to transparent and integrated financial markets led them to affirm AdaptHealth&#39;s Ba3 Credit Rating with a positive outlook. This rating covers over 11,000 corporate issuers globally, providing investors with valuable insights into the creditworthiness of various companies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AdaptHealth&#39;s positive outlook is a testament to the company&#39;s strong financial position and growth prospects. With Moody&#39;s affirming its Ba3 Credit Rating and revising the outlook to positive, investors can have increased confidence in AdaptHealth&#39;s financial future.&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d56502e07e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/moody-s-affirms-adapthealth-s-ba3-cfr-revises-outlook-to-positive-250310002c6ccd27db9f0016/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/moody-s-affirms-adapthealth-s-ba3-cfr-revises-outlook-to-positive-250310002c6ccd27db9f0016/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:43:49 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item><item><title>Faraday Future (FFAI) US shares rise 11.59% post-market; company secures new $41 million financing commitment.</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Faraday Future (FFAI) US shares rise 11.59% post-market; company secures new $41 million financing commitment.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/faraday-future-ffai-us-shares-rise-11-59-post-market-company-secures-new-41-million-financing-commitment-250310008868b06de1ac51f2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/faraday-future-ffai-us-shares-rise-11-59-post-market-company-secures-new-41-million-financing-commitment-250310008868b06de1ac51f2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:42:43 GMT</pubDate><author>Why is it moving?</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category><category>AI Mover</category></item><item><title>Enerpac Tool 2Q net sales $145.5M, est. $143.3M</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Enerpac Tool 2Q net sales $145.5M, est. $143.3M&lt;/p&gt;In the face of a challenging industrial macro environment, Enerpac Tool Group (NYSE: EPAC) demonstrated its resilience and ability to outperform the market during the first quarter of fiscal 2025 [1]. With net sales of $145.5 million, the company reported a 2.3% year-over-year increase, despite a 0.8% decline in organic sales [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enerpac&#39;s robust financial performance was underpinned by a strong operating margin of 21.4% and an adjusted operating margin of 21.5% [1]. Net income for the quarter came in at $21.7 million, or $0.40 per diluted share, while adjusted net income stood at $21.9 million, also $0.40 per diluted share [1]. Both GAAP and adjusted EPS showed notable year-over-year increases of 21% and 3%, respectively [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company&#39;s financial success was not limited to its core operations. Adjusted EBITDA reached $34.3 million, and the adjusted EBITDA margin stood at a healthy 23.6% [1]. These figures reflect Enerpac&#39;s ongoing commitment to operational efficiency and productivity.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enerpac&#39;s first-quarter performance was particularly noteworthy given the challenging market conditions. The company&#39;s President &amp;amp; CEO, Paul Sternlieb, expressed confidence in Enerpac&#39;s ability to continue outperforming the market, citing the company&#39;s global brand leadership, targeted growth strategy, customer-driven innovation, and continuous improvement process [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, Darren Kozik, added that the first quarter of fiscal 2025 was essentially in line with expectations, reflecting Enerpac&#39;s ability to operate effectively in a soft market while lapping strong growth from the first quarter of fiscal 2024 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Enerpac&#39;s recent acquisition of DTA is also contributing to the company&#39;s growth and success. The integration of DTA is reportedly well underway, and the acquisition is expected to enhance Enerpac&#39;s product offerings and broaden its customer base [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, Enerpac Tool Group&#39;s first-quarter financial results demonstrate the company&#39;s resilience and ability to outperform the market, even in challenging economic conditions. With a strong financial performance, ongoing growth initiatives, and a commitment to operational efficiency, Enerpac is well-positioned to continue delivering value to its shareholders.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Enerpac Tool Group Reports First Quarter Fiscal 2025 Results. (2024, December 18). Retrieved from https://ir.enerpactoolgroup.com/news/news-details/2024/Enerpac-Tool-Group-Reports-First-Quarter-Fiscal-2025-Results/default.aspx&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d53569945f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/enerpac-tool-2q-net-sales-145-5m-est-143-3m-250310009f6a927780c21105/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/enerpac-tool-2q-net-sales-145-5m-est-143-3m-250310009f6a927780c21105/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:30:47 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>American Electric Power offers $2 billion in shares</title><description>&lt;p&gt;American Electric Power offers $2 billion in shares&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d52e9b145f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/american-electric-power-offers-2-billion-in-shares-25031000ab61e35ed9bbe54a/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/american-electric-power-offers-2-billion-in-shares-25031000ab61e35ed9bbe54a/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:29:10 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>not Penny stock</category><category>us_low_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>US Postmaster General Louis DeJoy to step down today</title><description>&lt;p&gt;US Postmaster General Louis DeJoy to step down today&lt;/p&gt;The US Postal Service (USPS) announced on Tuesday that Postmaster General Louis DeJoy will be stepping down from his position, effective immediately [1]. DeJoy&#39;s departure comes after a nearly five-year tenure marked by the coronavirus pandemic, surges in mail-in election ballots, and efforts to stem losses through cost and service cuts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy, who took the helm of the postal service in the summer of 2020, was a Republican donor and the first postmaster general in nearly two decades who was not a career postal employee. He developed a 10-year plan to modernize operations and stem losses, which included making the mail delivery system more efficient and less costly by consolidating mail processing centers [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Critics, including members of Congress from several states, have argued that these consolidations slowed service and could particularly hurt rural mail delivery. DeJoy disputed these claims and told a US House subcommittee during a contentious September hearing that the Postal Service had embarked on long-overdue investments in &quot;ratty&quot; facilities and making other changes to create &quot;a Postal Service for the future&quot; that delivered mail more quickly [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy also oversaw the postal service during two presidential elections that saw spikes in mail-in ballots. In the lead-up to the 2020 presidential election, a federal judge limited one of the postal service&#39;s cost-cutting practices after finding it contributed to delays in mail delivery [1]. DeJoy had restricted overtime payments for postal workers and stopped the agency&#39;s longtime practice of allowing late and extra truck deliveries in the summer of 2020, which reduced mail delivery speeds [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy&#39;s resignation comes at a time when the USPS is facing significant financial challenges. In 2020, the postal service reported a net loss of $9.2 billion, its largest annual loss in its history [2]. DeJoy previously stated that postal customers should get used to &quot;uncomfortable&quot; rate hikes as the postal service seeks to stabilize its finances and become more self-sufficient [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[1] CNN. (2023, February 18). Louis DeJoy, USPS Postmaster General, to step down. https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/18/politics/louis-dejoy-usps-postmaster-general-steps-down/index.html&lt;br&gt;[2] USPS. (2021). FY 2020 Annual Report. https://about.usps.com/who-we-are/financials/financial-reports/ar-2020.pdf&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d5226acc7e002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-to-step-down-today-2503100030a757639166f320/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-to-step-down-today-2503100030a757639166f320/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:25:33 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Postmaster General Louis DeJoy resigns today - agency</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Postmaster General Louis DeJoy resigns today - agency&lt;/p&gt;The United States Postal Service (USPS) has witnessed a significant change in leadership as Postmaster General Louis DeJoy announced his resignation on February 18, 2025 [1]. DeJoy&#39;s departure follows a tumultuous five-year tenure marked by the COVID-19 pandemic, increased mail-in election ballots, and efforts to modernize operations and stem losses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DeJoy, who took the helm of the USPS in the summer of 2020, was a Republican donor and former logistics business owner before his appointment. His 10-year plan aimed to modernize the postal service by making it more efficient and less costly [1]. Critics, however, argued that consolidating mail processing centers and implementing cost-cutting measures could negatively impact rural mail delivery and slow down service [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of DeJoy&#39;s most contentious decisions was restricting overtime payments for postal workers and stopping the USPS&#39; longstanding practice of allowing late and extra truck deliveries in the summer of 2020 [1]. These moves contributed to delays in mail delivery, particularly during the 2020 presidential election when a federal judge limited one of the postal service&#39;s cost-cutting practices [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the criticism, DeJoy defended his actions, stating that the USPS had embarked on long-overdue investments in &quot;ratty&quot; facilities and was creating a more efficient and self-sufficient postal service [1]. He also oversaw the USPS during two presidential elections that saw spikes in mail-in ballots.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In his farewell letter, DeJoy expressed gratitude for the opportunity to serve the American people and lead the 640,000 employees of the USPS through an unprecedented period [1]. As the search for his successor begins, the USPS will continue to navigate the challenges of modernization, cost containment, and maintaining the trust of the American public.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] CNN. (2025, February 18). Louis DeJoy, USPS postmaster general, to step down. https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/18/politics/louis-dejoy-usps-postmaster-general-steps-down/index.html&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d51918585f002.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-resigns-today-agency-25031000d7d269eec7ee1af2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/postmaster-general-louis-dejoy-resigns-today-agency-25031000d7d269eec7ee1af2/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:23:01 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>Airbus supply chain exec: 30% of suppliers are on watch, 1-2% determining pace of production</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Airbus supply chain exec: 30% of suppliers are on watch, 1-2% determining pace of production&lt;/p&gt;Airbus, the European aerospace giant, is known for its unwavering commitment to innovation and growth. Despite encountering persistent supply chain issues, Airbus remains optimistic about increasing production in 2024, with a target of 800 commercial aircraft deliveries [1]. The company&#39;s CEO, Guillaume Faury, emphasizes the importance of monitoring suppliers&#39; investment rates and supply chain management to ensure they can keep pace with Airbus&#39; production increases [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;One of Airbus&#39; key suppliers, Spirit AeroSystems, has faced economic challenges, leading to financial losses and cash flow issues [1]. To mitigate the impact of these issues on its production, Airbus has been engaging in discussions with Spirit regarding the contractual relationship [1]. Instead of offering direct financial assistance, Airbus is bolstering Spirit&#39;s industrial capabilities [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Airbus has also been proactive in addressing the risk of supply chain disruption by growing its supply chain management team by 150% over the past two years [1]. The company now deploys supply chain personnel to critical supplier sites and closely monitors suppliers in financial distress to avoid disruptions [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The complexity of managing a supply chain with thousands of suppliers is a constant effort for Airbus. Faury acknowledges that the strength of any link on the supply chain depends on the type of activities, their geographical position, and the ease of hiring and training people [1]. Despite these challenges, Airbus remains committed to increasing production and delivering on its 2024 targets.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] SupplyChainDigital. (2023, February 28). Airbus aiming high in 2024 despite supply chain issues. Retrieved from https://supplychaindigital.com/supplier-relationship-management-srm/airbus-aiming-high-in-2024-despite-supply-chain-issues&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4eee4d85f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/airbus-supply-chain-exec-30-of-suppliers-are-on-watch-1-2-determining-pace-of-production-250310002f41e0716c7f069b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/airbus-supply-chain-exec-30-of-suppliers-are-on-watch-1-2-determining-pace-of-production-250310002f41e0716c7f069b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:11:25 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category></item><item><title>US stocks close higher on Monday</title><description>&lt;p&gt;US stocks close higher on Monday, Dow rises 1.42%, Nasdaq rises 2.27%, S&amp;amp;P 500 rises 1.76%&lt;/p&gt;The US stock market experienced a notable rebound on Monday, with the Dow Jones Industrial Average, S&amp;amp;P 500, and Nasdaq Composite all closing higher [1]. This upturn followed several weeks of volatile trading and marked the second consecutive day of gains for the major indices.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The S&amp;amp;P 500 recorded a 0.6% increase, closing at 5,675.12, while the Dow Jones Industrial Average added 0.9%, finishing at 41,841.63 [1]. The Nasdaq Composite demonstrated a more substantial gain, rising 0.3% to close at 17,808.66 [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Several factors contributed to this positive market sentiment. One of the primary drivers was optimism surrounding President Donald Trump&#39;s tariff plans. Reports emerged suggesting that the tariffs might be more targeted than initially anticipated, which alleviated concerns among investors [2]. Additionally, the US services-sector PMI data came in higher than expected, indicating continued growth in the sector [2].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite these positive developments, market volatility persisted. The Federal Reserve&#39;s upcoming decision on interest rates and ongoing concerns about President Trump&#39;s trade war continue to cast shadows over the market [1]. However, the recent rebound offers a glimmer of hope for investors, who are eager to see the market stabilize in the face of these challenges.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] Associated Press. (2022, January 10). U.S. stocks climb again following weeks of scary swings. https://apnews.com/article/wall-street-stocks-dow-nasdaq-c2391c3562c980eaa017ad03e4d8a179&lt;br&gt;[2] MarketWatch. (2022, January 10). U.S. stocks end sharply higher on Monday, with investors optimistic about narrower Trump tariffs. https://www.marketwatch.com/livecoverage/stock-market-today-dow-s-p-500-and-nasdaq-set-for-early-gains-on-reports-of-lighter-tariffs/card/u-s-stocks-end-sharply-higher-with-investors-hopeful-for-narrower-trump-tariffs-8z5jhoPVgLXl8Zudk3B6&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4e89e985f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-stocks-close-higher-on-monday-25031000f7f3a41347d1cd6b/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/us-stocks-close-higher-on-monday-25031000f7f3a41347d1cd6b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 20:09:54 GMT</pubDate><author>Why is it moving?</author><category>us_middle_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category><category>AI Mover</category></item><item><title>Russian official expects Moscow, Washington to agree on more initiatives</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Russian official expects Moscow, Washington to agree on more initiatives&lt;/p&gt;In the aftermath of the recent U.S. presidential election, Russian officials have expressed cautious optimism about the possibility of resuming dialogue with Washington. According to local media reports, Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov indicated that there is a &quot;modest hope&quot; that some level of dialogue may resume between the two nations [1].&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Peskov emphasized that making statements during an election campaign is one thing, but the actions of elected leaders can change once they assume office. He also noted that the outcome of the bilateral relationship would depend on the individuals appointed to key positions in the new U.S. administration.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Donald Trump, who previously served as U.S. president from 2017 to 2021, won the 2024 election in a surprising upset, defeating Democratic candidate and incumbent Vice President Kamala Harris. Trump has long expressed admiration for Russian President Vladimir Putin and has claimed to have a good relationship with him [2]. However, Putin has yet to comment on the election results.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Despite the potential for improved relations, it is essential to note that U.S.-Russia ties have been strained in recent years due to tensions over issues such as Ukraine, sanctions, diplomatic standoffs, and allegations of Russian election interference [1][2]. Any resumption of dialogue would likely face significant challenges.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;References:&lt;br&gt;[1] China Daily Hong Kong. (2024, June 5). Kremlin expects dialogue with Washington to resume after Trump&#39;s victory. https://www.chinadailyhk.com/hk/article/597898&lt;br&gt;[2] The Moscow Times. (2024, November 6). Russian officials cautiously welcome Donald Trump&#39;s re-election. https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2024/11/06/russian-officials-cautiously-welcome-donald-trumps-re-election-a86917&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh-prod-oper-pub-opercenter.s3.amazonaws.com/discovery-image/compress-1a6d4c0a4ac5f001.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.ainvest.com/news/russian-official-expects-moscow-washington-to-agree-on-more-initiatives-25031000f69accfcc62da3a5/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ainvest.com/news/russian-official-expects-moscow-washington-to-agree-on-more-initiatives-25031000f69accfcc62da3a5/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:59:03 GMT</pubDate><author>AInvest</author><category>us_high_importance</category><category>stock</category><category>positive</category></item></channel></rss>