<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Russian Politics &amp; Diplomacy - TASS</title><link>https://docs.rsshub.app</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.henry.wang/tass/politics" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Russian Politics &amp; Diplomacy - TASS - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://tass.com/img/blocks/common/tass_logo_share_eng.png</url><title>Russian Politics &amp; Diplomacy - TASS</title><link/></image><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:47:18 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>14</ttl><item><title>Karasin, Beseda to report to Putin on topics discussed during talks with US</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The talks between the two delegations lasted for more than 12 hours&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 25. /TASS/. Representatives of the Russian delegation at consultations with the United States in Riyadh, Grigory Karasin and Sergey Beseda, will brief Russian President Vladimir Putin on the issues raised during the negotiations and will determine what will be communicated to the public, First Deputy Chairman of the Federation Council Committee on International Affairs Vladimir Dzhabarov said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I believe that the matters being discussed by the Russian delegation with the American delegation will only be known later, once they return to Moscow, report to the president, and determine what will be shared with the broader public,&quot; he said during an appearance on Channel One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talks between the two delegations lasted for more than 12 hours. The Russian delegation is led by head of the Federation Council Committee on International Affairs Grigory Karasin and adviser to the director of Russia&#39;s Federal Security Service (FSB) Sergey Beseda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US delegation included senior director for European and Russian affairs at the National Security Council Andrew Peak, State Department’s Policy Planning Director Michael Anton, as well as aides to Donald Trump&#39;s special envoy for Ukraine and Russia Keith Kellogg, and national security advisor Mike Waltz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933355</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933355</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:46:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kiev regime once again reveals its brutal nature — Russian Foreign Ministry</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;Maria Zakharova also attributed the increase in terrorist attacks carried out by the Kiev regime to the realization by the Armed Forces of Ukraine that they are incapable of inflicting damage on the Russian Armed Forces on the battlefield&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 25. /TASS/. Russian Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova has commented on the attacks by Ukrainian forces on Russian journalists, denouncing the Zelensky regime as terrorist and emphasizing Ukraine’s lack of reliability as a negotiating partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Kiev regime has once again shown its terrorist and brutal nature. The series of brutal executions of Russian journalists by Ukrainian neo-Nazis serves as yet another striking testament to their readiness to commit any crimes against civilians without hesitation. According to international law, as outlined in the 1949 Geneva Conventions and Additional Protocol I, media representatives are considered civilians. The undeniable facts of these crimes further underscore the complete unreliability of the Zelensky regime as a negotiating party,&quot; Zakharova said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mid.ru/ru/foreign_policy/news/2005154/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; on the ministry’s official website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zakharova also attributed the increase in terrorist attacks carried out by the Kiev regime to the realization by the Armed Forces of Ukraine that they are incapable of inflicting damage on the Russian Armed Forces on the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Kiev regime not only continues its campaign of terror against Russian civilians and energy infrastructure - something we have repeatedly stated - but has once again targeted representatives of Russian media, whose professional duty is to report on events ‘on the ground’ without taking up arms. The frequency of such terrorist acts is rising in direct proportion to the neo-Nazi regime’s growing awareness of its inability to inflict any damage on the Russian Armed Forces on the battlefield,&quot; Zakharova said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933353</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933353</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:59:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lavrov plans to talk about aspects of Riyadh talks in TV interview on March 25</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;Spokeswoman for the Russian Foreign Ministry Maria Zakharova announced an interview with Channel One&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;news-media news-media_photo&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-include text-include-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;text-include-photo__img&quot; ng-class=&quot;{&#39;resize&#39;:undefined}&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-media.tass.ru/tass/m2/en/uploads/i/20250325/1441455.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov Sergey Bulkin/TASS&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-include-photo__title&quot;&gt;Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;text-include-photo__source&quot; data-ng-href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;© Sergey Bulkin/TASS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 25. /TASS/. Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov will discuss some aspects of the Russian-US consultations held in Riyadh on Monday in a televised interview on March 25, spokeswoman for the Russian Foreign Ministry Maria Zakharova said on her &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/MariaVladimirovnaZakharova/10086&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Sergey Lavrov will talk about some aspects of these contacts tomorrow in an interview with Channel One,&quot; the diplomat noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talks lasted for more than 12 hours. The Russian delegation is led by head of the Federation Council Committee on International Affairs Grigory Karasin and adviser to the director of Russia&#39;s Federal Security Service (FSB) Sergey Beseda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US delegation included senior director for European and Russian affairs at the National Security Council Andrew Peak, State Department’s Policy Planning Director Michael Anton, as well as aides to Donald Trump&#39;s special envoy for Ukraine and Russia Keith Kellogg, and national security advisor Mike Waltz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933345</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933345</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:26:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian official expects Moscow, Washington to agree on more initiatives</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;Vance stood up for the envoy amid criticism of the latter’s recent remarks on Ukraine&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Russian Direct Investment Fund (RDIF) CEO Kirill Dmitriev has expressed hope that Washington and Moscow will soon agree on new initiatives in addition to the deal to halt strikes on energy infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Very true! WWIII avoided. Energy infrastructure ceasefire achieved. Other initiatives to be agreed soon! Under the leadership of President Putin and President Trump the world is becoming safer,&quot; Dmitriev wrote on the X social media platform, commenting on US Vice President JD Vance’s remark that US Special Presidential Envoy Steve Witkoff was &quot;doing an incredible job.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vance stood up for the envoy amid criticism of the latter’s recent remarks on Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Witkoff made a number of high-profile statements on Ukraine in an interview with American journalist Tucker Carlson on March 21. In particular, he claimed that Kiev has agreed to hold a presidential election, while Vladimir Zelensky and his chief of staff Andrey Yermak have largely admitted that Ukraine will not become a NATO member. The US envoy also said that the status of Crimea, the Donetsk and Lugansk People’s Republics and the Zaporozhye and Kherson regions was at the heart of the Ukraine conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander Merezhko, head of the Ukrainian parliamentary committee on foreign affairs and interparliamentary cooperation, described those statements as shocking. Merezhko slammed Witkoff as naive and unprofessional, saying he needed to do some more research so that he could gain a basic understanding of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933279</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933279</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:57:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UN need to rethink peacekeeping strategies — Russia’s UN mission</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;&quot;The peacekeeping and political aspects of UN activities need to be revised, improved and returned to realistic approaches,&quot; Anna Yevstigneyeva said&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNITED NATIONS, March 24. /TASS/. The UN&#39;s peacekeeping missions do not work as currently implemented, and need to be re-evaluated, Russian Permanent Representative to the UN Anna Yevstigneyeva said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The peacekeeping and political aspects of UN activities need to be revised, improved and returned to realistic approaches,&quot; she told an open UN Security Council debate on peacekeeping operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russia is convinced that the work of peacekeepers needs to be objectively assessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;It will be difficult to move forward without an honest analysis of why host nations question the need for the deployment of peacekeepers or why they chose other, more efficient forms of cooperation. A political, not technical solution to the emerging problems can only be found on the basis of these assessments,&quot; she added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, she pointed out that a &quot;formal search for new methods, which are &amp;lt;...&amp;gt; sometimes clearly contrived&quot; appears to be unjustified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We believe that the organization has accumulated sufficient expertise and instruments for almost 80 years of its work to help countries prevent conflict, sign peace agreements, facilitate compliance with them and assist in peace-building. A unique solution can be found for any situation that may arise,&quot; she added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933267</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933267</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:02:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian, US expert groups wrapping up talks in Riyadh — Russian delegate</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The meeting is taking place behind closed doors&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Expert groups from Russia and the United States are currently wrapping up their consultations in Riyadh, one of the members of the Russian delegation, Chairman of the Federation Council Committee on Foreign Affairs Grigory Karasin has told TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The negotiations are being concluded,&quot; he told TASS in a phone call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting is taking place behind closed doors at The Ritz-Carlton hotel in Riyadh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Russian delegation is led by Grigory Karasin, the head of the Federation Council Committee on International Affairs, and Sergey Beseda, adviser to the director of Russia&#39;s Federal Security Service (FSB). The US delegation includes State Department’s Policy Planning Director Michael Anton, as well as aides to Donald Trump&#39;s special envoy for Ukraine and Russia Keith Kellogg and national security advisor Mike Waltz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, Russian Presidential Press Secretary Dmitry Peskov told TASS that no documents are planned for signing in the wake of the talks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933269</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933269</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:00:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian, US delegations to Riyadh talks trying to agree joint statement — source</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The talks will be over once the parties agree on a joint statement&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;news-media news-media_photo&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-include text-include-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;text-include-photo__img&quot; ng-class=&quot;{&#39;resize&#39;:undefined}&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-media.tass.ru/tass/m2/en/uploads/i/20250324/1441443.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;text-include-photo__source&quot; data-ng-href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;© TASS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;RIYADH, March 24. /TASS/. Today’s talks between the delegations of Russia and the United States, which are ongoing in the Saudi capital of Riyadh, will be over once the parties agree on a joint statement, a source in the Russian delegation told TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The consultations are expected to end soon. The negotiators are trying to agree on a joint statement,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933263</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933263</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:53:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian MFA to seek OSCE, UNESCO reaction to death of reporter Fedorchak</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;&quot;Another crime by the Kiev regime against freedom of speech and journalism will not be overlooked through the &#39;strategic silence&#39; funded by Western handlers,&quot; Maria Zakharova stated&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. The Russian Foreign Ministry will request a response from the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), UNESCO, and other relevant agencies regarding the death of Izvestiya correspondent Fedorchak, which was caused by the Ukrainian army, Russian Foreign Ministry Spokeswoman Maria Zakharova stated in a commentary to the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Another crime by the Kiev regime against freedom of speech and journalism will not be overlooked through the &#39;strategic silence&#39; funded by Western handlers,&quot; the diplomat stated. &quot;We will not only bring this information to the attention of the relevant international organizations but will also seek their response. The OSCE, UNESCO, and other specialized international institutions are obliged to react,&quot; she added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933249</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933249</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:22:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Izvestia correspondent Fedorchak dies in special military operation zone — agency</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The correspondent worked in the Kharkov Region’s Kupyansk direction, the newspaper stated&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. The Izvestia newspaper has reported the death of its correspondent Alexander Fedorchak in the special military operation zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Izvestia correspondent Alexander Fedorchak died in the special military operation zone. This became known on Monday, March 24. Details of the incident are being clarified,&quot; a statement published on the agency’s website said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correspondent worked in the Kharkov Region’s Kupyansk direction, the newspaper added. &quot;Fedorchak’s last coverage was filmed just a day earlier,&quot; it stated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933247</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933247</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:59:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No breakthroughs to be expected at Riyadh meeting, as multiple issues on table — MFA</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The talks are conducted behind closed doors&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Russian Foreign Ministry Spokeswoman Maria Zakharova has stated that one should not anticipate any breakthroughs from the ongoing Russia-US consultations in Saudi Arabia’s Riyadh, as there are numerous issues to work out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;These are talks conducted behind closed doors. Of course, one should not expect some kind of breakthroughs, but rather understand that the work is being conducted in several areas,&quot; the diplomat said at a meeting with students at the Plekhanov Russian University of Economics as part of the Monthly Top project carried out by the First Media Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negotiations between Russia and the US launched on Monday morning. The Russian delegation is led by Chairman of the Federation Council Committee on International Affairs Grigory Karasin, and Advisor to the Director of the Federal Security Service (FSB) Sergey Beseda. The United States is represented by Andrew Peek, senior director at the White House National Security Council, and Michael Anton, a senior State Department official, as well as assistants to Keith Kellogg, special envoy for Ukraine, and Mike Waltz, National Security Advisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Russian Presidential Aide Yury Ushakov, the main topic of the consultations is the resumption of the Black Sea grain initiative in accordance with an agreement between Russian President Vladimir Putin and his US counterpart Donald Trump, reached during a telephone conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933239</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933239</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:55:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia, US have no plans of signing documents after talks in Riyadh — Kremlin spokesman</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;Negotiations between Russia and the United States in Saudi Arabia’s Riyadh began on Monday morning&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;news-media news-media_photo&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-include text-include-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;text-include-photo__img&quot; ng-class=&quot;{&#39;resize&#39;:undefined}&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-media.tass.ru/tass/m2/en/uploads/i/20250324/1441439.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Russian Presidential Spokesman Dmitry Peskov Alexander Shcherbak/TASS&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-include-photo__title&quot;&gt;Russian Presidential Spokesman Dmitry Peskov&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;text-include-photo__source&quot; data-ng-href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;© Alexander Shcherbak/TASS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Russian and US expert groups, which convened for a meeting in Saudi Arabia’s Riyadh earlier in the day, do not plan to sign any documents in the wake of the talks, Russian Presidential Press Secretary Dmitry Peskov said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;No, no documents are planned,&quot; he said in answer to a corresponding question from TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negotiations between Russia and the United States began on Monday morning. The Russian delegation is headed by Grigory Karasin, Chairman of the Federation Council Committee on International Affairs, and Sergey Beseda, Advisor to the Director of the Federal Security Service. The US delegation is led by Andrew Peek, a senior director at the White House National Security Council, and Michael Anton, a senior State Department official. Assistants to Keith Kellogg, special envoy for Ukraine, and Mike Waltz, National Security Advisor, also participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russian Presidential Aide Yury Ushakov said the main topic of the consultations is the resumption of the Black Sea grain initiative in accordance with an agreement between the Presidents of Russia and the United States, Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump, reached during a telephone conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933231</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933231</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:47:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian ambassador to represent his country during Lukashenko’s inauguration — embassy</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;According to the report, citing Alexander Lukashenko’s press secretary Natalia Eismont, the official swearing-in ceremony will take place on March 25, begin at noon, and be attended by 1,100 invited persons&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MINSK, March 24. /TASS/. Russian Ambassador to Belarus Boris Gryzlov will represent his country during the swearing-in ceremony of the republic’s elected President Alexander Lukashenko, embassy spokesman Alexey Maskalyov said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Boris Gryzlov will represent Russia during the inauguration ceremony [of Lukashenko],&quot; he stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BelTA&amp;nbsp;news agency reported, citing Natalia Eismont, Lukashenko’s press secretary, that the official swearing-in ceremony will take place on March 25, begin at noon, and be attended by 1,100 invited persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Belarusian Central Election Commission, incumbent President Alexander Lukashenko won the presidential election that had taken place on January 26, garnering 86.82% of the electoral vote. This will be Lukashenko’s seventh term as president. It was earlier noted that the Belarusian format of inauguration does not imply attendance by foreign heads of state.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933193</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933193</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:48:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Putting nuclear power plants in US hands to turn Ukraine into colony — Russian senator</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;Natalia Nikonorova emphasized that Russia did not target Ukrainian nuclear power plants, being acutely aware of &quot;the seriousness of such actions and committed to adhering to universally recognized norms of international humanitarian law&quot;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Ukraine, should it transfer the management of its nuclear power plants to the United States, risks becoming an energy colony, focused on exporting electricity to Europe, Natalia Nikonorova, a member of the Russian Federation Council’s Committee on International Affairs and former head of the DPR Foreign Ministry, said in an interview with TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;US Energy Secretary Chris Wright has indicated that Washington is prepared to assume control of Ukrainian nuclear power plants, if this could help bring an end to the conflict in Ukraine. Earlier, following a telephone conversation between US President Donald Trump and Vladimir Zelensky, Washington expressed its willingness to assist Ukraine in operating its nuclear facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The rationale behind the United States&#39; interest in controlling Ukrainian nuclear power plants is quite evident - it could be profitable. It appears that the US plans to supply the resulting electricity to European countries, effectively transforming the remnants of Ukraine into an energy colony for the Americans,&quot; Nikonorova remarked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She noted that currently, four nuclear power plants are under Kiev&#39;s control: the Rovno, Khmelnitsky, South Ukraine, and the decommissioned Chernobyl plant, which has been inactive since 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I do not believe that the decision to take control of Ukrainian nuclear power plants is directly related to, or will have a direct impact on the resolution of the conflict. It seems more like the US is masking its financial interests with claims of peaceful intentions. The logic is straightforward: the Kiev regime has been receiving American aid for years, neglecting the reality that the only free cheese is found in a mousetrap. For the administration in the White House, the welfare of their country is a priority. It is time for Kiev to pay the bills,&quot; she added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Strikes on nuclear power plants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikonorova also emphasized that Russia does not target Ukrainian nuclear power plants, being acutely aware of &quot;the seriousness of such actions and committed to adhering to universally recognized norms of international humanitarian law.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The same cannot be said for our adversary; the Zaporozhye Nuclear Power Plant is regularly attacked,&quot; the senator noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 18, Russian President Vladimir Putin and US President Donald Trump discussed the situation in Ukraine, conditions to prevent escalation, and various international issues via telephone. According to the Kremlin press service, Putin concurred with the US leader&#39;s proposal for both parties in the conflict to refrain from striking energy infrastructure for 30 days. The White House reported that the leaders also agreed to initiate technical talks aimed at establishing a ceasefire in the Black Sea, achieving a complete ceasefire, and working toward permanent peace. A key condition emphasized by the Kremlin for resolving the conflict is &quot;a complete halt to foreign military aid and the provision of intelligence information to Kiev.&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933197</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933197</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:46:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Senior Russian diplomat, UNCTAD chief discuss safety of navigation in Black Sea</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The parties also discussed the parameters for the implementation of Russia’s humanitarian missions, including the free handover of mineral fertilizers, which have been arbitrarily blocked at EU ports, the statement says&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Sergey Vershinin has held consultations in Moscow with UN Trade and Development (UNCTAD) Secretary General Rebeca Grynspan and UN experts, discussing the safety of navigation in the Black Sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The parties addressed issues related to the safety of navigation in the Black Sea. They also discussed the parameters for the implementation of Russia’s humanitarian missions, including the free handover of mineral fertilizers, which have been arbitrarily blocked at EU ports, to the poorest counties,&quot; the Russian Foreign Ministry said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the ministry, the parties also touched upon global food security, focusing on efforts to ensure the implementation of the Russia-UN memorandum on normalizing Russian agricultural exports. &quot;Particular emphasis was made on the key importance of unrestricted access to the global markets for Russian fertilizers and food as the West’s illegal unilateral sanctions continue to significantly complicate their exports,&quot; the Russian Foreign Ministry added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russian Presidential Spokesman Dmitry Peskov said earlier that the agenda of the consultations between Russian and US delegations that are taking place in Riyadh today included the safety of navigation in the Black Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933187</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933187</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:36:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia overcomes West’s &#39;ideological blitzkrieg,&#39; diplomat says</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;&quot;The West was betting on the fact that the people would splinter, generations would fight with each other and we would not be able to get through it because of the economic difficulties they had created for us,&quot; Maria Zakharova noted&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. The West’s ideological blitzkrieg against Moscow has failed, Russian Foreign Ministry Spokeswoman Maria Zakharova said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We have withstood the blow. They planned what was supposed to be a blitzkrieg in every sense of the word. I won’t speak about the theater of war as it’s not my responsibility. However, as for the ideological blitzkrieg, this is definitely what they planned,&quot; the diplomat pointed out at a meeting with students at the Plekhanov Russian University of Economics as part of the Monthly Top project carried out by the First Media Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;They were betting on the fact that the people would splinter, generations would fight with each other and we would not be able to get through it because of the economic difficulties they had created for us. &amp;lt;...&amp;gt; However, we overcame it all, we are overcoming it and we will overcome it,&quot; Zakharova added.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933177</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933177</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:18:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Participants in US-Russia talks in Riyadh leave for another break</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The meeting has already been disrupted twice&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;RIYADH, March 24. /TASS/. Representatives of Russia and the United States, who are holding consultations in Riyadh, have taken another break in the talks, a source close to Moscow&#39;s delegation told TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting has already been disrupted twice. The first break was announced at around 1 p.m. Moscow time (10 a.m. GMT). An hour and a half later, the delegations resumed the meeting. For the second time, the participants made a brief pause at around 4 p.m. Moscow time (1 p.m. GMT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first round of talks between the technical teams of Ukraine and the United States took place in the afternoon of Sunday, March 23, with the discussions lasting about six hours. The Ukrainian delegation included Defense Minister Rustem Umerov, deputy head of the Ukrainian presidential office Pavel Palisa, as well as representatives of the armed forces and energy specialists. The main topic was the cessation of strikes on energy infrastructure facilities. The representatives of the parties did not provide details of the discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US delegation includes State Department’s Policy Planning Director Michael Anton, as well as aides to Donald Trump’s special envoy for Ukraine Keith Kellogg and National Security Advisor Mike Waltz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Russian presidential aide Yury Ushakov, the resumption of the Black Sea grain initiative, which Russia&#39;s President Vladimir Putin and US leader Donald Trump have agreed on during a telephone conversation, is the key topic of the consultations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933175</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933175</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:09:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Some European leaders do not want real settlement in Ukraine — Russian envoy</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;Earlier, Russian Presidential Spokesman Dmitry Peskov remarked in an interview with VGTRK journalist Pavel Zarubin that instead of addressing the root causes of the Ukrainian conflict, Europe is merely exacerbating the situation by increasing military spending and considering the deployment of its forces in Ukraine&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;BERLIN, March 24. /TASS/. Some leaders in European countries are not interested in achieving a genuine settlement of the Ukrainian conflict, according to Mikhail Ulyanov, Russia&#39;s permanent representative to international organizations in Vienna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Based on the statements and erratic actions of certain European leaders, it appears they may act as spoilers if given a seat at the negotiating table. There is no reason to believe they are genuinely seeking a resolution to the situation in Ukraine,&quot; Ulyanov stated on his Telegram channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, Russian Presidential Spokesman Dmitry Peskov remarked in an interview with VGTRK journalist Pavel Zarubin that instead of addressing the root causes of the Ukrainian conflict, Europe is merely exacerbating the situation by increasing military spending and considering the deployment of its forces in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933151</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933151</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:38:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>IN BRIEF: Ukraine carries out assault on Russian energy infrastructure</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The Russian Defense Ministry pointed out that the strikes involved both attack drones and HIMARS rockets&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;news-media news-media_photo&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;text-include text-include-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;text-include-photo__img&quot; ng-class=&quot;{&#39;resize&#39;:undefined}&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn-media.tass.ru/tass/m2/en/uploads/i/20250324/1441427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;text-include-photo__source&quot; data-ng-href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;© Sergey Bobylev/TASS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;MOSCOW, March 24. /TASS/. Over the past few days, Ukraine has assaulted Russia’s energy infrastructure. On March 22, Kiev carried out two drone strikes on the Valuika gas distribution station in the settlement of Shvedunovka in Russia’s borderline Belgorod Region. A day later, on March 23, Russian air defenses repelled a Ukrainian drone attack on the Glebovskoye gas condensate field on Crimea’s Cape Tarkhankut Crimea. And early on March 24, the enemy tried to conduct a drone attack on the Kropotkinskaya oil pumping station, the Russian Defense Ministry said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TASS has gathered the key information about Ukraine’s attacks on Russian energy infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attack on gas distribution station&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- The Kiev regime carried out two drone strikes on the Valuika gas distribution station located in the settlement of Shvedunovka in Russia’s Belgorod Region between 5:00 a.m. and 8:45 a.m. Moscow time (2:00-6:45 a.m. GMT) on March 22, the Russian Defense Ministry reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- The attack damaged technological equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attack on gas condensate field&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- According to the Defense Ministry, Russian air defenses repelled an attack involving four Ukrainian unmanned aerial vehicles on the Glebovskoye gas condensate field on Cape Tarkhankut in Crimea between 9:00 p.m. and 9:50 p.m. Moscow time (6:00-6:50 p.m. GMT) on March 23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- The field is used for gas supplies across Russia’s Crimean Peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attack on Kropotkinskaya oil pumping station&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- The Defense Ministry also reported a Ukrainian attack on the Kropotkinskaya oil pumping station belonging to the Caspian Pipeline Consortium, which had taken place in Russia’s southern Krasnodar Region at about 2:00 a.m. Moscow time on March 24 (11:00 p.m. on March 23 GMT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- According to the ministry, Russian air defenses intercepted a Ukrainian drone seven kilometers away from the Kropotkinskaya station, which is part of international energy infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Russian Defense Ministry&#39;s response&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Attacks on Russian energy sites, including international facilities, once again make it clear that the Kiev regime doesn&#39;t want peace, the Russian Defense Ministry stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- The ministry pointed out that the strikes involved both attack drones and HIMARS rockets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933141</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933141</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:14:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia-US consultations resume after second break — source</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The US delegation includes State Department’s Policy Planning Director Michael Anton, as well as aides to Donald Trump’s special envoy for Ukraine Keith Kellogg and National Security Advisor Mike Waltz&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;RIYADH, March 24. /TASS/. Talks between the Russian and US delegations in Riyadh have resumed after a second brief break, a source close to the Russian delegation told TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consultations have been going on for more than six hours. The first break in the talks was announced around 1 p.m. Moscow time (10 a.m. GMT). An hour and a half later, the delegations resumed their meeting. The second round of the Russian-American negotiations lasted only one hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first round of talks between the technical teams of Ukraine and the United States took place in the afternoon of Sunday, March 23, with the discussions lasting about six hours. The Ukrainian delegation included Defense Minister Rustem Umerov, deputy head of the Ukrainian presidential office Pavel Palisa, as well as representatives of the armed forces and energy specialists. The main topic was the cessation of strikes on energy infrastructure facilities. The representatives of the parties did not provide details of the discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US delegation includes State Department’s Policy Planning Director Michael Anton, as well as aides to Donald Trump’s special envoy for Ukraine Keith Kellogg and National Security Advisor Mike Waltz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933119</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933119</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:41:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukrainian forces begin to use ATACMS missiles less often due to lack of them — expert</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;news-header__lead&quot;&gt;The media outlet earlier reported, citing sources in the US presidential administration, that Ukraine no longer has ATACMS missiles&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;LUGANSK, March 24. /TASS/. The Ukrainian armed forces show a lack of ATACMS missiles, as the enemy has started to use the stockpiled missiles for strikes against Russian territory more sparingly, Andrey Marochko, a military expert, told TASS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Ukrainian forces, indeed, do not have many ATACMS at the moment, but I would not say that they do not have any at all, simply because they are now using them to carry out strikes on civilian infrastructure in the Belgorod Region. &amp;lt;…&amp;gt; It is true that they have begun to use them far less frequently now. And, naturally, this is precisely due to the fact that they do not have that many of these missiles and the shipments are very restricted,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Associated Press earlier reported, citing sources in the US presidential administration, that Ukraine no longer has ATACMS missiles. According to it, the United States had provided Kiev with less than 40 of such missiles, and their reserves ran out in late January.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://tass.com/politics/1933103</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://tass.com/politics/1933103</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:29:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>