<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Dragoneer and the American Health Care System - dsc85 | Journal Comments</title><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.email-once.com/furaffinity/journal-comments/10925112" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Fur Affinity | Dragoneer and the American Health Care System by dsc85 - Journal Comments - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:04:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>You know the problem is the corruption. Every damn year the US spends a trillion dollars for healthcare, but where in the hell does that money go. I m...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/20250319/queens22333.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; Queens22333: You know the problem is the corruption. Every damn year the US spends a trillion dollars for healthcare, but where in the hell does that money go. I mean i mostly consider myself as a moderate conservative, but I don&#39;t see a reason for the US not to have universal health care, since its already paying for it.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60661752</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:10:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Queens22333</author></item><item><title>Glad I&#39;ve been backing my FA stuff and the art I cherish the most for &lt;i class=&quot;bbcode bbcode_i&quot;&gt;years&lt;/i&gt;, always on the lookout for the day shit hit...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1717363359/crushedcrowd.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; CrushedCrowd: Glad I&#39;ve been backing my FA stuff and the art I cherish the most for &lt;i class=&quot;bbcode bbcode_i&quot;&gt;years&lt;/i&gt;, always on the lookout for the day shit hits the fan on this website. I hope Dragoneer&#39;s demise doesn&#39;t mean that FA will go down the gutter, but at least we have other alternatives available right now.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It&#39;s disheartening to know the story behind his death. Unfortunately, instead of we seeing an investment being made to build a NHS in the USA, we are actually witnessing the corporate lobbies trying to destroy the public healthcare systems in other countries. Here in mine, most public obstetrics ER are not working during this month, because of a lack of health personnel available to work during the Summer holidays season. Just the other day, a pregnant woman who had a spontaneous abortion was left to die with a severe haemorrhage at the doors of a hospital, because she was denied entry. She was saved from death when she was taken by the firefighters to another healthcare unit, more than 100km away from her home. This would be something unthinkable to happen just a few years ago.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Let us brace ourselves for the times to come, because there&#39;s definitely something eerie going on...</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60645328</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 09:34:00 GMT</pubDate><author>CrushedCrowd</author></item><item><title>didn&#39;t know him personally, but despite he could be a bit controversial, we can&#39;t deny that without him this site wouldn&#39;t exist and I wouldn&#39;t have t...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1637692143/eagledade93.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; EagleDade93: didn&#39;t know him personally, but despite he could be a bit controversial, we can&#39;t deny that without him this site wouldn&#39;t exist and I wouldn&#39;t have the chance to follow artists that I like and make new friends.&lt;br&gt;
It&#39;s awfult that the american health system wasn&#39;t able to help him properly&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
So RIP Dragoneer, and condolences to his family, and for the great loss that this site has got</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60640782</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:50:00 GMT</pubDate><author>EagleDade93</author></item><item><title>As a Canadian I agree. Can&#39;t afford to give the people of the US Universal Healthcare but can spend a billion dollars on a single fighter plane.</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1424255659/kane01.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; Kane01: As a Canadian I agree. Can&#39;t afford to give the people of the US Universal Healthcare but can spend a billion dollars on a single fighter plane.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60637900</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:51:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Kane01</author></item><item><title>Yea.. as a Fellow Brit this also has to stop in America.. its truly disgusting</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1615235856/speedybolt.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; speedybolt: Yea.. as a Fellow Brit this also has to stop in America.. its truly disgusting</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636378</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:24:00 GMT</pubDate><author>speedybolt</author></item><item><title>Speaking as an Aussie, I couldn’t agree more.</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1643526119/raptorialshifter.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; RaptorialShifter: Speaking as an Aussie, I couldn’t agree more.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636316</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:04:00 GMT</pubDate><author>RaptorialShifter</author></item><item><title>R.I.P. Dragoneer, I met him once and bought a FurAffinity T-shirt.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Speaking as a Brit, Americans have every, every right to be furious about ...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1565030597/desiringchange.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; desiring_change: R.I.P. Dragoneer, I met him once and bought a FurAffinity T-shirt.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Speaking as a Brit, Americans have every, every right to be furious about their healthcare system.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636184</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 15:27:00 GMT</pubDate><author>desiring_change</author></item><item><title>This system is a terrible mess, when my appendix went bad in 2008 they chased me for a credit card, drugged up and woken from what little sleep I coul...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1590413792/arcturax.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; arcturax: This system is a terrible mess, when my appendix went bad in 2008 they chased me for a credit card, drugged up and woken from what little sleep I could get laying on a gurney in a waiting area just to get me a room. Just recently getting a very stubborn wart treated, they had to cut a piece of skin.  I got charged $120 for a tiny disposable blade used to cut a few mm of skin off, and it still didn&#39;t solve the problem.  Insurance declined it.  If you are uninsured you are screwed.  They will put you on the back of the bus if you can&#39;t pay.  If he had insurance or money they might, just might have acted faster or prioritized it.  The system is so broken is not even funny.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636145</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 15:14:00 GMT</pubDate><author>arcturax</author></item><item><title>My understanding, you can&#39;t inherit debt, but they can go after the estate so any homes/property sold might get garnished to pay the debts. IANAL, may...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1590413792/arcturax.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; arcturax: My understanding, you can&#39;t inherit debt, but they can go after the estate so any homes/property sold might get garnished to pay the debts. IANAL, maybe ask that badger lawyer guy if you want better info.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636135</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate><author>arcturax</author></item><item><title>As far as I&#39;m aware, debt cannot be transferred in general unless the next of kin decide to inherit the estate. I&#39;m not sure if medical debt gets disc...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1598719639/dsc85.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; dsc85: As far as I&#39;m aware, debt cannot be transferred in general unless the next of kin decide to inherit the estate. I&#39;m not sure if medical debt gets discharged upon death.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636106</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:58:00 GMT</pubDate><author>dsc85</author></item><item><title>Is it true that the money he owed to the hospital gets transferred to next of kin since he died? I don&#39;t know much about the American healthcare syste...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1734542621/aevsivs.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; Aevsivs: Is it true that the money he owed to the hospital gets transferred to next of kin since he died? I don&#39;t know much about the American healthcare system, other than the general notion that it&#39;s AWFUL, but if that&#39;s the case that&#39;s some serious mafioso type stuff.</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636091</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:53:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Aevsivs</author></item><item><title>We have got to file a class action lawsuit against this sorry excuse of a health system we have. Every single doctor these are nothing but quacks. We ...</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://a.furaffinity.net/1735164917/shadow078.gif&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt; Shadow078: We have got to file a class action lawsuit against this sorry excuse of a health system we have. Every single doctor these are nothing but quacks. We lost a founder of a great site because of thier incompetence and negligence</description><link>https://www.furaffinity.net/journal/10925112</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60636083</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:50:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Shadow078</author></item></channel></rss>