<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>News - Immigration and Citizenship</title><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/gov/immiau/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Australia Government, Department of Home Affairs - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:33:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Annual indexation of skilled visa income thresholds from 1 July 2025</title><description>&lt;p&gt;From 1 July 2025, skilled visa income thresholds will be increased by 4.6%. This is in line with changes to the annual 
   &lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; aria-label=&quot;Average Weekly Ordinary Time Earnings (AWOTE) - external link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.abs.gov.au/statistics/labour/earnings-and-working-conditions/average-weekly-earnings-australia/latest-release&quot;&gt;Average Weekly Ordinary Time Earnings (AWOTE)&lt;/a&gt;. This delivers on the commitment outlined in the Migration Strategy, as recommended by the Migration Review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Income thresholds are indexed annually so wages for skilled migrants increase at the same rate as Australian workers. This ensures that people cannot use skilled migration to undercut Australian workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From 1 July 2025, indexation changes will be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 
   &lt;strong&gt;Core Skills Income Threshold (CSIT)&lt;/strong&gt; will increase from AUD73,150 to AUD76,515. This will impact nomination applications for the Core Skills stream of the Skills in Demand visa (subclass 482) and the Employer Nomination Scheme visa (subclass 186).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 
   &lt;strong&gt;Specialist Skills Income Threshold (SSIT)&lt;/strong&gt; will increase from AUD135,000 to AUD141,210. This will impact nomination applications for the Specialist Skills stream of the Skills in Demand visa (subclass 482).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 
   &lt;strong&gt;Temporary Skilled Migration Income Threshold (TSMIT)&lt;/strong&gt; used for the Skilled Employer Sponsored Regional visa (subclass 494) and the Regional Sponsored Migration Scheme (RSMS) (subclass 187) will increase from AUD73,150 to AUD76,515. This is in line with the CSIT and subject to approval of relevant legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New nomination applications from 1 July 2025 must meet the new relevant income threshold or the 
   &lt;a href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/visas/employing-and-sponsoring-someone/sponsoring-workers/nominating-a-position/salary-requirements&quot;&gt;annual market salary rate&lt;/a&gt;, whichever is higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This change will not apply to existing visa holders and nominations lodged before 1 July 2025.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1308</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1308</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Immi</author><category>Immigration and citizenship</category></item><item><title>New Designated Area Migration Agreement for Northern Territory</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On 19 March 2025, a new Designated Area Migration Agreement (DAMA) for Northern Territory comes into effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DAMA is the third DAMA established for the territory and will be in effect until 30 June 2030. It enables employers facing workforce shortages to access an additional 1,500 overseas workers annually across a broad range of occupations that are in critical shortage in the territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/visas/working-in-australia/regional-migration/dama&quot;&gt;Designated Area Migration Agreement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1305</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1305</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Immi</author><category>Immigration and citizenship</category></item><item><title>Systems maintenance 21-22 March 2025</title><description>&lt;p&gt;We will be doing systems maintenance on some of our online systems between 8:30pm (AEDT) Friday 21 March 2025 and 12:00pm (AEDT) Saturday 22 March 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we are making these changes, the following online services may&amp;nbsp;not be available:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ImmiAccount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eLodgement (online visa and citizenship applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visa Entitlement Verification Online (VEVO)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LEGENDcom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australian Trusted Trader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employment Suitability Clearances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detention Visitor Application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APEC Business Travel Card (ABTC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humanitarian Entrants Management System (HEMS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adult Migrant English Program Reporting and Management System (ARMS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education Provider Report (eBIT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visa Pricing Estimator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSI Register&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australian Migration Status (AMS) Training Portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online Payment Portal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you receive a &#39;Service Temporarily Unavailable&#39; error message during this time, please try again after the outage period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your current visa is due to expire on 21 March 2025 and you intend to stay in Australia, ensure that you lodge your next visa application before 8:30pm on Friday 21 March 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologise for any inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1303</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1303</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Immi</author><category>Notifications</category></item><item><title>Don&#39;t get caught in a visa scam</title><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re applying for an Australian visa, be careful of scam migration agents who attempt to deceive and exploit applicants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These scams often happen through social media. Scam agents may charge excessive fees, use fraudulent documents, make false promises, or encourage you to work illegally in Australia.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Australia, it is illegal for anyone to give immigration advice for money unless they are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a registered migration agent with the Office of the Migration Agents Registration Authority (OMARA)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;an Australian legal practitioner.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are applying from outside of Australia, it is best to use a registered migration agent or Australian legal practitioner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can check if an agent is registered by using the OMARA search tool and user guide available on the OMARA website. Every registered migration agent has a Migration Agents Registration Number (MARN). Always ask the agent for their MARN and confirm it on the 
   &lt;a aria-label=&quot;OMARA website - External link&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https://portal.mara.gov.au/search-the-register-of-migration-agents/&quot;&gt;OMARA website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you use a scam agent, you could risk:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;losing money&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;having your visa cancelled&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;being ineligible for future visas&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;being refused entry or banned from Australia&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;being left stranded or sent back to your home country.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about how to identify a scam, visit the 
   &lt;a aria-label=&quot;What you need to know about visa scams page - External link&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/help-support/visa-scams/what-you-need-to-know&quot;&gt;What you need to know about visa scams page&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you know about visa fraud or believe you have been scammed, report it on the 
   &lt;a title=&quot;https://www.homeaffairs.gov.au/about-us/what-we-do/borderwatch&quot; class=&quot;data-haurltarget&quot; href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1294#&quot;&gt;Border Watch page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find more information on the 
   &lt;a aria-label=&quot;Visa scams page - External link&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/help-support/visa-scams&quot;&gt;Visa scams page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1294</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1294</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Immi</author><category>Immigration and citizenship</category></item><item><title>14th edition of The Administration of the Immigration and Citizenship Programs Paper now available</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The 14th edition of The Administration of the Immigration and Citizenship Programs Paper was released on 21 February.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This edition provides updated figures and information on the management of Australia’s immigration program, with data updated to the end of 31 December 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immigration is central to Australia’s national story and identity. The department continues to manage Australia’s immigration program in a way that anticipates and responds to changes in both the domestic and international environment. This advances our national interests and supports migrants and their families.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The department also supports the government’s reform agenda. This reform will deliver sustainable levels of migration and attract migrants that will help fill labour shortages and drive productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a copy of the paper, visit&lt;a href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/what-we-do/the-administration-of-the-immigration-program&quot;&gt; The Administration of the Immigration and Citizenship Programs Paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1293</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1293</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Immi</author><category>Immigration and citizenship</category></item><item><title>Welcoming Australia’s newest citizens</title><description> 
&lt;p&gt;This year, local government councils and other organisations will host more than 380 citizenship ceremonies as part of their Australia Day event programs. More than 20,600 people from over 150 countries have been invited to attend one of these ceremonies. At the ceremonies, our newest citizens will pledge their commitment to Australia and officially become Australians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Canberra, the annual National Citizenship and Flag Raising Ceremony will be on 26 January at Rond Terrace. ABC will televise the ceremony from 9:00&amp;nbsp;am with the Hon Anthony Albanese MP, Prime Minister of Australia presiding over the ceremony. The Governor-General, Her Excellency the Honourable Ms&amp;nbsp;Sam&amp;nbsp;Mostyn&amp;nbsp;AC, will lead the Australian Citizenship Affirmation. This ceremony is an opportunity to celebrate the diversity of Australia, the value of citizenship, and the values that unite us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those becoming citizens will join more than 6 million other Australians who have had their citizenship conferred since the first ceremony in 1949. Australia welcomes every new citizen who pledges their commitment to Australia and commits to our shared values. The department encourages every Australian to engage in active citizenship by becoming involved in their local communities. They can do this through respectful engagement, inclusion and helping others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our continued sponsorship of the Local Hero category in the National Australia Day Council’s Australian of the Year Awards highlights the importance of active citizenship. People show active citizenship through Australian values such as respect, equality, freedom and compassion. Local Hero recipients lead by example. They are role models who encourage others to be active citizens in their own communities and become agents of positive change alongside their fellow Australians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2025 Australia’s Local Hero is selected from the state and territory winners and will be announced on 25&amp;nbsp;January 2025. ABC will live-stream the Australian of the Year Awards from 7:30&amp;nbsp;pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more ideas on celebrating Australian citizenship, visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Celebrating citizenship - External link&quot; class=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/citizenship/celebrating-citizenship&quot;&gt;Celebrating citizenship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1288</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://immi.homeaffairs.gov.au/news-media/archive/article?itemId=1288</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Portfolio</author><category>Immigration and citizenship</category></item></channel></rss>