<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Stock Edge</title><link>https://web.stockedge.com/daily-updates?section=news</link><atom:link href="http://rss.owo.nz/stockedge/daily-updates/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Daily Updates on stockedge.com - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:12:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Dhanlaxmi Bank Limited has announced the appointment of Mr. Santhosh Kumar R as the Chief Credit Officer of the Bank. [Banking]</title><description>Dhanlaxmi Bank Limited has announced the appointment of Mr. Santhosh Kumar R as the Chief Credit Officer of the Bank.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Dhanalakshmi Bank was incorporated in 1927 by group of entrepreneurs at Thrissur located in Kerala. The bank started with a seed capital of Rs.11,000 and with workforce of 7 employee.Much later in 1977, the bank was converted into Scheduled Commercial Bank.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/dhanlaxmi-bank/7566</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/dhanlaxmi-bank/7566</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Bank - Private</category><category>Banking</category></item><item><title>Wipro Limited announced new agentic AI services to empower nations around the globe to develop and deploy artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities. [...</title><description>Wipro Limited announced new agentic AI services to empower nations around the globe to develop and deploy artificial intelligence (AI) capabilities. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Company is engaged in IT Software, Services and related activities. With a track record of several years in IT Services, the company is focused entirely on the global Information Technology business. The services offered by Wipro include Data, Analytics &amp;amp; AI, Applications, Consulting etc.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/wipro/5199</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/wipro/5199</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>IT - Software</category><category>Information Technology</category></item><item><title>The Board of Bajaj Electricals Limited approved CapEx of Rs 300 crores for setting up the Company&#39;s Manufacturing Unit. [Consumer Durables]</title><description>The Board of Bajaj Electricals Limited approved CapEx of Rs 300 crores for setting up the Company&#39;s Manufacturing Unit.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Company is engaged in the business of Consumer Products (Appliances, Fans, Lighting), EPC (Illumination, Power Transmission and Power Distribution) and Exports. It also has presence in premium home appliances and cookware segments with brands like Morphy Richards and Nirlep.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/bajaj-electricals/5690</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/bajaj-electricals/5690</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Consumer Durables - Domestic Appliances</category><category>Consumer Durables</category></item><item><title>Vodafone Idea Limited is in exploratory talks with various Satcom providers including Starlink to enhance the quality of service [Telecom]</title><description>Vodafone Idea Limited is in exploratory talks with various Satcom providers including Starlink to enhance the quality of service&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Company is engaged in the business of Mobility and Long Distance services, trading of handsets and data cards. It is offering voice, data, enterprise services and other value added services (VAS), including short messaging services, digital services, IoT etc.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/vodafone-idea/7532</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/vodafone-idea/7532</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Telecommunication - Service  Provider</category><category>Telecom</category></item><item><title>Board of Directors of Bajaj Electricals Limited has approved formation of a Wholly-owned Subsidiary of the Company in the United Arab Emirates [Consum...</title><description>Board of Directors of Bajaj Electricals Limited has approved formation of a Wholly-owned Subsidiary of the Company in the United Arab Emirates&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Company is engaged in the business of Consumer Products (Appliances, Fans, Lighting), EPC (Illumination, Power Transmission and Power Distribution) and Exports. It also has presence in premium home appliances and cookware segments with brands like Morphy Richards and Nirlep.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/bajaj-electricals/5690</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/bajaj-electricals/5690</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Consumer Durables - Domestic Appliances</category><category>Consumer Durables</category></item><item><title>NBCC (India) Limited has successfully sold 1,046 residential units at Aspire Centurian Park, Greater Noida (W), U.P through an e-auction at total sale...</title><description>NBCC (India) Limited has successfully sold 1,046 residential units at Aspire Centurian Park, Greater Noida (W), U.P through an e-auction at total sale value of approx. Rs 2,353 crores.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;NBCC&#39;s areas of operation encompass three Primary Segments namely: Project Management Consultancy (PMC)- Executing landmark projects in diversified sectors as also Redevelopment Projects for Government, Engineering Procurement &amp;amp; Construction (EPC)- Working in a niche market and constructing Chimneys, Cooling Towers for Power Sector and Real Estate Development- Developing Residential and Commercial inventories for Governments and the Public at large</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/nbcc-india/5290</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/nbcc-india/5290</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Construction - Real Estate</category><category>Realty</category></item><item><title>Tata Consultancy Services Limited partners with Air New Zealand to Drive AI-Led Transformation, Enhance Passenger Experience [Information Technology]</title><description>Tata Consultancy Services Limited partners with Air New Zealand to Drive AI-Led Transformation, Enhance Passenger Experience&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;TCS is an IT services, consulting and business solutions organization that has been partnering with many of the world&#39;s largest businesses. TCS offers a consulting-led, cognitive powered, integrated portfolio of IT, business &amp;amp; technology services, and engineering. This is delivered through its unique location independent agile delivery model, recognized as a benchmark of excellence in software development.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/tata-consultancy-services/6797</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/tata-consultancy-services/6797</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>IT - Software</category><category>Information Technology</category></item><item><title>Aurobindo Pharma&#39;s subsidiary company&#39;s Telangana unit has received Establishment Inspection Report classifying the facility as &quot;Voluntary Action Indi...</title><description>Aurobindo Pharma&#39;s subsidiary company&#39;s Telangana unit has received Establishment Inspection Report classifying the facility as &quot;Voluntary Action Indicated&quot; from USFDA&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Aurobindo Pharma continues to be one of the world&#39;s fastest growing Active Pharmaceutical Ingredients (API) manufacturing companies, driven by cost leadership, flexibility to produce multiple products in the same manufacturing facilities and capabilities in various therapeutic domains. Its API business has ensured the profitability and growth of its formulations business through seamless vertical integration. Its API business is supported by technologically advanced research and development infrastructure, which develops new products and plays a role in the delivery of products to the market. It has built a strong presence in key therapeutic segments such as Central nervous system (CNS), cardiovascular (CVS), anti-retroviral (ARV), anti-diabetics, gastroenterology and antibiotics. Also, it is building a diversified pipeline in high-margin specialty generic formulations segment.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/aurobindo-pharma/6543</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/aurobindo-pharma/6543</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Pharmaceuticals &amp; Drugs</category><category>Healthcare</category></item><item><title>Shivalic Power Control Limited has received an order from Victora Auto Private Limited for the Supply of LT Panels [Capital Goods]</title><description>Shivalic Power Control Limited has received an order from Victora Auto Private Limited for the Supply of LT Panels&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Shivalic Power Control is engaged in the business of manufacturing of electrical panels. It is a technology-driven company with a strong focus on quality, design and product development, which has allowed it to develop products suited to its customers’ requirements.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/shivalic-power-control/111943</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/shivalic-power-control/111943</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Electric Equipment</category><category>Capital Goods</category></item><item><title>Allcargo Terminals’ CFS volumes in February 2025 was 48.5 ‘000 TEUs – down by 10% compared to January 2025. [Logistics]</title><description>Allcargo Terminals’ CFS volumes in February 2025 was 48.5 ‘000 TEUs – down by 10% compared to January 2025.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company is engaged in the business of operating Container Freight Stations.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/allcargo-terminals/110810</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/allcargo-terminals/110810</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Logistics</category><category>Logistics</category></item></channel></rss>