<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Stock Edge</title><link>https://web.stockedge.com/daily-updates?section=news</link><atom:link href="http://rss.owo.nz/stockedge/daily-updates/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Daily Updates on stockedge.com - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:46:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>JTL Industries Limited deploys 250,000 MT of Advanced Direct Forming Technology (DFT) at its facility in Maharashtra to manufacture square tubes up to...</title><description>JTL Industries Limited deploys 250,000 MT of Advanced Direct Forming Technology (DFT) at its facility in Maharashtra to manufacture square tubes up to 350x350 mm and rectangular tubes up to 400x300 mm with a thickness of up to 14 mm&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;JTL produces Black &amp;amp; Galvanized ERW Steel Pipes &amp;amp; Tubes, hollow sections and structural steel that are extensively used in major engineering and construction projects. Over the years, JTL has stayed committed to strengthening technical expertise and working pro-actively with customers to develop innovative products. Today, JTL offers a wide range of integrated tube &amp;amp; steel pipe solutions embracing standard tubes &amp;amp; pipes. An emerging global network, coupled with an ingrained reputation for offering quality products, allows company to draw upon vast resources. These include in-house specialists in material technology and a dedicated team of industry veterans who provide local knowledge and support across various markets globally. Its growing presence in Europe, the Middle East and America further gives it an insight into emerging and mature steel markets.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/jtl-industries/6489</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/jtl-industries/6489</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Steel &amp; Iron Products</category><category>Iron &amp; Steel</category></item><item><title>Varun Beverages Limited has started commercial production of carbonated soft drinks and packaged drinking water at its production facility at Kangra, ...</title><description>Varun Beverages Limited has started commercial production of carbonated soft drinks and packaged drinking water at its production facility at Kangra, Himachal Pradesh.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Varun Beverages is the second largest franchisee in the world (outside US) of carbonated soft drinks (CSDs) and non-carbonated beverages (NCBs) sold under trademarks owned by PepsiCo and a key player in the beverage industry. The company produce and distribute a wide range of CSDs, as well as a large selection of NCBs, including packaged drinking water. PepsiCo CSD brands sold by the company include Pepsi, Diet Pepsi, Seven-Up, Mirinda Orange, Mirinda Lemon, Mountain Dew, Seven-Up Nimbooz Masala Soda, Evervess Soda, Duke’s Soda and Sting. PepsiCo NCB brands sold by the company include Tropicana (100%, Essentials &amp;amp; Delight), Tropicana Slice, Tropicana Frutz, Seven-Up Nimbooz, Gatorade and Quaker Oat Milk as well as packaged drinking water under the brand Aquafina. In addition, the company also been granted the franchise for Ole brand of PepsiCo products in Sri Lanka.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/varun-beverages/83193</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/varun-beverages/83193</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Consumer Food</category><category>Fast Moving Consumer Goods</category></item><item><title>Epigral Limited has successfully commissioned India’s first Chlorotoluenes Value Chain Facility at its Dahej Complex in Gujarat [Chemicals]</title><description>Epigral Limited has successfully commissioned India’s first Chlorotoluenes Value Chain Facility at its Dahej Complex in Gujarat &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Company is primarily engaged in manufacturing and selling of Chlor Alkali &amp;amp; its Derivatives. The Company is also engaged in Trading of Agrochemical products.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/epigral/99976</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/epigral/99976</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Chemicals</category><category>Chemicals</category></item><item><title>Diamond Power Infrastructure Limited has received an order from Adani Green Energy Limited worth Rs. 214.65 crores for supply of Conductors for Khavda...</title><description>Diamond Power Infrastructure Limited has received an order from Adani Green Energy Limited worth Rs. 214.65 crores for supply of Conductors for Khavda Power Project, Gujarat.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Starting out as a fledgling ACSR conductor manufacturing facility in 1970, Diamond Power Infrastructure (DPIL) has emerged as India&#39;s largest and only integrated manufacturer of power transmission equipment and turnkey services provider (EPC). The company&#39;s world class manufacturing facilities, a vastly experienced team of professionals and the ability to pioneer newer technologies have earned it a leadership position in the power transmission &amp;amp; distribution sector in India.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/diamond-power-infrastructure/8686</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/diamond-power-infrastructure/8686</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Cable</category><category>Electricals</category></item><item><title>HEC Infra Projects Limited has received Work order worth Rs 12.50 crore from Ahmedabad Municipal Corporation for upgradation of elctro-mechanical &amp; in...</title><description>HEC Infra Projects Limited has received Work order worth Rs 12.50 crore from Ahmedabad Municipal Corporation for upgradation of elctro-mechanical &amp;amp; instrumentation including Civil works for Clear Water pump house at 200 MLD WTD at Kotarpur of AMC&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;HEC is an EPC (Engineering, Procurement and Construction) and SIRC (supply installation Testing &amp;amp; Commission) contractor in the field of Electrical engineering. The company is registered as a Class-I Composite Category with Central Public Works Department (CPWD). It has also been awarded contractor license from Gujarat Energy Transmission Corporation limited (GETCO) as Class - C Contractor and is a registered EPC Contractor with Indian Farmers Fertilizer Cooperative Limited (IFFCO).</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/hec-infra-projects/14923</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/hec-infra-projects/14923</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Engineering - Construction</category><category>Infrastructure</category></item><item><title>L&amp;T Energy Green Tech Limited (LTEGL) and John Cockerill signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to explore various technologies in Concentrated So...</title><description>L&amp;amp;T Energy Green Tech Limited (LTEGL) and John Cockerill signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to explore various technologies in Concentrated Solar Power (CSP) and Thermal Energy Storage (TES).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Larsen &amp;amp; Toubro (L&amp;amp;T) is a major technology, engineering, construction, manufacturing and financial services conglomerate, with global operations. L&amp;amp;T addresses critical needs in key sectors - Hydrocarbon, Infrastructure, Power, Process Industries and Defence - for customers in over many countries around the world.  L&amp;amp;T is engaged in core, high impact sectors of the economy and our integrated capabilities span the entire spectrum of ‘design to deliver’.  It has unmatched expertise across technology, engineering, construction, infrastructure projects and manufacturing, and maintain a leadership in all our major lines of business.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/larsen-toubro/4964</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/larsen-toubro/4964</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Engineering - Construction</category><category>Infrastructure</category></item><item><title>Carysil Limited plans to invest Rs 500 crore to increase production capacity [Fast Moving Consumer Goods]</title><description>Carysil Limited plans to invest Rs 500 crore to increase production capacity&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Acrysil was incorporated in 1987. The company&#39;s plant is located at Bhavnagar in Gujarat, India and has its registered office at number 312, Bhavnagar-Rajkot Highway, Navagam, Vartej, Bhavnagar, Gujarat. The company is a leading manufacturer of composite quartz and granite kitchen sinks in India.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/carysil/6854</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/carysil/6854</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Household &amp; Personal Products</category><category>Fast Moving Consumer Goods</category></item><item><title>Wanbury Limited is about to launch two new products, for formulation (Branded generic) div., Branded Hematinic Iron tablets WANBUEY C-RED and API- KET...</title><description>Wanbury Limited is about to launch two new products, for formulation (Branded generic) div., Branded Hematinic Iron tablets WANBUEY C-RED and API- KETAMINE HYDROCHLORIDE.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Wanbury was incorporated in 1990 as a private limited company under the name of Pearl Distributors Private Limited. The name of the company was changed to &#39;Pearl Organics Private Limited on January 17, 1991 and the company was converted into a public limited company on August 6, 1991.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/wanbury/5340</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/wanbury/5340</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Pharmaceuticals &amp; Drugs</category><category>Healthcare</category></item><item><title>Canarys Automations Limited has received a work order to transform SEC&#39;s business planning and forecasting from Manali Consulting Pte Ltd. [Informatio...</title><description>Canarys Automations Limited has received a work order to transform SEC&#39;s business planning and forecasting from Manali Consulting Pte Ltd. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The company is a leading IT solutions provider. Its expertise lies in enabling digital transformation for businesses through its comprehensive range of software solutions in the space of Digitalization, Modernization, Automation and Intelligence. Its business operates across two verticals viz., Technology solutions and Water Resource Management Solutions.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/canarys-automations/110982</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/canarys-automations/110982</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>IT - Software</category><category>Information Technology</category></item><item><title>J. Kumar Infraprojects Limited has received a project order from CIDCO Maharashtra for Design and Construction of Coastal Road from Jalmarg Sector-16,...</title><description>J. Kumar Infraprojects Limited has received a project order from CIDCO Maharashtra for Design and Construction of Coastal Road from Jalmarg Sector-16, Kharghar to PMAY Housing scheme near Kharghar Railway Station &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;J Kumar Infraprojects&#39; foundation dates back to the year 1980. The foundation of the business was laid when its Promoter Jagdishkumar M Gupta setup his proprietorship concern under the name and style of J Kumar &amp;amp; Co. Under his able stewardship the proprietary concern made a modest beginning by maintenance of PWD buildings and scaled up to get registered with Public Works Department, Government of Maharashtra as a Class I-A Civil Contractor. With this registration, he started executing civil contracts for government, semi government and other various private organizations relating to infrastructure and civil engineering construction contracts, comprising mainly of roads, flyovers, bridges, irrigation projects, commercial buildings, railway buildings, sports complexes and airport contracts.</description><link>https://web.stockedge.com/share/j-kumar-infraprojects/7202</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://web.stockedge.com/share/j-kumar-infraprojects/7202</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Engineering - Construction</category><category>Infrastructure</category></item></channel></rss>