<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Korea Herald - National</title><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/National</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/koreaherald/National" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>The Korea Herald - National - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:25:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>[Graphic News] Spring blooming delayed by colder weather - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-gif size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;div class=&quot;gif-area&quot;&gt;    &lt;figure&gt;      &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.96042ae94afa4babbdf2aa606802f8e1_P1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the Korea Forest Service’s predictions, which include the blooming periods of plants such as Korean azaleas and cherry trees, 2025’s blossoms will come slightly later than last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Average temperatures dropped to minus 1.8 degrees Celsius from December to February, 2.5 degrees lower than last year. The colder winter is expected to lead spring flowers to emerge a little later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from Jeju Island in mid march, blooming season is expected to gradually spread across the southern regions, reaching Seoul and northern parts of the country by early April. The full bloom periods for different species are predicted as follows: Korean azaleas on April 4 and cherry blossoms on April 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;don@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445524</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445524</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Nam Kyung-don</author></item><item><title>Industry minister to visit US for talks on tariffs, &#39;sensitive&#39; country listing - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-subtitle type02&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industry minister to visit US for talks on tariffs, &#39;sensitive&#39; country listing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.d42378153dce4918a43cfbda1cc726c8_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;South Korean Industry and Trade Minister Ahn Duk-geun (Left) and US Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick pose for a photo during their meeting in Washington on Feb. 27, in this file photo released by the South Korean industry ministry. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;South Korean Industry and Trade Minister Ahn Duk-geun (Left) and US Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick pose for a photo during their meeting in Washington on Feb. 27, in this file photo released by the South Korean industry ministry. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industry Minister Ahn Duk-geun will visit the United States this week for talks with US officials on Washington&#39;s impending tariffs and its listing of South Korea as a &quot;sensitive&quot; country, his ministry said Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahn will visit Washington on Thursday and Friday, just three weeks after his previous trip to the US capital, for another meeting with US Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick on the &quot;reciprocal tariffs&quot; the Trump administration plans to impose on April 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahn will highlight South Korean businesses&#39; contributions to the US economy through jobs and investments, and call for Washington&#39;s nondiscriminatory treatment of South Korea under its new tariff scheme, his ministry said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The minister also plans to meet with US Energy Secretary Chris Wright to request the Department of Energy&#39;s removal of South Korea from its &quot;sensitive and other designated countries list,&quot; a designation that has led to concerns about possible new restrictions on scientific and technological cooperation between Seoul and Washington.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We will stress that South Korea-US cooperation in strategic industries, such as shipbuilding, energy and advanced industries, is very important at this time, and ask the US to minimize any negative impact on South Korean businesses from US tariff measures and other trade policies,&quot; Ahn said. (Yonhap)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445503</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445503</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:06:33 GMT</pubDate><author>Yonhap</author></item><item><title>Keeping memory alive - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-mtitle type02&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gwangju’s battle to restore historic landmark nearly over&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.a9577a313cf84821b49a4c6ea37d898e_P1.png&quot; alt=&quot;People walk past the restoration site of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office in Gwangju on Feb. 12. The sign reads &amp;quot;This is the former South Jeolla Provincial Office, the final stronghold of the May 18 Democratic Uprising. We will ensure a proper restoration, as you have waited a long time.&amp;quot;  (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;People walk past the restoration site of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office in Gwangju on Feb. 12. The sign reads &quot;This is the former South Jeolla Provincial Office, the final stronghold of the May 18 Democratic Uprising. We will ensure a proper restoration, as you have waited a long time.&quot;  (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.6d164446888c47b68c4e0434b5edca1e_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On May 18, 2020, a ceremony marking the 40th anniversary of the May 18 Democratic Uprising was held at Geumnam-ro Square in front of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office in Gwangju. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;On May 18, 2020, a ceremony marking the 40th anniversary of the May 18 Democratic Uprising was held at Geumnam-ro Square in front of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office in Gwangju. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.0b1f02874d734b71acf3dc2b65f06785_P1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Citizens gather at a square in front of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office in Gwangju on May 15, 1980, to protest againt martial law and military dictatorship. (5.18 Archives)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Citizens gather at a square in front of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office in Gwangju on May 15, 1980, to protest againt martial law and military dictatorship. (5.18 Archives)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GWANGJU -- In the heart of Gwangju, a decade-long struggle to preserve a site of immense historical significance is finally nearing its conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The former South Jeolla Provincial Office, a key landmark of the 1980 Gwangju Democratic Uprising, was partially demolished in 2015 before protests halted its destruction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, after years of fierce opposition, discussions and even a fire that threatened to derail restoration efforts, the project is set to be completed in the second half of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among those who fought tirelessly to protect the building are the mothers of those who lost their lives during the pro-democracy movement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In protest, those opposed to the demolition, including the members of the Mothers of May, the mothers of those who died in the Gwangju Uprising, shaved their heads, held demonstrations and mobilized public pressure to halt the demolition. Their efforts eventually led to a reversal of government plans and the decision to restore the annex instead of removing it. In 2023, the restoration process started in earnest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.b71cdf47c96a4829bca4606aedbdb9e9_P1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Culture Minister Yu In-chon meets with the representatives of the Guardians of the Former South Jeolla Provincial Office Restoration, who are family members of  the victims who lost their lives during the pro-democracy movement on May 18  in 1980, Feb. 11 in Gwangju. (MCST)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Culture Minister Yu In-chon meets with the representatives of the Guardians of the Former South Jeolla Provincial Office Restoration, who are family members of  the victims who lost their lives during the pro-democracy movement on May 18  in 1980, Feb. 11 in Gwangju. (MCST)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Feb. 11, Culture, Sports and Tourism Minister Yu In-chon met with the representatives of the Guardians of the Former South Jeolla Provincial Office Restoration, who are family members of the victims who lost their lives during the Gwangju Pro-democracy Movement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s been 10 years. When we first started this, we did not expect to take this long. ... In the meantime, we shaved our heads and went on a hunger strike,” Chu Hye-seong, the leader of Mothers of May, also a member of the Guardians, told Yu, urging him to closely oversee the restoration process. Chu’s husband suffered from illnesses caused by torture inflicted on him during the uprising.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Right now, our priority is restoration. Once it&#39;s completed later this year, we will focus on transforming the venue into a museum dedicated to democratic movements and history. We will make great efforts to develop meaningful content to fill this space,&quot; Yu stated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.a83741e96edf418a97a5874b4418c064_P1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;This photo, taken Feb. 12, shows the National Asian Culture Center, located adjacent to the restoration site of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office. (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This photo, taken Feb. 12, shows the National Asian Culture Center, located adjacent to the restoration site of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office. (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The demolition was initially intended to help the city move forward from its painful past while creating a new symbol of cultural progress with the establishment of the Asia Culture Center. The ACC, now renamed National Asian Culture Center, opened in 2015. It was envisioned as a major hub for Asian arts, cultural exchange and creative industries, to bring contemporary art exhibitions, performances and research institutes to Gwangju. The demolished part — 24 meters out of the 54-meter-long annex — was supposed to serve as the new gate for the modern culture center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.41c5d995d137461284a8966d25ec376c_P1.png&quot; alt=&quot;This photo, taken  Feb. 12, shows an office inside the Provincial Police Headquarters within the the former South Jeolla Provincial Office complex. (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This photo, taken  Feb. 12, shows an office inside the Provincial Police Headquarters within the the former South Jeolla Provincial Office complex. (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.d66819f4764340308376f36a90edc3e3_P1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;This photo, taken Feb. 12, captures the interior of  the Provincial Police Headquarters of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office, where restoration work is currently underway. (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This photo, taken Feb. 12, captures the interior of  the Provincial Police Headquarters of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office, where restoration work is currently underway. (Park Ga-young/The Korea Herald)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After years of debates, a consensus was reached to restore the original form as a reminder of what it costs to keep the nation’s democracy. In October 2023, the government announced a plan to restore the six designated buildings — including the main and annex buildings of the former South Jeolla Provincial Office, the government conference room, the main and civil affairs office of the Provincial Police Headquarters, and Sangmugwan Hall — to their original state in May 1980. The interior and exterior structures, as well as the connecting passageways, were to be restored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When completed, the Main Building will showcase the 10-day struggle from May 18 to May 27, 1980; the Provincial Police Headquarters will focus on the stories of citizens who participated in the uprising.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sangmugwan Hall, which temporarily housed the bodies of victims during the Gwangju Uprising, will serve as a permanent memorial space. This location is also central to Nobel Prize winner Han Kang’s novel &quot;Human Acts,&quot; which powerfully depicts the trauma, resilience and suffering of those involved in the uprising. The novel’s harrowing accounts of victims’ bodies being temporarily laid in Sangmugwan have been instrumental in raising global awareness of the historical significance of this site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.927143b6ae674132bec67e489fa646da_P1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Coffins holding the victims of the Gwangju Democratic Uprising are placed inside Sangmugwan Hall in this photo taken on May 23, 1980. Previously, the hall served as a gymnasium for police officers under the Jeollanam-do Provincial Police Agency. It is also one of the key settings in Han Kang&#39;s novel &amp;quot;Human Acts,&amp;quot; which vividly portrays the tragic events of the uprising. (5.18 Archives)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Coffins holding the victims of the Gwangju Democratic Uprising are placed inside Sangmugwan Hall in this photo taken on May 23, 1980. Previously, the hall served as a gymnasium for police officers under the Jeollanam-do Provincial Police Agency. It is also one of the key settings in Han Kang&#39;s novel &quot;Human Acts,&quot; which vividly portrays the tragic events of the uprising. (5.18 Archives)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mothers of May &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, as the Mothers of May await the completion of the restoration later this year, they have found a new path to healing in recent years: singing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2022, all 15 members have participated in &quot;Songs of the Mothers of May,&quot; a performance that transforms 40 years of grief and longing into music. They have performed at the ACC in Gwangju and across the country. In May and June of last year, the group commemorated both Jeju’s 4.3 Incident and Seoul’s June 10 Democratic Protest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeju’s 4.3 Incident refers to the state-led massacre that took place on Jeju Island between April 3, 1948, and 1954, during which tens of thousands of civilians were killed amid the government’s suppression of an alleged communist insurgency. Seoul’s June 10 Democratic Protest in 1987 was a pivotal moment in South Korea’s fight for democracy, as mass demonstrations against the military regime led to direct presidential elections and the country’s transition to democratic rule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We started the performances to tell our stories through singing. Now that we&#39;re getting older and there isn&#39;t a sufficient budget, we cannot do as much as we hoped. For this year, we will perform once in Gwangju and once in Japan in June, and we will make some changes,” Chu said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.56de95026a51441887a43ab087a8cf59_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mothers of May performs during a cocnert at the National Asian Culture Center in May 2023. (ACC)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Mothers of May performs during a cocnert at the National Asian Culture Center in May 2023. (ACC)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;gypark@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445444</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445444</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:31:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Park Ga-young</author></item><item><title>Exonerated ex-teacher to be compensated for jail time - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.fdc7cd81aaad4c72a8754fd76fcaae12_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lee Tae-yeong (third from right) poses with his wife (fourth from right) on Dec. 11 in front of the Busan District Court, after being exonerated of accusations made against him in 1980. (Photo courtesy of the Korean Teachers &amp;amp; Educational Worker&#39;s Union)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Lee Tae-yeong (third from right) poses with his wife (fourth from right) on Dec. 11 in front of the Busan District Court, after being exonerated of accusations made against him in 1980. (Photo courtesy of the Korean Teachers &amp;amp; Educational Worker&#39;s Union)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 70-year-old former teacher who was recently exonerated of his anti-state charges will receive compensation for being wrongly imprisoned for two years, according to the Ministry of the Interior and Safety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Busan District Court on Feb. 25 ruled that the state should give Lee Tae-yeong 291.4 million won ($200,000) for the damages inflicted by his time behind bars in the 1980s. The initial sentence was handed down in 1980 when then-high school teacher Lee was serving his mandatory military duty in Busan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March of 1980, Lee was arrested by the military authorities for violating the now-defunct anti-communism act and was sentenced to two years in jail. He was accused of speaking in favor of North Korea&#39;s totalitarian regime during his college days, saying then-North Korean leader Kim Il-sung is &quot;no different than (former South Korean President) Park Chung-hee in terms of long-term ruling.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Park was officially president of South Korea for 16 years but maintained dictatorial rule over the country for effectively 18 years after taking power in a 1961 military coup. His revision of the Constitution allowed presidents to run for unlimited terms and abolished direct presidential elections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee had also said the anti-communism act, which the Park administration had enacted in 1961 after the coup, was repressive toward the people and must be abolished. The act was eventually abolished in December 1980, due to most of its content overlapping with the National Security Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After Lee’s release in 1982, the education authorities in South Gyeongsang Province subjected him to a disciplinary committee and took away his teaching license. He was banned from leaving the Busan area while on parole until 1990.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee was reinstated as a high school teacher in 1999, and retired in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The state-commissioned Truth and Reconciliation Commission investigated Lee&#39;s case last year upon his request. It found that he had been illegally detained and probed in the 1980 investigation, a process that included torture and physical assault. He requested a retrial based on the findings in October and was found not guilty by Busan District Court in December.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The defendant&#39;s testimonies are not to be used as evidence, since it can be said that he had been illegally detained without a warrant on March 8, 1980, and had been subject to brutality since. ... Even if he had praised Kim Il-sung, it cannot be said that (the comment) represents a clear danger to the safety and existence of the state,&quot; the court said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;minsikyoon@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445441</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445441</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:28:46 GMT</pubDate><author>Yoon Min-sik</author></item><item><title>Around 30 percent of elementary schools use AI textbooks: data - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.c9d70db9683c49f6a2f1085616a5ee3f_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teachers and students examine AI-based digital textbooks at an exhibition in Busan on Feb. 21. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Teachers and students examine AI-based digital textbooks at an exhibition in Busan on Feb. 21. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Government data showed Wednesday that around 30 percent of elementary schools in South Korea are using artificial intelligence-backed digital textbooks within their first year of introduction, with a comparably smaller number of middle and high schools using them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the 6,339 elementary schools across the country, 1,843 (29.1 percent) have adopted the AI textbooks for 3rd grade English while 1,813 schools (28.6 percent) use them for 3rd grade math, according to the Ministry of Education data submitted to Rep. Baek Seung-a of the main opposition Democratic Party of Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For fourth grade English and math, the selection rates were 29.6 percent and 29.2 percent, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AI textbooks, introduced into public education for the first time this academic year starting in March, are available for subjects of English, math and computer informatics -- referring to IT and computer education -- in the third and fourth grades of elementary school, the first year of middle school, and the first year of high school. Use of the AI textbooks is optional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first leg of a plan to gradually introduce AI textbooks to all grades across most compulsory subjects by 2028, except for art, music, physical education and ethics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For middle schools, 26.9 percent of schools across the country have adopted AI textbooks for first-year English, while 26.1 percent use them for first-year math. Some 24.4 percent of high schools use AI textbooks for first-year English while 23.8 percent selected them for math, the ministry data showed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the 11,932 schools nationwide, 3,870 (32.4 percent) have chosen to use textbooks in at least one of the three subjects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-mtitle type02&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Skepticisms about AI textbooks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing AI-based digital textbooks has been one of the key education policies of the Yoon Suk Yeol administration, but it has faced criticism over what some say is insufficient infrastructure and teacher training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Dec. 17, 2024, survey by the Korean Teachers &amp;amp; Educational Worker&#39;s Union of 2,626 teachers showed that 98.5 percent of the respondents consider the level of training provided for teachers by the ministry would not be enough for the March introduction of the AI textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The usage rate of AI textbooks varies greatly depending on the region. In Daegu, 98 percent of the schools are using AI textbooks for at least one subject.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In comparison, only 8 percent of schools in Sejong and 9 percent of those in South Jeolla Province, and 12 percent of Gwangju schools are using AI textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some suspect that the AI textbook adoption, as it is the conservative administration&#39;s key education policy, is closely linked to the ideological divide in the country. Daegu is a known conservative stronghold -- in which President Yoon garnered 75.34 percent of the votes in the presidential election -- while Gwangju and Jeolla Provinces are vote pockets for liberal factions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data shows that this is not necessarily the case for all regions, as pro-conservative South Gyeongsang Province recorded only a 10 percent usage rate while North Gyeongsang had a 45 percent usage rate. Schools in the Jeolla provinces generally tended to use AI textbooks sparingly, but 21 percent of North Jeolla Province schools were found to be using AI textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;minsikyoon@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445407</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445407</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:02:23 GMT</pubDate><author>Yoon Min-sik</author></item><item><title>False rumors about police spread ahead of ruling - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.d886af91f73d4b9c90ef28f869c2b4ee_P1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Photos of mobile police squad officers with longer or dyed hair have circulated on social media platforms X, Threads, YouTube and Ilbe this week. (X)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Photos of mobile police squad officers with longer or dyed hair have circulated on social media platforms X, Threads, YouTube and Ilbe this week. (X)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;False rumors about police deployed to protest sites is spreading among right-wing social media users, fueling conspiracy theories ahead of South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol’s impeachment ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On social media platforms such as X, photos of mobile police squad officers with long or bleached hair have spread, with claims alleging that such police are not Korean, but Chinese nationals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Referring to a screenshot of what appears to be the AI-generated response of an unknown large language model tool about police grooming regulations, one post on X claimed that a police officer must have “neatly groomed hair,” with male police officers having hair that is no longer than 7 centimeters at the front and does not touch the ears or the collar. The screenshot says police are also not allowed to dye their hair any color except black.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was no source given for the screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Article 5 of the Police Officials Service Regulations only states that “officers must maintain a neat appearance and dress appropriately to uphold their dignity,” without specifying any detailed rules about hairstyles. A police official also confirmed to The Korea Herald that there are no internal rules that prohibit officers from having long or dyed hair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the actual rules differing substantially from those in the screenshot, posts claiming police officers with long or bleached hair are “not real police officers” are still circulating on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A Korean police officer with long hair? As a South Korean national with common sense, this man is 100 percent not a Korean police officer, but is Chinese,” wrote one user on X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.fd277a9596244637bf28294e727fe571_P1.png&quot; alt=&quot;These translated posts criticizing a police officer&#39;s hair length are written on X, alleging that police officers are not allowed to have long hair. (Screenshots of posts from X)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;These translated posts criticizing a police officer&#39;s hair length are written on X, alleging that police officers are not allowed to have long hair. (Screenshots of posts from X)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, conspiracy theories have emerged on social media platforms in Korea, such as far-right YouTube channels and online forums, claiming that the police are “infiltrated by leftists” or “fake Chinese agents.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anti-China sentiment is common among right-wing circles, along with claims that China is &quot;interfering&quot; in Korean politics, economics and media narratives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supporters of the suspended president have clashed with law enforcement during their protests, accusing police of unjustly suppressing their demonstrations while being lenient toward groups they perceive as &quot;pro-China&quot; or &quot;commies.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts warn that fake news, especially those that target law enforcement, should be regulated, as it can lead to the “weakening of public trust in law enforcement and the police force.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Fake news ridiculing or undermining law enforcement can diminish police authority and public trust in law enforcement,” Kwak Dae-kyung, a professor in Dongguk University’s Department of Police Administration, told The Korea Herald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The spread of such misinformation targeting law enforcement must be countered, as it could create social disorder and hinder effective law enforcement efforts. The repeated spread of distorted information about minor issues surrounding the police shouldn’t be left ignored, as it could ultimately extend to a general distrust of the entire police force, which could significantly weaken the ability of law enforcement to uphold social order,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;lee.jungjoo@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445389</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445389</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 07:38:32 GMT</pubDate><author>Lee Jung-joo</author></item><item><title>Anyang to enhance quality of life with innovation, entertainment - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250318.27e73a464cfb4ddc9c771fffca1d44e9_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anyang Mayor Choi Dae-ho speaks about examples of compact cities in other countries during a meeting held at Anyang City Hall in August 2024. (Anyang City)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Anyang Mayor Choi Dae-ho speaks about examples of compact cities in other countries during a meeting held at Anyang City Hall in August 2024. (Anyang City)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city of Anyang, located in the heart of Gyeonggi Province, plans to make a name for itself as one of the most livable cities in South Korea with innovative developments and new cultural activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recognized for its outstanding performance in administrative innovation since 2017, Anyang ranked No. 1 in the Ministry of the Interior and Safety’s annual innovation assessment of 75 local governments for two consecutive years in 2023 and 2024, earning the designation of &quot;self-sufficient city.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city was particularly noted for its urban design changes in residential areas — implemented to prevent late-night crime — and its AI-based safety services for senior citizens, which help emergency workers save lives in the crucial first hour of a medical emergency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Anyang Mayor Choi Dae-ho believes there are more areas where administrative efficiency can make citizens truly happy and enable them to enjoy a high quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is an in-depth look at some of the changes underway for Anyang in terms of urban space and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-mtitle type01&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bakdal Smart City, Indeogwon Compact City projects&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250318.8419fa6413ec414fa6aecd7786b8f1f0_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Anticipated design of Anyang&#39;s Indeogwon Compact City (Anyang City)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Anticipated design of Anyang&#39;s Indeogwon Compact City (Anyang City)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bakdal Smart City project is one of two key development projects that have been ongoing in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city government is set to relocate underground the existing military ammunition facilities in Manan-gu and renovate an area of about 3.28 million square meters into an integrated zone to attract &quot;fourth industrial revolution&quot;-themed global corporations and nurture local talent for new industries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Indeogwon Compact City is another plan to develop a densely populated urban area that integrates industry, housing and culture into a single space, allowing for convenient access to a wide range of facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the city government, this future-oriented complex has the potential to become a new city landmark due to its strategic location and easy access to four subway lines: the existing Seoul Subway Line No. 4; the GTX-C line, which links Yangju (north of Seoul) to Suwon (south of Seoul); the Wolpan Line, which connects Pangyo (east of Seoul) to Siheung (west of Seoul); and the Dongtan-Indeogwon Line. The latter three are currently under construction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though the two city projects are expected to be completed in the late 2020s, the city government believes the transformation will create jobs, including for young workers, revitalize the local economy, secure a new growth engine and promote Anyang as a place filled with creative ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-mtitle type01&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FC Anyang’s promotion to K League 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250318.10854da21e454ab9a924f3afb56eea53_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FC Anyang celebrates its promotion to K League 1 at Anyang Stadium in Dongan-gu, eastern Anyang, in November 2024. (Anyang City)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;FC Anyang celebrates its promotion to K League 1 at Anyang Stadium in Dongan-gu, eastern Anyang, in November 2024. (Anyang City)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, some of the city’s changes that can be felt this year relate to cultural life, such as local sports events and access to lesser-known natural areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After securing the top spot in K League 2 in 2024, FC Anyang has been promoted to the top-tier football league here — K League 1 — for the first time in club history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013, the team had not won a K League 2 title until last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the team&#39;s social media popularity, an FC Anyang-themed documentary film caught many sports fans’ attention by revealing the unique stories of Anyang-based fans who suddenly lost their team when Anyang LG Cheetahs moved to Seoul in 2004, changing its name to FC Seoul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team is set to entertain its supporters with 17 home games at Anyang Stadium in Dongan-gu, eastern Anyang, through October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-mtitle type01&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seoul Nat&#39;l Univ. Gwanak Arboretum&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250318.615dd2315f654e2099f3235851c4924e_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visitors walk along a path at the Seoul National University Gwanak Arboretum during its pilot opening in October 2024. (Anyang City)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Visitors walk along a path at the Seoul National University Gwanak Arboretum during its pilot opening in October 2024. (Anyang City)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The city government plans to unveil hidden areas of the Seoul National University Gwanak Arboretum to the public for the first time in 58 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The arboretum, created in 1967, stretches from Seoul’s Gwanak-gu into Anyang and Gwacheon in Gyeonggi Province. It has been secluded from the public eye since then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the city government, visitors will be able to explore a 900,000-square-meter area of the arboretum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though the exact date for its official opening has yet to be announced, the city government expects to welcome nature lovers from across the country as early as this spring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will also rename the arboretum the &quot;Seoul National University Anyang Arboretum&quot; to better reflect that the entrance for visitors is located not in Gwanak-gu but in Anyang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;sj_lee@heraldcorp.com
&lt;br&gt;fob140@heraldcorp.com
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445343</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445343</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 07:10:25 GMT</pubDate><author>Lee Si-jin, Park joung kyu</author></item><item><title>Democratic Party of Korea begins to weigh &#39;what if&#39; - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-mtitle type02&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who could replace Lee Jae-myung as the liberal presidential candidate?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/rcv.YNA.20250319.PYH2025031908370001300_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Democraic Party of Korea leader Rep. Lee Jae-myung arrives at the National Assembly on Wednesday. Yonhap&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Democraic Party of Korea leader Rep. Lee Jae-myung arrives at the National Assembly on Wednesday. Yonhap&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the impeachment verdict for President Yoon Suk Yeol takes longer than anticipated, anxiety within the Democratic Party of Korea is growing, as its most likely presidential candidate Rep. Lee Jae-myung&#39;s own verdict on an election law case draws near.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee is appealing a jail sentence he received in November 2024 that was strong enough to strip him of his ability to hold public office. If his jail term is upheld on March 26, the Democratic Party leader could see his chance at the presidency slide out of view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Lee could appeal to the Supreme Court, a recent poll showed that voters would not support him as a presidential candidate if the high court confirmed his sentence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The poll published Wednesday showed 51 percent of 1,000 eligible voters aged 18 and older said they were opposed to Lee running for president if he is found guilty in the upcoming ruling, while 44.8 percent said they supported it. The other 4.2 percent said they were unsure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More about the poll, conducted by pollster Research View through an automated telephone survey, can be found on the National Election Commission website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, the Democratic Party has been operating under the premise that the president&#39;s impeachment would be confirmed before the verdict on Lee&#39;s appeal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now Lee himself appears to be rethinking his calculations. Lee met with municipal council members, who were on hunger strike to demand Yoon&#39;s impeachment, on Tuesday in Gwangju, and said the Democratic Party &quot;ought to prepare for a long battle.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Democratic Party lawmakers are beginning to publicly acknowledge the possibility that the Constitutional Court could take more time to reach a verdict. One told The Korea Herald on condition of anonymity that the &quot;wake-up call&quot; hit hard when the court released Yoon from detention last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It&#39;s almost astounding that none of the Democratic Party&#39;s 170 lawmakers thought of it as a possibility,&quot; he said. &quot;Now we are starting to think anything is possible.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Democratic Party Rep. Kim Yong-min on the Assembly&#39;s judiciary committee told The Korea Herald that the Constitutional Court court may hold onto its verdict until before April 18, when two of its justices&#39; terms end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Lee enjoys a firm grip on his party, it still has a diverse pool of potential presidential candidates. Most of them are closely aligned with the former liberal President Moon Jae-in — which has become a fringe faction since Lee Jae-myung began to dominate the party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee Nak-yon, who was Moon&#39;s prime minister, said in his latest public appearances both the president and the Democratic Party leader &quot;need to go.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We need to answer the call of the times, and get rid of both Yoon Suk Yeol and Lee Jae-myung,&quot; Lee, who founded a minor liberal party after drifting from the Democratic Party last general election, said. The remarks from the former prime minister were taken by many within the Democratic Party as making his intentions to run for president official.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kim Kyung-soo, one of the most prominent pro-Moon figures, is on day 11 of his hunger strike urging the Constitutional Court to impeach Yoon. Kim has been working to increase his profile, visiting the Democratic Party&#39;s traditional stronghold of Gwangju, and regularly making press statements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kim Dong-yeon, the governor of Gyeonggi Province near Seoul, touted himself as a candidate &quot;without a liability&quot; in a radio interview Wednesday, taking a dig at the Democratic Party leader. The governor said he would announce whether or not to run for president after the Constitutional Court removes Yoon from office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Assembly&#39;s Speaker Woo Won-shik, who has not publicly hinted at his presidential intentions, is one of the widely speculated potential candidates, highlighted by his surprise meeting with Chinese President Xi Jinping on Feb. 7. Woo said he saw it as his role as speaker to fill in for the absence of leadership on the diplomatic stage while the country awaits the Constitutional Court&#39;s decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;arin@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445310</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445310</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 06:44:20 GMT</pubDate><author>Kim Arin</author></item><item><title>Korea to deploy 14,000 police to Seoul for impeachment ruling - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.930014dae30640c5ace6557a01cac582_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Police officers maintain order around the Constitutional Court in Jongno-gu, central Seoul on Wednesday. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Police officers maintain order around the Constitutional Court in Jongno-gu, central Seoul on Wednesday. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Korea National Police Agency will raise its emergency alert to the highest level on the day of the Constitutional Court’s final verdict on President Yoon Suk Yeol’s impeachment, deploying over 60 percent of the country&#39;s crowd control units in Seoul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is just one of many measures as authorities ramp up security efforts to preempt potential safety threats as it is widely believed that the Constitutional Court&#39;s final ruling nears though an exact date has not yet been released.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the police, it is set to issue a “gapho” emergency — the highest emergency level in the police’s emergency response system, which allows the mobilization of up to 100 percent of all available police personnel — across police agencies nationwide on the day of Yoon’s impeachment ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 20,000 officers in mobile police squads — the units used for crowd control — will be on standby for expected protests, with 338 units mobilized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police reportedly planned on deploying some 14,000 officers in Seoul, an increase from its initial plan of 12,000 officers. They will be able to use extendable batons and tear gas if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mobile police squads will be tasked with managing any large-scale gatherings, intense protests and attack threats on major facilities, including the Constitutional Court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The police said investigators would also be deployed to the court premises to arrest any protestors who break into the court building, adding that there would be zero tolerance for any violence or challenges to public authority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The areas near the Constitutional Court have been designated a &quot;no-fly” zone for drones since March 14, and police plan to deploy an antidrone system there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as the mobile police squads, special police units will be on standby to handle potential threats and emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional security measures in the general area will be implemented on the day of the impeachment ruling, including the temporary closures of one gas station, four construction sites and the rooftops of 22 buildings near the Constitutional Court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A total of 513 Seoul firefighter paramedics and 84 ambulances will be deployed to the four major protest sites -- Anguk Station, Gwanghwamun, Yeouido and Hannam-dong -- cooperating with the police.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On-site medical centers will temporarily be managed to offer emergency treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the event of any medical emergencies, the police reportedly made arrangements with Gangbuk Samsung Hospital, a major hospital about two kilometers from the court, to ensure the swift treatment of any patients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the Seoul Metropolitan Government decided to close Anguk Station on the day of the court’s ruling, it might also close Hangangjin Station on Line No. 6 — a metro station near the presidential residence in central Seoul — if concerns over safety issues arise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the discretion of the respective station director on the ruling day, subway trains may skip stops at Gyeongbokgung Station on Line No. 3; Gwanghwamun Station and Jongno 3-ga Station on Line No. 5; Jonggak Station and City Hall Station on Line No. 1; and Hanggangjin Station on Line No. 6 to ensure public safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;sj_lee@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445241</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445241</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 05:38:35 GMT</pubDate><author>Lee Si-jin</author></item><item><title>What&#39;s behind delay in Yoon Suk Yeol verdict? - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-subtitle type01&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts say delay in court&#39;s decision suggests disagreement among justices&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/rcv.YNA.20250319.PYH2025031910820001300_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This photo taken in central Seoul shows views of a statue of Haechi, a mythical animal believed to have distinguished good and evil, and Gwanghwamun, a main gate of Gyeongbokgung, on Wednesday. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This photo taken in central Seoul shows views of a statue of Haechi, a mythical animal believed to have distinguished good and evil, and Gwanghwamun, a main gate of Gyeongbokgung, on Wednesday. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Constitutional Court&#39;s deliberation on the motion to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol is taking longer than expected, as more than three weeks have passed since hearings ended in late February.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deliberations in the impeachment cases of former presidents Park Geun-hye and Roh Moo-hyun concluded within two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although Justice Cheong Hyung-sik, who presides over the case, stressed in December a speedy ruling on the case of Yoon and his short-lived martial law imposition, the court bench has yet to announce the date for its final verdict as of press time. The court typically announces verdict dates at least two or three weekdays in advance, meaning without an announcement Wednesday, it will likely be delivered next week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speculations abound over why the court&#39;s decision is being delayed. The court only told reporters that it would announce the verdict date after it notifies both the parliament and Yoon&#39;s representatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Representing the National Assembly in the impeachment trial of Justice Minister Park Sung-jae on Tuesday, Democratic Party of Korea Rep. Jung Chung-rae, asked the court to &quot;swiftly confirm the date of President Yoon&#39;s impeachment ruling.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A majority opinion of at least six of eight justices is required to uphold an impeachment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kim Seon-taek, a professor of law at Korea University who specializes in constitutional law, said the amount of time it was taking suggested a lack of consensus among the justices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The court should have already completed writing its opinion given the time it takes to do so,&quot; he told The Korea Herald.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kim suggested that even if at least six justices agree to uphold Yoon&#39;s impeachment, one or two justices who oppose the president&#39;s impeachment may delay finalizing their dissenting opinions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conversely, if at least three of the eight justices oppose impeachment, those in favor might be stalling until left-leaning appointee Ma Eun-hyuk is confirmed, he said. Acting President Choi Sang-mok has so far refused to approve the appointment, despite a court ruling that found his inaction unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/rcv.YNA.20250319.PYH2025031911040001300_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Protesters engage in intermittent fasting in front of Gwanghwamun in Seoul on Wednesday, to protest President Yoon Suk Yeol&#39;s martial law declaration last December. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Protesters engage in intermittent fasting in front of Gwanghwamun in Seoul on Wednesday, to protest President Yoon Suk Yeol&#39;s martial law declaration last December. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rep. Yoo Sang-bum of the ruling People Power Party told reporters Wednesday that he believed justices at the court &quot;have conflicting opinions between themselves while deliberating on the case,&quot; given the verdict is being delayed by more than a week compared with previous cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seoul Mayor Oh Se-hoon also thinks there is likely disagreement on the bench, telling TV Chosun Monday that &quot;some circumstances have arisen that make it difficult to reach a consensus.&quot; He added that some of the right-leaning justices at the court might have diverged from the majority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh is one of the potential conservative contenders if an early presidential election is held.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Kim Dong-yeon, governor of Gyeonggi Province and former deputy prime minister, said Tuesday the court&#39;s delay was due to &quot;its process to reach a unanimous decision to minimize social division.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rival parties are spinning the Constitutional Court&#39;s delay in their favor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruling party lawmaker Rep. Jang Dong-hyeok told reporters Tuesday that there is &quot;no reason for (the court&#39;s) acting chief justice Moon Hyung-bae to delay the ruling if it secured the minimum (of six justices) that have concurring opinions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Rep. Jeon Hyun-heui of the main opposition Democratic Party of Korea told MBC Monday that she believed the Constitutional Court &quot;had already reached a conclusion to uphold the impeachment&quot; while the court is internally working to narrow differences with dissenting justices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the date of the Yoon impeachment verdict, authorities in South Korea are bracing for any crowd violence amid deepening social division. Acting President Choi Sang-mok has urged citizens to peacefully accept the verdict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police will mobilize some 20,000 riot police officers nationwide on the impeachment ruling date, and are working to empty the 100-meter radius around the Constitutional Court. Also, Anguk Station of Seoul subway line No. 3 will be temporarily shut down from the Yoon ruling date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March 2017, four people died on the day of former President Park&#39;s verdict amid fierce protests against the court decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;consnow@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445192</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445192</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 05:15:19 GMT</pubDate><author>Son Ji-hyoung</author></item><item><title>72-year-olds in 2023 are as fit as 65-year-olds in 2011: study - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/news-p.v1.20250319.f73e6b4fc5e8444784fb62c61c58ff84_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;(123rf)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;(123rf)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The physical health of Koreans in their 70s in 2023 was similar to that of people in their mid-60s 12 years ago, according to a study by a Korean medical expert released Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lee Yun-hwan, a professor of preventive medicine and public health at Ajou University School of Medicine, presented his study at a government-hosted discussion, comparing the functional health of senior citizens in 2011 and 2023. He quantified the concept of &quot;healthy aging&quot; using an index he devised based on the physical conditions of the 65-69 and 70-74 age groups for each year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He assigned a score from 0 to 15 based on the number of chronic illnesses, disabilities and mental health issues experienced by each of the subjects in the survey, with higher scores indicating better health. Over the 12 years, the healthy aging index score increased by about one point overall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The average score for a 72-year-old in 2023 was 10.81, according to Lee&#39;s study, which was closest to the average score of 10.88 for a 65-year-old in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2011, the probability of experiencing a serious disability was 4.2 percent for the 65-69 age group and 4.9 percent for the 70-74 age group. By 2023, the figures had declined by 2.4 percent for the younger group and 4.4 percent for the older group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The baby boomers (defined as those born in Korea between 1955 and 1963) tend to be healthier than senior citizens of the previous generation, and they are spending less on medical expenses,&quot; Lee said. He noted that health among senior citizens differs greatly for each person, and said using only age as the criterion for welfare policies can limit their effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tuesday&#39;s meeting, organized by the Ministry of Health and Welfare, aimed to gather expert opinions on how to define senior citizens on the policy level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The South Korean government last month announced plans to raise the legal age for senior citizen status -- a designation qualifying individuals for benefits such as free subway rides -- from the current 65. The legal age for seniors has remained unchanged since the Welfare of Senior Citizens Act was enacted in 1981.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Statistics Korea, the life expectancy in South Korea jumped from 66.1 years in 1980 to 83.6 years in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;minsikyoon@heraldcorp.com&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445160</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10445160</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 04:52:37 GMT</pubDate><author>Yoon Min-sik</author></item><item><title>Police to deploy 14,000 riot officers on day of Yoon&#39;s impeachment ruling - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/rcv.YNA.20250318.PYH2025031819350001300_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Police officers conduct riot control training in this photo released by the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency on Tuesday. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Police officers conduct riot control training in this photo released by the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency on Tuesday. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police will deploy about 14,000 riot police officers in Seoul on the day of President Yoon Suk Yeol&#39;s impeachment ruling by the Constitutional Court to respond to possible social unrest, police officials said Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number represents 60 percent of all available riot control forces to be mobilized nationwide under the police&#39;s highest-level security alert, the officials said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court wrapped up the impeachment trial of Yoon over his Dec. 3 martial law declaration late last month and is scheduled to soon decide whether to remove him from office. The day of the sentencing hearing has yet to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police previously planned on deploying 12,000 officers in Seoul but have increased the scale to better cope with unexpected situations that may arise from large-scale gatherings and possible attacks on major facilities, including the court and its judges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In preparation for an emergency, criminal justice police officers will be deployed to the Constitutional Court premises and special police forces will also be on standby nearby, they noted, adding any protesters storming the court will be arrested on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The areas surrounding the court have been designated a no-fly zone since last Thursday but police will deploy anti-drone equipment there to prepare for the possibility of illegal drone flights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Schools, one subway station, one gas station and four construction sites near the court will all cease operations on the sentencing day and access to the rooftop entrances of 22 adjacent buildings has also been restricted, the officials said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January, supporters of Yoon stormed into the Seoul Western District Court in protest against the court&#39;s decision to formally arrest the suspended president. (Yonhap)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444834</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444834</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:52:33 GMT</pubDate><author>Yonhap</author></item><item><title>Govt. to use all available resources to rein in soaring home prices: acting president - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/rcv.YNA.20250313.PYH2025031316820001300_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apartments in Songpa-gu, Seoul (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Apartments in Songpa-gu, Seoul (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acting President Choi Sang-mok said Wednesday the government will use all available resources to curb the rise in home prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choi made the remarks in an economy-related ministers&#39; meeting, noting, &quot;Home prices have been on a recent rise in some parts of Seoul.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;We will view the situation seriously and the related ministries and local governments will cooperate to sternly respond to price hikes in the housing market to ease concerns,&quot; he said, adding the government will take special measures if needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning to global trade issues, the acting president said it was too early to assess the impact of global trade uncertainties on Korean companies, despite the US administration imposing tariffs on all steel and aluminum imports last week, with additional &quot;reciprocal&quot; tariff on their way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, the government will devise measures to lessen the burden on local industries and continue to communicate with the US and other major economies on trade barriers, he was quoted as saying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choi said the government also plans to provide 75.4 trillion won in policy financing to foster new growth engines. (Yonhap)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444781</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444781</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:19:15 GMT</pubDate><author>Yonhap</author></item><item><title>Some &#39;reciprocal&#39; tariffs may not take effect on April 2 under pre-negotiated deal: Bessent - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/19/rcv.YNA.20250314.PRU20250313343601009_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;US Secretary of the Treasury Scott Bessent speaks to reporters before walking into the White House in Washington, US, Thursday. (Reuters-Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;US Secretary of the Treasury Scott Bessent speaks to reporters before walking into the White House in Washington, US, Thursday. (Reuters-Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent said Tuesday that some new US tariffs may not have to be imposed on April 2 under a pre-negotiated deal or negotiation after that date, when President Donald Trump said his administration would levy country-by-country &quot;reciprocal&quot; tariffs on US imports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bessent made the remarks in a Fox Business interview as the Trump administration plans to roll out reciprocal tariffs on the date to match what other countries impose on US goods in pursuit of &quot;fair and reciprocal&quot; trade. The new tariffs are to be pegged to US trading partners&#39; duties, non-tariff barriers and other elements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am optimistic that (on) April 2, some of the tariffs may not have to go on because a deal is pre-negotiated or once countries receive their reciprocal tariff number, right after that, they will come to us and want to negotiate it down,&quot; Bessent said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The secretary said that on April 2, each country will receive a specific reciprocal tariff number that the US believes represents its tariffs, The tariff calculation is being determined by the US Trade Representative and the Commerce Department, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;On April 2, we are going to produce a list of other countries&#39; tariffs, and we are going to go to them and say: Look, here&#39;s where we think the tariff levels are, non-tariff barriers, currency manipulation, unfair funding, labor suppression,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;And if you will stop this, we will not put up the tariff wall. If you do, then we will put up the tariff wall to protect our economy, protect our workers and protect our industry.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He claimed that the reciprocal tariff policy is designed to create a &quot;win-win&quot; situation with US trading partners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Either the trade friction that these other countries have come down, and we get fair trade, and if they don&#39;t follow President Trump&#39;s lead, then he will raise the tariff wall,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The secretary also mentioned &quot;Dirty-15&quot; countries with high tariffs on US goods, but he did not elaborate on those countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There is what we would call kind of the Dirty 15, and they have substantial tariffs,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;As important as the tariff ... some of these non-tariff barriers, where they have domestic content production, where they do testing on... whether it&#39;s our food, our products that bear no resemblance to safety or anything that we do to their products.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;South Korea has been cranking up diplomatic efforts to avoid new US tariffs amid concerns that its trade surplus, which reached $55.7 billion last year, and Trump&#39;s seemingly negative view of Korea as a trading partner, could put Asia&#39;s fourth largest economy into his crosshairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During an address to Congress earlier this month, Trump claimed that South Korea&#39;s average tariff rate is four times higher than that of the US -- a charge that Seoul countered by saying that it stands at less than 1 percent under a bilateral free trade agreement with the US&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;South Korea&#39;s average tariff on its most-favored nations stands at around 13.4 percent -- compared with the US&#39; 3.3 percent on its MFNs -- but that rate is not applicable to countries with FTAs with Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a media interview on Monday, White House National Economic Council Director Kevin Hassett singled out South Korea, China and European countries as those that the US has &quot;persistent&quot; trade deficits with -- a view that added to tariff concerns in Seoul. (Yonhap)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444742</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444742</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:57:55 GMT</pubDate><author>Yonhap</author></item><item><title>Avian influenza antigens found in dead wild mammal for 1st time - The Korea Herald</title><description>&lt;div class=&quot;article-subtitle type01&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Avian influenza antigens found in dead wild mammal for 1st time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-photo-wrap size-l align-c&quot;&gt;  &lt;figure class=&quot;article-img&quot;&gt;     &lt;img src=&quot;https://wimg.heraldcorp.com/news/cms/2025/03/18/news-p.v1.20250318.5ec6245f150c4f75a8842fc20136d993_P1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This Monday photo shows an egg farm in Cheonan, about 80 kilometers south of Seoul. (Yonhap)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;     &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This Monday photo shows an egg farm in Cheonan, about 80 kilometers south of Seoul. (Yonhap)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;newline&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Avian influenza antigens of the H5 strain have been detected in a dead wild mammal in the first case reported in South Korea, the environment ministry said Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bird flu antigens were detected in the body of a wild leopard cat found near a reservoir in the southwestern county of Hwasun, 277 kilometers south of Seoul, according to the ministry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ministry has notified relevant government agencies and conducted emergency anti-epidemic measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is expected to take up to five days to determine whether the antigens are highly pathogenic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, bird flu antigens can be found in mammals that have eaten infected birds. (Yonhap)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444538</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.koreaherald.com/article/10444538</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:10:30 GMT</pubDate><author>Yonhap</author></item></channel></rss>