<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Sustainability Magazine Articles</title><link>https://https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles</link><atom:link href="http://rss.owo.nz/sustainabilitymag/articles" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Sustainability Magazine Articles - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:29:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Inside Microsoft’s Global Water Conservation Initiatives</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/8f43591b9825a46cfeccf7f5fba71312:be0834f1aa6cf8a0bc2b5aa3655c94f7/microsoft-funds-dozens-of-water-replenishment-and-water-access-projects-around-the-world.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft funds dozens of water replenishment and water access projects around the world | Credit: Microsoft&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Microsoft funds dozens of water replenishment and water access projects around the world | Credit: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has made substantial advances in its global water conservation efforts, revealing progress across multiple fronts including new data center designs that eliminate cooling water usage and the successful delivery of clean water access to more than 1.5 million people worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology giant has been working across five strategic pillars since 2020 to guide its water conservation journey, with the ultimate goal of becoming water positive by 2030.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CgEZNJSeofs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Water use reduction innovations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a significant technological breakthrough, Microsoft launched a new data centre design in August 2024 that consumes zero water for cooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This development represents a major step forward in the company&#39;s commitment to increasing efficiency and scaling water recycling and reuse across its operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The zero-water cooling system demonstrates how innovation can drive substantial water reductions in energy-intensive technology infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/4599e729db12275ae970e563aa1888d1:65b2d7fbc29bca7f584f7860615207a2/microsoft-have-a-huge-amount-of-data-centres-all-of-which-require-an-abundance-of-water-for-cooling-purposes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft have a huge amount of data centres, all of which require an abundance of water for cooling purposes | Credit: Microsoft&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Microsoft have a huge amount of data centres, all of which require an abundance of water for cooling purposes | Credit: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Replenishment efforts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&#39;s water replenishment portfolio has expanded considerably, with the company now supporting 76 projects across 25 global locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These initiatives collectively are estimated to replenish more than 100 million cubic metres of water over their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has pledged to replenish more water than it consumes across its global operations, positioning water restoration as a central environmental commitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/96079c61f55a5b24e8eb7aace5cbb4dd:d14d61b54c363a65ce37216303127019/water-replenishment.png&quot; alt=&quot;A global map of Microsoft&#39;s water conservation projects | Credit: Microsoft&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A global map of Microsoft&#39;s water conservation projects | Credit: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Access achievements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;We&#39;ve already met our water access target by providing more than 1.5 million people with access to clean water and sanitation solutions,&quot; Microsoft notes in its progress report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This achievement highlights the social impact dimension of the company&#39;s water strategy, extending beyond operational improvements to address community needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through partnerships with organisations like Water.org, Clean International Inc. and Aqua Clara International, Microsoft has significantly expanded water access in underserved communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Investment in solutions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has allocated US$45m through its Climate Innovation Fund specifically to scale innovative water solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This investment approach complements the company&#39;s operational improvements with financial support for emerging technologies and approaches to water conservation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funding represents a substantial commitment to advancing the broader water innovation ecosystem beyond Microsoft&#39;s direct operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing is clear: the future of water depends on the actions we take today, and we must keep up the momentum.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Policy advocacy&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company is actively working to influence water policy through strategic partnerships with specialist organisations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has joined forces with the Water Reuse Association&#39;s Coalition for Water Recycling and Water Europe to advocate for expanded water reuse and enhanced water security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These partnerships aim to create systemic change in how water resources are managed and protected globally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/1007cebc86223a4d45cf231c7dae8746:1168a3cdef81576912faf14a927987df/melanie-nakagawa-cso-at-microsoft-speaking-at-websummit-2023.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Melanie Nakagawa, CSO at Microsoft, speaking at websummit 2023&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Melanie Nakagawa, CSO at Microsoft, speaking at websummit 2023&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Creating lasting impact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Chief Sustainability Officer, Melanie Nakagawa, emphasised the importance of these initiatives beyond corporate targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;This work is about more than just meeting goals,” she explains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It&#39;s about creating lasting impact. Sustainable water access drives economic growth, strengthens communities, and builds resilience for the future.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company has launched an interactive map showcasing its 89 water replenishment and access projects, providing transparency into the geographic distribution and impact of its water initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and be part of the conversation at our global conference series,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/inside-microsofts-global-water-conservation-initiatives</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/inside-microsofts-global-water-conservation-initiatives</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:00:25 GMT</pubDate><author>James Darley</author><category>Sustainability</category></item><item><title>NetApp: How AI Expansion is Challenging the UK&#39;s Green Goals</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/f8656be5d3ed31a4e9c4af58d54aec55:dc87301ed6ade797bd45c9df7ef58775/netapp-hq-900x636.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NetApp finds that UK tech companies struggle to marry data’s carbon footprint and AI’s data hunger&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;NetApp finds that UK tech companies struggle to marry data’s carbon footprint and AI’s data hunger&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;UK technology companies are grappling with how to &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://technologymagazine.com/articles/netapp-ais-impact-on-investment-security-sustainability&quot; href=&quot;https://technologymagazine.com/articles/netapp-ais-impact-on-investment-security-sustainability&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;harmonise sustainability targets with their aspirations in artificial intelligence (AI)&lt;/a&gt;, amidst difficulties in managing data, according to insights from &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://technologymagazine.com/articles/netapp-gets-sbti-validation-but-is-it-a-really-big-deal&quot; href=&quot;https://technologymagazine.com/articles/netapp-gets-sbti-validation-but-is-it-a-really-big-deal&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NetApp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research shows an overwhelming 92% of IT leaders in the UK recognise the detrimental environmental effects attributed to single-use data – bits of information gathered, stored, but hardly ever used again – and express a strong commitment to curtailing emissions tied to IT operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the enticements of AI compel enterprises to boost their data storage capacities, sparking concerns over their impact on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industry experts predict an average surge of 41% in data volume due to AI initiatives, which could escalate their carbon footprints if not strategically managed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Addressing single-use data&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite these challenges, the imperative to maintain sustainability drives firms to emphasise IT roles in achieving ecological objectives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NetApp&#39;s study notes that 85% of IT chiefs underline data management as pivotal in decreasing their environmental imprint, with the mitigation of emissions playing a central role in tackling the inefficiencies of single-use data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;92% of UK IT leaders are aware of the environmental impact of single-use data&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Business leaders estimate AI projects will cause data volumes to grow by 41%&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;85% of IT leaders view data management as key to cutting their carbon footprint&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;38% of data remains unused in UK tech companies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;30% of IT leaders struggle to identify which data to retain for AI projects&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though many organisations have instituted measures like routinely purging redundant data from their stocks – collectively known as data estates – about 38% of institutional data reportedly still goes unused. The tech companies in the UK find it burdensome to sift through massive volumes of data; hence, they find it more financially viable to expand storage solutions than to optimise existing setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NetApp notes that just over 30% of IT leaders find it challenging to discern which data to keep for future use, particularly for AI endeavours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Today&#39;s findings identify not just a challenge in data management, but a conundrum and a fine balance: British businesses want to reap the benefits and opportunities presented by AI, while reducing the carbon footprint of their data,&quot; says&amp;nbsp;Matt Watts, Chief Technology Evangelist at NetApp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/2f7daea0f6db82e915758c67deb99baf:e2684fd3bbe4c3387601a642d78c2241/matt-watts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chief Technology Evangelist at NetApp, Matt Watts&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Chief Technology Evangelist at NetApp, Matt Watts&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Tackling single-use data is a key piece of this puzzle and businesses must continue to invest more in reviewing and staying on top of their data estates.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Navigating AI implementation and environmental responsibility&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the environmental stakes, British technology enterprises remain steadfast in their pursuit to seize opportunities presented by AI technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/eXdVDhOGqoE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;NetApp’s research discloses that three out of four IT leaders have fine-tuned their data management frameworks to accommodate AI and are gearing up for the inevitable expansion, acknowledging that adept data handling is crucial for AI success. They anticipate a 41% average increase in their data footprint resulting from AI, which represents a significant scale-up for companies that are already handling extensive, oftentimes mismanaged, historical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, more than a quarter (27%) expect this growth to exceed 50%, spotlighting the extensive data demands AI operations necessitate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While awareness around the environmental impacts of AI and data is front of mind for many now, translating that awareness into action is where things get complex,&quot; says&amp;nbsp;Nicola Acutt, Chief Sustainability Officer at NetApp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/39a83c9846f6a69c6d9dc028a12aa56b:3baee2f5b02ce27ff14f46f340146cc0/nicolar-acutt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CSO at NetApp, Nicola Acutt&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;CSO at NetApp, Nicola Acutt&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The answer isn&#39;t necessarily to downsize data, or to make do with less. Businesses require practical expertise, resources and solutions, with sustainability baked in from the very start, to effectively manage their data and ensure more responsible AI implementation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/e9a7be7e8c765c158cd4a58c12314044:571da9827353a1c441cb0369f6864e24/sue-daley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Director at techUK, Sue Daley OBE&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Director at techUK, Sue Daley OBE&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sue Daley OBE, Director at techUK, adds: “It is encouraging to see many taking an active effort to reduce the emissions of IT operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As AI implementation accelerates across businesses, it will be important to further build on these efforts, ensuring that resources and infrastructure are aligned to support responsible growth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/netapp-why-uk-firms-face-an-ai-sustainability-balancing-act</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/netapp-why-uk-firms-face-an-ai-sustainability-balancing-act</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:00:07 GMT</pubDate><author>Charlie King</author><category>Tech &amp; AI</category></item><item><title>Meet Kate Brandt, Google’s Chief Sustainability Officer</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/df69dd70855463d8ad770056b3405270:61d7ab119350012da1c2c413184469b0/sustainability-top-250-women-top10-cms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kate Brandt, Chief Sustainability Officer at Google&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Kate Brandt, Chief Sustainability Officer at Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day, Google processes more than 16 billion searches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s not to mention its millions of servers, billions of Gmail users or trillions of YouTube views.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this company has an enormous impact on the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kate Brandt, Google’s Chief Sustainability Officer, has led its global sustainability efforts since 2018.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kate has been named number one in &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazine/top-250-women-in-sustainability-2025&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazine/top-250-women-in-sustainability-2025&quot;&gt;Sustainability Magazine’s Top 250 Women in Sustainability 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/919bdf3fab46cefc6ab652caa969088f:726110de52f22b5ebbd232056e8cec82/kate-brandt-headshot-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kate Brandt, Chief Sustainability Officer at Google&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Kate Brandt, Chief Sustainability Officer at Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Kate Brandt’s career&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kate graduated from Brown University with honours in 2007 and earned a masters degree in international relations from the University of Cambridge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She worked for the White House Office of Energy and Climate Change as a policy analyst before serving as energy advisor to US Navy Secretary Ray Mabus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2014, US President Obama named Kate the country’s first Chief Sustainability Officer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, she was responsible for improving the sustainability of the government’s buildings – more than 8,800 of them – and vehicles.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/47551f79c979cd5e328e7160cbea3afd:e277ef25fff19f5f8a1870b1636b2d1d/stefan-k-tcpcjzohkeu-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The River Cam flows through Cambridge near the university&#39;s colleges&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The River Cam flows through Cambridge near the university&#39;s colleges&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;She joined Google in 2016 as its Lead for Sustainability before taking on Chief Sustainability Officer in 2018.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kate also became a Member of the Board of Trustees for the National Geographic Society in 2024.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As the climate crisis continues to demand urgent action, women are stepping into leadership roles to drive sustainability across industries,” Kate says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“From tech giants to luxury brands, their influence spans sectors, proving that bold leadership is key to creating lasting environmental and social change.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Leadership at Google&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under Kate’s leadership, Google has achieved many sustainability milestones including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Matching energy use with 100% renewable energy for seven consecutive years&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintaining carbon neutrality since 2007&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Circular packaging for Google products&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Diverting more than 80% of food waste from landfills&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Partnerships with companies including Unilever, the Ellen MacArthur Foundation and Closed Loop Partners.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;She is also steering the company towards achieving some ambitious sustainability goals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By 2030, Google aims to help individuals, cities and other partners to collectively reduce a gigaton of carbon equivalent emissions annually.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yVnD-cv8-5E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the same year, it hopes to reach net zero emissions across its operations and value chain, supported by its goal of operating its data centres and office campuses with 24/7 carbon free energy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also replenish 120% of the freshwater volume it consumes on average across all of its offices and data centres by 2030 alongside helping to restore and improve the quality of water and health of ecosystems in the communities where it operates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate says: “I am grateful to be in the position to lead Google’s efforts to achieve its sustainability goals across our business through both our products and our operations.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Deploying technology for sustainability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are probably hundreds, if not thousands, of technology solutions Google has created that can support sustainability efforts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is leveraging &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/google-expands-wildfire-tracking-to-adapt-to-climate-change&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;machine learning and AI&lt;/a&gt; to address the growing threat of climate change – including tracking wildfire boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tracking uses AI and satellite imagery to map the boundaries of large wildfires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data is then displayed on Google Maps and Google Search alongside information from local authorities to help people stay informed of potential dangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/google-uses-ai-and-traffic-lights-to-fight-fuel-emissions&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Project Green Light&lt;/a&gt; is an initiative designed to reduce stop-go traffic, and the emissions produced by it, by adjusting traffic light timings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Google Maps and Search, the company is highlighting places consumers can &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/e-waste-clothing-plastic-how-google-supports-recycling&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recycle&lt;/a&gt; different items and materials.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/kate-brandt-googles-chief-sustainability-officer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/kate-brandt-googles-chief-sustainability-officer</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:53:30 GMT</pubDate><author>Jasmin Jessen</author><category>Tech &amp; AI</category></item><item><title>Q&amp;A: EY Legal Experts on the EU Omnibus and CSRD</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/98fbb15a6debe10ae1c7ce100ca44778:79dd82d9c19bd36cc56e4ea0cac85940/dsb05382.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero, Michelle Davis featured on the Future of Energy Transition panel&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;At Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero, Michelle Davis featured on the Future of Energy Transition panel&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michelle Davis is Global Sustainability Legal Services Leader at EY and Partner, Law at Ernst &amp;amp; Young LLP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She has been involved in sustainability and clean energy for more than 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her key focus is on helping clients operationalise sustainability so that they can better manage or avoid risk and importantly access value.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/fb8ff105a1d9d9534c939dc00068d0a1:ee625ff0dd0e861af09b57879b80fd2a/dsb05340.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Michelle Davis speaking at Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero 2025&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Michelle Davis speaking at Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero 2025&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her and the team’s clients include some of the largest corporations, banks, asset managers and institutional investors globally as well as governments, public sector bodies and NGOs.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jess Etherington is a lawyer on the Sustainability Team at EY.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/8ea07a246948cb1354dc60e562f5c84f:b54a7d61f4db507d6ba1a3f3130e63be/jess-etherington.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jess Etherington, Sustainability Lawyer at EY&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Jess Etherington, Sustainability Lawyer at EY&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;She is a sustainability regulatory lawyer and works with Michelle to provide sustainability and regulatory advice for clients.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero, Michelle featured on the Future of Energy Transition panel, a discussion highlighting the importance of the energy transition in determining how governments and businesses can build a sustainable and resilient economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michelle and Jess shared their expertise with Sustainability Magazine at Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Could you talk us through the EU omnibus package and its sustainability impacts?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jess&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission last year announced that it had plans to &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/deregulation-how-will-the-eu-omnibus-impact-sustainability&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/deregulation-how-will-the-eu-omnibus-impact-sustainability&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;simplify&lt;/a&gt; some of the existing regulations and directives which had passed through years ago. Its main focus at the moment is simplification of the reporting requirements. As part of its first omnibus package, what it&#39;s proposing to do is simplify the CSRD and the CSDDD, as well as packaging in simplification for the EU taxonomy regulation and CAM as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/41cdc7066549c58e0e83cf61d9d7d510:0b3d90e5400c39c936d3b16d94de8dc1/a7402536.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero 2025 was co-located with Procurement &amp;amp; Supply Chain LIVE: Sustainability&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero 2025 was co-located with Procurement &amp;amp; Supply Chain LIVE: Sustainability&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quite interestingly, what it&#39;s &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/what-does-the-eu-omnibus-proposal-mean-for-sustainability&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/what-does-the-eu-omnibus-proposal-mean-for-sustainability&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proposing&lt;/a&gt; to do is increase the thresholds for the CSRD. This could bring up to about 80% of companies that are currently in scope out of it. It&#39;s quite a substantive and substantial change that it&#39;s proposing, which we really didn&#39;t expect to happen. It&#39;s also reposing to delay the reporting requirements for large entities by two years. In addition to that, simplifying some of the requirements that the CSDDD is imposing in respect of its due diligence obligations for some of the largest entities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot is happening right now. It&#39;s yet to be seen whether this proposal will be enacted as proposed; it&#39;s got to go to the European Parliament and the Council now to be debated. There is a lot of change at the moment including with the current political environment. A lot of our clients specifically are thinking, ‘how do we best deal with these changes?’ ‘How do we best approach it?’ What we are kind of seeing at the moment is potentially a wait and see approach.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We always say what you have to do is not just what the regulation tells you to do, but what your key stakeholders require of you. Even if organisations fall out of scope, but their stakeholders still want reporting on that information because maybe they&#39;ve got used to it or were expecting it, or were recalibrating their own risk assessment because they were assuming they were going to get this information, they may still require it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not as straightforward as just looking at the law. You have to look at what those that are keeping you in business and keeping you valuable want you to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is complex to get your head around at the best of times. Even though the EU is saying that it wants to simplify things, that&#39;s not always as simple as it sounds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/d1n5KSy7aVQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What would your advice be to your clients on that front?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, sustainability should just be embedded in strategy. It shouldn&#39;t be something that sits over here and gets dealt with separately. It does need to be embedded, because there are risks associated with it and key stakeholders need to be aware of those risks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key advice I would give to business leaders right now where there is a juxtaposition between sustainability activity and perceived value fiduciary duties is to have a very clear transition or sustainability strategy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that the only thing that&#39;s certain is uncertainty at the moment around sustainability, so be prepared to change your plan. Have a very clear engagement strategy with your stakeholders and be transparent with them as you adjust and recalibrate your strategy or plan. It&#39;s all about transparency, clarity and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s absolutely critical that sustainability and value are now linked and there is a very, very clear narrative and engagement around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/q-a-ey-legal-experts-on-the-eu-omnibus-and-csrd</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/q-a-ey-legal-experts-on-the-eu-omnibus-and-csrd</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:39:58 GMT</pubDate><author>Jasmin Jessen</author><category>ESG</category></item><item><title>How are GM and PG&amp;E Supporting the Grid with EVs?</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/4c660cf819eac958fe2880a5949c090e:10b6ca3f6bb17f899f5366129325a86b/gm-pg-e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GM&#39;s pilot programme empowers consumers to give back to the grid&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;GM&#39;s pilot programme empowers consumers to give back to the grid&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you know electric vehicles (EVs) can do more than just reduce emissions and serve as eco-friendly alternatives to traditional cars?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through an innovative partnership between &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/gm-boosts-solar-power-and-cuts-natural-gas-at-indiana-plant&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/gm-boosts-solar-power-and-cuts-natural-gas-at-indiana-plant&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;General Motors (GM)&lt;/a&gt; and Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric (PG&amp;amp;E), EV owners are stepping into a new era of energy resilience, efficiency and sustainability.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is the Vehicle-to-Everything pilot programme?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;GM and PG&amp;amp;E&#39;s Vehicle-to-Everything (V2X) pilot programme provides eligible GM EV owners in Northern California with up to US$4,500 in rebates on qualifying GM Energy home products that enable bidirectional charging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This initiative showcases the potential of EVs as multifaceted energy assets, not only capable of powering homes during blackouts but also potentially contributing to grid stability and resilience in the future. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By integrating vehicles with home energy systems, the programme aims to redefine the role of EVs beyond mere transportation, positioning them as key components in a more sustainable and efficient energy ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/H0ahvLZD1YI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;“By unlocking bidirectional charging for Vehicle-to-Home applications, GM and &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/pg-es-electricity-100-greenhouse-gas-free-utility-says&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/pg-es-electricity-100-greenhouse-gas-free-utility-says&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PG&amp;amp;E&lt;/a&gt; are demonstrating that electric vehicles can be more than just a mode of transportation,” &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/renewable-energy/gm-brings-forward-its-target-100-renewable-energy&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/renewable-energy/gm-brings-forward-its-target-100-renewable-energy&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GM&lt;/a&gt;’s CRO Aseem Kapur says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The product experience and the value for customers does not end when a GM EV is parked. The value keeps going without the customer needing to interact with the vehicle at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We call this the all-electric lifestyle.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The future of V2G?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Vehicle-to-Home (V2H) technology provides tangible advantages for individual homeowners, the transformative potential lies in &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/sustainability/v2g-charging-towards-greener-future&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/sustainability/v2g-charging-towards-greener-future&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vehicle-to-Grid (V2G)&lt;/a&gt; applications.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;V2G technology does what it says on the tin, allowing EVs to send power back to the grid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The value keeps going without the customer needing to interact with the vehicle at all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aseem explains: “Imagine thousands of EVs plugged in and ready to provide energy back to the grid when it’s needed most — during heat waves, storms or other demand spikes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This virtual power plant distributed energy resource &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/bi-directional-charging-lowers-the-cost-and-emissions-of-evs&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/bi-directional-charging-lowers-the-cost-and-emissions-of-evs&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can alleviate pressure on the grid, helping to prevent blackouts and stabilise energy supply&lt;/a&gt; and potentially lower costs across the market.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other benefits of V2G technology include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grid resilience: &lt;/strong&gt;By tapping into EV batteries during peak demand, utilities can reduce strain on power plants and enhance overall grid stability&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renewable energy integration:&lt;/strong&gt; V2G technology can help balance the intermittent nature of renewable energy sources like solar and wind&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumer empowerment:&lt;/strong&gt; EV owners gain more control over their energy usage and costs, potentially earning incentives for participating in grid-support programmes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accelerated EV adoption: &lt;/strong&gt;As EVs become valuable energy assets, the economic case for ownership strengthens, potentially driving faster adoption rates.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;“With the right incentives and policies in place, programmes like this one could accelerate the shift toward a more distributed energy model,” Aseem continues.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Making the most of clean power&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kurt Kelty, GM&#39;s VP of Battery, Propulsion and Sustainability, highlights the significance of this initiative in addressing California&#39;s energy challenges. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He points out that a staggering 3,400GWh of clean power was wasted due to supply surpassing demand — an amount sufficient to power 1.3 million electric vehicles for a full year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/ed95cbc345f90a6a0bd7526c58212ffe:1457554abb503cb58f2883fa6d03a025/gm-s-vp-of-battery-propulsion-and-sustainability-kurt-kelty.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Kurt Kelty, VP of Battery, Propulsion and Sustainability at GM&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Kurt Kelty, VP of Battery, Propulsion and Sustainability at GM&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Curtailment is expected to rise, unless we improve energy storage,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That’s where batteries come in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The batteries powering EVs are one part of the solution. They can be charged when surplus electricity is available and they can help power homes during power outages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Batteries aren’t just transforming transportation — they’re empowering customers, stabilising the grid and making the most of renewable energy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What the pilot has taught us&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aseem contends that, by leveraging the outcomes of this pilot programme, GM can collaborate with PG&amp;amp;E to refine the user experience,“ensuring bidirectional-capable vehicles can seamlessly integrate into the grid and be beneficial for overall grid resilience”.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach aims to optimise the synergy between electric vehicles and the energy infrastructure, potentially revolutionizing how we manage and distribute power in the future&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He adds: “While giving customers the ability to use their GM EV as a back-up home generator is an incredible, practical benefit to customers, it is just the beginning of what we can do to help encourage mass EV adoption with this technology.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aseem hopes that GM’s collaboration with PG&amp;amp;E will lay a foundation for other V2G applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/aea00e9e62e66efe899914e7a3d46208:6c75d22460c4764bf92b55b6ce195901/aseem-kapur-chief-revenue-officer-gm-energy.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Aseem Kapur, Chief Revenue Officer at GM Energy&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Aseem Kapur, Chief Revenue Officer at GM Energy&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The PG&amp;amp;E pilot is just the beginning,” he says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;GM’s EV initiatives&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time GM has innovated the EV and energy space in the name of stability and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;GM Energy is forging partnerships with utilities and energy aggregators nationwide to investigate the potential of electric vehicles in bolstering grid resilience and energy security.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As GM Energy advances its bidirectional charging technology and energy management systems, it is paving the way for a transformative future in energy distribution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aseem concludes: “By positioning EVs as versatile energy assets, GM Energy is not only revolutionising the automotive industry but also reshaping the broader energy landscape.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and be part of the conversation at our global conference series,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/general-motors-pg-e-turning-evs-into-home-energy-assets</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/general-motors-pg-e-turning-evs-into-home-energy-assets</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:30:36 GMT</pubDate><author>Maya Derrick</author><category>Sustainability</category></item><item><title>The Global Sustainability &amp; ESG Awards: The Categories, Pt 3</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/ff90bd17ff716116aa5b4183640c1f80:081f224f093eeac7b85a8ad2854e33fb/sus-awards-2025-cms-categories-part-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards - 10 September 2025&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards - 10 September 2025&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heading to 8 Northumberland Avenue in London, &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/awards/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/awards/&quot;&gt;The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards&lt;/a&gt; will take place on 10 September 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The awards honour the trailblazers redefining corporate responsibility, environmental leadership and sustainable innovation. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They recognise businesses, individuals, projects and organisations that are driving meaningful change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From net zero strategies and circular economy innovations to ethical governance and social impact initiatives, the awards celebrate those leading the charge towards a more sustainable future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As sustainability moves from ambition to action, companies are under growing pressure to align with ESG goals while maintaining commercial success.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These awards bring together top executives, policymakers and sustainability experts to highlight groundbreaking projects, showcase leadership and drive forward-thinking discussions on the future of responsible business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entries are &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://awards.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; href=&quot;https://awards.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NOW OPEN&lt;/a&gt; for The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards and close on 2 May 2025. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discover six of the award categories below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Tb-pQYLLdIQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Social Impact Award&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Social Impact Award recognises initiatives that create meaningful and measurable change in society.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winning projects address specific social challenges, from improving access to education and healthcare to tackling inequality and supporting underrepresented communities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These initiatives go beyond surface-level engagement, delivering tangible outcomes that positively impact people’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Brand Campaign of the Year Award&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Brand Campaign of the Year Award celebrates marketing and communications efforts that effectively promote sustainability and ESG values.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winning campaigns go beyond traditional advertising, using compelling storytelling and innovative strategies to engage audiences and drive meaningful change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A successful campaign conveys a clear, impactful message that aligns with the brand’s sustainability commitments. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether tackling climate action, ethical sourcing or corporate social responsibility, the campaign must reflect authentic values and resonate with both consumers and stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/1b9655416c855eac104e76d941d2b525:6d43a14da74012d9b86697c1c7913130/net-zero-klarna-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Klarna won the Net Zero Award at the Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards 2024, collected by Salah and Sara Davidson, Senior Global Marketing Manager at Klarna&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Klarna won the Net Zero Award at the Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards 2024, collected by Salah and Sara Davidson, Senior Global Marketing Manager at Klarna&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Partnership Award&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Partnership Award recognises collaborations that drive meaningful environmental and social change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether between businesses, NGOs, governments or cross-industry alliances, these partnerships demonstrate the power of collective action in addressing global sustainability challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winning partnerships align with the sustainability and ESG goals of both organisations. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strong collaborations are built on shared values, ensuring that sustainability is a central priority rather than a secondary consideration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These alliances work towards a common purpose, leveraging their combined strengths to maximise impact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sustainability Strategy Award&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sustainability Strategy Award recognises organisations that have developed and implemented comprehensive sustainability strategies that drive real impact.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These companies go beyond isolated initiatives, embedding sustainability into their core business operations and long-term vision to create meaningful and measurable change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A winning strategy is one that is fully aligned with the organisation’s broader mission and objectives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sustainability is not treated as a standalone project but as an integral part of business strategy, influencing everything from product development and supply chain management to corporate culture and customer engagement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/e119a19335b04761c04bbfd97ab717e8:13fc1c5cff175c0cf02738a08349ac9a/lifetime-achievement-noel-anderson.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Noel Anderson, Chief Sustainability Officer at American Red Cross, was awarded the Lifetime Achievement in Sustainability Award at the Global Sustainability and ESG Awards 2024&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Noel Anderson, Chief Sustainability Officer at American Red Cross, was awarded the Lifetime Achievement in Sustainability Award at the Global Sustainability and ESG Awards 2024&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Start-Up Award&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Start-Up Award celebrates emerging companies that are driving measurable progress in sustainability and ESG through innovation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These start-ups are disrupting industries with fresh ideas, bold solutions and business models designed for long-term sustainability, proving that responsible business practices and profitability can go hand in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A standout start-up demonstrates how its innovations contribute to measurable sustainability progress. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether through breakthrough technology, circular economy solutions or pioneering business practices, these companies introduce new ways to address environmental and social challenges.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Lifetime Achievement Award (Non-Entry)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lifetime Achievement Award honours a sustainability executive whose career has been dedicated to responsible business and ESG leadership. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This award recognises individuals who have made a lasting impact, influencing industries, policies and future sustainability leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A defining characteristic of the recipient is their significant influence on sustainability and ESG practices. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Their career has been marked by bold decision-making, shaping the corporate sustainability agenda and setting industry-wide precedents that continue to drive change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entries are &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://awards.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; href=&quot;https://awards.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NOW OPEN&lt;/a&gt; for The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards for 2025, entries close on 2 May 2025.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read parts &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/the-global-sustainability-esg-awards-the-categories-part-1&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/the-global-sustainability-esg-awards-the-categories-part-1&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/the-global-sustainability-esg-awards-the-categories-part-2&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/the-global-sustainability-esg-awards-the-categories-part-2&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; of this series.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/feKiLZ9Z1Z4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Essential diary dates for 2025&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the essential diary dates for Sustainability Magazine and its sister publications – Procurement Magazine and Supply Chain Digital.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To follow Sustainability LIVE on LinkedIn, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/sustainability-live-event/posts/?feedView=all&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To enter for the Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://awards.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-2024-dubai/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE Dubai&lt;/a&gt; | 22 April&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-chicago-2025/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE Chicago&lt;/a&gt; |&amp;nbsp; 28-29 May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://live.supplychaindigital.com/chicago-procurement/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Procurement LIVE Chicago&lt;/a&gt; | 28-29 May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://live.supplychaindigital.com/chicago-home/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Supply Chain LIVE Chicago&lt;/a&gt; | 28-29 May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-london-climate-action-week/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE: London Climate Action Week&lt;/a&gt; | 26 June&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE London &lt;/a&gt;| 9-10 September&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/awards/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards&lt;/a&gt; | 10 September&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-climate-week-nyc/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE: Climate Week NYC&lt;/a&gt; | 22 September&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainability LIVE: COP 30 Brazil | 11 November&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/the-global-sustainability-esg-awards-the-categories-part-3</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/the-global-sustainability-esg-awards-the-categories-part-3</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:09:03 GMT</pubDate><author>Georgia Collins</author><category>Sustainability</category></item><item><title>What is bp&#39;s New Sustainability Strategy?</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/b9e94cf8c5df9d156e8bec4f20f8676e:3a2d9def60e7b5e46c99e5aad05ec203/cherry-point-refinery-2021.avif&quot; alt=&quot;bp&#39;s Cherry Point Refinery in Washington, US in 2021 - Credit: bp&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;bp&#39;s Cherry Point Refinery in Washington, US in 2021 - Credit: bp&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, bp’s operational Scope 1 and 2 emissions were 38% lower than in 2019 – but increased from 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/how-could-bps-poor-2024-results-hit-its-low-carbon-spend&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/how-could-bps-poor-2024-results-hit-its-low-carbon-spend&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;downturn in profits&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in 2024, the business announced that it will&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/has-oil-gas-giant-bp-turned-its-back-on-clean-energy&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/articles/has-oil-gas-giant-bp-turned-its-back-on-clean-energy&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;cut its renewable investments&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by more than US$5bn per year and ramp up its commitment to fossil fuels.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It is five years since we introduced a strategy underpinned by our sustainability frame and I am pleased with how far we have come,” says Giulia Chierchia, EVP Strategy, Sustainability and Ventures at bp.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/346571c216236736ab0a36ede2fb5bd0:4ebae61583ac1d06600d1c3e8630bcc3/screenshot-2025-03-19-101436.png&quot; alt=&quot;Giulia Chierchia, EVP Strategy, Sustainability and Ventures at bp&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Giulia Chierchia, EVP Strategy, Sustainability and Ventures at bp&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are now focusing our aims on those that are most relevant to the long-term success of our business and to our net zero ambition.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A new sustainability strategy&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One outcome of bp’s “fundamental reset” in strategy is a “more focussed” set of sustainability aims.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murray Auchincloss, CEO at bp, says in the report: “bp’s portfolio is predominantly oil and gas and we continue to invest in this core business. But the past five years have also seen us build strong positions in lower carbon energies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/P6LojYxqh0U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It&#39;s been a team effort in every way. The energy transition has to be a collaboration between business, government and wider society.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company now has five sustainability aims:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net zero operations:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Bringing Scope 1 and 2 emissions within bp’s operational control to net zero by 2050&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net zero sales:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Reducing the average lifecycle carbon intensity of the energy products it sells by 2050&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Supporting its employees and local communities through the energy transition&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biodiversity:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Support biodiversity where it operates&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Reducing its net freshwater use in stressed catchments where it operates.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, bp’s sustainability reports included a goal of achieving “net zero production”, reducing its Scope 3 emissions across the carbon in its upstream oil and gas production by 2050.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its 2023 sustainability report also contained an aim to increase the proportion of investment it makes into its non-oil and gas businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When its strategy changes were announced, Helge Lund,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/oil-and-gas/in-brief-whats-happened-at-india-energy-week-2025-so-far&quot; href=&quot;https://energydigital.com/oil-and-gas/in-brief-whats-happened-at-india-energy-week-2025-so-far&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bp’s&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Chair, said: “The board believes that this is an important strategic reset for bp and is confident that it, together with rigorous performance management, will deliver improved performance and sustainable value for bp’s shareholders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/68b0b43b77303a1557e9f5f5e94bd88e:59a186648b511cbe1bf04e19a8bde5a3/screenshot-2025-02-26-113518.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Helge Lund, bp’s Chair&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Helge Lund, bp’s Chair&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Over the past 12 months, we have worked closely with Murray and his team as they have developed the new direction, ensuring it reflects the significant changes we have seen in energy markets and our purpose of delivering energy to the world today and tomorrow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This new direction places free cash flow growth, returns and value at its heart.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its 2024 results, the company reported a 35% fall in annual profits to US$8.9bn and a 61% drop in fourth quarter profits year-on-year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Net zero operations at bp&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report says: “Our aim is to reach net zero by 2050 or sooner for Scope 1 and 2 emissions within bp’s operational control (on a CO₂ e basis), including by maintaining ‘near-zero’ methane intensity across our operated producing assets, enabled by supportive government policies.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is targeting a 20% reduction in its operational emissions by the end of 2025 and aiming for between a 45% and 50% reduction by the end of 2030 against its 2019 baseline.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/17ae29d8ee57818dfa227c424f2f2b1f:02c6727e1ef3c1f84bc3b526560b6164/screenshot-2025-03-19-100010.png&quot; alt=&quot;bp’s Scope 1 and Scope 2 GHG emissions within its operational control boundary between 2019 and 2024 - Credit: bp&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;bp’s Scope 1 and Scope 2 GHG emissions within its operational control boundary between 2019 and 2024 - Credit: bp&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, its Scope 1 emissions increased to 32.8MtCO₂e from its 2023 level of 31.1MtCO₂e and its Scope 2 emissions decreased by 0.2MtCO₂e.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Looking ahead, we continue our work on our sustainability frame, including the activities that now fall within our day-to-day work,” Giulia said on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This progress provides the opportunity to simplify our aims, focusing them on those most relevant to our long-term success and net zero ambition.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/how-bp-has-changed-its-approach-to-sustainability</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/how-bp-has-changed-its-approach-to-sustainability</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:47:47 GMT</pubDate><author>Jasmin Jessen</author><category>Renewable Energy</category></item><item><title>Sustainability LIVE Dubai Welcomes Four New Speakers</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/f28ae4de43f069d15f2617e37ee12677:4b97cd30803e471c6f84a3f822af7aaa/sus-dubai-25-speaker-graphics-ahmed-hassan-christina-herden-seneca-cottom-belvinder-soni.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sustainability LIVE Dubai - 22 April 2025&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Sustainability LIVE Dubai - 22 April 2025&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;A must-attend event for industry leaders, sustainability innovators and climate tech experts in the Middle East and Africa, Sustainability LIVE Dubai will take place on 22 April 2025.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Secure your FREE virtual tickets, &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/events/sustainability-live/sustainability-live-dubai-2025/watch-virtually&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/events/sustainability-live/sustainability-live-dubai-2025/watch-virtually&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ahmed Hassan, Sustainability Specialist at Bureau Veritas&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahmed Hassan is a Sustainability Specialist at Bureau Veritas (BV) Abu Dhabi and a member of UNFCCC Roster of Experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At BV, Ahmed provides expert guidance on sustainability strategies, greenhouse gas accounting and climate change solutions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His role encompasses driving sustainable practices for organisations across various sectors, ensuring compliance with international standards and delivering innovative solutions to meet client needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/ec6043ec5d6db606890321fdd0d26b76:9fd200448e0f11bc5d4f9752ff83e0b2/photo-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ahmed Hassan, Sustainability Specialist at Bureau Veritas&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ahmed Hassan, Sustainability Specialist at Bureau Veritas&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahmed is a Certified Sustainability Practitioner from GRI, complementing his expertise in sustainability reporting and adherence to international frameworks. Ahmed is also a Certified GHG Accounting Practitioner and LCA Specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahmed holds a Bachelor’s degree in Environmental Engineering from the Faculty of Engineering, Zewail City, and is currently pursuing a Master’s degree in Oil &amp;amp; Gas Management from East London University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, Ahmed will take part in a fireside chat titled – The Urgency Paradox: No Longer ‘IF’, but ‘WHEN’ and ‘HOW MUCH’.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Christina Herden, Senior Director of Sustainability at HCLTech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christina Herden is the Senior Director of Sustainability at HCLTech. As an experienced sustainability professional Christina is skilled in strategy development, ESG reporting, analysis and CSR initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/a5175b0d97a83f2f6943f4fdef952147:70fa099d652d5215d47607645d186c86/christina-herden008.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Christina Herden, Senior Director of Sustainability at HCLTech&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Christina Herden, Senior Director of Sustainability at HCLTech&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;She also has previous experience in strategic marketing, information technology and services, sales and business planning.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, Christina will take part in a fireside chat.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Seneca Cottom, Head of Sustainability at Alshaya Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seneca Cottom is the Head of Sustainability at Alshaya Group.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over a decade of experience leading operational efficiency and strategy programmes, Seneca has – for the last five years – been driving sustainable transformation in the retail and restaurant sectors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her current role, she oversees sustainability initiatives spanning diverse markets including the Middle East, Turkey and Europe.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seneca focuses on integrating sustainability into core business strategies, championing circular economy principles, sustainable supply chains and eco-friendly operations across Alshaya Group’s portfolio of globally recognised brands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/c7ffd1b64fa63a4e2b4a796e754c92e0:4762745d6329e91552954b556ec60555/20240319-141725-0-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Seneca Cottom, Head of Sustainability at Alshaya Group&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Seneca Cottom, Head of Sustainability at Alshaya Group&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, Seneca will take part in the Sustainable &amp;amp; Responsible Business panel. Alongside her fellow panellists, Seneca will explore the vital role of businesses in advancing sustainability and fostering responsibility as a core value.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experts will discuss practical approaches for integrating sustainability into corporate strategies, from embedding environmental and social goals into day-to-day operations to leveraging leadership to champion a culture of responsibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Belvinder Kaur Sron, CEO at the Malaysian Palm Oil Council (MPOC)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belvinder Kaur Sron, is the CEO of the Malaysian Palm Oil Council (MPOC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her role, she is responsible for positioning Malaysia as the global leader in certified sustainable palm oil and promoting Malaysian palm oil as a healthy, sustainable and ethical choice for consumers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With nearly three decades of senior management experience, Belvinder has been pivotal in promoting Malaysian palm oil globally and advocating for greater transformation in the palm oil industry through sustainable practices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/631e3dcb60db8eb8ff25a1f4d90603eb:e63dcb222c235a4ca4d6114b83a5f5fc/picture1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Belvinder Kaur Sron, CEO at the Malaysian Palm Oil Council (MPOC)&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Belvinder Kaur Sron, CEO at the Malaysian Palm Oil Council (MPOC)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beginning her career at MPOC in 1994, she became Deputy CEO in 2016 and CEO in February 2022. In addition to her role at MPOC, she serves as a non-executive director at United Plantations Berhad, a Malaysian public-listed palm oil company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the event, Belvinder will take part in the Sustainable Supply Chains panel exploring the evolving landscape of sustainable supply chains in the region, offering deep insights into the strategies, innovations and collaborative partnerships reshaping the industry.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Networking opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond insights, Sustainability LIVE Dubai is an excellent platform for networking opportunities with industry experts and peers via the Brella platform.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you attend one of our events in person or virtually, Brella helps you stay up-to-date with the event agenda and network seamlessly with participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t miss your chance to be part of this sustainability event. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/events/sustainability-live/sustainability-live-dubai-2025/watch-virtually&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Get your FREE virtual ticket&lt;/a&gt; now and take your sustainability strategy to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Participating in Sustainability LIVE Dubai, organised by BizClik, was an outstanding and well-coordinated experience. The seamless logistics and engaging virtual platform were top-notch. Seeing how the audience was still able to interact made the event really powerful. I&#39;m grateful for the opportunity to connect with industry professionals and share valuable insights in this dynamic setting.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Essential diary dates for 2025&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the essential diary dates for Sustainability Magazine and its sister publications – Procurement Magazine and Supply Chain Digital.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To follow Sustainability LIVE on LinkedIn, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/showcase/sustainability-live-event/posts/?feedView=all&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To enter for the Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://awards.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-2024-singapore/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE Singapore&lt;/a&gt; | 18 March&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-2024-dubai/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE Dubai&lt;/a&gt; | 22 April&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-chicago-2025/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE Chicago&lt;/a&gt; |&amp;nbsp; 28-29 May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://live.supplychaindigital.com/chicago-procurement/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Procurement LIVE Chicago&lt;/a&gt; | 28-29 May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://live.supplychaindigital.com/chicago-home/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Supply Chain LIVE Chicago&lt;/a&gt; | 28-29 May&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-london-climate-action-week/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE: London Climate Action Week&lt;/a&gt; | 26 June&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE London &lt;/a&gt;| 9-10 September&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/awards/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Global Sustainability &amp;amp; ESG Awards&lt;/a&gt; | 10 September&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/sustainability-live-climate-week-nyc/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sustainability LIVE: Climate Week NYC&lt;/a&gt; | 22 September&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainability LIVE: COP 30 Brazil | 11 November&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/sustainability-live-dubai-welcomes-four-new-speakers</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/sustainability/sustainability-live-dubai-welcomes-four-new-speakers</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:45:10 GMT</pubDate><author>Georgia Collins</author><category>Sustainability</category></item><item><title>Q&amp;A: The Law Chronicle CEO on Sustainability Regulations</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/0de17fa67f82bbdd4d9d456ba3a73f83:a5e24682feccf2613560c26ec2ed29a0/saffron-gilbert-kaluba-ceo-of-the-law-chronicle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saffron Gilbert-Kaluba, CEO of the Law Chronicle&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Saffron Gilbert-Kaluba, CEO of the Law Chronicle&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following her panel discussion on finance and stakeholder engagement at Sustainability LIVE: Net Zero, Saffron Gilbert-Kaluba, CEO and Founder of the Law Chronicle, stopped to speak with Sustainability Magazine about her meteoric rise to influence in the world of sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, Saffron had just begun her studies at university. Fast forward to 2025 and she is the CEO of a sustainability law consultancy, a UN Ambassador and a member of the UK’s Party Parliamentary Group on Entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our Q&amp;amp;A, Saffron spoke about her lifelong dedication to sustainability, how she helps huge financial institutions navigate sustainability regulations, lobbying regulators, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9eKMn6P8k8M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2&gt;I&#39;m here with Saffron Gilbert-Kaluba of the Law Chronicle. How are you doing today?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m doing really well today. I am just so happy that the sun has decided to come out and it’s a beautiful day to discuss sustainability.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such beautiful weather, I think you have to look around the world and see which areas which may not be as fortunate because of the effects of climate change and a lack of awareness when it comes to sustainability, and we have to invest in that for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;You&#39;ve recently come off stage – how was your panel discussion?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found it so amazing and transformative.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in the ESG and sustainability space, sometimes you feel like you are the only one thinking about sustainability, so it was so lovely to be in a room of people with that same goal in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really nice to hear different perspectives as well; not only were there other financial services companies – which I work closely with – but there were also people from building companies and a consultancy company too.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing all the different perspectives was just so refreshing and I&#39;m full of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/0c8c24b97978ce239994d2080c8bf848:9c45e2d985a44c7434248c6e9c0b1940/at-sustainability-live-net-zero-saffron-participated-in-a-panel-discussion-on-finance-and-stakeholder-engagement.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At Sustainability LIVE Net Zero, Saffron participated in a panel discussion on finance and stakeholder engagement&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;At Sustainability LIVE Net Zero, Saffron participated in a panel discussion on finance and stakeholder engagement&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;It would be great to know a little bit more about the Law Chronicle, the sort of work you do, what your role is, and what a day in your life looks like.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m the Founder and CEO of the Law Chronicle. We work with financial institutions – our main aim is to bring together the regulator and the regulated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Often within the regulatory space you’re given different regulations, but it&#39;s not exactly clear what the financial institution is meant to do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You wind up having these financial institutions involuntarily breaking these rules because no one knows where that line is.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, what we try to do is work closely with the regulators, like the Financial Conduct Authority, the Bank of England or &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/what-does-great-british-energy-mean-for-sustainability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/what-does-great-british-energy-mean-for-sustainability&quot;&gt;the UK governmen&lt;/a&gt;t, to make it clearer for our clients.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They can range from credit unions and community banks, to e-money providers and traditional banks, all the way up to asset managers who manage trillions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With our high-end clients, we try to encourage them to make more sustainable investments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have a company, they manage trillions, but in different jurisdictions when it comes to ESG, they&#39;re persecuted in different ways.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some ways they&#39;re being told they&#39;re not doing enough in other ways, they&#39;re being told actually the fact that you followed ESG protocols means that you had lower returns for your investors.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really want to champion a kind of standardised blanket form of regulations that promotes sustainability internationally, not only nationwide, so that the earth is a happier place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s what I do at the United Nations as the Ambassador for the Net Zero Facilities Capital Fund, where I try to make the member states invest sustainably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/r0tUTlbF_aE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How did you first become an ambassador at the UN?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before the Law Chronicle, I ran the Corporate Law Journal. We still run it today, and it&#39;s basically an area in which we analyse the law and the news that is happening today and its legal impacts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A significant part of that publication was about ESG and the different laws affecting the environment and &lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/the-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/the-united-nations-sustainable-development-goals&quot;&gt;the UN’s Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I guess I got noticed because I got a random email one day saying: “Hi, would you be able to come to Geneva? We&#39;d love to have you as an ambassador for our Net Zero Facility Capital Fund.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought it was fake! So I went on LinkedIn and I saw the president of it and I waited to connect. He had hundreds of thousands of followers. Then he accepted me and said: “Pack your bags and come to Geneva!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;That&#39;s an incredible journey that you&#39;ve been on in such a short space of time.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know, everyone asks me if I planned this from when I first started university in 2019, but I just go with the flow. I think as long as you have an idea in mind of what you want to do and what you want to achieve, the opportunities come.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think just having a good ethos at heart will take you to the moon and back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/a7c9031abf37d7992b93195eb0529f77:a116b448ba69d6f8a34af1261c7fce4f/in-addition-to-her-work-at-the-law-chronicle-saffron-also-has-ambassadorial-roles-at-the-un-and-within-the-uk-government.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In addition to her work at the Law Chronicle, Saffron also has ambassadorial roles at the UN and within the UK government&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;In addition to her work at the Law Chronicle, Saffron also has ambassadorial roles at the UN and within the UK government&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2&gt;It&#39;d be great to know a little bit about what your targets are for the year ahead when it comes to sustainability.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest issues when it comes to net zero and sustainability is what I touched on before in terms of there not being standardised definitions of certain areas or procedures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for the year is to campaign on a national and international level to try and push for some standardisation when it comes to sustainability.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m part of the Party Parliamentary Group for Entrepreneurship, and with that we try to lobby the government for our different causes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that role I’m trying to get different officials on board that cannot only make a change on an individual level, but can change things from the top down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always say – not just because I come from a legal background – if you can legislate it or regulate it, it lessens the focus on money, which means we can live a greener future rather than playing profit politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;If you had to give one piece of sustainability advice, what would it be?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about a climate issue or sustainability issue that really interests you or concerns you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, try to search for groups you can join to help make your voice louder, because, as a collective, we can be much more powerful than we are alone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we come together when it comes to sustainability and net zero, we really can make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and be part of the conversation at our global conference series,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/q-a-the-law-chronicle-ceo-on-sustainability-regulations</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/q-a-the-law-chronicle-ceo-on-sustainability-regulations</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:30:57 GMT</pubDate><author>James Darley</author><category>Sustainability</category></item><item><title>Ben &amp; Jerry’s Says Unilever Fired its CEO over Activism</title><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/66f24632ecd596865010e90776e590d2:66449ee0c66b554929f30e6148fb0081/mirko-fabian-bbwtzqomykg-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry&#39;s was founded in 1978 and acquired by Unilever in 2000&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry&#39;s was founded in 1978 and acquired by Unilever in 2000&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://fooddigital.com/retail/unilever-to-sell-off-ice-cream-with-loss-of-7-5k-jobs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://fooddigital.com/retail/unilever-to-sell-off-ice-cream-with-loss-of-7-5k-jobs&quot;&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s&lt;/a&gt; says that parent company Unilever decided to remove its Chief Executive David Stever in a dispute over its activism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company says that Unilever advised on 3 March it was removing David because of his commitment to the brand’s social mission, not because of concerns about his job performance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The allegation is part of a lawsuit where Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s is looking to stop Unilever’s efforts to &quot;silence” its “social mission&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Unilever has repeatedly threatened Ben &amp;amp; Jerry&#39;s personnel, including CEO David Stever, should they fail to comply with Unilever&#39;s efforts to silence the social mission,&quot; Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s filing says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both Unilever and Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s did not immediately respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;About David Stever&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;David joined Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s in 1988 as a tour guide and served as Chief Marketing Officer before taking on the role of CEO.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/da2704f1ab392af738fe856003400813:7d5db117b5bec9c4d2ded06fbb0bf2fe/1691102869935.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David Sterver, CEO at Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;David Sterver, CEO at Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s Board Chair, Anuradha Mittal, said on his appointment in May 2023 that David is “the best choice to write the next chapter in Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s remarkable story”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The brand’s website says that David has been involved in numerous campaigns and initiatives, including commitments to use Fair Trade ingredients, supporting LGBTQ+ rights and fighting climate change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is not currently clear if David still holds his position as CEO.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s social action&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://fooddigital.com/food/unilever-growth-driven-by-innovation-investment&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://fooddigital.com/food/unilever-growth-driven-by-innovation-investment&quot;&gt;Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s&lt;/a&gt; regularly takes public stances on social issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its Core Values, detailed on its website, include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Human rights and dignity: honouring the rights of all people “to love with liberty, security, self esteem, freedom of expression and protest and to have the opportunity to provide for their own needs and contribute to society”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Social and economic justice: “achieving equity, opportunity and justice for communities across the globe that have been historically marginalised”.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Environmental protection, restoration and regeneration: a “positive, life-giving environmental impact”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;iframe id=&quot;ytplayer&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mwZWGaC3fOk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s strives to be a social justice company that makes ice cream,” its website says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Unilever’s relationship with Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&quot;https://technologymagazine.com/articles/how-unilever-is-using-ai-and-digital-solutions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://technologymagazine.com/articles/how-unilever-is-using-ai-and-digital-solutions&quot;&gt;Unilever&lt;/a&gt; bought Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s in 2000. The brand operates as an independent subsidiary.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the acquisition agreement, Unilever agreed to carry on the company&#39;s tradition of engaging &quot;in these critical, global economic and social missions&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agreement requires an independent board to approve any changes made to the product, licensing deals, new markets and social mission statements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2021, Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s announced that “it is inconsistent with our values for Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s ice cream to be sold in the Occupied Palestinian Territory” and it would be ending its relationship with its Israel franchisee.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unilever then sold the Israeli ice cream business, sparking a legal battle that was later resolved.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In February 2025, Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s accused Unilever of demanding it not criticise US President Donald Trump in a lawsuit.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some reports have said founders Ben Cohen and Jerry Greenfield are considering buying the brand back from Unilever.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unilever plans to spin off its ice cream business, including brands Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s, Magnum and Wall’s, by the end of 2025.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ian Meakins, Chair and Non-Executive Director at Unilever, said: “The Board is determined to transform Unilever into a higher-growth, higher-margin business that will deliver consistently for all stakeholders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Improving our performance and sharpening our portfolio are key to delivering the improved results we believe Unilever can achieve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://assets.bizclikmedia.net/1800/b30ec825f0a1bb83f4a3045dfaf06ccf:028011d9cb3a348c0c43ca31cd6da3f8/screenshot-2025-03-19-123825.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ian Meakins, Chair and Non-Executive Director at Unilever&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ian Meakins, Chair and Non-Executive Director at Unilever&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The separation of Ice Cream and the delivery of the productivity programme will help create a simpler, more focused, and higher performing Unilever. It will also create a world-leading ice cream business, with strong growth prospects and an exciting future as a standalone business.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the latest edition of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainabilitymag.com/magazines&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and be part of the conversation at our global conference series, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability LIVE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discover all our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sustainability-live.com/get-your-tickets/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;upcoming events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and secure your tickets today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainability Magazine is a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizclikmedia.com/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;BizClik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/ben-jerrys-says-unilever-fired-its-ceo-over-activism</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sustainabilitymag.com/articles/ben-jerrys-says-unilever-fired-its-ceo-over-activism</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:45:36 GMT</pubDate><author>Jasmin Jessen</author><category>Sustainability</category></item></channel></rss>