<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>NBER Working Paper</title><link>https://www.nber.org/papers</link><atom:link href="http://rss.owo.nz/nber/new" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>National Bureau of Economic Research Working Papers articles - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:08:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>The Short-Run Effects of Congestion Pricing in New York City</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
Starting in January 2025, New York City became the first city in the United States to introduce a fee for vehicles entering its central business district (CBD). Using Google Maps Traffic Trends, we show that the policy increased speeds in the CBD, had spillovers onto non-CBD roads, and reduced estimated vehicle emissions throughout the metro area. Relative to a set of control cities, average traffic speeds in NYC’s CBD increased by 15% following the introduction of congestion pricing, with larger effects during the most congested hours. Roads commonly traversed on routes to the CBD before the policy have also seen an increase in speeds and a decrease in estimated vehicle CO₂ emission rates. Overall, these speed changes reduced realized travel times on trips to and within the CBD by approximately 8%. The increase in speed is greatest in neighborhoods closer to the CBD, with no significant difference between neighborhoods with different income levels.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33584/w33584.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33584</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33584</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Cody Cook, Aboudy Kreidieh, Shoshana Vasserman, Hunt Allcott, Neha Arora, Freek van Sambeek, Andrew Tomkins, Eray Turkel</author></item><item><title>The New Geography of Labor Markets</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We use matched employer-employee data to study where Americans live in relation to employer worksites. Mean distance from employee home to employer worksite rose from 15 miles in 2019 to 26 miles in 2023. Twelve percent of employees hired after March 2020 live at least fifty miles from their employers in 2023, triple the pre-pandemic share. Distance from employer rose more for persons in their 30s and 40s, in highly paid employees, and in Finance, Information, and Professional Services. Among persons who stay with the same employer from one year to the next, we find net migration to states with lower top tax rates and areas with cheaper housing. These migration patterns greatly intensify after the pandemic and are much stronger for high earners. Top tax rates fell 5.2 percentage points for high earners who stayed with the same employer but switched states in 2020. Finally, we show that employers treat distant employees as a more flexible margin of adjustment.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33582/w33582.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33582</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33582</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Mert Akan, Jose Maria Barrero, Nicholas Bloom, Thomas Bowen, Shelby R. Buckman, Steven J. Davis, Hyoseul Kim</author></item><item><title>New Data and Insights in Regional and Urban Economics</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
This chapter surveys new data sources employed in urban and regional economics in the past decade and the insights they have enabled. We first provide a primer on the data sources, including advantages, disadvantages and use cases. Historical data sources include linked census records as well as digitized maps and directories. Contemporary data come from satellites, mobile phones, social media and wikis, posted prices and listings, e-commerce and payment card transactions, newly available administrative sources, and text, among others. We then discuss the advances these data have enabled in substantive areas throughout urban and regional economics, with historical and contemporary examples in each area. We conclude with some predictions and warnings
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33561/w33561.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33561</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33561</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Ran Abramitzky, Leah Platt Boustan, Adam Storeygard</author></item><item><title>In-kind Government Assistance and Crowd-out of Charitable Services: Evidence from Free School Meals</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
Many community organizations provide services similar to government programs, but there is limited evidence how increased government aid affects the use and availability of charitable services. This study examines how greater access to federal nutrition assistance through schoolwide free meal programs affects food bank use within the U.S.’s largest food bank network. A 10 percent increase in access to free school meals reduces the amount of food that food banks distribute by 0.9-1.4 percent, without significantly reducing donations, fundraising activity, or the amount of food available. The reduction of food bank use is only found in areas where relatively few students previously qualified for government aid. Our findings highlight that even safety net programs that serve a specific population and offer distinct services can reduce pressures on charitable organizations, particularly in areas previously underserved by government assistance.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33562/w33562.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33562</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33562</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Krista J. Ruffini, Orgul Ozturk, Pelin Pekgun</author></item><item><title>The Academic Consequences of Affirmative Action Bans Combined with Diversity Targets</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
This paper examines the problem of a college affected by both a legal ban on affirmative action in admissions and pressure to raise enrollment of underrepresented minorities (URMs), as exemplified by UCLA, which adopted a holistic admissions process in 2006 in response to protests over low URM enrollment. The new process increased the URM share of admitted students by about 3 percentage points, but the primary effects of the changes were on admissions decisions within racial/ethnic groups. Within all groups, admission rates for applicants with high SAT scores and low income and parental education declined. Measured relative to UCLA’s pre-2006 revealed preferences, achieving the increase in URM admissions via holistic admissions was roughly 4-5 times as costly as doing so via a simple reallocation of slots between groups. Had UCLA complied with a stricter interpretation of the affirmative action ban, it would have been significantly more costly.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33563/w33563.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33563</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33563</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Eric Zitzewitz</author></item><item><title>The Road Not Taken: How Driving Distance and Appointment Availability Shape the Effects of Abortion Bans</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We use difference-in-differences research designs to estimate the effects of abortion bans on births at the county level, leveraging data on changes in driving distance and appointment availability at the nearest facility where abortion remains legal. We find that bans alone increase births, but their total impact depends on geographic barriers to access. Even in counties where distance and appointment availability remain unchanged, a total ban leads to a 1.0% increase in births, suggesting a chilling effect—potentially due to legal uncertainty, misinformation, or logistical hurdles—that is independent of measurable barriers. However, the effects grow substantially with travel burdens. In counties where the nearest abortion facility was 50 miles away pre-Dobbs, a total ban increases births by 2.8% when distance rises to 300 miles. Limited appointment availability in destination cities further amplifies these effects, resulting in an additional 0.4 percentage point increase in births. The largest increases occur among Black and Hispanic women, those without a college degree, and unmarried women. We do not observe evidence that the effects have diminished with time despite expanded logistical, financial, and telehealth abortion support, underscoring the persistent role that geographic barriers play in abortion access.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33548/w33548.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33548</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33548</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Caitlin K. Myers, Daniel L. Dench, Mayra Pineda-Torres</author></item><item><title>The Optimal Monetary Policy Response to Tariffs</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
What is the optimal monetary policy response to tariffs? This paper explores this question within an open-economy New Keynesian model and shows that the optimal monetary policy response is expansionary, with inflation rising above and beyond the direct effects of tariffs. This result holds regardless of whether tariffs apply to consumption goods or intermediate inputs, whether the shock is temporary or permanent, and whether tariffs address other distortions.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33560/w33560.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33560</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33560</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Javier Bianchi, Louphou Coulibaly</author></item><item><title>Racial Disparities and Bias in Consumer Bankruptcy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We document substantial racial disparities in consumer bankruptcy outcomes and investigate the role of racial bias in contributing to these disparities. Using data on the near universe of US bankruptcy cases and self-reported and manually-identified measures of race, we show that minority filers are unconditionally 12.7 and 2.3 percentage points more likely to have their bankruptcy cases dismissed without debt relief in Chapters 13 and 7, respectively. We uncover strong evidence of racial homophily: in Chapter 13, where trustees have more discretion, minority filers are 2.3 percentage points more likely to be dismissed when randomly assigned to a White bankruptcy trustee than to a minority trustee. Black and Hispanic Chapter 13 filers are the most negatively affected by homophily. To interpret our findings, we develop a general decision model and new identification results relating homophily to bias. Our homophily approach is particularly useful in settings where traditional outcome tests for bias are not feasible because the decision-maker&#39;s objective is not well defined or decision-relevant outcomes or risk factors are unobserved. Applying this framework to our homophily estimate implies that at least 15% of the unconditional Chapter 13 dismissal gap and 53% of the conditional dismissal gap for minority filers is due to either taste-based or inaccurate statistical discrimination.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33575/w33575.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33575</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33575</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Bronson Argyle, Sasha Indarte, Benjamin Iverson, Christopher Palmer</author></item><item><title>Expropriation Without Compensation: Copper in Chile, 1970-1973</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
In this essay, I analyze the nationalization of large copper mines during Salvador Allende’s socialist government in Chile in the 1970s. This is one of the earliest cases “nationalization without compensation.” Chile’s legal argument was based on the novel idea that “adequate” payment should be calculated as book value minus “excessive profits.” In turn, excessive profits were defined, for every year, as profits above 12% of book value. I analyze the economic arguments that led to nationalization, and I deconstruct and critically evaluate the methodology used to calculate “excessive profits” and “adequate compensation.” I analyze the US and multinationals’ response to Chile’s nationalization policies.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33572/w33572.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33572</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33572</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Sebastian Edwards</author></item><item><title>Expert Patients’ Use of Avoidable Health Care</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We measure whether expert patients – those trained as physicians and nurses – have fewer emergency department visits and the reasons for these differences. Relative to similar patients physicians and nurses had 19.8% and 5.1% fewer ED visits, principally due to fewer avoidable visits. The differences in avoidable visits between physicians and other patients were largest for diagnoses commonly requiring prescriptions, which physicians often self-prescribed. Our results suggest that improving access to prescriptions for acute symptoms, more than improving patient education, may reduce avoidable health care.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33573/w33573.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33573</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33573</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Pragya Kakani, Simone Matecna, Amitabh Chandra</author></item><item><title>Should Friday be the New Saturday? Hours Worked and Hours Wanted</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
This paper investigates self-reported wedges between how much people work and how much they want to work, at their current wage. More than two-thirds of full-time workers in German survey data are overworked—actual hours exceed desired hours. We combine this evidence with a simple model of labor supply to assess the welfare consequences of tighter weekly hours limits via willingness-to-pay calculations. According to counterfactuals, the optimal length of the workweek in Germany is 37 hours. Introducing such a cap would raise welfare by .8-1.6% of GDP. The gains from a shortened workweek are largest for workers who are married, female, white collar, middle aged, and high income. An extended analysis integrates a non-constant wage-hours relationship, falling capital returns, and a shrinking tax base.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33577/w33577.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33577</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33577</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Gregor Jarosch, Laura Pilossoph, Anthony Swaminathan</author></item><item><title>Human Capital at Home: Evidence from a Randomized Evaluation in the Philippines</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
Children spend most of their time at home in their early years, yet efforts to promote human capital at home in many low- and middle-income settings remain limited. We conduct a randomized controlled trial to evaluate an intervention which encourages parents and caregivers to foster human capital accumulation among their children between ages 3 and 5, with a focus on math and phonics skills. Children gain 0.52 and 0.51 standard deviations relative to the control group on math and phonics tests, respectively (p&amp;lt;0.001). A year later effects persist, but math gains dissipate to 0.15 (p=0.06) and phonics to 0.13 (p=0.12). We also measure impacts on parents, including both fathers and mothers. Effects appear to be mediated largely through instructional support by parents and not other parent investment mechanisms, such as more positive parent-child interactions or additional time spent on education at home beyond the intervention. We also do not find any crowd-out effects on labor market outcomes, likely since the approach tested is highly efficient, delivering large learning gains in a short period of time. Our results show that parents can be effective conduits of educational instruction even in low-resource settings.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33574/w33574.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33574</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33574</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Noam Angrist, Sarah Kabay, Dean Karlan, Lincoln Lau, Kevin Wong</author></item><item><title>Supply Constraints do not Explain House Price and Quantity Growth Across U.S. Cities</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
The standard view of housing markets holds that the flexibility of local housing supply–shaped by factors like geography and regulation–strongly affects the response of house prices, house quantities and population to rising housing demand. However, from 2000 to 2020, we find that higher income growth predicts the same growth in house prices, housing quantity, and population regardless of a city&#39;s estimated housing supply elasticity. We find the same pattern when we expand the sample to 1980 to 2020, use different elasticity measures, and when we instrument for local housing demand. Using a general demand-and-supply framework, we show that our findings imply that constrained housing supply is relatively unimportant in explaining differences in rising house prices among U.S. cities. These results challenge the prevailing view of local housing and labor markets and suggest that easing housing supply constraints may not yield the anticipated improvements in housing affordability.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33576/w33576.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33576</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33576</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Schuyler Louie, John A. Mondragon, Johannes Wieland</author></item><item><title>Rules versus Discretion in Capital Regulation</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We study capital regulation in a dynamic model for bank deposits. Capital regulation addresses banks’ incentive for excessive leverage that dilutes depositors, but preserves some dilution to reduce bank defaults. We show theoretically that capital regulation is subject to a time inconsistency problem. In a model with non-maturing deposits where optimal withdrawals make deposits endogenously long-term, we find commitment to have important effects on the optimal level and cyclicality of capital adequacy. Our results call for a systematic framework that limits capital regulators’ discretion.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33578/w33578.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33578</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33578</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Urban Jermann, Haotian Xiang</author></item><item><title>The Rise of Healthcare Jobs</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
Healthcare employment has grown more than twice as fast as the labor force since 1980, overtaking retail trade to become the largest industry by employment in 2009. We document key facts about the rise of healthcare jobs. Earnings for healthcare workers have risen nearly twice as fast as those in other industries, with relatively large increases in the middle and upper-middle parts of the earnings distribution. Healthcare workers have remained predominantly female, with increases in the share of female doctors offsetting increases in the shares of male nurses and aides. Despite a few high-profile examples to the contrary, regions experiencing manufacturing job losses have not systematically reinvented themselves by pivoting from ``manufacturing to meds.&#39;&#39;
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33583/w33583.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33583</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33583</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Joshua D. Gottlieb, Neale Mahoney, Kevin Rinz, Victoria Udalova</author></item><item><title>Methane Abatement Costs in the Oil and Gas Industry: Survey and Synthesis</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
There is growing recognition of the relative importance of anthropogenic emissions of methane as a contributor to global climate change. An important source of such emissions in some countries, including the United States, is the oil and gas (O&amp;amp;G) sector. This points to the importance of developing understanding of the marginal abatement cost functions for methane emissions reductions. Scholars have employed a diverse set of methodologies to estimate abatement costs, including engineering cost models, econometric analysis of natural gas markets, and statistical retrospective analysis of state-level regulation. We critically summarize these approaches and synthesize their results. We find significant potential for low-cost methane abatement in the O&amp;amp;G sector in the United States and elsewhere, although claims of widespread negative abatement cost opportunities should be taken with a grain of salt. We also find that the potential for low-cost abatement is not without limit. Whereas it appears that cutting methane emissions in half would be relatively inexpensive, a sharp uptick in marginal abatement cost may occur when reductions exceed 60 to 80 percent below baseline levels. This threshold may change over time with technological advances in remote sensing, which can reduce abatement costs at various levels of ambition.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33564/w33564.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33564</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33564</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Joseph E. Aldy, Forest L. Reinhardt, Robert N. Stavins</author></item><item><title>A Quest for AI Knowledge</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
This paper examines how the introduction of artificial intelligence (AI), particularly generative and large language models capable of interpolating precisely between known data points, reshapes scientists&#39; incentives for pursuing novel versus incremental research. Extending the theoretical framework of Carnehl and Schneider (2025), we analyse how decision-makers leverage AI to improve precision within well-defined knowledge domains. We identify conditions under which the availability of AI tools encourages scientists to choose more socially valuable, highly novel research projects, contrasting sharply with traditional patterns of incremental knowledge growth. Our model demonstrates a critical complementarity: scientists strategically align their research novelty choices to maximise the domain where AI can reliably inform decision-making. This dynamic fundamentally transforms the evolution of scientific knowledge, leading either to systematic “stepping stone” expansions or endogenous research cycles of strategic knowledge deepening. We discuss the broader implications for science policy, highlighting how sufficiently capable AI tools could mitigate traditional inefficiencies in scientific innovation, aligning private research incentives closely with the social optimum.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33566/w33566.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33566</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33566</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Joshua S. Gans</author></item><item><title>Macroeconomics and Climate Change</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
This paper surveys the literature that links macroeconomics and climate change. We organize our review into three categories: (i) loss and damage, which assesses long-run economic costs and non-market impacts from climate change; (ii) mitigation and the energy transition, which evaluates the macroeconomic consequences of shifting away from fossil fuels toward renewable energy; and (iii) adaptation, which explores the economic adjustments necessary to manage heat stress, more frequent severe weather events and rising seas. We discuss macroeconomic frameworks that quantify these structural shifts as well as empirical estimates that guide their calibration. We suggest areas in which macroeconomic research on climate is needed.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33567/w33567.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33567</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33567</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Adrien Bilal, James H. Stock</author></item><item><title>Recovering Credible Trade Elasticities from Incredible Trade Reforms</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We study how trade-policy dynamics affect the dynamics of trade volumes and the implications of these effects for estimates of the trade elasticity. We use data on US imports and trade policy from 1974–2017 for China and Vietnam—the countries with the largest import growth and the largest tariff reductions over the last fifty years—and a heterogeneous-firm dynamic trade model to recover the dynamic path of the trade elasticity following an unanticipated, permanent tariff change. We estimate a short-run trade elasticity of about three and a long-run trade elasticity of about 14, and find that it takes about five years to close half of the gap between the current and long-run levels of trade. We argue that the expected dynamics of future trade policy before and after these reforms biases down reduced-form estimates of the long-run trade elasticity and biases up estimates of the short-run elasticity. We argue that these measurement issues are even more problematic for other trade reforms, especially those within the Normal Trade Relations (NTR) regime that constitute the majority of the data.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33568/w33568.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33568</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33568</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>George A. Alessandria, Shafaat Yar Khan, Armen Khederlarian, Kim J. Ruhl, Joseph B. Steinberg</author></item><item><title>Standardized Test Scores and Academic Performance at Ivy-Plus Colleges</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We analyze admissions and transcript records for students at multiple Ivy-Plus colleges to study the relationship between standardized (SAT/ACT) test scores, high school GPA, and first-year college grades. Standardized test scores predict academic outcomes with a normalized slope four times greater than that from high school GPA, all conditional on students’ race, gender, and socioeconomic status. Standardized test scores also exhibit no calibration bias, as they do not underpredict college performance for students from less advantaged backgrounds. Collectively these results suggest that standardized test scores provide important information to measure applicants’ academic preparation that is not available elsewhere in the application file.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33570/w33570.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33570</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33570</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>John N. Friedman, Bruce Sacerdote, Douglas O. Staiger, Michele Tine</author></item><item><title>The Effects of Competition in the Retail Gasoline Industry</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We estimate the effect of competition on incumbent firm pricing by using high frequency price data and the precise geographic location for all gas stations in California. Using an event study design, we find that the entry of a new station is associated with a 2.5 cent decrease in prices at incumbent stores, which equates to a 7% reduction in estimated retail markups. The effects are immediate, persistent, and show no sign of deterrence or limit pricing behavior. In contrast, nearby exit results in precisely estimated null effects on prices with no evidence of predatory pricing in the lead up to the station departure. The results are consistent across all fuel blends and dissipate with station distance. Finally, we explore the asymmetric effects, showing that the difference cannot be attributed to difference in branding, proximity to highway, or data quality idiosyncrasies, although we find suggestive evidence that exit tends to happen in more competitive markets and amongst less heavily trafficked stations.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33569/w33569.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33569</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33569</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Reid B. Taylor, Erich Muehlegger</author></item><item><title>From Access to Wellness: Early Life Exposure to Abortion Legalization and the Next Generation’s Health</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We examine the multigenerational impacts of legalized abortion in the United States by analyzing how early-life exposure to this policy shift affects birth outcomes in the next generation. Using event study and two-way fixed effects models, we link maternal early-life exposure to legal abortion with improved birth outcomes in the subsequent generation, including higher birth weights and reduced rates of low birth weight. Our analysis of the mechanisms shows that these improvements in birth outcomes are not driven by changes in maternal racial or age composition within the treated generation. Instead, enhanced educational attainment and increased prenatal care utilization among the treated generation appear to play a critical role. Our results highlight the far-reaching implications of reproductive health policies, especially relevant in the post-Dobbs era, where access may once again become constrained for many.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33571/w33571.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33571</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33571</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Hamid Noghanibehambari, David Slusky, Hoa Vu</author></item><item><title>Recombinant Innovation, Novel Ideas, and the Start of Nobel Prize-Winning Work</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We draw on a recombinant view of innovation, where being in a new location and/or multiple locations leads to exposure to novel combinations of ideas that increase the creativity of top scientists. Using a rich, unique dataset we helped assemble, we estimate the empirical relationship between being in a new location and/or multiple locations and the expected interval before an eventual Nobel laureate (ENL) commences their prize-winning work.  We find that being in a new location and in multiple locations are substantially and significantly associated with a shorter expected interval before ENLs commence their prize-winning work.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33579/w33579.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33579</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33579</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>John Ham, Brian Quistorff, Bruce A. Weinberg</author></item><item><title>A Test of the Efficiency of a Given Portfolio in High Dimensions</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
We generalize the seminal Gibbons-Ross-Shanken test to the empirically relevant case where the number of test assets far exceeds the number of observations. In such a setting, one needs to use a regularized estimator of the covariance matrix of test assets, which leads to biases in the original test statistic. Random Matrix Theory allows us to account for these biases and to evaluate the test’s power. Power increases with the number of test assets and reaches the maximum for a broad range of local alternatives. These conclusions are supported by an extensive simulation study. We implement the test empirically for state-of-the-art candidate efficient portfolios and test assets.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33565/w33565.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33565</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33565</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Mikhail Chernov, Bryan T. Kelly, Semyon Malamud, Johannes Schwab</author></item><item><title>Why Are Nordic Workers so Remote?: Potential Causes and (Some) Indirect Labor Market Consequences</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
In this article, we show that working from home is much more prevalent in the Nordic countries than in the rest of Europe and we discuss potential causes and labor market consequences of this stylized fact. Likely contributing causes include a good technological infrastructure and comparatively widespread digital preparedness in the population.  Recent research also suggests that trust is a crucial prerequisite for maintaining a spatial separation between supervisors and workers in marginal occupations. We show that survey measures of trust are extremely high in all Nordic countries, and that these measures correlate very strongly with work-from-home across countries and industries in Europe even controlling for a range of cross-country differences. Finally, we discuss potential spillover effects of increased hybrid work on the Nordic labor markets. We show evidence suggesting that increased hybrid work has caused a relocation of the production of local service firms from business centers to high-work-from-home residential areas, without affecting average commuting distances of service workers.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33581/w33581.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33581</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33581</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Adam Gill, Lena E. Hensvik, Oskar Nordström Skans</author></item><item><title>The Origins and Evolution of Occupational Licensing in the United States</title><description>&lt;p&gt;
The analysis of occupational licensing has concentrated largely on its labor market and consumer welfare effects. By contrast, relatively little is known about how occupational licensing laws originated or the key factors in their evolution. In this paper, we study the determinants of U.S. licensing requirements from 1870 to 2020. We begin by developing a model where licensing arises as an endogenous political outcome and use this framework to study how market characteristics and political incentives influence regulators’ choices. Our empirical analysis draws on a novel database tracking the initial enactment of licensing legislation for hundreds of unique occupations, as well as changes to the specific qualifications required to obtain a subset of licenses over time. We first show that, consistent with the predictions of our model, licensing requirements are more common and were adopted earlier for occupations whose tasks plausibly pose some risk to consumers. Second, large, urbanized states are significantly more likely to produce new policies. Third, among occupations regulated before 1940, licensing requirements appeared earlier in states with more practitioners and where incumbent workers likely experienced greater labor market competition. After 1980, state-level factors are more strongly associated with the timing of policy adoption. Finally, political organization, as measured by the establishment of a state professional association, significantly increases the probability of regulation. Together, our findings suggest that both public and private interests have contributed to the diffusion of licensing requirements across states and occupations.
&lt;/p&gt;

             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w33580/w33580.pdf&quot;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; </description><link>https://www.nber.org/papers/w33580</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nber.org/papers/w33580</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Nicholas A. Carollo, Jason F. Hicks, Andrew Karch, Morris M. Kleiner</author></item></channel></rss>