<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>CryptoSlate</title><link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.rssforever.com/cryptoslate" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-US</language><image><url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url><title>CryptoSlate</title><link>https://cryptoslate.com/</link></image><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:19:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Bitcoin reclaims $85k after Fed signals slowdown in quantitative tightening</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;) reclaimed the $85,000 threshold following the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) median forecast of 50 basis-point cuts in interest rates in 2025.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In addition to signaling potential rate cuts, the Federal Reserve announced plans to slow the pace of its balance sheet runoff, also known as quantitative tightening (QT), beginning April 1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monthly cap on Treasuries maturing without replacement will be reduced to $5 billion, down from the previous $25 billion limit. The announcement caused global markets across the board to surge, including crypto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bitcoin jumped from $84,235.71 to nearly $86,000 before settling at $85,363 as of press time, based on CryptoSlate data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Despite Bitcoin’s nearly 2% price increase, not all major altcoins did not react as strongly. Ethereum (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/&quot;&gt;ETH&lt;/a&gt;) is priced at $2,039.11 after a 0.6% positive variation in the same period, and Cardano (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/cardano/&quot;&gt;ADA&lt;/a&gt;) secured a slight 0.5% growth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/&quot;&gt;XRP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bnb/&quot;&gt;BNB&lt;/a&gt; showed virtually no price variation. However, Solana (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/&quot;&gt;SOL&lt;/a&gt;) crossed the $130 threshold and was trading at $133.55 as of press time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Federal Reserve Chair &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/jerome-powell/&quot;&gt;Jerome Powell&lt;/a&gt; emphasized that the decision should not be interpreted as a broader policy shift but rather as a technical adjustment to ensure smooth market functioning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fed’s rate path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The updated projections reveal a more cautious stance among FOMC members regarding the pace and extent of rate cuts. The median forecast brings the interest rate to approximately 3.9% by year-end.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Nine policymakers anticipate two cuts in 2025, down from 10 in December, while eight now expect only one or no cuts, an increase from four in the previous forecast.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, two members foresee three cuts, a drop from five in December, and none project more than three rate reductions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Longer-term expectations remain largely unchanged. The median forecast for the federal funds rate at the end of 2026 is 3.4%, while the 2027 projection is 3.1%. The Fed’s longer-run estimate of the neutral interest rate remains steady at 3%.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Moreover, the Fed’s latest economic forecasts indicate slow economic growth. The median 2025 GDP projection was revised downward to 1.7% from 2.1% in December.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The unemployment rate forecast for 2025 has increased slightly to 4.4% from 4.3%, signaling expectations of modest labor market softening.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The central bank also adjusted inflation projections upward, expecting the Personal Consumption Expenditures (PCE) inflation rate to reach 2.7% in 2025, up from the previous 2.5% estimate. Core PCE inflation, which excludes food and energy, is projected to rise to 2.8%, compared to the earlier forecast of 2.5%.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Impact of tariffs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;During his post-meeting press conference, Powell addressed concerns over inflationary pressures, particularly the impact of tariffs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;He noted that a significant portion of recent inflation upticks could be attributed to tariff-related factors but stated that their long-term impact remains uncertain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Powell also described tariff-driven inflation as “transitory” but acknowledged the difficulty of assessing its effects. He reiterated that the Fed monitors economic data for any signs of weakness but emphasized that policymakers are not hurrying to cut rates.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;With persistent inflationary pressures and slowing economic growth, the Fed’s latest projections indicate a more measured approach to monetary policy adjustments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The central bank’s willingness to slow quantitative tightening while maintaining a cautious stance on rate cuts reflects a balancing act between sustaining economic stability and controlling inflation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-reclaims-85k-after-fed-signals-slowdown-in-quantitative-tightening/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin reclaims $85k after Fed signals slowdown in quantitative tightening&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-reclaims-85k-after-fed-signals-slowdown-in-quantitative-tightening/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470457</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:12:48 GMT</pubDate><author>Gino Matos</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bitcoin-pullback-bull.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Crypto</category><category>Featured</category><category>Macro</category><category>Market</category><category>Politics</category><category>Price Watch</category></item><item><title>Crypto.com reports record $1.5B revenue in 2024 to become the third largest exchange</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/companies/crypto-com/&quot;&gt;Crypto.com&lt;/a&gt; recorded a staggering $1.5 billion in revenue during 2024, with CEO &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/kris-marszalek/&quot;&gt;Kris Marszalek&lt;/a&gt; attributing the growth to strong trading activity from its 140 million users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exchange’s operational efficiency helped generate approximately $1 billion in gross profit after covering salaries and other expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;355&quot; data-end=&quot;589&quot;&gt;Amid the impressive revenue figures, Crypto.com invested heavily in expanding its market presence. The company said it allocated around $700 million to user acquisition, incentives, and branding, leaving it with a net profit of $300 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;591&quot; data-end=&quot;894&quot;&gt;Additionally, the exchange benefited from Bitcoin’s (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;) rally to new all-time highs since it holds the asset as part of its treasury strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;591&quot; data-end=&quot;894&quot;&gt;Marszalek noted that Crypto.com plans to reinvest in itself and the broader crypto market, positioning the company for aggressive expansion even in less favorable market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;591&quot; data-end=&quot;894&quot;&gt;He stated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;591&quot; data-end=&quot;894&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We are in position to invest aggressively in the unlikely event of a market downturn, building business organically and through M&amp;amp;A. We intend to do both.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 data-start=&quot;591&quot; data-end=&quot;894&quot;&gt;Market growth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crypto.com’s strong financial performance aligns with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/binance-and-okx-lose-ground-in-market-share-over-2024-while-crypto-com-records-growth/&quot;&gt;rapid expansion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CoinGecko &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coingecko.com/research/publications/largest-centralized-crypto-exchanges&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; ranks it the fastest-growing exchange of 2024, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-and-ethereum-dominate-97-of-trades-on-crypto-com/&quot;&gt;trading volume surging&lt;/a&gt; nearly 1,000% from $120.6 billion in 2023 to $1.29 trillion. This growth positioned Crypto.com as the third-largest exchange, holding a 6.85% market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marszalek attributed this success to the company’s regulatory footprint across 100 jurisdictions spanning five continents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to him, the crypto exchange holds &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-com-obtains-new-mica-license-to-officially-service-european-customers/&quot;&gt;notable regulatory licenses&lt;/a&gt; across different regulatory jurisdictions, including Singapore, the UK, Dubai, and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the US, the exchange holds over 40 state Money Transmitter Licenses, along with registration under the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN). It also operates as a designated contract market (DCM) and a derivatives clearing organization (DCO) under the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), strengthening its compliance credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, Marszalek confirmed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-com-becomes-first-exchange-to-secure-mica-license-for-eu-operations/&quot;&gt;Crypto.com’s momentum in 2024&lt;/a&gt; will drive its expansion plans for 2025. The company has already made strategic acquisitions and secured licenses to introduce derivatives trading while working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-crypto-com-among-exchanges-planning-stablecoin-launches-in-eu/&quot;&gt;new product offerings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marszalek added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are very bullish on our future, particularly in the US market given the new Administration’s enthusiasm for our sector. My meetings with the President give me confidence that he will deliver on his campaign promise to make the US a global leader in cryptocurrency.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-com-reports-record-1-5b-revenue-in-2024-to-become-the-third-largest-exchange/&quot;&gt;Crypto.com reports record $1.5B revenue in 2024 to become the third largest exchange&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-com-reports-record-1-5b-revenue-in-2024-to-become-the-third-largest-exchange/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470415</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:30:43 GMT</pubDate><author>Oluwapelumi Adejumo</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cryptocom.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Exchanges</category><category>bitcoin</category><category>Crypto.com</category></item><item><title>Bitnomial set to launch CFTC-approved XRP futures on March 20, withdraws SEC lawsuit</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bitnomial will launch its CFTC-approved &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/&quot;&gt;XRP&lt;/a&gt; futures contracts on March 20 and drop its lawsuit against the US Securities and Exchange Commission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The firm said its decision to withdraw its lawsuit was driven by the regulator’s move to abandon legal action against &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ripple/&quot;&gt;Ripple&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;According to the March 19&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/Bitnomial/status/1902384594604708005&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the contracts will be physically settled, providing a new regulated trading instrument for institutional and retail investors’ exposure to XRP.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bitnomial clients will gain access to XRP futures immediately at launch. In contrast, prospective clients can onboard through Futures Commission Merchant (FCM) partners, including R.J. O’Brien and Associates, Marex Capital Markets, and Bitnomial Clearing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The introduction of these contracts follows the broader trend of increased regulatory clarity in the crypto sector, particularly as legal developments reshape the landscape for digital assets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;One such development was Ripple’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-surges-10-as-ripple-claims-decisive-win-over-sec-regulations/&quot;&gt;decisive victory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; against the SEC. The regulator formally dropped its appeal in the long-standing legal battle over XRP’s classification. Ripple CEO Brad Garlinghouse confirmed the resolution on March 19, calling it a significant moment for the industry.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Initiated in December 2020, the case accused Ripple of conducting unregistered securities sales worth $1.3 billion. A key ruling in August 2024 determined that XRP is not a security when traded on public exchanges, although penalties were upheld for institutional sales.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The ruling ordered Ripple to pay $125 million in penalties, significantly lower than the SEC’s original demand of nearly $2 billion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The regulator and Ripple appealed the decision, with the SEC ultimately deciding to let go of its appeal. However, Ripple’s appeal to avoid the fine and clear XRP’s status as security on institutional sales is still up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitnomial ends lawsuit against SEC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In tandem with the launch of its XRP futures, Bitnomial announced it has voluntarily dropped its lawsuit against the SEC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; The firm had sued the regulator in October 2024 over jurisdictional disputes concerning futures contracts based on XRP’s price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Bitnomial initially filed for its XRP futures product in August 2024 after the federal ruling that XRP is not a security, challenging the SEC’s stance on overseeing XRP derivatives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The firm’s decision to dismiss its case is based on the shifting regulatory environment and improving clarity regarding digital asset classification.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/bitnomial-set-to-launch-cftc-approved-xrp-futures-on-march-20-withdraws-sec-lawsuit/&quot;&gt;Bitnomial set to launch CFTC-approved XRP futures on March 20, withdraws SEC lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitnomial-set-to-launch-cftc-approved-xrp-futures-on-march-20-withdraws-sec-lawsuit/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470422</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:00:54 GMT</pubDate><author>Gino Matos</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/xrp-futures.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Crypto</category><category>Derivatives</category><category>Featured</category><category>Legal</category></item><item><title>Trump’s crypto Czar slams media for misrepresenting divestment as dump</title><description>&lt;p&gt;White House AI and crypto advisor &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/david-sacks/&quot;&gt;David Sacks&lt;/a&gt; criticized claims that he “dumped” his crypto holdings and clarified that&lt;span style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;&quot;&gt;, after being appointed by President &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/&quot;&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;, he was required to divest due to government ethics rules&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a March 19 social media post, Sacks addressed recent reports suggesting he had sold off his Bitcoin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;), Ethereum (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/&quot;&gt;ETH&lt;/a&gt;), and Solana (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/&quot;&gt;SOL&lt;/a&gt;) investments, stating that the characterization was misleading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I did not ‘dump’ my cryptocurrency; I divested it. Obviously, I would have preferred not to, but government ethics rules required it. It’s an honor to serve President Trump and the American people.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a White House memo, Sacks liquidated more than $200 million in digital assets before Trump took office. His firm, Craft Ventures, also exited positions in crypto-related stocks, including Coinbase (COIN), Robinhood (HOOD), and the Bitwise 10 Crypto Index Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move came amid scrutiny over Sacks’ role in the administration, with some speculating that his influence played a part in discussions about incorporating certain cryptocurrencies into a potential US digital asset reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Media coverage sparks debate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sacks’ clarification reignited discussions about how crypto is portrayed in the media. Some industry figures argue that skepticism about digital assets influences how news outlets frame stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bankless HQ co-founder David Hoffman suggested that negative headlines reflect broader public sentiment rather than deliberate bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoffman wrote in response to Sacks’ post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Most people are crypto-less and don’t want crypto to do well because they don’t want to hold cognitive dissonance about making any wealth in crypto. Media is titling headlines to cater to this need.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binance founder Changpeng ‘CZ’ Zhao echoed the sentiment and said media outlets prioritize engagement over accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CZ wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The media only sells clicks, not ethics.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also criticized a recent Wall Street Journal report alleging that the Trump family considered acquiring a stake in Binance US in exchange for a pardon, calling the story baseless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-crypto-czar-slams-media-for-misrepresenting-divestment-as-dump/&quot;&gt;Trump’s crypto Czar slams media for misrepresenting divestment as dump&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-crypto-czar-slams-media-for-misrepresenting-divestment-as-dump/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470435</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:15:23 GMT</pubDate><author>Assad Jafri</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/david-sacks-bitcoin.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Crypto</category><category>Featured</category><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Tom Emmer says 1M Bitcoin reserve will be enacted under current Congress</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Congressman and Vice Chairman of the Digital Assets Subcommittee &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/tom-emmer/&quot;&gt;Tom Emmer&lt;/a&gt; believes the strategic Bitcoin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;) reserve plan to acquire 1 million BTC will be enacted before the end of this Congress.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;While participating in the Digital Asset Summit, he acknowledged the multiple bills to implement state-level Bitcoin reserves. According to data from the Bitcoin Laws, 23 US states have legislation proposing Bitcoin reserves.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Emmer said:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“So, yes, there is legislation. And I believe that before this Congress is done, that will be enacted.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;He also shared that the Digital Assets Subcommittee is deeply interested in stablecoins, as they represent an “enhanced form of currency” and expand access to the US dollar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1M BTC in 5 years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Regarding the Bitcoin reserve, Emmer referenced the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/senate-house-lawmakers-reintroduce-bitcoin-act-legislation-to-accumulate-1-million-btc/&quot;&gt;recently reintroduced&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; BITCOIN Act, authored by Senator &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/cynthia-lummis/&quot;&gt;Cynthia Lummis&lt;/a&gt; and cosponsored by five Republican Senators.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The legislation authorizes the US government to add up to 1 million BTC to its treasury over five years, funded by the Federal Reserve’s net earnings and adjustments to Treasury certificates based on the Fed’s gold holdings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The amount acquired would then be held for at least 20 years, managed by the Treasury Department. The bill allows divesting, although it prevents any Treasury Secretary from reducing more than 10% of the reserve within a two-year timeframe.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;&quot;&gt;President&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Donald Trump’s&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Bitcoin reserve plans were introduced in an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-signs-bitcoin-reserve-order-but-wont-buy-more-for-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;executive order signed on March 7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and are separate from legislative efforts being made by lawmakers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The executive order focuses on maintaining Bitcoin seized by US authorities as a long-term store of value and does not establish timeframes for acquiring or holding BTC. Estimates suggest that the US currently has nearly 200,000 BTC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Additionally, it mandates that any Bitcoin purchase should happen through budget-neutral strategies devised by Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent and Commerce Secretary &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/howard-lutnick/&quot;&gt;Howard Lutnick&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/tom-emmer-says-1m-bitcoin-reserve-will-be-enacted-under-current-congress/&quot;&gt;Tom Emmer says 1M Bitcoin reserve will be enacted under current Congress&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/tom-emmer-says-1m-bitcoin-reserve-will-be-enacted-under-current-congress/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470441</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:27:44 GMT</pubDate><author>Gino Matos</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/tom-emmer-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Crypto</category><category>Featured</category><category>Legislation</category><category>Regulation</category></item><item><title>First Solana ETFs in the US set for trading debut on March 20</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Volatility Shares will launch the first-ever Solana (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/&quot;&gt;SOL&lt;/a&gt;) futures exchange-traded fund (ETF) in the US on March 20, Bloomberg News reported on March 19.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The issuer will introduce two products: the Volatility Shares Solana ETF (SOLZ) and the Volatility Shares 2X Solana ETF (SOLT).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Bloomberg ETF analyst &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/eric-balchunas/&quot;&gt;Eric Balchunas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; compared&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; them to Bitcoin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;BTC&lt;/a&gt;) ETFs BITO and BITX. He also noted that the launch is unlikely to live up to the standards set by spot Bitcoin ETFs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;He &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1902397245837746539&quot;&gt;added&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“It’s the first altcoin after Ethereum to be approved. But history has shown that ETF investors crave holding the physical asset as much as possible.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanding SOL offering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;SOLZ will provide exposure to Solana futures, while SOLT will offer leveraged exposure at twice the returns of Solana futures movements. The ETFs carry expense ratios of 0.95% and 1.85%, respectively.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Volatility Shares initially submitted its application to the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in December, continuing the trend of crypto-based ETFs predicted by Bloomberg analysts Eric Balchunas and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/james-seyffart/&quot;&gt;James Seyffart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Volatility Shares CEO Justin Young credited the launch to “renewed optimism for crypto innovation in the US” brought by President &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/&quot;&gt;Donald Trump’s&lt;/a&gt; administration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;While the SEC has not approved a spot Solana ETF, industry analysts see these futures-based funds as a potential precursor. Bitcoin and Ethereum took a similar path, with issuers introducing futures ETFs before gaining approval for spot ETFs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appetite for futures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The first Solana futures started trading on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/companies/cme-group/&quot;&gt;CME&lt;/a&gt;) on March 17.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/companies/k33/&quot;&gt;K33&lt;/a&gt; head of research Vetle Lunde&lt;/span&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/VetleLunde/status/1901983776235766024&quot;&gt;highlighted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; that the launch day volumes of SOL futures reached $12.3 million, significantly below BTC’s $102.7 million and ETH’s $31 million.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Open interest was also substantially smaller, with SOL futures reaching nearly $8 million, while BTC and ETH reached at least $20 million in their launches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Despite the seemingly lackluster numbers, Lunde said that by normalizing volumes to the assets’ market caps at launch days, Solana aligns with both Bitcoin and Ethereum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/first-solana-etfs-in-the-us-set-for-trading-debut-on-march-20/&quot;&gt;First Solana ETFs in the US set for trading debut on March 20&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/first-solana-etfs-in-the-us-set-for-trading-debut-on-march-20/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470431</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:22:15 GMT</pubDate><author>Gino Matos</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/solana-etf.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Crypto</category><category>ETF</category><category>Featured</category><category>TradFi</category><category>Trading</category></item><item><title>Czech central banker questions Bitcoin’s place as a reserve asset amid volatility concerns</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Jan Kubíček, a Czech National Bank’s (CNB) board member, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/europe/czech-central-banker-kubicek-sceptical-bitcoin-reserve-asset-2025-03-19/&quot;&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; questioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s&lt;/a&gt; suitability as a reserve asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He pointed to its legal uncertainty and price instability as key reasons for skepticism, casting doubt on whether the bank will integrate the digital asset into its portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the report, Kubíček acknowledged that Bitcoin is under review as part of the CNB’s reserve diversification plan. However, he expressed concerns about its legal status, noting that adopting it would require overhauling the bank’s accounting and auditing systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The banking experts further argued that incorporating Bitcoin into the reserve structure presents significant challenges without clear regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market volatility remains another primary concern. Kubíček pointed out that BTC’s fluctuating price, which has ranged from $77,186 to $109,021 this year, complicates risk assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also suggested that if more institutional investors adopt BTC, its behavior could shift, making future volatility harder to predict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We cannot be certain that Bitcoin’s volatility in the coming years will mirror the patterns observed over the past decade because I suspect that, if more institutional investors accept Bitcoin as an investment asset, it will start to behave differently from what we have seen so far.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;1314&quot; data-end=&quot;1736&quot;&gt;Kubíček’s position differs from that of CNB Governor Ales Michl, who has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/czech-national-bank-considers-bitcoin-for-reserve-diversification/&quot;&gt;pushing to add Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; to the bank’s reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;1314&quot; data-end=&quot;1736&quot;&gt;Earlier this year, Michl proposed that BTC could be a strategic asset for diversification. If approved, the CNB could &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/cnb-considers-shifting-up-to-5-percent-of-czech-reserves-into-bitcoin/&quot;&gt;allocate up to 5%&lt;/a&gt; of its $146.13 billion reserves to Bitcoin, translating to an estimated $7.3 billion investment—far exceeding its current $4.3 million gold holdings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;1738&quot; data-end=&quot;1956&quot;&gt;Michl has also &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/czech-central-bank-governor-urges-study-of-bitcoin-as-a-distinct-asset-from-other-cryptocurrencies/&quot;&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt; that central banks should explore Bitcoin’s potential rather than dismiss it outright. He believes that BTC and its underlying technology could enhance rather than disrupt financial stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;1958&quot; data-end=&quot;2213&quot; data-is-last-node=&quot;&quot; data-is-only-node=&quot;&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, Kubíček confirmed that the CNB is still studying BTC and other emerging asset classes. The findings, expected by October, will likely determine whether BTC gains a foothold in the Czech Republic’s reserve strategy or remains an unlikely candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/czech-central-banker-questions-bitcoins-place-as-a-reserve-asset-amid-volatility-concerns/&quot;&gt;Czech central banker questions Bitcoin’s place as a reserve asset amid volatility concerns&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/czech-central-banker-questions-bitcoins-place-as-a-reserve-asset-amid-volatility-concerns/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470385</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:10:21 GMT</pubDate><author>Oluwapelumi Adejumo</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/czech-bitcoin-reserve-.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Adoption</category><category>Crypto</category><category>bitcoin</category><category>czech</category></item><item><title>North Dakota sets $2,000 daily limit for crypto ATM transactions</title><description>&lt;p&gt;North Dakota lawmakers have taken a decisive step toward &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/&quot;&gt;regulating crypto ATMs&lt;/a&gt;, approving a bill imposing a $2,000 daily transaction limit per user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;margin: 0px; padding: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #333333;&quot;&gt;On March 18, the state Senate passed&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ndlegis.gov/assembly/69-2025/regular/documents/25-1011-03000.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;House Bill 1447&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #333333;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;advancing legislation designed to curb fraud and enhance oversight.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p data-start=&quot;363&quot; data-end=&quot;591&quot;&gt;HB 1447 seeks to protect residents from &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/occrp-investigation-reveals-surge-in-crypto-atm-usage-among-scammers-criminals/&quot;&gt;rising fraud cases linked to crypto ATMs&lt;/a&gt;. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinatmradar.com/state/35/bitcoin-atm-north-dakota/&quot;&gt;Coin ATM Radar&lt;/a&gt;, North Dakota currently hosts around 45 Bitcoin ATMs out of approximately 29,730 machines across the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Senate approval secured, the bill will likely return to the House for further consideration before reaching the governor’s desk for final approval. If enacted, North Dakota would establish a stronger regulatory framework to address crypto ATM fraud while maintaining user accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bill details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HB 1447 introduces stricter guidelines for crypto ATM operators, requiring them to obtain a money transmitter license before running their machines in North Dakota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill requires clear and easily readable disclosures of terms and conditions in the customer’s preferred language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also mandates using blockchain analytics tools to detect fraudulent transactions, track suspicious wallet activity, and flag potential money laundering schemes. Regulators would be able to request proof that operators are using these tools effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crypto ATMs will also be required to display fraud warnings before processing transactions, helping users identify potential scams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, operators must establish and maintain a written anti-fraud policy, ensuring proactive steps are taken to detect and prevent fraudulent activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bill stated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A virtual – currency kiosk operator shall take reasonable steps to detect and prevent fraud, including establishing and maintaining a written antifraud policy.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to security measures, the legislation enforces a $2,000 daily withdrawal cap. Initially, lawmakers proposed a $1,000 limit, but the threshold was later raised to allow greater flexibility while maintaining fraud safeguards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;s3&quot;&gt;The bill mandates that ATM operators provide live assistance on weekdays from 8 A.M. to 10 P.M. Central Time to improve customer support. A toll-free customer service number must be prominently displayed on the machine or its interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/north-dakota-sets-2000-daily-limit-for-crypto-atm-transactions/&quot;&gt;North Dakota sets $2,000 daily limit for crypto ATM transactions&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/north-dakota-sets-2000-daily-limit-for-crypto-atm-transactions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470344</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:40:18 GMT</pubDate><author>Oluwapelumi Adejumo</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/crypto-atm.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Adoption</category><category>Crypto</category><category>Featured</category><category>Regulation</category><category>Crypto ATMs</category><category>North Dakota</category></item><item><title>Traders increase leverage as Bitcoin rebounds in March</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s&lt;/a&gt; Estimated Leverage Ratio (ESL) rebounded 9% this month, rising from a YTD low of 0.2218 on Mar. 4 to 0.2417 on Mar. 18. This recovery pushed ESL back to levels last seen in late January, though it remains well below the YTD peak of 0.2709 seen on Feb. 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;ESL measures how much leverage derivatives traders use by calculating the ratio between open interest and exchange reserves. Monitoring ESL shows when investors are taking or reducing high-leverage risk when trading derivatives,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s price was well above $98,300 on Feb. 20, so the ESL reflected a very bullish and leveraged market. As Bitcoin’s price dropped below $80,000, ESL also hit its low, showing that traders were closing leveraged positions in response to the downward volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;The subsequent ESL increase through mid-March follows the stabilization of Bitcoin’s price and its move toward previous resistance levels. It shows the market’s continued willingness to engage leverage during price recoveries. If Bitcoin’s price holds above recent support, ESL could trend higher, showing a rising risk exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;However, a rising ESL brings higher liquidation risks if the market turns unexpectedly. If Bitcoin’s price were to drop sharply again, a high ESL could exacerbate market movements by rapidly triggering forced liquidations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Monitoring the 7-day SMA of ESL alongside price swings will reveal traders’ risk tolerance. This month’s rebound shows that, despite near-term volatility, derivatives traders are still inclined to utilize leverage to capitalize on the volatility in Bitcoin’s price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/insights/traders-increase-leverage-as-bitcoin-rebounds-in-march/&quot;&gt;Traders increase leverage as Bitcoin rebounds in March&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/insights/traders-increase-leverage-as-bitcoin-rebounds-in-march/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_insight&amp;p=470325</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:10:55 GMT</pubDate><author>Andjela Radmilac</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/trading.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure></item><item><title>Curetopia raises $1.77M to drive decentralized biotech breakthroughs using Solana</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Curetopia has secured $1.77 million in funding to expedite treatments for rare diseases through a decentralized biotech model leveraging Solana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundraising effort, supported by more than 1,000 individual contributors, highlights growing momentum in the decentralized science (DeSci) sector, particularly amid a sustained US &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/19/universities-medical-research-cuts-nih-trump&quot;&gt;freeze&lt;/a&gt; on traditional &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breastcancer.org/news/nih-funding-freeze-tnbc-drug-research&quot;&gt;funding sources&lt;/a&gt; like the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and National Science Foundation (NSF).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Curetopia DAO, launched on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/revolutionizing-biotech-paul-kohlhaas-discusses-decentralized-science-and-open-innovation/&quot;&gt;Bio Protocol&lt;/a&gt; with backing from Binance seeks to address an estimated $1 trillion rare disease market historically underserved by large pharmaceutical companies. Utilizing blockchain-based crowdfunding, Curetopia enables rare disease patients and researchers to collaboratively finance drug development projects, sharing ownership of resulting treatments through tokenization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curetopia recently identified a potential treatment for AARS2 progressive leukoencephalopathy, a fatal mitochondrial disease lacking any approved therapies. This discovery, arising from screening 8,500 repurposable compounds via yeast models, represents one of the first instances of a crypto-backed research project potentially reaching commercialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curetopia is currently filing a provisional patent for this discovery. Any proceeds from subsequent commercialization will be reinvested into the DAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curetopia’s operational model incorporates direct engagement with patient communities, a strategy championed by founder Dr. Ethan Perlstein, a Harvard PhD and former Y Combinator participant. Perlstein previously demonstrated cost-effective clinical development by advancing a rare disease treatment to Phase 3 trials for $5 million—markedly lower than traditional pharmaceutical pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perlstein emphasized that decentralized drug development empowers rare disease patients and families to directly influence therapeutic development, breaking the cycle of neglected research due to limited commercial incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants in Curetopia’s decentralized trials receive CURES tokens, effectively becoming stakeholders in the therapies they help develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curetopia’s model, which leverages drug repurposing, tokenized intellectual property, and community-driven trials, seeks to accelerate regulatory approval processes, significantly reducing both time and financial costs relative to conventional drug development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAO also recently partnered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/combinedbrain_announcing-a-new-opportunity-for-combinedbrain-activity-7300371781842804737-M5kW&quot;&gt;COMBINEDBrain&lt;/a&gt; and Unravel Biosciences to provide drug screening services to organizations representing more than 100 genetic neurodevelopmental disorders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a focus on drug repurposing, Curetopia aims to capitalize on regulatory advantages such as FDA Priority Review Vouchers and Orphan Drug Designation, which offer expedited pathways and incentives for rare disease therapeutics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/curetopia-raises-1-77m-to-drive-decentralized-biotech-breakthroughs-using-solana/&quot;&gt;Curetopia raises $1.77M to drive decentralized biotech breakthroughs using Solana&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptoslate.com/&quot;&gt;CryptoSlate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://cryptoslate.com/curetopia-raises-1-77m-to-drive-decentralized-biotech-breakthroughs-using-solana/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=470360</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Liam &#39;Akiba&#39; Wright</author><enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/disease-research.jpg" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>DAOs</category><category>Technology</category><category>Web3</category></item></channel></rss>