<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Book Reviews</title><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/book</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.email-once.com/caareviews/book" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Book Reviews - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:26:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>The Unseen Truth: When Race Changed Sight in America</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4432//The%20Unseen%20Truth.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Editor’s Note: Following author Sarah Lewis’s decision to decapitalize the word &quot;black,” this review retains the lowercase when referring to the racial category/ethnic group&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; **********&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;A Companion to American&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;Art, published by Blackwell in 2015, I surveyed how scholars of American art had been approaching the critical study of race and visual representation since the late twentieth century. At the time, those approaches included either foregrounding or decentering race in interpretations of the work of black artists; speaking about race in relation to a broader range of (especially white-produced) artistic production; and even imagining “post-racial” art and art history. The last of these emerged in the context of the presidential campaign and election of Barack Obama in 2008, when Americans were envisioning a world where someone’s life experience would not be defined exclusively by their racial or ethnic identity. If Darby English’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;How to See a Work of Art in Total Darkness&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(2007) heralded the possibility of a postracial art history in the era of Obama, Sarah Lewis’s latest book,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;: When Race Changed Sight in America&lt;/i&gt;, signals the emergence of a new approach to race and representation in the context of the anti-black racism and antiracist discourse that have defined the last decade in the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Rather than centering the artist or the object of representation, Lewis’s book explores what she calls racial observation, or the culture of seeing the world “through the filter of race” (8). It joins other critical studies of what it means to see (and not see) in modern Euro-American culture, from Jonathan Crary’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Techniques of the Observer: On Vision and Modernity in the Nineteenth Century&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Press, 1992) to Michael Leja’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Looking Askance: Skepticism and American Art from Eakins to Duchamp&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(University of California Press, 2004). Among the relatively few of these studies to consider deeply the relationship between race and vision are Nicole R. Fleetwood’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Troubling Vision: Performance, Visuality, and Blackness&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(2010), which interrogates how blackness has come to be seen as (in)visible, and Nicholas Mirzoeff’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Right to Look: A Counterhistory of Visuality&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(2011), which associates chattel slavery with the visual regime of classification. As its citations attest, Lewis’s book also stands on the shoulders of scholarship in critical whiteness studies, especially the writings of David Roediger, Matthew Frye Jacobson, Toni Morrison, and Nell Irvin Painter, whose&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The History of White People&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(W. W. Norton, 2010) serves as a beacon throughout the book. For&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a study of how popular ideas about racial whiteness were constructed in and through visual culture, and how those notions—however spurious they turned out to be—shaped how white Americans looked at themselves and racialized others in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;That vision, Lewis argues, was tied to the mythmaking that surrounded the Caucasus, particularly the region once known as Circassia, which ran along the northeastern edge of the Black Sea (now part of Russia). In the 1795 edition of his influential treatise&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;On the Natural Variety of Mankind&lt;/i&gt;, the German physician Johann Friedrich Blumenbach equated the region with the highest ideal, indeed the very origin, of whiteness, despite having no reliable evidence to support the claim. The racial signification of the Caucasus was upheld, albeit by a humbug, in the 1860s, as the famous showman P. T. Barnum exhibited a group of light-complexioned women who performed as “Circassian Beauties.” That signification began to unwind in the 1870s, when the American George Kennan documented the entire region and widely disseminated his findings about its racial diversity. Lewis’s dogged archival research reveals that references to the Caucasus started to fall away from maps in the US by the 1890s, only to resurface in the context of Woodrow Wilson’s presidency (1913–21).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In relation to the evolving discourse surrounding the Caucasus, Lewis identifies two primary modes of vision: negative assembly and racial detailing. In chapter four, which considers mapmaking as an important form of racial observation at the turn of the twentieth century, Lewis defines negative assembly as “excisions to prevent a reckoning with the fictions of racial hierarchy,” and as “a central, structural feature for the maintenance of racial hierarchies in American life” (141). Americans have learned, in other words, how to disregard anything that might disrupt “narratives of white racial dominance” (139). While negative assembly operates through omission and a refusal to see, racial detailing involves a building up of small details to form a complete vision. As Lewis puts it in chapter five, it describes the action of “assembling seemingly small, procedural features to constitute a totalizing and inhumane regime” (202). Lewis associates this form of racial observation with the popular eugenics movement, which encouraged Americans to evaluate details of the face and physique and add them up to assess an individual’s social fitness. She further locates racial detailing in Wilson’s federal government, whose practices of racial segregation were carefully constructed, one discriminatory detail at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;not only examines how these ways of seeing have promoted anti-black racism and white supremacism, but also how they have been coopted by black writers and visual artists seeking to “undermine” those ideologies. Lewis argues, for example, that contemporary artist Kerry James Marshall’s remaking of a famous lynching photograph taken in 1930 in Marion, Indiana, visualized—as a form of critique—the process of “racial detailing.” Titled&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Heirlooms &amp;amp; Accessories&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(2002), his artwork extracts the faces of three women from the apparently all-white audience to a gruesome murder of two black men, and places each of them in a golden locket—a piece of jewelry passed down, as a keepsake, from generation to generation. A century earlier, the sociologist W. E. B. Du Bois used maps in exhibitions as forms of resistance to “negative assembly.” Unlike illustrated atlases and the “instructional scripts” designed for geography classes in American schools, Du Bois’s maps, on display in venues like the 1900 Paris Exposition, visualized for broad audiences the trajectory of “black progress” (177).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;not only calls upon readers to approach “vision analytically, as a process of assembly, and to consider its blind spots” (134), but the book also encourages them to attend similarly to its own process of argument-making. To build her claims about race and vision, Lewis engages in a rigorously critical and creative process of unearthing, interrogating, juxtaposing, and layering—a method she deployed to great effect in her 2014 book&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Rise: Creativity, the Gift of Failure, and the Search for Mastery&lt;/i&gt;. Chapter two of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;, for example, begins by considering Frederick Douglass’s thoughts on photographs as instruments of democracy and social justice. Before reflecting on the legal adjudication of racial identity in the early twentieth century, it returns to the photographs of the so-called Circassian Beauties analyzed in chapter one, comparing them to Dion Boucicault’s tragic play&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Octoroon&lt;/i&gt;, the famous story of Ellen and William Craft’s escape from enslavement to freedom, representations of poet Alexander Pushkin’s multiracial identity, and more. Chapter three likewise draws connections among a diverse collection of objects, practices, and ideas that shared temporal proximity, such as Frank Duveneck’s painting of a Circassian soldier from 1870, changes in the racial signification of the Caucasus in the 1870s, the emphasis on comparative looking in eugenics, court practices of visually inspecting bodies for their “whiteness,” and the commissioning of “white common soldier monuments” during and after the Civil War. In other cases, the proximity is geographic, as in the coexistence within several city blocks of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The New York-Caucasian&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;newspaper’s office, one of the largest mapmakers in the US, a photographic portrait studio where the Circassian Beauties posed, and P. T. Barnum’s American Museum, where they were exhibited publicly. Taken on their own, each of the subjects Lewis assembles has generated significant scholarship in recent decades. (Consider the number of recent books devoted to Douglass’s engagement with photography or to the art history of Civil War monuments.) Lewis nevertheless offers fresh and impactful insights by envisioning these subjects in relation to one another. Each chapter of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is thus a brilliantly constructed composition that teaches us how to see as American people had once been trained to do, consciously or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In the book’s epilogue, Lewis speaks directly about her research process, which brought her to visit Wilson’s tomb, opposite stained-glass windows by Kerry James Marshall, at the National Cathedral in Washington, DC. “I had nearly missed the memorial bay for Wilson,” she recalled. “To see it, I had to move up close, shift my vantage point, and stay aware of the full detail that surrounded me, not just what might be of interest for my current task” (261). This passage pulls back the curtain to reveal Lewis’s own engagement with racial detailing, as a form of political resistance, in the making of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Unseen Truth&lt;/i&gt;. Self-reflective and deeply committed to social justice, this is the book art historians working in the US urgently need now, as we learn to apply our critical tools—from close looking to socio-historical analysis—to understanding and undermining systemic racism in America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/818&quot;&gt;Tanya Sheehan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Colby College&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4290</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4290</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Sarah Lewis</author></item><item><title>A View of Venice: Portrait of a Renaissance City</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4466//A%20View%20Of%20Venice%20.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Few images, if any, are as iconic—even synecdochic—of life, culture, and politics in Renaissance Venice than Jacopo de’ Barbari’s monumental &lt;i&gt;View of Venice&lt;/i&gt;. The Italian artist’s six-sheet woodblock print showcasing a bird’s-eye-view of the city and its lagoon was produced circa 1497–1500 with the support of the German publisher Anton Kolb. It stood as the largest print produced in Europe at the time (1.35 × 2.75 meters) whose magnitude and inventiveness were recognized by the Venetian government’s granting to Kolb of one of the earliest known copyright permissions for a printed image. Marveled by commentators since its inception for its at-once synoptic, multifocal aerial &lt;i&gt;veduta&lt;/i&gt; of the city as well as the minutely detailed portrayal of the urban landscape, Barbari’s map emerged as the topic of serious scholarly investigation roughly one hundred years ago, most notably in Alvise Zorzi’s &lt;i&gt;Venezia scomparsa &lt;/i&gt;(1922), and has generated an enormous literature since. Kristin Love Huffman’s lengthy and elegant new edited volume of essays, &lt;i&gt;A View of Venice: Portrait of a Renaissance City&lt;/i&gt;, nevertheless presents a trove of fresh insights on Barbari and his most famous print. It not only stands as the most comprehensive book to date on this topic but also promises to serve as the definitive text on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The genesis of Huffman’s volume lies in two projects she curated: the international collaborative digital humanities enterprise &lt;i&gt;Visualizing Venice&lt;/i&gt; and the 2017 exhibition &lt;i&gt;A Portrait of Venice: Jacopo de’ Barbari’s &lt;/i&gt;View of 1500. An integral theme in those projects and one Huffman emphasizes in her text is how interpretive richness and novelty are achieved when innovative methodologies are brought to bear on traditional media. Huffman enlists a distinguished set of contributors from an array of fields to fulfill this multidisciplinary interrogation involving the production, function, and reception of Barbari’s woodblock print. Beyond leading specialists on Venetian Renaissance art and architecture, varied essays from musicology, civil engineering, political economy, gender studies, urban studies, media studies, and environmental history illuminate the interrelated dimensions of Venetian life underpinning the woodcut’s imagery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In general, the essays proceed from the long-held theoretical assumption that the print operates not as objective cartography, but instead as a highly mediated artwork promoting Venetian commercial, political, and maritime superiority—in sum, a manifesto of the “myth of Venice.” As Huffman states, the &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt; thus animates “its tension between perceived realism and idealization” (2). Optically, many views are altered or combined to produce an image that more legibly showcases conspicuous landmarks throughout the city, such as the Piazza San Marco&lt;i&gt;, Arsenale, &lt;/i&gt;and&lt;i&gt; Mercerie&lt;/i&gt;, along with prominent &lt;i&gt;palazzi&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;giardini&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;campi&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;The editor also proposes to consider anew and clarify two long-standing conundrums about the iconic print, “the exact ‘how’ and ‘why’ it was made” (3).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;This expansive collection of twenty-three somewhat terse essays, each roughly ten pages long, is divided into two main sections, the first titled “The &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt; as a Printed Cartographic and Artistic Visualization,” and the second, “The &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt; as a Reflection of Venice and Venetian Life.” The contributions are bookended by an introductory essay by Huffman and an eloquent epilogue by Tracy E. Cooper. Within the first part, the authors mine the mathematical, commercial, cartographic, and perspectival attributes of Barbari’s &lt;i&gt;View &lt;/i&gt;to evince how acumen in these arenas were particularly prized in Venetian culture at this time. While impossible to dutifully summarize each essay and its carefully poised arguments, particularly noteworthy amongst these contributions in part one is Valeria Cafà’s fascinating study examining the wood blocks (matrices) used to print the &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt;, material artifacts rarely discussed in relation to the print. Another fresh perspective is Giorgio Tagliaferro’s theorization of the &lt;i&gt;View &lt;/i&gt;as a semi-biographical portrait of Barbari and his artistic network. Little remains known hitherto about Barbari’s activities in Venice, although Rangsook Yoon’s essay in this section outlines what is certain. Therefore, Tagliaferro’s examination of &lt;i&gt;vedute&lt;/i&gt; imagery as interpersonal markers reaffirms speculation that Barbari was of Venetian birth, a fact the map evidently then signposts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Essays in part two embark on the well-trodden path interrogating the &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt;’s visual density alongside the “myth of Venice,” that is, the city and its inhabitants’ miraculous nature that allowed them to remain unconquered for over one thousand years. Several studies in this section compellingly refocus upon traditionally marginalized yet poignant features of the printed map, as Patricia Fortini Brown does with her marvelously conceived investigation of the over two hundred fifty Venetian wellheads dotting Barbari’s archipelago. This eco-critical turn rediscovering Venetians’ strategic manipulation of their aqueous environment, initially propelled by Élisabeth Crouzet-Pavan’s, &lt;i&gt;Venise triomphante: les horizons d’un mythe&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;(Albin Michel, 1999) and Karl Appuhn’s &lt;i&gt;A Forest on the Sea. Environmental Expertise in Renaissance Venice &lt;/i&gt;(Johns Hopkins University Press, 2009), is a theme taken up as well in the present volume by Richard Goy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;A propitious feature of &lt;i&gt;A View of Venice&lt;/i&gt; is its handsome package and modest price tag which will undoubtedly encourage a wide readership and accessibility amongst anyone intrigued by early modern Venice. In addition to the full-color illustrations in each essay and handful of selected details from Barbari’s woodblock print, a high-resolution reproduction of it is included as a foldout plate—thus skirting the dilemma of presenting the panoramic map across a two-page spread and breaching the visual unity of its design. The aforementioned &lt;i&gt;Visualizing Venice &lt;/i&gt;project serves as a digital companion to the textual studies in Huffman’s volume and is intended to enable a deep dive into the primary archival materials at hand.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Several infelicities evident in the text, however, bear mention. The chief shortcoming falls upon Huffman’s own introductory essay which offers surprisingly sparse review of the copious literature on Barbari and his famous woodcut. No discussion is present here of the historiography of the print, previous publications, or the state of the field and literature on the topic. Huffman’s Introduction inserts merely two footnotes: one a laundry list—albeit useful—of publications on Barbari’s &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt;, the other a technical explanation on the Venetian calendar. While her fluent prose demonstrates clear knowledge of primary and secondary sources, this lack of scholarly apparatus acknowledging the shoulders her work stands on is scant. This tendency persists in her other essay, “The &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt; and Its Relevance Today: Venice Then and Now,” included as Appendix 1, where a sole footnote appears.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Much more useful in this regard is Cooper’s literature review contained in her epilogue which outlines how the assembled authors’ contributions reshape our understanding of Barbari’s print in relation to previous studies and charts a trajectory for future investigations. Given its indispensability, one wishes therefore that Cooper’s essay had been conceived instead as a prologue, rather than a post-hoc assessment of the preceding text. Moreover, several curious editorial decisions were made in Appendices 2 and 3, which, regrettably, merely reproduce or transcribe—rather than translate—archival documents pertaining to Kolb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Additionally, one wonders whether, in the age of macrophotography and ultra high-resolution digital scans, such as those reproduced of the &lt;i&gt;View&lt;/i&gt; in Huffman’s text, such contemporary viewing procedures affording limitless legibility, infinite detail, and granular observation misconstrue—or even pervert—the visual consumption of the woodcut early modern audiences experienced. Surely, only a privileged minority inspected this notoriously expensive artwork at close range with the degree of scrutiny enabled by current imaging tools—and never in the manner of “microexamination” (309), as Cooper terms it, possible at present through modern optical interventions. Magnifying technologies existed and were readily available in sixteenth-century Europe, but not to the maximal degree Huffman touts as a key 21st-century hermeneutic to recovering the woodcut’s true meaning. A fascinating potential study, though missing from his volume, would be to examine how understanding and interpolation of the cartographic view evolved in relation to parallel optical technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Despite these quibbles, Huffman and the contributors achieve a volume likely to become the standard reference text for Barbari’s print and are to be applauded for the energy they bring to such an oft-reproduced image. One key revelation in this vein&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;is Karen-edis Barzman’s essay on the Venetian state’s overriding “mapping impulse” (to borrow a phrase from Svetlana Alpers) in the Quattrocento leading up to the conception of Barbari’s project. Barzman’s study goes a long way in explaining the primary motivations and audiences for the print, adducing through archival discoveries how the Serenissima was long-intent upon capturing Venetian geographical data through an analog proto-&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GIS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;It is genuinely revealing how the volume critically plumbs overlooked yet consequential details of the print, mining meaning not only from details once construed as frivolous minutiae, such as belltowers (Jonathan Glixon), marginalia (Anna Christine Swartwood House), vessels (Monique O’Connell), gardens (Ludovica Galeazzo), canals and bridges (Julia A. DeLancey) but also further multitudinous features of the urban fabric virtually invisible heretofore in scholarship on the print. Huffman duly emphasizes how the critical approaches of the contributors effectively mirror in spirit the cutting-edge enterprise of Kolb and Barbari that wielded broad networks of knowledge alongside the new tool of the printing press in order to reconceive how the city envisioned itself and its place in the world.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3513&quot;&gt;James R. Jewitt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
School of Visual Arts, Virginia Tech&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4316</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4316</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Kristin Love Huffman, ed.</author></item><item><title>Eternal Sovereigns: Indigenous Artists, Activists, and Travelers Reframing Rome</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4440//Eternal%20Sovereigns.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In &lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns: Indigenous Artists, Activists, and Travelers Reframing Rome&lt;/i&gt;, Gloria Jane Bell considers Indigenous cultural belongings held in Vatican Museums collections. As she turns attention to the stories they tell—and the Vatican’s efforts to silence them—she locates these possessions within a long history of Indigenous travelers with creative ties to Rome. The book&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;traces these ties through discussions of prominent Indigenous artists, stolen Indigenous artworks, and the mobile, tenacious sovereignty they have maintained in the face of papal dominance. Bridging multiple disciplines including art history, material studies, and archival studies, &lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns &lt;/i&gt;suggests a “new, entangled, and unsettling” way to read relationships between Indigeneity, Rome, and the Vatican (8). This thoroughly researched text raises absorbing questions for scholars invested in the possibilities of transatlantic Indigenous art history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Bell builds out her research from the 1925 Vatican Missionary Exhibition (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), where the Indigenous cultural belongings at the center of &lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns&lt;/i&gt; were first displayed in Rome. The &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, opened by Pope Pius XI, was a sprawling exhibition of global Indigenous art and artifacts intended to honor Catholic missionary work (4). Following papal bulls and conversion projects, the exhibition portrayed Indigenous people as naive, uncivilized, and in need of Christian redemption, altogether strengthening the Vatican’s efforts to render them voiceless. Bell notes Pius XI’s description of the artworks’ “silent eloquence” throughout &lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns&lt;/i&gt;, offering correctives in the form of archival speculation, reflections on Indigenous agency, and an understanding of Indigenous cultural belongings as “eternal sovereigns” (4,129). Despite occasionally losing track of conceptual threads (such as Indigenous “audacity” and Rome’s development into a modern city), Bell nonetheless deftly pulls together locations, disciplines, and historical moments (8). Furthermore, she reminds readers of her project’s stakes for Indigenous nations with keen commitment informed by her own heritage ties to the Métis people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Bell intersperses the text with first-person accounts of her archival research, including altered photographs, and draws these personal experiences into her textual analysis. These contributions are conversational and pithy, pulling affective dimensions of her research into relief. “I wanted to throw a rock into the glass cases and shatter the exhibition,” she writes after viewing an outdated Missionary Ethnological Museum exhibition of Indigenous cultural belongings (4). She describes her personal writings as efforts to “tilt the hierarchy of value that exists within . . . European and American archival structures and modes of history writing,” expanding the art historical record (5). When Bell shapes her firsthand observations into fleshy analytic devices—as in her chapter four reading of a Passamaquoddy wooden sculpture of Christ on the cross, which links Christ’s represented suffering with the sensed suffering of trapped Indigenous cultural belongings—&lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns &lt;/i&gt;hits its stride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Throughout the book, the personal writings illuminate Bell’s research process. Descriptions of a dismissive conservator suggesting that “Indigenous people need to get over genocide” and a surreptitious visit to the Vatican Fototeca underscore the need for &lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns&lt;/i&gt;’ correctives within cultural institutions holding Indigenous materials (12). Other writings suggest ambivalence, blending awed reactions to the Eternal City, “I would glance over the wall onto Saint Peter’s and feel the glory and power of being in Rome,” Bell writes of lunch breaks at Propaganda Fide College with bubbling anger toward Catholic authority, expressed in archival frustrations and the desire to free trapped cultural belongings (127). This ambivalence mirrors the tension between Vatican hegemony and Indigenous sovereignty Bell considers throughout the book, particularly in her first chapter on two 19th-century artists: Ferdinand Pettrich and Edmonia Wildfire Lewis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In this chapter Bell places Pettrich, a German sculptor known for his busts of Indigenous diplomats, and Lewis, a Haitian and Anishinaabe sculptor who lived and worked in Rome, in conversation. While Pettrich showed work in the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and Lewis did not—and there is no record of a relationship between them—Bell asks how “considering their efforts in tension” may provide insight into Indigenous presence and representational agency in Rome and the Vatican (19). She reflects on the artists’ shared Neoclassical influences, tracing the movement’s equation of 20th-century Indigenous people with a vanished Greco-Roman culture, and distinguishes Pettrich’s romantic representations of Indigenous subjects from Lewis’s layered, fluid ones. Memorably, she contemplates Indigenous creative agency in Lewis’s 1868 sculpture &lt;i&gt;Minnehaha&lt;/i&gt;, which blends “European and Native American ideals,” materials, and references (45). Throughout these discussions she highlights gaps in the historical record, speculating on what may have been left out of Lewis’s archival story. The chapter’s focus on two artists offers an intimate view of art historical tensions which unfold on larger scales in the following chapters on the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Furthermore, its comparative, speculative approach primes readers to consider archival gaps and Indigenous agency within these analyses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The second chapter walks readers through the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; itself, describing the exhibition and its function as Vatican propaganda. Bell details a space as chaotic as it was totalizing, a disorienting blend of Catholic ritual procession and curiosity cabinet. As she critiques the Vatican’s collapsing of Indigenous culture, she points to “glitches in the system” where the exhibition’s internal logic breaks down (100). More attention to the philosophy underpinning this logic could have strengthened her arguments. While Bell continually gestures toward the VME’s ritual elements and, more significantly, the destabilizing potential of Indigenous art for Catholic viewers, she chooses not to read the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; through Catholic theology or anthropology as other scholars have done. While this move allows her to “[center] and [add] nuance to Indigenous American visual culture,” a clearer sense of how Catholic cosmology works could help readers understand why Indigenous cosmologies threaten its hegemony (and make glitchy moments—including a description of a bizarre missionary artwork made of fleas—more affecting) (6). Nonetheless, Bell’s reading raises a key divide between the VME’s focus on the visual, material aspects of Indigenous cultural belongings over their spiritual, intangible presence. By turning toward this presence in the next two chapters she finds gaps in the VME’s silencing regime, filling them with “ancestral art history lessons full of persuasive power and aesthetic brilliance” (131).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The third chapter focuses on idealized missionary perspectives at the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Bell reads a set of children’s board games based on missionary travels and conversion efforts, counterposing them with a discussion of residential schools’ horrific realities. Drawing on Manu Vimalassery, Juliana Hu Pegues, and Alyosha Goldstein’s concept of “colonial unknowing,” she returns to the VME’s gaps and silences (95). An ongoing pattern becomes clearer in this chapter: Bell raises an interesting entry point for analysis, such as museum cannibalism or “cringey!” as a personal response to &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; dioramas—before racing forward or reiterating arguments about the Vatican fixing Indigenous culture in the past (109). These fleeting images, expanded and explored in visual-textual analysis, could help us better understand how&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;the Vatican does so. Could a critical lens on museum cannibalism inform broader exhibition readings as well as object-specific ones? What might it look like to linger on “cringing” as an aesthetic response to colonial displays? While some readings could benefit from further reflection, the chapter as a whole is well-considered. Bell approaches disturbing connections between residential schools and the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; with care, noting that many artworks in the exhibition were made by residential school students otherwise barred from cultural engagement. She draws a haunting connection between the children and their extracted works in observing that “[residential school] missionaries kept children against their will during the most aggressive assimilationist period; so too were their cultural belongings kept as prisoners and displayed under glass at the VME” (117).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The fourth and final chapter returns to the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; cultural belongings held in the Vatican Museums collection today, seeking their agency and vocal “eloquence” (156). Here, Bell positions these cultural belongings as “eternal sovereigns,” embodiments of Indigenous cosmologies that “resonate beyond missionary anxiety” and Vatican space (21). She criticizes the Vatican Museums’ unwillingness to partner with their home nations (let alone support repatriation) and offers close, culturally-informed readings of five works: an Anishinaabe, Nipissing, and Kanien’kehá:ka wampum belt, a Passamaquoddy wooden sculpture, a Lakota Sun Dance drawing, Cree beaded moccasins, and a Kwakwaka’wakw ancestral sun mask. Her strongest readings are her most specific ones, including a discussion of the Lakota Sun Dance drawing written in consultation with multimedia Lakota artist Dana Claxton. This chapter is an impactful mirror to the first chapter’s discussion of Lewis; Bell opens and closes her argument with a focus on Indigenous creativity and its impact in Rome. Her epilogue brings in two additional, fascinating threads that place the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in a more global context: Australian Aboriginal activist Anthony Martin Fernando’s protest at the exhibition, and the VME’s possible influence on the aesthetics of 20th-century Italian fascism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Bell’s extensive footnotes, combined with her first-person accounts of archival research, reveal her breadth of knowledge and indefatigable commitment to her project. Her appendix letters to Pope Francis and Justin Trudeau—the former requesting &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;VME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; collection access, and the latter linking her research to broader Indigenous political projects—underscore an already clear awareness of her work’s international stakes. Altogether, &lt;i&gt;Eternal Sovereigns: Indigenous Artists, Activists, and Travelers Reframing Rome &lt;/i&gt;is a thoughtful consideration of Indigenous presence and creativity in Rome. I am curious to see how Bell’s questions on archival gaps, sovereign relationships, and Indigenous influence will unfold in her future work and in research on transatlantic Indigenous art history at large.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3420&quot;&gt;Lois Taylor Biggs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(Cherokee Nation/White Earth Ojibwe), Rice Curatorial Fellow in Native American Art, Art Institute of Chicago&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4294</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4294</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Gloria Jane Bell</author></item><item><title>The Organic Line: Toward a Topology of Modernism</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4464//The%20Organic%20Line.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Organic Line: Toward a Topology of Modernism&lt;/i&gt;, by Irene V. Small, has the ambition and potential to become a classic. Its starting point is the inflection forged by the work of Lygia Clark on the history of modernism, and its guiding thread is the discovery of the “organic line” in the mid-1950s. This line, which appears wherever two monochromatic planes juxtaposed on the same surface meet, transforms void into breath. Its discovery opened a whole realm of artistic possibilities, which Clark unfolded in her extensive experimentations. What this book explores are the countless reverberations of this organic line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;My commentary is divided into two parts. In the first part I analyze some of the book’s considerable virtues: its theoretical scope, its meticulous critical analyses, and its endeavor to rethink the history of modernism through an oeuvre from the periphery of Western capitalism. In the second part I problematize some of Small’s choices, which are symptomatic of certain biases in current-day academic studies: a particular type of cultural anachronism whereby issues external to the work discussed are projected onto its specific cultural and historical context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The lengthy introduction to the book makes a decisive contribution to comparative studies between historically displaced modernisms. The organic line is what Small uses to guide her thinking about weak links and plagiotropic relations in modern and contemporary art histories. She does not endeavor simply to include Lygia Clark in the hegemonic history of modernism (which has already been done), but to reveal how Clark’s oeuvre and the articulations it suggests with other moments in modern art displace all forms of teleology and historical determinism. As Small explains, “I resist the tendency to chart a linear development that either culminates in or narrowly proceeds from Clark’s discovery in favor of fleshing out multiplicities that pertain to the organic line’s conditions of possibility and conceptual application. These are multiplicities that exceed the artist’s oeuvre and move backward and forward in time” (72).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Plagiotropic relations—a term borrowed from concrete poet Haroldo de Campos’s investigations into translation and from studies of botany—displace the anxiety of influence into a horizontal chain of artistic germinations spawned not through historical belonging but also through creative appropriation. The great merit of Small’s book is the critical density it lends to this plagiotropic movement. Nothing happens by chance, even if there are unexpected movements in which the critical and creative articulation of seemingly distant works results in their cross-fertilization, expanding how we understand the narratives of art history. Therefore, the organic line “allows us to conceptualize modernist art not as a Euclidean space marked by centers and peripheries, vertical traditions, and horizontal circumventions, but as a topological field of interactive, destabilizing tensions” (45).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Small also borrows mathematician René Thom’s concept of “catastrophe” to think about these horizontal fertilizations, in which an initially dysfunctional poetic gesture can produce “a radical and qualitative change in the system’s behavior” (49). This productive dysfunctionality is the reason why the organic dimension was so dear to Clark, yielding nondeterministic and qualitative leaps between cause and effect, creative gesture, and historical processes. In the relations spawned by the organic line, which both separates and composes, it “offers a paradigm of misalignment, rather than cohesion, that defamiliarizes the autonomy and self-evidence of subjects and works of art alike” (158).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In this respect, the proposed dialogue with the work of the Argentinian group Madi and the minimalist paintings of Frank Stella is fundamental. Certainly, they share the same interest in unfolding the articulations between geometric elements and external space and the dialogue between inside and outside of the picture plane. “Works penetrated by actual space are joined by articulated and multipanel paintings, moveable sculptures, irregularly shaped works in relief, canvases with both flat and built-up frames, even pieces that are little more than frames themselves” (107). However, Clark and Neo-Concrete artists in general explored their own quest for the subjective and expressive dimension of art beyond the “ultraformalist,” self-referential playoff between form and space. This was not about returning to the subject, but about searching for a fertilizing encounter among body, form, and space, transforming the spectator into an active coparticipant. This “experience–body” permeates all of Clark’s poetic language. According to Small, “Clark herself later noted that the conflation of the concrete and the geometric was a false affinity, one that could not fully account for her own appeal to the organic as a quality that involves entering or participating in that place, that space, of the picture” (172).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;From here the organic line unfolds into new articulations: (i) with a feminine conception of creation, and (ii) with the “non-geometric” poetics of Roberto Burle-Marx and Jean Arp. Exploring the inversion highlighted by Clark between ovulation and fertilization—“in her process, she is fertilized and then ovulates” (63)—Small proposes an interesting displacement between discovery and invention, between a feminine way of unveiling and a masculine process of invention, of bringing and putting into sight. In a quote from Clark shortly before her death, we can see how this interpretative key works: “‘I, as a Woman—which must have been my weakness and my force—went more towards things that were no longer so visible, so touchable.” Building on this remark, Small continues: “An art history under the sign of the organic line attends to this conjunction of ‘weakness and force’” (345). As for the interaction with Arp and Burle-Marx, the connection between the nonmaking of the organic line and the autopoiesis of botanical life is brought forth. In words reminiscent of Clark, Arp explained in 1944 that “we want to produce like a plant produces fruit, and not reproduce” (172).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Now, we will enter the second part of this review. Throughout Small’s book, there is a noteworthy effort to bring Clark into current political and cultural debates. However, this often ends up forcing the organic line beyond what it can actually show. For example, bringing Clark into the debate concerning abstraction and raciality gives her a voice that, in my view, she does not have. While the discussion of race in the history of art is clearly pressing and pertinent, some of the artists and works that the book treats as political offshoots of the organic line seem arbitrary. For instance, I cannot see this discussion’s echoes in the interventions made by Frente 3 de Fevereiro in the streets and soccer stadiums of São Paulo. Instead, it seems to me that works by artists like Castiel Vitorino Brasileiro and Wagner Schwartz, with their open and subversive bodies, have more to do with this proliferous affiliation of Clark’s organic line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The discussion in chapter two, which associates the organic line with John Cage’s musical silence, contains some original critical speculations but gains little from the inclusion of the racialized musical body in Julius Eastman’s performances. No doubt this discussion is of great interest to students of Cage, but it adds little, I feel, to considerations about Clark’s oeuvre. It might be worth pursuing some other alliances in the political ramifications of the organic line, such as the influence of care theory on the development of less normative and more experimental institutional practices, or the way in which critical and therapeutic issues reverberate in contemporary artistic processes that push back disciplinary boundaries and do not bow to the demands of the art market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The long detour to discuss sexist and racist aspects in the work of architect Le Corbusier is another case in point. Given his influence on modern architecture, this discussion is clearly important. However, taken together with Clark’s work, a commentary on how the more fluid contours of Brazilian architecture deconstructed the orthodoxy of the Corbusian line would be more pertinent. This is certainly something that interfaces with the organic line. Indeed, Oscar Niemeyer’s sinuous ramps offer an original articulation between inside and outside, incorporating whoever enters and moves around the space into the architectural experience. The organic element and participation are thus put together in a very original way here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Finally, bringing in a matter of personal interest, I am always surprised at how some of the best art critics and historians in the US tend to neglect Alexander Calder’s work. In her discussion of an exhibition at the Museo de la Solidaridad Salvador Allende in Chile, Small focuses entirely on connections between Clark’s and Stella’s works. Yet besides them, as the photograph shows, there was a small mobile by Calder—so admired by the art critic Mario Pedrosa and so present on the Brazilian scene when the organic line emerged. There is, regrettably, not a single mention in the entire book of this artist, who gave life and movement to the line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;None of what I said above, to be clear, detracts from Small’s merit in dealing so meticulously and comprehensively with Lygia Clark’s organic line and its critical reverberations. To the contrary, the history of modern and contemporary art gains new and valuable interpretative insights, multiplying its geopolitical perspectives of analysis through some of the challenges, complications, and contentious issues that manifest themselves in Small’s study.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3511&quot;&gt;Luiz Camillo Osorio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Associate Professor, Philosophy Department at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PUC&lt;/span&gt;-Rio; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CNPQ&lt;/span&gt; Researcher; Curator at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PIPA&lt;/span&gt; Institute&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4313</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4313</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Irene V. Small</author></item><item><title>Visual Disobedience: Art and Decoloniality in Central America</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4422//Visual%20Disobidience.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In &lt;i&gt;Visual Disobedience: Art and Decoloniality in Central America&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;Kency Cornejo surveys contemporary political art in Central American countries. The book includes analyses of forty artists and more than eighty works, underscoring the abundance and diversity of artistic experimentation in the region. The author reads these pieces through her concept of “visual disobedience,” a decolonial mode of resistance that posits art as a direct intervention in a specific sociopolitical reality. For Cornejo, these works embody a sensorial practice where the tactile, auditory, and visual coexist and are fundamentally motivated by love for the “&lt;i&gt;damnés&lt;/i&gt;,”—the condemned, as put by Franz Fanon. The chapters of the book are structured around four main interconnected themes: Indigenous art, gender and sexuality, migration, and the carceral system. Such categories allow the author to deal with pressing issues such as femicide, the separation of migrant children from their families, anti-Blackness, the violation of human rights under prison captivity, and violence against queer people, among many others. Cornejo approaches these topics and their entanglement with artistic practices through a methodology that highlights the history of violence and power in the region, particularly its ties to colonialism and US imperialism. For Cornejo, the practices included in her different chapters embody “a critical understanding of how colonial legacies and US empire fuel the mass exodus of refugees and asylum seekers arriving at the US-Mexico border” (5).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The book’s conceptual scaffolding begins in the introduction, where Cornejo states how visual disobedience “is a defiance of both state repression and visual coloniality” (10). She defines visual coloniality as a result of historical processes of visual erasure, visual thingnification, and visual extractivism that remain ongoing today. Visual erasure refers to the rejection of Indigenous systems of knowledge and artistic practices by European colonizers; the “colonial deletion of Indigenous artistic history and significance to impose colonial standards as superior and unreachable” (28). Visual thingification is the commodification of the colonized and its transformation through symbolic and physical procedures that justify the perpetuation of violence. Last, Cornejo’s notion of visual extractivism is connected to how Indigenous communities have historically faced “looting of resources, pollution of water and land, privatization and food scarcity, diseases, and decreased life expectancy” (25). For the author, visual extractivism refers to the appropriation of Indigenous visual design: from the looting of Indigenous objects by European explorers to the presence of Indigenous designs in contemporary fashion, or the touristification of Indigenous elements. In return, Indigenous peoples are targeted and discriminated against when they use their traditional garments and clothing. The artists surveyed in the book defy such processes by aesthetic means, and it is this understanding of art as political praxis that for the author, constitutes a decolonial mode of aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The first chapter of the book analyzes the work of contemporary Mayan artists. During the Guatemalan Civil War (1960–96) thousands of Indigenous people were killed, and Mayan children were explicitly targeted by the military, led by the dictator José Efraín Ríos Montt, because they were deemed a future threat. Cornejo shows how the artists included in this chapter, who were children during the conflict, respond to the aftermath of the genocide and approach the numerous forms of violence that Indigenous communities face in the present. Cornejo analyzes the work of Benvenuto Chavajay, Sandra Monterroso, and Ángel Poyón, artists who use performance to demand justice and heal the historical trauma caused by the war, but also “across centuries of settler colonial violence and coloniality” (43). She also studies practices that engage with Indigenous worldviews in myriad ways. In the works of Chavajay and Ángel Poyón, objects are resignified to challenge Western conceptions of linear time and to insist on natural elements as sacred. Artist Fernando Poyón critiques the imposition of Christianity on Indigenous communities, and Antonio Pichillá enacts the inaccessibility of Mayan spirituality as a form of visual resistance. In addition, Cornejo shows how artists like Monterroso, Marilyn Elany Boror Bor, and Edgar Calel problematize identity through pieces that address the forced assimilation of Indigenous subjects and the effects of cultural uprooting, displacement, and migration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The second chapter deals with postwar feminist and queer art in the region. Cornejo identifies a turn to the body in Central American postwar artistic practices characterized by performative interventions in public spaces, where the body becomes “a site of protest, dissidence, testimony, healing, intervention, remembering, and memory making” (82). She surveys the work of artists Regina José Galindo, Isabel Ruiz, Alexia Miranda, Natalia Domínguez, Jorge Oquelí, and Priscilla Monge, who use their bodies to condemn state violence, feminicide, sexual violence, and violence against queer people. In particular, the work of Galindo and Monge aims to dismantle the divide between the private and public dimensions of feminicide and domestic violence. Moreover, in this chapter, the author engages with the intersection between gender and labor. The pieces by Colectivo Artería and by Dalia Chévez show women’s exploitation in &lt;i&gt;maquiladoras&lt;/i&gt;—factory workspaces on the rise after the implementation of Central America-Dominican Republic Free Trade Agreement (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CAFTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)—an expansion of The North American Free Trade Agreement (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NAFTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) that includes Central American countries. On a similar note, Lucy Argueta, Monterroso, and Galindo problematize the connection between the exploitation of women’s bodies and that of natural resources. Cornejo’s intersectional feminism also insists on how race impacts the configuration of gender. The work of Katie Numi Usher exposes anti-Blackness in the region and critiques the body shaming that results from Western beauty standards, a concern that takes place in pieces by María Raquel Cochez too. Lastly, the chapter closes with analyses of artists Martin Wannam and Elyla (Fredman Barahona). Cornejo focuses on their claim to erotic autonomy and on the exclusion of queer subjects from revolutionary narratives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The third chapter opens with an analysis of a piece by artist Mauricio Esquivel where a tattoo of the line of an autopsy incision covers his body. Cornejo reads this work through the connection between borders and violence, which she also examines in the foundational painting &lt;i&gt;El Sumpul &lt;/i&gt;(1984) by Carlos Cañas, and in embroidery art made by Salvadoran women. In this chapter, the author explores how Central American artists are producing counternarratives of mass migration in the region. These works “shift the border”: they portray borders as mobile and expansive, as regimes that surpass specific national frontiers. They also move beyond the US-Mexico border. The work of Guillermo “Habacuc” Vargas shows the violent consequences of antiimmigrant sentiments in Costa Rica and Nicaragua, fueled by citizen passivity, failed revolutionary promises, and anti-Blackness. Here Cornejo explains how Mexico can be understood as a &quot;vertical border” (148), due to the anti-immigration policies implemented throughout the country to deter mobility. The work of Regina José Galindo addresses migrant experiences in Mexico, and for the author, her performative pieces place the body as the main target of the externalization of border practices developed by the US. In her words, “Galindo’s actions are a reminder of both the physical harm of such policies and the ongoing physical resistance to the violent spatial logics of mobility control” (152). The author also engages with representations of migration that overcome victimization and focus on creativity and collectivity, as seen in the work of Ronald Morán and Guadalupe Maravilla. Artists like Walterio Iraheta and Catalina del Cid highlight the emotional toil of migration. At the same time, Myra Barraza, Simón Vega, and Adán Vallecillo use different media to explore the effect of remittances in Central America and their connection to international businesses. For Cornejo, these artists offer a complex portrayal of migration in its personal, geographical, and financial dimensions and portray “cartographic disobedience,” or the production of maps based on embodied engagements with space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The last chapter of the book deals with criminalization, prisons, and social cleansing in the region. The author states that the artists surveyed depict a carceral logic “that perpetuates the criminalization of Central Americans across borders and that is inseparable from the colonial agenda of social cleansing of poor, racialized, and marginalized people” (183). The work of the collective Los Siempre Sospechosos de Todo (“The Ever Suspected Ones”), created after the unfounded arrest of a twenty-one-year-old man, critiques the judicial system in Central America through performance and participation. Artists Danny Zavaleta, Simón Vega, Jorge de León, and Alma Leiva engage with urban and domestic spaces and explore how these are shaped by criminality and fear, for instance, in the expansion of security systems or the self-confinement provoked by street violence. In addition, Cornejo explains how the work of Alicia María Siu and Marton Robinson insists on the criminalization of Indigenous and Black subjects, highlighting the historical intersection between race, class, and visual thingnification. The pieces by Zavaleta and Jhafis Quintero also reflect on the experience of inmates in Central American prisons through personal letters, objects, and survival manuals. For Cornejo, in Central America the prison is a site of social cleansing, something explored in the work of Galindo, Jorge Oquelí, and Gabriel Galeano. These artists respond to multiple cases of prison fires that were not properly investigated by the law. Finally, the chapter deals with the portrayal of migrant children detention in the works of Ernesto Bautista, Maravilla, and Galindo. The author explains how these artists highlight the harm that migrant children endure, but also register their testimonies in ways that counteract portrayals of helplessness and victimhood, and move towards creation and survival.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In &lt;i&gt;Visual Disobedience: Art and Decoloniality in Central America &lt;/i&gt;the reader will find a substantial survey of contemporary Central American art that deals with a wide variety of political issues. Cornejo approaches these through detailed historical and geographical contextualization. She produces an innovative cartography of dissident practices in the region that complicate both aesthetic and political assumptions about migration, violence, and oppression. The author’s analyses are direct, concise, and guided by thematic correspondences. Most importantly, they focus on what the works can politically do in their context of production. Cornejo understands the examined pieces as direct interventions in the public sphere that question patriarchal, colonial, and neoliberal forms of visuality. The book is an important contribution to Latin American art histories because of its careful conceptual framework, extensive research, and exploration of pressing sociopolitical questions in Central America. It establishes the relevance of aesthetics for the disentanglement of power structures.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3485&quot;&gt;Irene Rihuete-Varea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Brown University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4280</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4280</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Kency Cornejo</author></item><item><title>East Asian Aesthetics and the Space of Painting in Eighteenth-Century Europe</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4442//East%20Asian%20Aesthetics%20.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The intriguing title of Isabelle Tillerot’s monograph both piques curiosity and encapsulates the thesis that its text develops in detail. Deploying astute observations and subtle insight, this study follows the evolution of room decoration in seventeenth and eighteenth-century European, principally French royal and aristocratic dwellings. Its focus is on the close relationship between the ornamental designs of these spaces and the paintings embedded within them, projects that required the joint efforts of artists and artisans of varied specializations and status. Ultimately it asserts that the full flowering of rocaille—the author rejects the nineteenth-century term “rococo”—decor coincides with the adoption of a specific set of formal characteristics derived from East Asian art. Following a warmly appreciative foreword by Mark Ledbury, the introduction promises a focus on the transcultural impact of Chinese and Japanese painting, although this subject is not approached until the fourth chapter, halfway through the text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In the first chapter, “The Places of Painting,” Tillerot introduces the theme of interactions between paintings and the objects and surfaces surrounding them. Concentrating on the importance of carved and gilded frames, molding, and paneling, she considers ”the décor as the place of painting” (62). The text then provides detailed descriptions of rooms in the seventeenth-century Parisian hôtel de Lauzun and hôtel Lambert, the latter decorated by Eustache Le Sueur and Charles Le Brun, that present characteristically Baroque &lt;i&gt;da sotto in su &lt;/i&gt;perspective, trompe l’oeil grisailles of sculpture, and fictive architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Chapter two, “Decor and Time,” examines aspects of this pairing in seventeenth- and eighteenth-century Parisian interiors. The painted illusion of outside distance visible through an opening in a wall is discussed first. Practiced in classical antiquity, this genre of painting was revived in the early modern age, linking eras divided by a vast span of time. Next considered is the possible chronological difference between ornamental arrangements and the paintings they enclose. Generally, this involved the placement of an earlier composition into a later decorative scheme, but the reverse procedure was also employed. In either situation, Tillerot contends, the ornamental carving, stucco works, and trompe l’oeil features surrounding the paintings relegated them to secondary status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In the early eighteenth century a painting received more attention when it was from the same era as its surroundings. Increased townhouse construction in the first half of the century created further opportunities for paintings, which were emphasized by frames that mediated between them and the carved decorations. Ceiling painting having become unfashionable late in the seventeenth century, its imagery became limited to overdoors and areas above mantels and mirrors; in the Princess’s Oval Salon in the hôtel de Soubise the restricted space allotted to Charles Joseph Natoire’s works dictated their compositions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt; The third chapter, “The Trajectory of the Arabesque,” traces the progression and varieties of this quintessential rocaille decorative component. Characterizing it as the ornamental form “that has effected the greatest transformation of the role of the picture” (109). Tillerot lists its typical elements, including “abstract, floral, linear, and geometrical figures” in the form of “cartouches (a term left undefined), foliated scrolls, [and] meanders of ribbon” (110). This is followed by many examples supporting the assertion that the arabesque allowed artists freedom from the constraints that architectural structuring had placed on their work. Contributions by a series of ornamentist artists are examined; these include Jean I Bérain, whose “airy compositions give greater prominence to empty spaces than to markings” (111). The term “grotesque” is employed here, also without definition, as companion to “arabesque.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Singeries, further noted in the chapter, were included in the work of Claude &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;III&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Audran beginning in 1709; representational painters, including Jean Antoine Watteau and Nicolas Lancret, furnished figural images that were surrounded by his arabesques. The art of Juste Aurèle Meissonnier, to which the term rocaille was first applied, receives attention, as well as that of sculptor Nicolas Pineau, characterized by complex undulating scrolls; both artists notably favored asymmetry. Works by Jacques de Lajoüe elaborated the framing decoration by incorporating extensive figural features and favoring the cartouche. Describing a drawing by sculptor-designer Pierre Edme Babel, Tillerot observes that use of the arabesque enables the establishment of a new formal unity between a pictorial image and its frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The fourth chapter, “Asian Motifs in European Decoration,” is devoted to the characteristics of chinoiserie—European art and material culture based on Asian, especially Far Eastern, imagery. Following the claim that interior design was the principal creative form to reflect Asian models, Tillerot details the panels painted by Watteau for the château de la Muette. She notes that his sources were imports from East Asian delete and Chinese drawings sent to France by Jesuit missionaries as well as engravings illustrating Johan Nieuhoff’s account of the first Dutch embassy in China. Watteau’s depictions became sources for images on numerous objects, including furniture, screens, porcelain figurines, textiles, and wall paintings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Tillerot finds the singerie and chinoiserie combined with European imagery painted by Christophe Huet in the Château de Chantilly and elsewhere to be superficial rather than displaying genuine absorption of Chinese and Japanese approaches. She explores European fascination with premier East Asian materials, detailing collections of porcelain and noting the particular popularity of blue-and-white style and celadon. Often adorned with gold, imported lacquer objects were also coveted. Some European chinoiserie cabinets decorated with Chinese themes and figures displayed imitations of these luxury substances.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;In Chapter five, “The East Asian Idea of Taste,” we finally come to the crux of Tillerot’s thesis. Adopting the concept of “taste” as an entry point, she distinguishes between enthusiasm for Asian objects and subjects on the one hand and “elements of a comprehensive non-European approach to design and representation” that “elicited a more enduring refashioning of the mind” (177) on the other. By the mid-eighteenth century the transition between these two forms of reception had begun, with East Asian imports modified by being cut down and given gold, silver, or bronze accessories as well as being displayed in collections. The juxtapositions provided a surprise for the eye, engendered pleasure, and contributed to developing taste.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;This is followed by the observation that Chinese art was first integrated as a subsidiary feature in interior decoration, kept at the edges of rooms, tapestries, and wall and ceiling designs; similarly early Chinese rooms created in Europe were at the outer areas or entirely outside of buildings. Examples presented include the Japanese Cabinet at the Hermitage Old Palace at Bayreuth and the Chinese Pavilion at Drottningholm Castle in Sweden, but the Chinese village created for Catherine the Great at Tsarskoye Selo is not mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Tillerot then contends that East Asian employment of emptiness in design had a fundamental impact on the West, demonstrated in lacquerwork cabinetry. This choice elicited praise for whiteness in Chinese and Japanese gardens, known from imported objects and travelers’ accounts. After recounting the contributions to Chinese garden theory by Jean Denis Attiret and especially by William Chambers, Tillerot details its goal: the integration of natural features and architecture with the passage of time experienced by one walking through the location, accomplished through shaping formal elements to create surprise impressions.&amp;nbsp; She affirms the significant effects of interior decoration adopting the whiteness that evokes distances in Chinese gardens and painting; when not left white, walls were painted in pale hues. Various greens, suggesting landscape, were also employed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The sixth chapter, “Another Way of Representing the World,” cites the contrast between East Asian art and the symmetry and regularity characterizing ancient Greco-Roman creations.&amp;nbsp; Following is a discussion of textiles, among the first chinoiserie productions, with attention to the highly successful tapestry series, &lt;i&gt;The Story of the Emperor of China&lt;/i&gt;. The earliest European work with a Chinese subject, these compositions still display traditional Western perspective and horizon lines. The same structure marks the works of François Boucher, who owned “an immense collection of Asian” (222) items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Tillerot then considers European adoption of Asian ambiguous, indefinite portrayal of space accompanied by chinoiserie motifs and surrounded by rocaille arabesques. Backgrounds are left plain, shadowing is eliminated, and compositions are asymmetrical, with empty, open areas. Typically, in Jean Pillement’s drawings small vignettes float in a void. Paintings he created or inspired harmonize with adjoining arabesque areas by employing similar background hues. The spectator’s gaze is guided in new ways within and around the image, ornamentation having been freed from the control of the architectural structure. Chinoiserie’s association with the rocaille, Tillerot observes, kept it from being taught in the academies. The status of ornamentist artisans was as a result intensely debated but ultimately they achieved recognition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The short conclusion, titled “Asian Caprice, or Making an Island of the Picture,” adds some observations that might appropriately have appeared earlier in the text: we learn that the “Chinese picture begins in its lower part and ends in its upper part,” that “everything that tends toward the distance . . . is represented high on the surface” (248) and that its visible elements suggest those that are invisible. In her characteristically evocative language this section sums up the author’s thought-provoking thesis concerning the transformative impact of East Asian art on Western design.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3500&quot;&gt;Anne Betty Weinshenker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Professor Emerita, Department of Art and Design, Montclair State University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4298</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4298</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Isabelle Tillerot</author></item><item><title>The Minjian Avant-Garde: Art of the Crowd in Contemporary China Anxiety Aesthetics: Maoist Legacies in China, 1978–1985</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4392//The%20Minjian.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Joining a growing number of publications that have sought to reexamine China’s socialist legacy, two new books examine the ways in which contemporary art practice and discourse reengaged the social and political commitments of the Maoist period (1949–76). Jennifer Lee’s &lt;i&gt;Anxiety Aesthetics: Maoist Legacies in China, 1978–1985&lt;/i&gt; focuses on the roughly eight years immediately following the end of the Cultural Revolution (1966–76) to examine how artists and intellectuals reconfigured socialist aesthetics for the post-Mao era. In &lt;i&gt;The Minjian Avant-Garde: Art of the Crowd in Contemporary China&lt;/i&gt;, Chang Tan looks to a later moment in the 1990s and early 2000s when artists deliberately invoked, thematized, and incorporated the “&lt;i&gt;minjian,&lt;/i&gt;” or the nonelite mass public, in their art practices. While both books focus on the search for artistic subjectivities that are informed by the contradictions of the post-Mao transition, they take fundamentally different approaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Anxiety Aesthetics&lt;/i&gt; covers an understudied period in current art historical scholarship. While many scholars have focused on contemporary art well after the end of the Cultural Revolution and others including Julia Andrews, Denise Ho, and Yi Gu, have looked back to reassess the Mao years, few—with the exception of Jane Debevoise and Martina Köppel-Yang— have paid close attention to the immediate aftermath of the revolution. Lee shows us that this period of artistic transition is indeed worthy of our attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Focusing “less on object-oriented approaches to works of art and more on a holistic portrait that takes up the discourse, intellectual history, and events that together form the maker of art,” &lt;i&gt;Anxiety Aesthetics&lt;/i&gt; foregrounds socialist aesthetics—a lineage of socially engaged art practices and aesthetic theories—which constitutes what Lee sees as a prehistory of contemporary art in China today (5).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Lee distinguishes her account from previous efforts to examine appropriations of Mao-era imagery in contemporary art by her aims to take socialism seriously. Lee hones in on what she calls a period of revolutionary failure to develop her key concept of “anxiety aesthetics,” which she defines through John Dewey’s concept of a “structure of feeling,” as a “a persistent revolutionary episteme, an order of knowing the world through both radical practices and the language of socialist materialist logic” (11). Anxiety offers Lee a way to situate this period and its artists within a more expansive history of postsocialism that connects strains of intellectual thought both before and after the end of the Cultural Revolution. In exploring how the intellectual and discursive genealogy of socialist art was earnestly taken up by artists and critics after the end of the Cultural Revolution, her account challenges the longstanding paradigm of a radical break between the Mao and post-Mao years. Instead, she argues that artists and intellectuals in the immediate aftermath of the Cultural Revolution did not simply reject socialist aesthetics wholesale, but rather painstakingly reworked it in ways that reasserted art’s political engagement in social life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Balancing three chapters focused on artists and their art practices with two chapters focused on the analysis of art criticism, Lee introduces readers to a key group—artist and activist Huang Rui who founded the Stars Art Group, artist and critic Wu Guanzhong, artist Qu Leilei, and critic Liu Zaifu—who sees art practice as a continuation of socialism’s commitments to the transformation of social consciousness. Their anxiety to transmit art’s social aims, Lee argues, can be linked to a longer legacy of twentieth-century Chinese intellectuals who “worried about China” and who saw their creative output as having the power to guide and transform society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter one connects the artistic activity of the well-known Stars Art Group with their political participation in the Beijing Spring (1978–80) and collective actions centered around the Democracy Wall. These activities included the posting of big and small character posters—a practice that continued from the Cultural Revolution—and the publication and display of citizen magazines, including the new poetry magazine &lt;i&gt;Today&lt;/i&gt;. Focusing on the social and political significance of the Stars’ activities rather than their works’ visual qualities, Lee analyzes the ways in which the group’s exhibition techniques “reproduced and repurposed strategies of collective action and grassroots organization established during the Mao-era campaigns after 1949” in order to “push against the government’s promotion of a slow historical amnesia that represses collective memory” (17).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter two analyzes Huang Rui’s 1981 painting &lt;i&gt;Democracy Wall&lt;/i&gt;, which captures key cultural agitators of the Beijing Spring against the backdrop of the eponymous wall where many of their collective actions occurred. Lee explores Huang’s art practice as a process of self-definition and the ways in which the artist negotiated his identity as both artist and activist. Huang’s painting and its various preparatory sketches, she argues, can be understood as an act of bearing witness to and memorializing the democratic aspirations of the Beijing Spring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter three, a particularly strong chapter that showcases Lee’s deftness with literary history and theory, examines the artist and critic Wu Guanzhong’s attempts to redefine and promote a distinctly socialist strain of abstraction in the post-Mao period. In a move consistent with the author’s discursive approach to art, Lee locates Wu’s aesthetic contributions squarely in the realm of discourse rather than in his prolific art practice and the paintings themselves. Tracing the strains of intellectual thought that inform Wu’s seminal 1979 article, “Formalist Aesthetics in Painting,” Lee uncovers the convergence of art historical concepts of abstraction with notions of abstraction in Maoist scientific socialism. Lee’s achievements in this chapter have much larger implications as it outlines a lineage of abstraction that was historically specific to the postsocialist Chinese context. As Lee reveals, “abstraction maintained meanings in China that diverged . . . from its canonical positioning in modernist critique throughout North America and Western Europe from the mid-twentieth century on” (72). By taking socialist aesthetics seriously, Lee manages to illuminate a different set of urgent stakes for abstraction that go beyond the conventional Cold War ideologies around American abstraction versus Socialist bloc realism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter four examines the diary images and drawings of the artist Qu Leilei, a founding member of the Stars Art Group, to reveal how the artist drew upon earlier twentieth-century modes of publicly oriented formats that combined text and image such as woodblock prints, posters of the socialist laborer or Mao imagery, into more private, internalized forms of historical memory and creative subject-formation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter five returns to literary history by analyzing the writings of Liu Zaifu, a scholar writing on the subject of literary subjectivity in the mid-1980s. The chapter delves deeply into early Mao-era Chinese socialist discourse that drew from Marxist writings and includes close reading of dense literary passages to uncover the ways in which Liu’s writings were informed by this longer tradition of Marxist thought. Lee shows how Liu repurposed Maoist socialism in order to formulate an emergent post-Mao subjectivity that was commensurate with Reform Era society in the mid-1980s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Deftly extrapolating an expansive intellectual history from a tight temporal timeframe, &lt;i&gt;Anxiety Aesthetics&lt;/i&gt; paints a picture of Maoist legacies that reveals it to be neither monolithic nor unchanging. Rather, socialist aesthetics emerges as a rather malleable set of material practices and intellectual traditions that its inheritors can and do actively reshape in their efforts to redefine a postrevolutionary subjecthood characterized by an anxious sense of individual agency and social responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In &lt;i&gt;The Minjian Avant-Garde&lt;/i&gt;, Tan turns to a later period to also examine how artists and artworks revived and reworked aspects of the socialist legacy for the present. Whereas Lee tracks a discursive and intellectual history to tell a history of socialist aesthetic theory, Tan emphasizes a more object-oriented approach that foregrounds artmaking, artworks, and artistic networks. Examining the “&lt;i&gt;minjian&lt;/i&gt; avant-garde,” which she defines as “art that uses the material, demographic, and territorial marginality of &lt;i&gt;minjian&lt;/i&gt; as a means to critique, revitalize, and transform itself, and, at the same time, to engage and bring changes to the &lt;i&gt;minjian&lt;/i&gt; it encounters,” Tan puts critical pressure on the contradictions between these dual and often competing goals (4).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Like Lee, Tan maintains that the art practices she examines are a domestic phenomenon, albeit one that comes to intersect with the global art world that Chinese artists increasingly encountered into the 1990s and early 2000s. Acknowledged throughout the book—particularly in Tan’s references to the tension between “the singular” and “the multitude”—is the way in which the minjian avant-garde is related to the global development of socially engaged art or collaborative art practices described in studies by Grant Kester and Claire Bishop, among others. Tan attends to these international influences as well as the competing sets of artworlds and value systems that motivated the minjian avant-garde, ultimately suggesting that this global context plays no small role—and perhaps even more consequential of a role than any distinctly postsocialist domestic intellectual lineage—in shaping the concerns of Chinese artists during this period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter one shares the greatest overlap with Lee’s study. It examines Mao Xuhui and Huang Yong Ping, two “proto-minjian avant-gardes” and their works from the mid-1980s. Tan contextualizes their art practice within the post-Mao culture of the 1980s, a period when new notions of individualism and self-expression had to be reconciled with an increasingly pervasive mass commercial culture. Through collages featuring texts and images culled from print culture, the appropriation of found everyday materials, or the relocation of artworks outside of institutional museum spaces, Mao and Huang challenged art’s singularity by foregrounding intersections between avant-garde art and minjian popular culture. Yet as Tan points out, the avant-garde artists’ desire to engage audiences often resulted in unexpected results of public hostility and misunderstanding—a tension further explored in several of the following chapters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter two focuses on the artist Qiu Zhijie’s use of calligraphy to blur the boundaries between the private and public as well as the individual and the collective. Tan argues that through methods of copying and sourcing writings from everyday individuals, Qiu privileges the act of “writing words” over the elite “art of calligraphy,” ultimately framing writing—an impersonal, collective act that is informed by repetitive training, rules, and regulation—as an embodied “archive” of the minjian. Tan’s attention to the dynamics of the individual versus the collective that undergirds Qiu’s work allows her to offer a nuanced account of Qiu’s seminal piece &lt;i&gt;Assignment No. 1: Copying the ‘Orchid Pavilion Preface’ 1,000 Times&lt;/i&gt;, which she argues was not simply a cynical act of self-erasure, but an attempt to articulate an alternative mode of selfhood that is “embodied, affectively potent, yet &lt;i&gt;neither&lt;/i&gt; self-contained &lt;i&gt;nor&lt;/i&gt; singular” (53). Yet, as Tan points out, Qiu’s embrace of calligraphy as a minjian practice also stems from his encounters with multiple art worlds, and his broader aims to recuperate the minjian to counter both Eurocentric standards of art and Sinocentric discourses on calligraphy. Ironically, these goals ultimately redirect his interest and audience back to the elite contemporary art world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter three examines &lt;i&gt;The Long March: A Walking Visual Display&lt;/i&gt; (2002), a multisited curatorial project initiated by the UK trained curator Lu Jie and Qiu Zhijie, in which artist participants re–walk the historical journey of the Red Army during its retreat to Yan’an during the Chinese Civil War. Along the way, artists engaged locals in collaborative art projects and challenged the mythical status of the revolutionary past. As Tan explains, however, these attempts to collaborate with villagers and initiate art activities that connected to their everyday lives resulted in only a few rare cases of affective connection, among interactions largely characterized by misunderstanding and miscommunication. Invoking Hal Foster’s critique of art’s “ethnographic turn,” Tan points to the pitfalls of avant-garde art’s “primitivist” tendencies and the ways in which the minjian avant-garde “share the predicament of all participatory and socially engaged art” (92). Yet Tan also suggests that this predicament is “uniquely compounded by the Maoist heritage” (92). Without further elaboration, however, the reader is left to wonder—with a nod to Lee’s more discursive methodology—how the artists might have had to reframe the aims of collectivism and populism given its excesses during the Cultural Revolution or how the historic experience of young urban intellectuals “sent down to the countryside” might have complicated the relationship between the minjian avant-garde and villagers during the project. In this chapter, further attention to the discursive specificity of China’s postsocialist condition would have enhanced the conclusions Tan draws from this case study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter four examines several artists who engage the minjian primarily through their interest in commodity objects and mass culture. From Jiao Xingtao’s recreation of a commercial sculpture studio as an installation in an art museum to Li Mu’s staging of reproductions of well-known works of contemporary Western art in the everyday spaces of his rural hometown or the Yangdeng Co-op’s efforts to collaborate with villagers on projects that responded to their daily lives in a small town in the remote Guizhou Province, these art practices aim to challenge hierarchies between creative and productive labor and between the rarefied status of contemporary art and everyday material culture and spaces. As Tan demonstrates, however, these projects either end up reaffirming the distinctions between avant-garde art and the minjian, or becoming so thoroughly absorbed into the conventional everydayness of minjian life that they end up losing their critical edge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The last chapter focuses on the internationally renowned artist Ai Weiwei, who has most visibly championed minjian causes through large-scale socially engaged projects. Tan sees Ai as the minjian avant-garde artist par excellence: his ability to combine the singular and the multiple in both his artworks and his public persona reflects the appeal and the socio-political aims of minjian-based art practice, yet it is also rife with the many internal contradictions that are central to her critique of the minjian avant-garde. Tan foregrounds Ai’s ability to mobilize and connect networks of human and financial resources both domestically and internationally to promote the minjian, but also points to the ways in which his cultural capital and the ability to move flexibly across different worlds fundamentally distinguish him from the disenfranchised minjian he seeks to represent. Like many of the artists discussed in the book, Ai’s incorporation of members of the minjian in his projects allows him to draw on their “marginal” status to re-present his work as a radical alternative to the global art world despite the ways in which he and his art projects are part and parcel of it. Ultimately, Tan argues that Ai’s centrality as the singular artist orchestrating his works, undercuts his invocation of the multitude and underscores “the fundamental inequality and disconnection between the one and the many” (134).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Throughout the book Tan maintains a critical attitude towards the minjian&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;avant-garde, highlighting its uneasy alliance with the state’s neo-socialist policies, its uncritical embrace of the banal aspects of mass culture, its disconnect with its purported subjects, and its overdetermined motivations in positioning avant-garde art practice within domestic and international arenas. The crux of these problems, as Tan reveals, is the fundamental contradiction between the avant-garde imperative to critically stand apart from the masses and the ideals of becoming indistinguishable from the minjian—a condition, which Tan acknowledges in the end may never be fully resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Anxiety Aesthetics&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;The Minjian Avant-Garde&lt;/i&gt; both offer illuminating accounts of the complexity of art practices after the Maoist period and the ways in which artists sought to articulate and act upon the aims of a socially and politically engaged art practice. If, as Lee asserts in the conclusion of her book, this postsocialist aesthetic lineage has significant consequences for our understanding of contemporary art after the 1980s, one would expect vestiges of these intellectual concerns to be found in Tan’s analysis of the minjian avant-garde. Yet the two sets of artists described in each of these books seem to inhabit entirely separate discursive worlds and orientations. At least in Tan’s portrayal, artistic engagements with the minjian feel more pragmatic and appropriative, than the kind of anxious, yet earnest working through of socialist aesthetics ideals described by Lee. As Tan insightfully notes, avant-garde art’s nativist turn toward the minjian is simultaneously also an outward turn to situate their art practice in relation to the global contemporary art world. This disparity would appear to reaffirm the longstanding periodization of the rupture between the 1980s and the 1990s that Lee argues against at the outset of her book and is evidenced by the “global turn” in contemporary art from China. To my mind, this only goes to prove how singular and important Lee’s account of the overlooked decade between the end of the Cultural Revolution and the mid-to-late 1980s is. Lee has given us the prehistory to the postsocialist contemporary; what still remains to be written is a history of where this socialist intellectual legacy in contemporary art from China goes from there.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3465&quot;&gt;Nancy P. Lin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cornell University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4257</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4257</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Chang Tan Jennifer Dorothy Lee</author></item><item><title>The Ghost in the City: Luo Ping and the Craft of Painting in Eighteenth-Century China</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4416//The%20Ghost%20In%20The%20City..jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Michele Matteini’s&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;The Ghost in the City: Luo Ping and the Craft of Painting in Eighteenth-Century China&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers insight on the&amp;nbsp;eighteenth-century artist Luo Ping’s (1733­–1799) position in the history of painting in China and sheds light on the intricate relationship between artist and patron. Known as one of the “Eight Eccentrics of Yangzhou,” Luo is primarily recognized for his unusual paintings of ghosts and his activities in the commercial city of Yangzhou. Luo Ping was introduced to audiences in Europe and the US through a 2009 exhibition that traveled between Museum Rietberg and the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and in studies by Kim Karlsson (&lt;i&gt;Luo Ping: The Life, Career, and Art of an Eighteenth-Century Chinese Painter&lt;/i&gt;, Peter Lang, 2004) and Ginger Hsu (&lt;i&gt;A Bushel of Pearls: Painting for Sale in Eighteenth-Century Yangchow, &lt;/i&gt;Stanford University Press, 2001). Interpretations of Luo have largely focused on the economic and historical circumstances of his work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;For Matteini, Luo Ping is no longer just one of the “Eight Eccentrics”; rather, Luo played an important role in historicizing Yangzhou experimentalisms after arriving in Beijing in the 1770s. The author suggests that Luo’s art was an essential link between the orthodox traditions, the innovations of earlier individualist artists Shitao (1642–1707) and Jin Nong (1687–1773), and later nineteenth-century practices that developed into modern ink painting. Matteini’s understanding of Luo Ping helps reposition art from eighteenth-century China, challenging the conventional understanding that paintings from this period were either regurgitations of the past or idiosyncratic products of eccentricity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Ghost in the City&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is set in Beijing in the late eighteenth century when Luo created works for some of the most influential political figures in the Qing dynasty (1644–1911) government. The book starts off with Luo Ping’s haunting&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;In the Realm of the Ghosts&lt;/i&gt;, ca. 1766. The ghosts and demons, which Luo was&amp;nbsp;allegedly able to see under broad daylight, are formed by subtle ink washes and blurry lines that capture the in-betweenness of their existence. This highly unconventional painting drew a great deal of attention and helped Luo Ping launch his career in the capital soon after its creation. While the ghost scroll is often interpreted as social and political satire, the author proposes that we “take ghosts as ghosts and not as ghosts of something” (7).&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;!—StartFragment—&amp;gt;&lt;span data-olk-copy-source=&quot;MessageBody&quot;&gt;In other words, to “take ghosts as ghosts” entails prioritizing what is on the&amp;nbsp;scroll, embracing its complexity and&amp;nbsp;ambiguity, and acknowledging that artworks and context are&amp;nbsp;interdependent and&amp;nbsp;mutually defined&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;!—EndFragment—&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;(10). It is under this premise that he approaches the dual goals of this book: trailing Luo Ping’s activities as they unfolded in Southern City in Qianlong-era (r. 1735–1796) Beijing and exploring the spaces in the capital as they appear in Luo Ping’s art (6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Matteini’s approach combines the careful examination of images, inscriptions, and context, without losing sight of the surface of the paintings. While there is room for further clarification and exploration,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Ghost in the City&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;concretizes the social mechanisms and creative considerations surrounding Luo Ping’s artistic practice. It not only lends insight into Luo’s art but can also inform our understanding of how other painters&amp;nbsp;in similar situations functioned&amp;nbsp;at that time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The first chapter introduces the physical and cultural geography of Beijing’s southern quarters, what was then known as the Southern City. He highlights the dynamic, informal social&amp;nbsp;networks prevalent among cultural elites in the area, where powerful officials supported their private entourage of political think tanks, literary advisors, and artists-in-residence.&amp;nbsp;The author links this close-knit web of relationships to a new development in paintings of literati gatherings—a shift of focus from individuals to shared values and experiences. Instead of close-up scenes that highlight individual participants, Luo Ping portrayed these social functions as a cozy affair set against a spacious courtyard. Matteini calls these paintings “conversational,” in that the colophons that crowd the margins replicate the overlapping voices at a social event (29–30).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In chapter two, Matteini effectively argues that Luo Ping’s success in Beijing was largely due to his ability to capitalize on specific artistic and literary references that matched the preferences of his patrons. By channeling the innovations of his artistic predecessors from Yangzhou while also engaging with orthodox styles, Luo marketed himself as a Southern artist who combined art historical erudition and artistic originality. This chapter offers a compelling analysis of the stylistic relationship between Luo Ping’s landscape albums and works by his recent artistic predecessors—Dong Qichang (1555–1636), who prioritized art historical erudition, and Yangzhou-based Shitao and Jin Nong, who were both known for their artistic originality (76–80). The author suggests that Luo Ping historicized and canonized the visual experiments of Shitao and Jin Nong, securing Yangzhou’s place on the map of painting history (92).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Chapter three centers upon Luo’s&amp;nbsp;painting &lt;i&gt;The Two Miaos and Su Shi&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;to discuss a cultural phenomenon where scholar-officials presented themselves as a reincarnation of their literary idols. In this painting, a scholar dressed in Su Shi’s signature headwear and staff greets a Buddhist monk and a Daoist priest, both named Miao. Weng Fanggang’s (1733–1818) title inscription tells us the “two Miaos” both painted Su Shi. But Matteini points out that the narrative in the image is intentionally ambiguous because none of the figures have clearly directed gazes. He argues that this “anti-theatricality” rejects a clear separation inside and outside the painting and suggests a continuity between the fictional and real worlds (102).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The relationship between the two worlds—fictional and real—is a recurring theme in &lt;i&gt;The Ghost in the City&lt;/i&gt;. Matteini cites the canonical eighteenth-century novel,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Dream of the Red Chamber,&lt;/i&gt; to illustrate how paintings can be taken as “real” instead of mere illusionary recreations of things. This epic story about the rise and decline of a prominent noble family is believed to be inspired by its author Cao Xueqin’s (1716–1762) family history. Cao’s novel is rich with allusions on these two worlds, starting from the “Land of Illusion” to the two surnames Zhen (real) and Jia (illusory). Matteini implies that the blurred boundary between real and fiction in Luo Ping’s art is comparable to that of the novel. But he makes no further indication&amp;nbsp;as to&amp;nbsp;whether this concept applies to the broader cultural production in eighteenth-century China and how this “worldview” compares to the theatricality in art and literature from seventeenth-century China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In chapter four, Matteini returns to Luo Ping’s landscape paintings. While the paintings portray mountains and waters, the real subject matter is the people represented by the landscapes. The culturally-loaded landscape is not a new phenomenon—Matteini discusses Ming dynasty (1368–1644) “style name paintings” and Yuan dynasty (1271–1368) “landscapes of property” as points of reference. However, Matteini suggests that Luo’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Sword Terrace&lt;/i&gt;, painted in celebration of Zhang Daowo’s (1757–1829) assignment to Sichuan, shows a notable departure from established genres in its combination of fictive, factual, and aspirational elements (163). Despite the author’s insistence upon Luo Ping’s departures from convention, Luo’s innovation remains opaque, given that preexisting examples of site-specific landscape paintings also demonstrate a mixture of reality and multiple, layered references. Comparison with other landscape subgenres, including farewell paintings, “geo-narrative” paintings discussed in Elizabeth Kindall’s &lt;i&gt;Geo-Narratives of a Filial Son&lt;/i&gt; (Harvard University Asia Center, 2016), and those that are associated with placed-based remembrance inspired by &lt;i&gt;huaigu &lt;/i&gt;(reminiscence of the past) literature, may provide further insight into how Luo Ping’s work differs from previous modes of landscape painting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Throughout the four chapters, Matteini examines how an educated professional artist from the south succeeded in the Qing capital and how regional styles from Yangzhou played out on the national level. As Luo Ping and his patrons (and everyone else in their circle) were each trying to position themselves in the cultural arena of Beijing’s Southern City, the agenda of the artist intertwined with that of his patrons. The patrons’ preferences influenced how and what the artist painted, and the artist helped shape the patron’s interests. This complicated set of considerations affected who painted what subject matter in what style, as well as who wrote the inscriptions and how the paintings circulated. Matteini’s careful treatment of Luo’s artistic choices sheds light on the implicit and complex relationship between artist and patron. Since Luo Ping’s major patrons, Ingliyan (1707–1783) and Faššan (1753–1813), were from bannerman backgrounds (a Manchu elite military institution), perhaps the next logical question is to consider their cultural pursuits from a multiethnic perspective of art history of the Qing dynasty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Ghost in the City: Luo Ping and the Craft of Painting in Eighteenth-Century China&lt;/i&gt; is not just a monograph on Luo Ping. It is many things at once: a book about Luo Ping’s career in Beijing; a book about the art historical role of Luo Ping and Yangzhou experimentalisms; a book about the art world in Qianlong-era Southern City; and a book about how artists operated in an age when painting was highly professionalized. Through his study of Luo Ping’s late works, Matteini&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;makes a valuable contribution to our understanding of painting in Qing dynasty China during the eighteenth century. Ultimately, he argues that art from the late eighteenth century was not in decline but reflects a “regained confidence in imagination and the potential of words and images to turn imagination into reality” (181).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3483&quot;&gt;Amy S. Huang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Assistant Professor, School of Art, Art History, and Design, University of Iowa&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4276</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4276</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Michele Matteini</author></item><item><title>Sartorial Japonisme and the Experience of Kimonos in Britain, 1865–1914</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4485//Satorial%20Japonisme.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sartorial Japonisme and the Experience of Kimonos in Britain, 1865—1914&lt;/i&gt;, explores the experience of kimono in Victorian and Edwardian Britain. Through the medium of painting, theatre, performance, dress, department stores, postcards, and drag, it examines the design, construction, dissemination, and reception of kimono as garments situated as a sartorial medium in the critical discourse of Japonisme. Approaching kimono as a unique space of transformation, the book includes the everyday experiences of kimono in Britain and of those people and spaces previously ignored or overlooked. Researched and written by Arisa Yamaguchi, assistant professor at the University of Tsukuba, it draws on research conducted at museums and archives in Britain and Japan to elicit new perspectives to established scholarship of Japonisme in the visual arts (Ono, Taylor and Francis, 2003; Kikuchi, &lt;i&gt;The Journal of Modern Craft&lt;/i&gt;, 2008; Tornier, &lt;i&gt;Journal of Japonisme&lt;/i&gt;, 2017; Emery and Rado, &lt;i&gt;Journal of Japonisme,&lt;/i&gt; 2024).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Starting with the concept of transformation, chapter one follows kimono’s material agency in transforming the body through paintings and theatrical performance. Initially constructed to frame nakedness in the representation of the female body, kimono was used to reveal, but also conceal and transform, whether through gender or race as actors wore kimonos to transcend normative boundaries. In this way, kimonos were brought to the attention of the upper classes as potentially emancipatory garments that provided a different space in which identities could be explored as fluid and transmutable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In chapter two, through the female dress reform movement, kimonos became associated with healthy and aesthetically acceptable feminine dressing that was comfortable and decorative, whilst also containing links to feminine intellectualism, art movements, and the classical world. Disseminated through department stores first as curios, kimono became a popular expression of Japonisme as fashion, translating into different forms more palatable for British tastes and uses, such as the tea gown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;As part of Japonisme, chapter three positions kimonos in the wider context of Orientalism as an imaginary space for the exploration, negotiation, and expression of identity, status, and positionality, in which the Orient becomes a place of British fantasy. As such, in chapter four, kimono can be seen as a space of contested power and agency in an age of empire. Initially romanticized as a pastoral and rural idyll, “Old Japan” became subject to the new disciplines of scientific knowledge and social Darwinism in the study of bodies and customs through the 1885 Japanese Native Village Exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Yet by the 1910 Japan-British Exhibition, military alliances and the modernization of the Japanese state meant that representations of Japan began to change from the bodies to the lives of people. This is evidenced in the demonstration of Japanese skills and the positioning of Japanese people as civilized in contrast to other East Asian cultures situated as more “native” in the exhibition, as well as images of modern Japanese people in postcards in chapter five.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Finally, through the dissemination of exhibitions, inscribed postcards, and use of kimono in drag, chapter five outlines the personal and interactive elements of Japonsime for all levels of people in their every day, of which the dissemination and consumption of kimono was such a vital part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In terms of its scholarship, this work was comprehensively researched, covering a variety of areas, drawing from a range of archived material of artworks to performances, pamphlets, posters, preserved costume and dress, photographs, and postcards. Specific examples were examined in depth, and it was evident a variety of sources were accessed that covered materials obtained from archives of exhibitions, theatre productions, and department stores in Britain and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;As such, the methodologies and analysis used were varied and intertextual, spanning historical, cultural, material, and garment analysis. This was especially evident in the materiality of the kimono as a method. Understanding how it was constructed, folded, hung, and draped over the body was pivotal to understanding its multifunctional uses as clothing, interior decoration, and stage prop. The potential for kimono to become a space of possibility was facilitated by this material analysis, expanding work on the area and adding to scholarship where &amp;nbsp;kimono goes beyond the purely material (Cliffe, Bloomsbury, 2017; Chiba, Routledge, 2022).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Kimono as fashion in chapter two was more conventional, examining the garment as fashion in Victorian and Edwardian Britain and the role department stores played. Of interest was the recounting of the Japanese department store Takashimaya, as the counterpart to the department stores in Britain, and its role in the dissemination of kimono as fashion aimed at the international market, featuring garments from the Kyoto Institute and the Takashimaya Historical Archive. To hear about the Japanese side of designing kimono-inspired garments is a valuable contribution to the field, especially through accessing Takashimaya archives, where there has been limited scholarship (McDermott, Monumenta Nipponica, 2010; Rado, Fashion Theory, 2015).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In the connection and analysis of kimono within the context of wider orientalism and colonialism, this research was particularly brave, tackling not only the implicit and open racism and Darwinism of the British Empire but also the historic complicity and ruthlessness of the Japanese imperial government towards its Indigenous subjects and their use as natives displayed and juxtaposed against the civilization of Japanese people. This book was unafraid to confront uncomfortable issues regarding empire, imperialism, colonialism, and nationalism from different perspectives of British and Japanese imperial history. Moreover, by connecting British and Japanese military interests to the portrayal of Japonisme in Britain, it identified Japanese nationalism and colonialism as strategies implemented beyond Asia in popular culture, which can be framed as influenced by British imperialism and militarism. In this, it adds to other work in the area that focuses on specific cultural items as a locus for cultural politics (Surak, Stanford University Press, 2012; Cwiertka, Reaktion, 2006).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;It also deftly connected the use of kimono to the anxieties of British citizens about the empire, making the case for kimono as a signifier of Japan to be utilized as a medium for British fantasy. In this, the very nature of kimono as an ambiguous, unstructured material was identified as enabling multiple interpretations, transgressing the body to encompass space itself. This metaphysical and metaphorical interpretation of kimono as Japonsime was particularly evident in the compelling inclusion of postcards and photographs of drag, in which the ambiguity of the garment enabled a more open interpretation of research materials about kimonos as a mode of communication and self-expression rather than worn clothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;However, for the book’s aim of bringing to the fore the everyday experiences of kimono as sartorial fashion in Victorian and Edwardian Britain, especially from previously unheard voices, it was rather sparse on actual voices and their thoughts on kimono fashion. Apart from a few quotes from newspaper columns and writings on postcards, there seemed little provision for the opinions of the wearers, users, and viewers of Japonisme and kimono. While the analysis of the events, exhibitions, and materials accessed was detailed and excellent, the inclusion of recorded narratives would have added a closer and more intimate dimension to the research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;A promising line was the account of the London Jewish community’s encounter with Japonisme through local exhibitions. However, although interesting, it was rather inconclusive and would have benefited from further development or a stronger message on the wider themes of colonialism, empire, race, or social Darwinism. Likewise, although adequate in summing up the research covered, considering the richness of the material, the conclusion was rather short and could have been more advanced for the greater significance of the research to the wider field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In conclusion, this body of work was a valuable contribution to the field, constructing a compelling argument that covered a variety of areas, materials, and transnational archives between the UK and Japan. Taking the kimono beyond the conventional scholarship as a worn garment, it was skilfully interwoven within the larger narratives of imperial power and competing interests and anxieties of modernity and different national interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;In addition to the material qualities of kimono, the metaphysical qualities were explored, leading to its significance not only as a draped and fashioned garment, but also as an exploratory space for self-expression, liberation, fantasy, and self-realization. This was conducted through rigorous analysis of the representation of kimono through a variety of mediums, from paintings, photographs, brochures, and postcards to performative use on stage, society balls, festivals, exhibitions, and drag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;However, a bit more development of individual and marginalized voices within the engagement with Japonsime and kimono would have raised the novelty of this research further, especially of the Jewish community, of which narrative appeared a promising line of inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;Nevertheless, this was a well-written and well-researched book, in which the writing was clear and well-supported with documented material evidence both textually and visually. Links were made between diverse areas to construct a compelling historical narrative and analysis in which kimono was reassessed, and its scope as a cultural artifact was widened to include politics, identity, and its significance as a transmedia object of Japonisme—a valuable and engaging addition to the field of Japanese and fashion historical studies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3499&quot;&gt;Hui-Ying Kerr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Senior Lecturer, Department of Fashion Management, Marketing and Communication, Nottingham Trent University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4297</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4297</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Arisa Yamaguchi</author></item><item><title>The Archeology of Modern Worlds in the Indian Ocean</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/images//book/4385//The%20Archeology%20of%20Modern.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt; 

  &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;article&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Archaeology of Modern Worlds in the Indian Ocean &lt;/i&gt;is a collection of historical archaeological studies from various places around the Indian Ocean World. By bringing together specialists in Indian Ocean historical archaeology, the editors, Mark William Hauser and Julia Jong Haines, create space for us to see the long histories of connections, networks, exchanges, and globalization that have created the Indian Ocean World. They make a strong case for an Indian Ocean-centered historical archaeology of the region. This framework and the chapters that act as evidence for its effectiveness are presented as a corrective to the overrepresentation of the Atlantic World and European influence within the field of historical archaeology. This book joins a small but growing collection of scholarly voices that see the archaeological record of the Indian Ocean as a useful counterpoint or contrast to Atlantic and European narratives of world history. At its center, this book emphasizes the relationality between far-flung sites of the Indian Ocean by using the productive tension between the “explicitly micro-historical, material, and situated approaches” (2) of the contributors and the broadly interconnected and transnational approach of the chapters when taken as a whole. When read comparatively, readers can make connections between various sites in the Indian Ocean, including the Mascarene Islands, Zanzibar, the Coromandel Coast, and Goa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;The book consists of an introduction, eight chapters each featuring a different historical archaeological site, and two commentary chapters acting as conclusions. Taking Hauser and Haines’ advice to read the connections between chapters as instructions, several notable interventions emerge from the work collected here. First, this book meaningfully centers the Indian Ocean within the conversation about the historical archaeology of globalization. Or, to draw on Supriya Varma’s commentary chapter, it is “a much-needed corrective by shifting the gaze from the Atlantic Ocean to the Indian Ocean” (243). This shifting gaze paves the way for Chapurukha Kusimba in chapter ten to compile archaeological evidence from the Swahili world and use it to understand the Indian Ocean as “one of the oldest examples of globalization” (228). This point contradicts the persistent notion that European exploration and colonization sparked globalization. The theme of connectivity within the Western Indian Ocean is picked up by Krish Seetah, Stefania Manfio, and Akshay Sarathi in chapter four, which emphasizes interisland relationships in its examination of the links between Zanzibar and Mauritius that formed as a result of the history of slavery. They present the island archaeology of the Indian Ocean as a counterpoint to notions of islands as isolated and bounded. In contrast, Zanzibar and Mauritius are presented as hyperconnected nodes within a globalized ocean world. The notion of water as connecting geographically distant sites rather than isolating them, surfaces in chapter eight by Haines and Hauser, who use the symbolic and social roles of water to draw comparisons between sites of diasporic labor in Mauritius and on the lower Coromandel coast of India. This book succeeds in rooting globalization in regional connections rather than European intervention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Another contribution that arises from reading across chapters is a relatively consistent argument for expanding the temporal frames of the archaeological study of the Indian Ocean. The title of the book cites “modern worlds” as a reference to the effort to focus on the historical archaeology of roughly the past five hundred years. This, in itself, is a contribution to Indian Ocean archaeology as the vast majority of archaeology in the region attends to the pre-1500 period. Varma elaborates on this theme of expanding time frames in his concluding commentary chapter wherein he highlights the tension between the modern-era orientation of the field of historical archaeology and the deeper time scale to which one could apply the methodology within the Indian Ocean (243). This book thus works simultaneously to pull the archaeological study of the Indian Ocean forward in time to consider the modern era and to pull the field of historical archaeology backward in time to apply the methodology to deeper timescales. This works better in some chapters than others. For example, Ellen Hsieh and Takashi Sakai’s thousand-year history of connections between Southeast Asia and the Indian Ocean is effective in bringing together analyses of different time periods to present an argument for the utility of &lt;i&gt;longue durée&lt;/i&gt; comparative archaeology. While forging connections between time periods is a useful aim, closer attention to the modern era might have helped provide some much-needed focus in a book that is already juggling many themes, locations, and peoples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;Finally, this book offers a series of useful cases centering on the experiences of ordinary people in our understanding of colonialism, historical heritage, migration, transnational connections, and the processes of history generally. In the context of Indian Ocean studies, this is particularly important as a mode of decolonizing history and shifting the focus away from the agency and priorities of European intervention. For example, Saša Čaval and Alessandra Cianciosi offer a gendered account of how female migrants, both enslaved and free, to the Mascarenes, experienced the colonial institution of quarantine stations. In the following chapter, Adria LaViolette and Neil Norman center an analysis of Portuguese colonialism in Zanzibar in a rural site of agricultural labor, rather than the more familiar imposing fortresses associated with this region. As a final example, Brian Wilson argues that the decline of European spatial organization within Goa did not mean that the city had fallen to ruins, as contemporary European commentary suggests, but rather made way for a robust subaltern population. His research on this population “calls for a reconsideration of the heritage management practices in Goa today that perpetuate these colonial narratives” and for centering these ordinary, subaltern populations within collective historical memory (208).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify; &quot;&gt;If there is a critique to be made, it is that this book leaves the implicit comparisons between chapters to do much of the heavy lifting rather than making these themes more explicit within the introduction. This would also have addressed the fact that this book does not do much interpretation for nonarchaeologists. Indian Ocean studies more generally is a rather small and interdisciplinary field, and it would be nice if nonarchaeologists had more access to the insights of historical archaeologists via this book. That said, there is much to recommend for audiences within the field of archaeology and for those willing to do the work to read across chapters. For archaeologists of the Indian Ocean, who are likely to be the primary audience, this book offers a refreshing temporal shift towards the modern era, argues for an expanded imagining of what time periods and people should be centered within Indian Ocean archaeology, and demonstrates that historical archaeology is a crucial methodological approach to studying the region. For historical archaeologists generally, this book makes a strong argument in defense of the Indian Ocean as an important space of analysis and point of contrast with other regions. This book ultimately succeeds in its goal of decentering Europe and Eurocentric narratives and instead offering some useful models for centering the Indian Ocean within the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;reviewer&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caareviews.org/reviewers/3462&quot;&gt;Jodie Marshall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Postdoctoral Fellow, Department of History&lt;br&gt;
Washington State University&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;



  


&lt;!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style addthis_32x32_style&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_twitter addthis_button_preferred_1&quot; title=&quot;Tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_facebook addthis_button_preferred_2&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_email addthis_button_preferred_3&quot; title=&quot;Email&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;addthis_button_compact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;


</description><link>http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4253</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caareviews.org/reviews/4253</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Mark William Hauser and Julia Jong Haines, eds.</author></item></channel></rss>