<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>WebCatalog Changelog</title><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/webcatalog/changelog" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>WebCatalog Changelog - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:14:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>February 2025 - Shared Spaces</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog Business users can now create shared spaces, enabling teams to collaborate effortlessly by accessing and managing the same spaces together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shared spaces work just like &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.webcatalog.io/en/articles/10356700-what-are-spaces&quot;&gt;regular spaces&lt;/a&gt;, with one key difference: all data—including subspaces, bookmarks, and settings—is synchronized and shared across the entire team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-February 2025-Shared Spaces</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>January 2025 - Smarter, Faster Search Experience</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;Search has always been central to WebCatalog, helping you quickly find and explore apps. However, as WebCatalog grew, search didn&#39;t always keep up—it could feel slow, unreliable, and less helpful than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve completely rebuilt the search system to be faster, more dependable, and powered by advanced AI technology. Now, with AI-driven language models, search is smarter and more intuitive, delivering better results and more accurate app suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This update also sets the stage for exciting new features that will make discovering and managing apps even easier. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; To keep using search, update WebCatalog Desktop to version 62+ and all apps, games, and spaces to Photon version 53+. Older versions will soon lose search functionality due to major infrastructure changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved App Update Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve improved how update notifications work based on your feedback. While updates are essential for bringing you new features and keeping your installed desktop apps and spaces secure, we understand that receiving frequent update notifications can be disruptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this better, we&#39;ve reduced the frequency of update notifications and added new customization options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose to receive notifications for all updates, only major updates, or turn them off entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default, you&#39;ll only receive notifications for major updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can adjust these settings in &lt;strong&gt;App/space settings &amp;gt; General &amp;gt; App update notifications&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can customize the app update reminder on the toolbar by going to &lt;strong&gt;app/space settings &amp;gt; Appearance &amp;gt; Show app update reminder on toolbar&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-January 2025-Smarter, Faster Search Experience</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>December 2024 - Subspace Bar Customization</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve introduced new customization options for the subspace bar, allowing you to tailor it to your preferences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customize the subspace captions (the text appears under the name of each subspace) on the subspace bar. Options include showing keyboard shortcuts, URLs, hostnames, or hiding captions entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now hide the &quot;Add Subspace&quot; button on the subspace bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can change these settings in &lt;strong&gt;App/Space Settings &amp;gt; Appearance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-December 2024-Subspace Bar Customization</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>November 2024 - Google Drive Integration</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog Desktop now works with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://support.google.com/drive/answer/10838124?hl=en&quot;&gt;the official Google Drive desktop sync client for macOS and Windows&lt;/a&gt;. This integration allows you to open Google Drive files (Docs, Sheets, Slides, Drawings, and Forms) directly in corresponding desktop apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open Google Drive files with any installed desktop apps or spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &quot;Open with&quot; options in Windows Explorer (Windows) or Finder (macOS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within any desktop app, select &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Open File...&lt;/strong&gt; from the menu bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also set WebCatalog&#39;s desktop apps (like Google Docs) or spaces as the default applications for opening Google Drive files by following one of these guides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/change-default-apps-in-windows-e5d82cad-17d1-c53b-3505-f10a32e1894d&quot;&gt;Set default app for a file type&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/guide/mac-help/mh35597/mac&quot;&gt;Set default app for a file type&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dashboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each space and desktop app now has a dashboard that gives you a quick overview of your subspaces—like apps, games, and accounts—making it easier to access and manage everything in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can switch it on or off anytime in &lt;strong&gt;App/Space Settings &amp;gt; Subspaces &amp;gt; Dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-November 2024-Google Drive Integration</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>September 2024 - Singlebox</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;Based on customer feedback and careful consideration, we&#39;re excited to reintroduce the &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://singlebox.app/&quot;&gt;standalone Singlebox app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standalone Singlebox app functions much like a &lt;a class=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;https://desktop.webcatalog.io/spaces/&quot;&gt;space&lt;/a&gt;—bringing together all your web apps, messaging services, and emails into one convenient window. However, it can be installed independently of WebCatalog Desktop, with automatic app updates. You can also install it alongside WebCatalog Desktop without any conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Singlebox shares the same account system and cloud storage as WebCatalog and is included in the WebCatalog subscription, giving you seamless access to both products under a single plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-September 2024-Singlebox</guid><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>August 2024 - Startup Page</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;You can now choose whether apps, spaces, and subspaces open on the home page or continue where you left off at startup. This setting can be customized for the entire app, game, or space, as well as for individual subspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Team Library&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share apps (including custom apps) and games with your team members (only available for WebCatalog Business subscription).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enhanced Auto-Reload&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve rebuilt the auto-reload feature to make it more reliable. Now, you can enable auto-reload for the entire app, game, or space, as well as for individual subspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-August 2024-Startup Page</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>July 2024 - Mousewheel Zoom</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;On Windows, you can now zoom in and out of a page by holding down the &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; key and scrolling up or down with your mousewheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proxy Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog now supports proxy servers that require authentication with a username and password. You can save your proxy credentials in settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-July 2024-Mousewheel Zoom</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>June 2024 - Private Browsing</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;Private Browsing is a new mode that enhances your privacy by not saving your browsing information, such as history and cookies. Once you end the session, no traces of your activity are left behind. You can turn it on in app/game/space&#39;s settings &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Security &amp;amp; Privacy &amp;gt; Private Browsing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-June 2024-Private Browsing</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>April 2024 - Improved Update Experience</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog Desktop now automatically closes running apps, games, and spaces during updates. Once the updates are complete, it seamlessly relaunches them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Secure DNS (DNS over HTTPS (DoH))&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it harder for people with access to your internet traffic to see which sites you visit with &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS_over_HTTPS&quot;&gt;DNS over HTTPS (DoH)&lt;/a&gt;. You can turn it on in app/game/space&#39;s settings &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Security &amp;amp; Privacy &amp;gt; Secure DNS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-April 2024-Improved Update Experience</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>March 2024 - Bookmarks</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;Create bookmarks so WebCatalog can remember your favorite and frequently visited links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Browsing History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep track of the websites or web pages that you have visited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-March 2024-Bookmarks</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>January 2024 - Subspace Icon Set</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;Customize your subspace icons with 1000+ icons in our new beautiful icon set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download Manager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manage, pause and resume downloads with the new download manager.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-January 2024-Subspace Icon Set</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>December 2023 - Dansk, עִבְרִית, Svenska, ภาษาไทย, українська</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog is now available in Danish, Hebrew, Swedish, Thai, Ukrainian.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-December 2023-Dansk, עִבְרִית, Svenska, ภาษาไทย, українська</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>November 2023 - العربية, Bahasa Indonesia, 한국어, Norsk (bokmål), Nederlands, Polski, Pyccкий, Türkçe, 中文（繁體）</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog is now available in Arabic, Indonesian, Korean, Norwegian (bokmal), Dutch, Polish, Russian, Turkish, Chinese (traditional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Theme Colors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve brought back the ability to customize your apps, games, spaces and subspaces with colors with more color choices and improved experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deutsch, Español, Français, Italiano, 日本語, Português, 中文（简体）&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog is now available in German, Spanish, French, Italian, Japanese, Portugese, and Chinese (simplified).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-November 2023-العربية, Bahasa Indonesia, 한국어, Norsk (bokmål), Nederlands, Polski, Pyccкий, Türkçe, 中文（繁體）</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>October 2023 - Redesign</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog app and websites have been redesigned with a brand new unified design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-October 2023-Redesign</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>September 2023 - Subspace Folders</title><description>

&lt;p&gt;You can now group subspaces together by dragging a subspace over another one on the subspace bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subspace folders are automatically backed up and synced across devices. (&lt;em&gt;only for WebCatalog Pro users&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tiếng Việt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WebCatalog is now available in Vietnamese.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://desktop.webcatalog.io/en/changelog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">webcatalog-September 2023-Subspace Folders</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>