<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>FX-Markets Trading</title><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.email-once.com/fx-markets/trading" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>FX-Markets Trading - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:21:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Trump’s tariff threats stress London gold market</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The London gold market is facing a mounting structural crisis.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bullion banks that lend precious metals to producers and each other moved over 200 tonnes of gold to New York in January in response to US President Donald Trump’s tariff threats, leaving the London market desperately short of physical supplies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dealers in London routinely borrow gold to fund customer positions. The cost of doing so, which has historically ranged from -20 basis points to +10bp, shot up to between 300bp for short&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949505/trumps-tariff-threats-stress-london-gold-market</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949505/trumps-tariff-threats-stress-london-gold-market</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TD, Goldman make strides with Ucits in FX forwards trades</title><description>&lt;p&gt;TD Securities and Goldman Sachs made the largest ranking moves among dealers serving the FX forwards market for European retail funds during the first half of last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Canadian bank gained $14.4 billion in notional from trades with Ucits funds, increasing its market share to 9.5% from 7% and becoming the second-largest dealer in the space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs followed close behind, adding $13.2 billion to its book, which doubled in size to 5% of the total. The growth propelled the US giant to the&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949502/td-goldman-make-strides-with-ucits-in-fx-forwards</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949502/td-goldman-make-strides-with-ucits-in-fx-forwards</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 12:56:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporates turn to structured notes to juice cash returns</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Some corporate treasurers are taking advantage of more volatile foreign exchange and interest rate markets to invest their foreign cash holdings into yield-enhancing structured products, as an alternative to deposits or money market funds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dealers say corporate treasurers are increasingly under pressure to improve returns on cash in the higher-rate environment, and have been turning to&amp;nbsp;dual currency notes (DCNs) as a result. Rising FX volatility and wider interest rate differentials result in a&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949499/corporates-turn-to-structured-notes-to-juice-cash-returns</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949499/corporates-turn-to-structured-notes-to-juice-cash-returns</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>XTX Markets hires Brook for Emea market-making</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Non-bank market-maker XTX Markets has hired Sam Brook for its European foreign exchange and equities trading team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brook joins from NatWest Markets, where he spent nine years in the UK bank’s electronic FX trading unit, primarily working on the buildout of its e-FX market-making desk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of the Europe, Middle East and Africa distribution team at XTX, Brook’s role will focus on providing customised and low-market-impact liquidity to clients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based in London, he will report to Jeremy Smart&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949498/xtx-markets-hires-brook-for-emea-market-making</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949498/xtx-markets-hires-brook-for-emea-market-making</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 11:38:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporates pressed on FX hedges as dollar surge bites</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Foreign exchange losses have begun to mount for some of the largest global corporates, with the likes of Amazon, Apple and Nike reporting revenues negatively affected by continued US dollar strength in the fourth quarter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since September, the dollar has risen by as much as 7% against many G10 and emerging market currencies, reducing the demand for exports and the value of foreign returns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past, it was common for analysts and investors simply not to ask about or even consider the FX hedging&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949496/corporates-pressed-on-fx-hedges-as-dollar-surge-bites</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949496/corporates-pressed-on-fx-hedges-as-dollar-surge-bites</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tariff news ‘ping pong’ gives FX options desks a headache</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Foreign exchange market-makers often say they prefer more volatile markets. But last week’s wild swings pushed many to their limits, as options volatility whipsawed on news of US president Donald Trump’s shifting tariff deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This week felt like a month,” said a senior FX options trader at one US dealer, speaking on Thursday (February 6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most bank traders, the chaos began on February 1 when Trump announced tariffs of 25% on all goods from Canada and Mexico, effective from February 4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949497/tariff-news-ping-pong-gives-fx-options-desks-a-headache</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949497/tariff-news-ping-pong-gives-fx-options-desks-a-headache</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:27:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Funds tap options on FX vol amid tariff disruptions</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hedge funds are increasingly taking out complex options structures that speculate on pricing of foreign exchange volatility levels across several currencies linked to US president Donald Trump’s tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investors have increasingly looked to incorporate vol-linked knockouts in vanilla FX options to cheapen them up and avoid crowded barrier zones. Others have looked at options directly on realised volatility, including spread trades across multiple currencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We continue to see a very inverted&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949495/funds-tap-options-on-fx-vol-amid-tariff-disruptions</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949495/funds-tap-options-on-fx-vol-amid-tariff-disruptions</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:09:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporates eye complex FX hedges as carry costs mount</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The shake-em-up economic policies trailed by new US president and so-called “disruptor-in-chief” Donald Trump have left corporate treasurers on both sides of the Atlantic nervously eyeing their cost of foreign exchange hedging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FX volatility has spiked amid continued threats by Trump of tough tariffs on Canada, Mexico, China and the European Union. Meanwhile, interest rate differentials between the US and Europe are expected to widen as analysts forecast higher-for-longer rates from the Federal&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949494/corporates-eye-complex-fx-hedges-as-carry-costs-mount</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949494/corporates-eye-complex-fx-hedges-as-carry-costs-mount</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 10:01:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Deutsche Bank hires JP Morgan’s James to run AutobahnFX</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Bank has appointed Richard James from JP Morgan to run its foreign exchange single-dealer platform, AutobahnFX.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;James will be responsible for the growth and distribution of the bank’s electronic FX client offering for cash and derivatives, as well as algorithmic execution on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He will be based in London and report to Ollie Jerome, head of European FX product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Richard will lead the development and distribution of the bank’s electronic FX product offering, keeping us relevant&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949493/deutsche-bank-hires-jp-morgans-james-to-run-autobahnfx</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949493/deutsche-bank-hires-jp-morgans-james-to-run-autobahnfx</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 14:30:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s tariff threats fuel corporate FX hedging revamp</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Corporate treasurers are turning to FX options and longer-dated derivatives to hedge the impact of US President Donald Trump’s planned tariffs on global trade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the run-up to Trump’s inauguration, threats of heavy tariffs on imports from China, Canada, Europe and Mexico led to a sharp rally in the US dollar and a significant pick-up in FX volatility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The moves set off a rush among firms with internal accounting approval to use FX options to buy protection against a stronger dollar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Corporates&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949491/trumps-tariff-threats-fuel-corporate-fx-hedging-revamp</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949491/trumps-tariff-threats-fuel-corporate-fx-hedging-revamp</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Does no-hedge strategy stack up for mag seven mavericks?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The so-called magnificent seven – the seven largest US tech companies that famously make up more than a third of the S&amp;amp;P 500 by market cap – are among the world’s largest firms. They also have some of the greatest geographical distributions – in some cases operating in over 100 countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet filings for these tech giants show that three of them – Amazon, Meta and Tesla – choose not to hedge their day-to-day foreign exchange exposures. They reveal no holdings of offsetting FX derivatives&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949487/does-no-hedge-strategy-stack-up-for-mag-seven-mavericks</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949487/does-no-hedge-strategy-stack-up-for-mag-seven-mavericks</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korea’s FX reforms working amid political crisis, dealers say</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Foreign exchange activity in the wake of South Korea’s political crisis indicates recent reforms aimed at bringing more Korean won trading onshore and away from the offshore non-deliverable forward (NDF) market are beginning to have an effect, dealers say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Korean won sunk to a succession of historic lows against the US dollar last month amid political turmoil sparked by President Yoon Suk Yeol’s surprise attempt to impose martial law. In late-hours trading on December 3, the gap between US&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949485/south-koreas-fx-reforms-working-amid-political-crisis-dealers-say</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949485/south-koreas-fx-reforms-working-amid-political-crisis-dealers-say</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:20:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BNY hires Deutsche Bank’s Wu to revamp e-trading</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BNY has appointed Shuo Wu as global head of electronic foreign exchange trading and strats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wu joins BNY in London and will report to Jordan Barnett, global head of FX trading and product, while regionally reporting to David McAnany, co-head of FX for Europe, the Middle East and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He left Deutsche Bank in the summer of 2024, having been global head of FX forwards electronic trading for nearly five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wu’s appointment marks a shift for the New York-based bank as it looks to merge e-FX spot&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949484/bny-hires-deutsche-banks-wu-to-revamp-e-trading</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949484/bny-hires-deutsche-banks-wu-to-revamp-e-trading</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon, Meta and Tesla reject FX hedging</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon, Meta and Tesla – three of the so-called magnificent seven tech firms that drive US stock market performance – decline to hedge their day-to-day foreign exchange exposures. So concludes a study by &lt;em&gt;FX Markets&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;of the firms’ quarterly filings over the past five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corporates operating in dozens of countries typically hedge the FX risk from their foreign revenues and expenses with derivatives. But a study of the three companies’ filings shows no evidence of any FX hedging activity. What’s&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949477/amazon-meta-and-tesla-reject-fx-hedging</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949477/amazon-meta-and-tesla-reject-fx-hedging</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Could LPs explore renting out their client franchise?</title><description>&lt;span class=&quot;article-body-wrapper paywall_content&quot;&gt;
              
  &lt;p&gt;Can you rent a liquidity provider? And not just any liquidity provider, but one like &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;JP&lt;/span&gt; Morgan or Deutsche Bank, to gain access to their huge client franchises?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This idea was raised during the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FX&lt;/span&gt; Markets Europe conference in London on December 3 (if you weren’t there, you missed an excellent event).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In outline, the rental arrangement might start with a regional bank that is seeking to execute an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FX&lt;/span&gt; trade on behalf of a local corporate client. The bank could take that trade to a big dealer in the hope that the resulting, skewed price would entice one of the dealer’s own clients – maybe a systematic hedge fund – to take the other side of the trade, potentially allowing both sides to get it done at a good level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;rdm-above-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;rdm-related&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the alternative involves venturing into one of the market’s primary venues – increasingly avoided by the biggest dealers – then it has obvious appeal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;id-ckeditor-plugins--pullquote align-right secondary sans-img&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;blockquote-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;h6&gt;The picture that’s emerging of an FX market-maker is quite different to the traditional stereotype&lt;/h6&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also raises some interesting questions. At the conference, this kind of arrangement was framed as a ‘rental’ of the dealer’s client franchise by the hypothetical regional bank.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The implications of this type of arrangement could mean the top LPs are evolving to become big distribution hubs where they manage a vast network of internalised flows and bilateral streams across different segments of the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, describing it as a rental scheme suggests that the regional bank is the one benefitting, and the one who should be paying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But couldn’t it be flipped the other way round? The dealer is getting to see a trading interest that it would otherwise not have exclusive access to, and is able to facilitate offsetting trades as a result. Who gets most value from this arrangement?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;aside class=&quot;id-ckeditor-plugins--related-article-single related-article-holder single align-offset horizontal secondary &quot;&gt;&lt;header class=&quot;component-header&quot;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;section-title-link&quot;&gt;Related&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/header&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;section group&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;related-article-inner&quot; data-article=&quot;7949337&quot;&gt;&lt;article&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-text-group-a&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;icon-text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fx-markets.com/fx-markets/7949337/keys-to-the-kingdom-dealers-open-doors-to-passive-trades&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.fx-markets.com/sites/default/files/styles/square_small_articles/public/2024-06/eFX-Getty-1560147086.jpg.webp?h=13b0e9b1&amp;amp;itok=Z272Kpxe&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;image-text-group-b&quot;&gt;&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;icon-text&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fx-markets.com/fx-markets/7949337/keys-to-the-kingdom-dealers-open-doors-to-passive-trades&quot; title=&quot;Keys to the kingdom: dealers open doors to passive trades&quot;&gt;Keys to the kingdom: dealers open doors to passive trades&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;truncate-listing&quot; data-short-summary=&quot;&quot;&gt;Banks provide entry to internal exchanges and principal trading desks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/article&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another question concerns the dividing lines between the rental trades and other, similar arrangements – such as white-label liquidity provision, which also connects big dealers with regional banks and raises the same kind of questions about who the biggest beneficiary is. The idea of placing passive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fx-markets.com/fx-markets/7949337/keys-to-the-kingdom-dealers-open-doors-to-passive-trades?ref=header-search&quot;&gt;resting orders&lt;/a&gt; within a dealer’s internal exchange also overlaps with both of these approaches – ‘renting’ a client franchise, and white-labelled liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how these partnerships are arranged, the result is the same – the ultimate consumer of liquidity is the corporate at the end of the chain. But who is actually generating the price? Who is providing value? And how much should they get paid for it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The picture that’s emerging of an FX market-maker is quite different to the traditional stereotype. In the old days, market-makers took price risk, liquidity risk and counterparty risk over varying horizons, and were paid for doing so. Perhaps, in future, success in FX market-making will be less about taking and managing risk, and more about building the biggest possible network of trading interests.&lt;/p&gt;

              &lt;/span&gt;
                          
            


                        &lt;div id=&quot;rdm-below-article-body&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
            
          </description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/our-take/7949474/could-lps-explore-renting-out-their-client-franchise</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/our-take/7949474/could-lps-explore-renting-out-their-client-franchise</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Franklin Templeton dethrones MSIM as top FX options user</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Franklin Templeton has become the largest user of foreign exchange options among US mutual funds, taking the top spot from Morgan Stanley Investment Management for the first time since the end of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The California-based fund manager increased notional volumes by around $340 million during the third quarter of 2024, taking the total size of its FX options book to nearly $5.9 billion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, MSIM continued to cut the size of its renminbi-denominated positions, this time by just over $700&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949470/franklin-templeton-dethrones-msim-as-top-fx-options-user</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949470/franklin-templeton-dethrones-msim-as-top-fx-options-user</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Review of 2024: FX traders face new paradigm</title><description>&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, all a foreign exchange trader had to do to plan his activity was to look at a calendar. Whether it was the more than 60 national elections that took place across the world or the various central bank policy meetings, traders knew when there was going to be volatility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traders though are comparatively flying blind in 2025. Instead of managing event risk and predictable data releases, they may have to get used to much more frequent pockets of short-term volatility from&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949464/review-of-2024-fx-traders-face-new-paradigm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949464/review-of-2024-fx-traders-face-new-paradigm</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pimco and Vanguard slash FX forwards trading with BNP Paribas</title><description>&lt;p&gt;BNP Paribas had its foreign exchange forwards book with US mutual funds halve during the third quarter of 2024, as Pimco and Vanguard significantly cut their activities with the French bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notional for BNP Paribas dropped from $132.2 billion to $66.9 billion, sending it falling down the dealer rankings from first to seventh. This was due to Pimco and Vanguard reducing their positions with it by $44.6 billion and $20.7 billion, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This enabled State Street to move up one place to take&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949465/pimco-and-vanguard-slash-fx-forwards-trading-with-bnp-paribas</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949465/pimco-and-vanguard-slash-fx-forwards-trading-with-bnp-paribas</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Profit and pain as macro turmoil engulfs Brazil</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Foreign exchange traders mostly profited from last week’s collapse in the Brazilian real, but the gains were offset by sizable losses on rates positions when the Brazilian central bank (BCB) intervened to stabilise the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doubts over Brazil’s fiscal stability and rising interest rate expectations in the US sparked a massive sell-off in the real, which hit a record low of 6.31 against the US dollar on December 18.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investors largely anticipated the move. “People were positioned short BRL and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949467/profit-and-pain-as-macro-turmoil-engulfs-brazil</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949467/profit-and-pain-as-macro-turmoil-engulfs-brazil</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:05:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Repo and FX markets buck year-end crunch fears</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A rise in the cost of repo and foreign exchange derivatives has become a year-end tradition for several years now, as banks try to shed balance sheet exposures to keep a lid on future capital requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The jump in secured funding costs and FX derivatives pricing at the end of September was therefore familiar, but the timing and magnitude of it led some to worry this period would be particularly intense come December 30 and 31.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, despite some unique pressures, market participants say&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949462/repo-and-fx-markets-buck-year-end-crunch-fears</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.fx-markets.com/trading/7949462/repo-and-fx-markets-buck-year-end-crunch-fears</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:23:43 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>