<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>TechCrunch</title><link>https://techcrunch.com</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.isrss.com/techcrunch/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Reporting on the business of technology, startups, venture capital funding, and Silicon Valley. - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:30:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>OpenAI’s o1-pro is the company’s most expensive AI model yet</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/GettyImages-2021258442.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;OpenAI has &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/OpenAIDevs/status/1902485690958450871&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a more powerful version of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/05/openais-o1-model-sure-tries-to-deceive-humans-a-lot/&quot;&gt;o1&lt;/a&gt; “reasoning” AI model, o1-pro, in its developer API. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;According to OpenAI, o1-pro uses more computing than o1 to provide “consistently better responses.” Currently, it’s only available to select developers — those who’ve spent at least $5 on OpenAI API services —  and it’s pricey. Very pricey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;OpenAI is charging $150 per million tokens (~750,000 words) fed into the model and $600 per million tokens generated by the model. That’s twice the price of OpenAI’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/27/openai-unveils-gpt-4-5-orion-its-largest-ai-model-yet/&quot;&gt;GPT-4.5&lt;/a&gt; for input and 10x the price of regular o1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;OpenAI is betting that o1-pro’s improved performance will convince developers to pay those princely sums. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“O1-pro in the API is a version of o1 that uses more computing to think harder and provide even better answers to the hardest problems,” an OpenAI spokesperson told TechCrunch. “After getting many requests from our developer community, we’re excited to bring it to the API to offer even more reliable responses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Yet &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/06/will-people-really-pay-200-a-month-for-openais-new-chatbot/&quot;&gt;early impressions&lt;/a&gt; of o1-pro, which has been available in OpenAI’s AI-powered chatbot platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/chatgpt/&quot;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/05/openai-confirms-its-new-200-plan-chatgpt-pro-which-includes-reasoning-models-and-more/&quot;&gt;ChatGPT Pro&lt;/a&gt; subscribers since December, weren’t incredibly positive. The model struggled with Sudoku puzzles, users found, and was tripped up by simple optical illusion jokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Furthermore, certain OpenAI &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/06/will-people-really-pay-200-a-month-for-openais-new-chatbot/&quot;&gt;internal benchmarks&lt;/a&gt; from late last year showed that o1-pro performed only slightly better than the standard o1 on coding and math problems. It did answer those problems more reliably, however, the benchmarks found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/openais-o1-pro-is-its-most-expensive-model-yet/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/openais-o1-pro-is-its-most-expensive-model-yet/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:40:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacked, leaked, exposed: Why you should never use stalkerware apps</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/getty-photo-mosh-stalkerware.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  


&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;There is a whole shady industry for people who want to monitor and spy on their families. Multiple app makers market their software — sometimes referred to as &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/31/techcrunch-reference-guide-to-security-terminology/#stalkerware&quot;&gt;stalkerware&lt;/a&gt; — to jealous partners who can use these apps to access their victims’ phones remotely.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Yet, despite how sensitive this data is, an increasing number of these companies are losing huge amounts of it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;According to TechCrunch’s tally, counting &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/&quot;&gt;the latest data breach of SpyX&lt;/a&gt;, there have been at least 25 stalkerware companies since 2017 that are known to have been hacked, or leaked customer and victims’ data online. That’s not a typo: At least 25 stalkerware companies have either been hacked or had a significant data exposure in recent years. And four stalkerware companies were hacked multiple times.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;SpyX is the latest stalkerware provider reported this year to have been breached, although the breach itself dates back to mid-2024. The breach reveals that the SpyX family of apps compromised the private phone data of almost two million victims at the time of its breach.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The SpyX breach comes after the data exposures of &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/27/spyzie-stalkerware-spying-on-thousands-of-android-and-iphone-users/&quot;&gt;Spyzie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/stalkerware-apps-cocospy-spyic-exposing-phone-data-of-millions-of-people/&quot;&gt;Cocospy, and Spyic&lt;/a&gt; surveillance operations that left messages, photos, call logs, and other personal and sensitive data of millions of victims exposed online, according to a security researcher who found a bug that allowed them to access that data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Prior to this year, there were at least four massive stalkerware hacks in 2024. The last stalkerware breach in 2024 affected &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/25/spytech-data-breach-windows-mac-android-chromebook-spyware/&quot;&gt;Spytech, a little-known spyware maker based in Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;, which exposed activity logs from the phones, tablets, and computers monitored with its spyware. Before that, there was a breach at mSpy, one of the longest-running stalkerware apps, which exposed &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/11/mspy-spyware-millions-customers-data-breach/&quot;&gt;millions of customer support tickets&lt;/a&gt;, which included the personal data of millions of its customers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Previously, an unknown hacker &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/25/spyware-app-pctattletale-was-hacked-and-its-website-defaced/&quot;&gt;broke into the servers of the U.S.-based stalkerware maker pcTattletale&lt;/a&gt;. The hacker then stole and leaked the company’s internal data. They also defaced pcTattletale’s official website with the goal of embarrassing the company. The hacker referred to a recent TechCrunch article where we reported &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/22/spyware-found-on-hotel-check-in-computers/&quot;&gt;pcTattletale was used to monitor several front desk check-in computers&lt;/a&gt; at a U.S. hotel chain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;As a result of this hack, leak and shame operation, pcTattletale founder Bryan Fleming &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/28/pctattletale-spyware-shutters-data-breach/&quot;&gt;said he was shutting down&lt;/a&gt; his company.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Consumer spyware apps like SpyX, Cocospy, mSpy and pcTattletale are commonly referred to as “stalkerware” (or spouseware) because jealous spouses and partners use them to surreptitiously monitor and surveil their loved ones.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;These companies often explicitly market their products as solutions to catch cheating partners by encouraging illegal and unethical behavior. And &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2017/nov/30/emma-cline-countersues-after-ex-claims-she-used-spyware-to-plagiarise-his-work&quot;&gt;there have been multiple court cases&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/tag/stalkerware/&quot;&gt;journalistic investigations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/alltechconsidered/2014/09/15/346149979/smartphones-are-used-to-stalk-control-domestic-abuse-victims&quot;&gt;surveys of domestic abuse shelters&lt;/a&gt; that show that online stalking and monitoring can lead to cases of real-world harm and violence.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;And that’s why hackers have repeatedly targeted some of these companies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Eva Galperin, the director of cybersecurity at the Electronic Frontier Foundation and a leading researcher and activist who has investigated and fought stalkerware for years, said the stalkerware industry is a “soft target.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“The people who run these companies are perhaps not the most scrupulous or really concerned about the quality of their product,” Galperin told TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Given the history of stalkerware compromises, that may be an understatement. And because of the lack of care for protecting their own customers — and consequently the personal data of tens of thousands of unwitting victims — using these apps is doubly irresponsible. The stalkerware customers may be breaking the law, abusing their partners by illegally spying on them, and, on top of that, putting everyone’s data in danger.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A history of stalkerware hacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The flurry of stalkerware breaches began in 2017 when a group of hackers &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/53vm7n/inside-stalkerware-surveillance-market-flexispy-retina-x&quot;&gt;breached the U.S.-based Retina-X&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/aemeae/meet-flexispy-the-company-getting-rich-selling-stalkerware-to-jealous-lovers&quot;&gt;Thailand-based FlexiSpy&lt;/a&gt; back to back. Those two hacks revealed that the companies had a total number of 130,000 customers all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;At the time, the hackers who — proudly — claimed responsibility for the compromises explicitly said their motivations were to expose and hopefully help destroy an industry that they consider toxic and unethical.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“I’m going to burn them to the ground, and leave absolutely nowhere for any of them to hide,” one of the hackers involved then told Motherboard.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Referring to FlexiSpy, the hacker added: “I hope they’ll fall apart and fail as a company, and have some time to reflect on what they did. However, I fear they might try and give birth to themselves again in a new form. But if they do, I’ll be there.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Despite the hack, and years of negative public attention, FlexiSpy is still active today. The same cannot be said about Retina-X.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The hacker who broke into Retina-X wiped its servers with the goal of hampering its operations. The company bounced back — &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/3k7a5k/hacker-wipes-spyware-retina-x-flexispy&quot;&gt;and then it got hacked again a year later&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of weeks after the second breach, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/neqgn8/retina-x-spyware-shuts-down-apps&quot;&gt;Retina-X announced that it was shutting down&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Just days after the second Retina-X breach, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/7x77ex/hacker-strikes-stalkerware-companies-stealing-alleged-texts-and-gps-locations-of-customers&quot;&gt;hackers hit Mobistealth and Spy Master Pro&lt;/a&gt;, stealing gigabytes of customer and business records, as well as victims’ intercepted messages and precise GPS locations. Another stalkerware vendor, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/qvm44m/hacker-steals-text-messages-android-spyware-company-spyhuman&quot;&gt;the India-based SpyHuman&lt;/a&gt;, encountered the same fate a few months later, with hackers stealing text messages and call metadata, which contained logs of who called who and when.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Weeks later, there was the first case of accidental data exposure, rather than a hack. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/9kmj4v/spyware-company-spyfone-terabytes-data-exposed-online-leak&quot;&gt;SpyFone left an Amazon-hosted S3 storage bucket unprotected online&lt;/a&gt;, which meant anyone could see and download text messages, photos, audio recordings, contacts, location, scrambled passwords and login information, Facebook messages and more. All that data was stolen from victims, most of whom did not know they were being spied on, let alone know their most sensitive personal data was also on the internet for all to see.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Other stalkerware companies that over the years have irresponsibly left customer and victims’ data online are FamilyOrbit, which left 281 gigabytes of personal data online &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/ywk8gy/spyware-family-orbit-children-photos-data-breach&quot;&gt;protected only by an easy-to-find password&lt;/a&gt;; mSpy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/05/mobile-spyware-maker-leaks-2-million-records/&quot;&gt;which leaked over 2 million customer records&lt;/a&gt; in 2018; Xnore, which &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/pa97g7/xnore-copy9-stalkerware-data-breach-thousands-victims&quot;&gt;let any of its customers see the personal data of other customers’ targets&lt;/a&gt;, which included chat messages, GPS coordinates, emails, photos and more; MobiiSpy, which left 25,000 audio recordings and 95,000 images &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/j573k3/spyware-data-leak-pictures-audio-recordings&quot;&gt;on a server accessible to anyone&lt;/a&gt;; KidsGuard, which had a&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/kidsguard-spyware-app-phones/&quot;&gt; misconfigured server that leaked victims’ content&lt;/a&gt;; pcTattletale, which prior to its hack also &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7ezj8/stalkerware-leaking-phone-screenshots-pctattletale&quot;&gt;exposed screenshots of victims’ devices uploaded in real time&lt;/a&gt; to a website that anyone could access; and Xnspy, whose developers &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/12/xnspy-stalkerware-iphone-android/&quot;&gt;left credentials and private keys left in the apps’ code&lt;/a&gt;, allowing anyone to access victims’ data; and now Spyzie, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/stalkerware-apps-cocospy-spyic-exposing-phone-data-of-millions-of-people/&quot;&gt;Cocospy and Spyic&lt;/a&gt;, which left victims’ messages, photos, call logs, and other personal data, as well as customers’ email addresses, exposed online.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;As far as other stalkerware companies that actually got hacked, apart from SpyX, there was Copy9, which saw &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/pa97g7/xnore-copy9-stalkerware-data-breach-thousands-victims&quot;&gt;a hacker steal the data of all its surveillance targets&lt;/a&gt;, including text messages and WhatsApp messages, call recordings, photos, contacts, and brows history; LetMeSpy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/05/letmespy-spyware-shuts-down-wiped-server/&quot;&gt;which shut down after hackers breached and wiped its servers&lt;/a&gt;; the Brazil-based WebDetetive, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/26/brazil-webdetetive-spyware-deleted/&quot;&gt;which also got its servers wiped&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://maia.crimew.gay/posts/fuckstalkerware-5/&quot;&gt;then hacked again&lt;/a&gt;; OwnSpy, which provides much of the back-end software for WebDetetive, also got hacked; Spyhide, which had a vulnerability in its code &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/24/spyhide-stalkerware-android/&quot;&gt;that allowed a hacker to access the back-end databases&lt;/a&gt; and years of stolen around 60,000 victims’ data; Oospy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/10/05/spyhide-oospy-hacked-phone-spyware-shuts-down/&quot;&gt;which was a rebrand of Spyhide,&lt;/a&gt; shut down for a second time; and the latest mSpy hack, which is unrelated to the previously mentioned leak.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Finally there is TheTruthSpy, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/20/thetruthspy-stalkerware-forged-passports-millions/&quot;&gt;network of stalkerware apps&lt;/a&gt;, which holds the dubious record of having been hacked or having leaked data on at least &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2021/10/19/stalkerware-security-phone-data-thousands/&quot;&gt;three&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/02/12/new-thetruthspy-stalkerware-victims-is-your-android-device-compromised/&quot;&gt; separate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/thetruthspy-investigation/&quot;&gt; occasions&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacked, but unrepented&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Of these 25 stalkerware companies, eight have shut down, according to TechCrunch’s tally.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;In a first and so far unique case, the Federal Trade Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/02/spyfone-ftc-stalkerware/&quot;&gt;banned SpyFone and its chief executive, Scott Zuckerman&lt;/a&gt;, from operating in the surveillance industry following an earlier security lapse that exposed victims’ data. Another stalkerware operation linked to Zuckerman, called SpyTrac, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/17/support-king-ftc-spytrac/&quot;&gt;subsequently shut down&lt;/a&gt; following a TechCrunch investigation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;PhoneSpector and Highster, another two companies that are not known to have been hacked, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/02/02/phonespector-highster-stalkerware-shut-down/&quot;&gt;also shut down&lt;/a&gt; after New York’s attorney general accused the companies of explicitly encouraging customers to use their software for illegal surveillance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;But a company closing doesn’t mean it’s gone forever. As with Spyhide and SpyFone, some of the same owners and developers behind a shuttered stalkerware maker simply rebranded.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“I do think that these hacks do things. They do accomplish things, they do put a dent in it,” Galperin said. “But if you think that if you hack a stalkerware company, that they will simply shake their fists, curse your name, disappear in a puff of blue smoke and never be seen again, that has most definitely not been the case.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“What happens most often, when you actually manage to kill a stalkerware company, is that the stalkerware company comes up like mushrooms after the rain,” Galperin added.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;There is some good news. In a report last year, security firm Malwarebytes said that &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/news/2023/10/stalkerware-activity-drops-but-glaring-problem-with-spying-revealed&quot;&gt;the use of stalkerware is declining&lt;/a&gt;, according to its own data of customers infected with this type of software. Also, Galperin reports seeing an increase in negative reviews of these apps, with customers or prospective customers complaining they don’t work as intended.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;But, Galperin said that it’s possible that security firms aren’t as good at detecting stalkerware as they used to be, or stalkers have moved from software-based surveillance to physical surveillance enabled by AirTags and other Bluetooth-enabled trackers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“Stalkerware does not exist in a vacuum. Stalkerware is part of a whole world of tech-enabled abuse,” Galperin said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Say no to stalkerware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Using spyware to monitor your loved ones is not only unethical, it’s also illegal in most jurisdictions, as it’s considered unlawful surveillance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;That is already a significant reason not to use stalkerware. Then there is the issue that stalkerware makers have proven time and time again that they cannot keep data secure — neither data belonging to the customers nor their victims or targets.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Apart from spying on romantic partners and spouses, some people use stalkerware apps to monitor their children. While this type of use, at least in the United States, is legal, it doesn’t mean using stalkerware to snoop on your kids’ phone isn’t creepy and unethical.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Even if it’s lawful, Galperin thinks parents should not spy on their children without telling them, and without their consent.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If parents do inform their children and get their go-ahead, parents should stay away from insecure and untrustworthy stalkerware apps, and use parental tracking tools built into &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/105107&quot;&gt;Apple phones and tablets&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://support.google.com/maps/answer/7326816&quot;&gt;Android devices&lt;/a&gt; that are safer and operate overtly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-recap-of-breaches-and-leaks&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recap of breaches and leaks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Here’s the complete list of stalkerware companies that have been hacked or have leaked sensitive data since 2017, in chronological order:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/53vm7n/inside-stalkerware-surveillance-market-flexispy-retina-x&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Retina-X&lt;/a&gt; (2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/neqgn8/retina-x-spyware-shuts-down-apps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/aemeae/meet-flexispy-the-company-getting-rich-selling-stalkerware-to-jealous-lovers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;FlexiSpy&lt;/a&gt; (2017)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/7x77ex/hacker-strikes-stalkerware-companies-stealing-alleged-texts-and-gps-locations-of-customers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Mobistealth&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/7x77ex/hacker-strikes-stalkerware-companies-stealing-alleged-texts-and-gps-locations-of-customers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Spy Master Pro&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/qvm44m/hacker-steals-text-messages-android-spyware-company-spyhuman&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;SpyHuman&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/9kmj4v/spyware-company-spyfone-terabytes-data-exposed-online-leak&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;SpyFone&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/ywk8gy/spyware-family-orbit-children-photos-data-breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;FamilyOrbit&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/09/05/mobile-spyware-maker-leaks-2-million-records/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;mSpy&lt;/a&gt; (2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/11/mspy-spyware-millions-customers-data-breach/&quot;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/pa97g7/xnore-copy9-stalkerware-data-breach-thousands-victims&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Xnore&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/pa97g7/xnore-copy9-stalkerware-data-breach-thousands-victims&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Copy9&lt;/a&gt; (2018)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/j573k3/spyware-data-leak-pictures-audio-recordings&quot;&gt;MobiiSpy&lt;/a&gt; (2019)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/kidsguard-spyware-app-phones/&quot;&gt;KidsGuard&lt;/a&gt; (2020)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7ezj8/stalkerware-leaking-phone-screenshots-pctattletale&quot;&gt;pcTattletale&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/m7ezj8/stalkerware-leaking-phone-screenshots-pctattletale&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/05/28/pctattletale-spyware-shutters-data-breach/&quot;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2022/12/12/xnspy-stalkerware-iphone-android/&quot;&gt;Xnspy&lt;/a&gt; (2022)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/24/spyhide-stalkerware-android/&quot;&gt;Spyhide&lt;/a&gt; (2023)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/mb4y5x/thetruthspy-spyware-domestic-abusers-hacked-data-breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;TheTruthSpy&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en/article/mb4y5x/thetruthspy-spyware-domestic-abusers-hacked-data-breach&quot;&gt;2021&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/22/stalkerware-network-spilling-data/&quot;&gt;2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/20/thetruthspy-stalkerware-forged-passports-millions/&quot;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/02/12/new-thetruthspy-stalkerware-victims-is-your-android-device-compromised/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/05/letmespy-spyware-shuts-down-wiped-server/&quot;&gt;LetMeSpy&lt;/a&gt; (2023)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://maia.crimew.gay/posts/fuckstalkerware-5/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;WebDetetive&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/26/brazil-webdetetive-spyware-deleted/&quot;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://maia.crimew.gay/posts/fuckstalkerware-5/&quot;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/08/26/brazil-webdetetive-spyware-deleted/&quot;&gt;OwnSpy&lt;/a&gt; (2023)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/10/05/spyhide-oospy-hacked-phone-spyware-shuts-down/&quot;&gt;Oospy&lt;/a&gt; (2023)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/25/spytech-data-breach-windows-mac-android-chromebook-spyware/&quot;&gt;Spytech&lt;/a&gt; (2024)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;Cocospy (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/stalkerware-apps-cocospy-spyic-exposing-phone-data-of-millions-of-people/&quot;&gt;2025&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;Spyic (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/stalkerware-apps-cocospy-spyic-exposing-phone-data-of-millions-of-people/&quot;&gt;2025&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;Spyzie (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/27/spyzie-stalkerware-spying-on-thousands-of-android-and-iphone-users/&quot;&gt;2025&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li class=&quot;wp-block-list-item&quot;&gt;SpyX (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/&quot;&gt;2025&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated on March 19, 2025, to include SpyX as the latest breach of a stalkerware provider.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you or someone you know needs help, the National Domestic Violence Hotline (1-800-799-7233) provides 24/7 free, confidential support to victims of domestic abuse and violence. If you are in an emergency situation, call 911. The&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stopstalkerware.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Coalition Against Stalkerware&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; has resources if you think your phone has been compromised by spyware.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/hacked-leaked-exposed-why-you-should-stop-using-stalkerware-apps/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/hacked-leaked-exposed-why-you-should-stop-using-stalkerware-apps/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Data breach at stalkerware SpyX affects close to 2 million, including thousands of Apple users</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/apple-csam-encrypted.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;A consumer-grade spyware operation called SpyX was hit by a data breach last year, TechCrunch has learned. The breach reveals that SpyX and two other related mobile apps had records on almost two million people at the time of the breach, including thousands of Apple users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The data breach dates back to June 2024 but has not been previously reported, and there is no indication that SpyX’s operators ever notified its customers or those targeted by the spyware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The SpyX family of mobile spyware is now, by our count, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/20/hacked-leaked-exposed-why-you-should-stop-using-stalkerware-apps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;the 25th mobile surveillance operation since 2017&lt;/a&gt; known to have experienced a data breach, or otherwise spilled or exposed their victims’ or users’ data, showing that the consumer-grade spyware industry continues to proliferate and put people’s private data at risk.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The breach also provides a rare look at how &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/31/techcrunch-reference-guide-to-security-terminology/#stalkerware&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;stalkerware&lt;/a&gt; like SpyX can also target Apple customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Troy Hunt, who runs data breach notification site &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/PwnedWebsites#Spyzie&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt;, received a copy of the breached data in the form of two text files, which contained 1.97 million unique account records with associated email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Hunt said the vast majority of the email addresses are associated with SpyX. The cache also includes less than 300,000 email addresses associated with two near-identical clones of the SpyX app called MSafely and SpyPhone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;About 40% of the email addresses were already in Have I Been Pwned, Hunt said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;As with previous spyware breaches, Hunt marked the SpyX data breach in Have I Been Pwned as &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/FAQs#SensitiveBreach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;“sensitive,”&lt;/a&gt; which allows only the person with an affected email address to see if their information is part of this breach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The operators behind SpyX did not respond to emails from TechCrunch with questions about the breach, and a WhatsApp number listed on SpyX’s website returned a message saying it was not registered with the messaging app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-another-spyware-another-breach&quot;&gt;Another spyware, another breach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;SpyX is billed as mobile monitoring software for Android and Apple devices, ostensibly for granting parental control of a child’s phone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Surveillance malware, like SpyX, also go by the term &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/31/techcrunch-reference-guide-to-security-terminology/#stalkerware&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;stalkerware&lt;/a&gt; (and spouseware) because sometimes the operators explicitly promote their products as a way to spy on a spouse or domestic partner, which is broadly illegal without that person’s knowledge. Even when the operators don’t explicitly promote this illegal use, spyware apps share much of the same stealthy data-stealing capabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Consumer-grade spyware, like stalkerware, usually works in one of two ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Apps that work on Android devices, including SpyX, are typically downloaded from outside of the official Google Play app store and require someone with physical access to a victim’s device — usually with knowledge of their passcode — to weaken its security settings and plant the spyware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Apple has stricter rules about which apps can be on the App Store and run on iPhones and iPads, so stalkerware usually taps into a copy of the device’s backup found on Apple’s cloud storage service, iCloud. With a person’s iCloud credentials, stalkerware can continuously download the victim’s most recent backup directly from Apple’s servers. iCloud backups &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204136&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;store the majority&lt;/a&gt; of a person’s device data, including messages, photos, and app data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;According to Hunt, one of the two files in the breached cache referred to iCloud in its filename and contained about 17,000 distinct sets of plaintext Apple Account usernames and passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Since the iCloud credentials in the breached cache clearly belonged to Apple customers, Hunt sought to confirm the authenticity of the data by reaching out to&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Have I Been Pwned subscribers whose Apple Account email addresses and passwords were found in the data. Hunt said several people confirmed that the information he provided was accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Given the possibility of an ongoing risk to victims whose account credentials might still be valid, Hunt provided the list of breached iCloud credentials to Apple prior to publication. Apple did not comment when reached by TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;As for the rest of the email addresses and passwords found in the breached text files, it was less clear if these were working credentials for any service other than SpyX and its clone apps.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, Google pulled down a Chrome extension linked to the SpyX campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“Chrome Web Store and Google Play Store policies clearly prohibit malicious code, spyware and stalkerware, and if we find violations, we take appropriate action. If a user suspects their Google Account has been compromised, they should take &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/6294825&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;recommended steps&lt;/a&gt; immediately to secure it,” Google spokesperson Ed Fernandez told TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-how-to-look-for-spyx&quot;&gt;How to look for SpyX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;TechCrunch has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2022/02/22/remove-android-spyware/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;spyware removal guide for Android users&lt;/a&gt; that can help you identify and remove common types of phone monitoring apps. Remember to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://stopstalkerware.org/resources/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;a safety plan in place&lt;/a&gt;, given that switching off the app may alert the person who planted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;For Android users, switching on &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/googleplay/answer/2812853&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Google Play Protect&lt;/a&gt; is a useful security feature that can help to protect against Android malware, including unwanted phone surveillance apps. You can enable Google Play from the app’s settings if it isn’t already enabled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Google accounts are far more protected with &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/10956730?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt;, which can better protect against account and data intrusions, and know &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/6294825?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;what steps to take if your Google account is compromised&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;iPhone and iPad users can check and &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/102560&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;remove any devices from your account that you don’t recognize&lt;/a&gt;. You should ensure that your Apple account uses a long and unique password (&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/12/25/cybersecurity-101-guide-password-manager/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;ideally saved in a password manager&lt;/a&gt;) and that your account also has &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/102660&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;two-factor authentication switched on&lt;/a&gt;. You should also change your iPhone or iPad passcode if you think someone may have physically compromised your device.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you or someone you know needs help, the National Domestic Violence Hotline (1-800-799-7233) provides 24/7 free, confidential support to victims of domestic abuse and violence. If you are in an emergency situation, call 911. The&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://stopstalkerware.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Coalition Against Stalkerware&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; has resources if you think your phone has been compromised by spyware.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/data-breach-at-stalkerware-spyx-affects-close-to-2-million-including-thousands-of-apple-users/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:30:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>X users treating Grok like a fact-checker spark concerns over misinformation</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/fact-checking-ai-getty.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Some users on Elon Musk’s X are turning to Musk’s AI bot Grok for fact-checking, raising concerns among human fact-checkers that this could fuel misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Earlier this month, X &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/07/x-now-lets-you-query-grok-by-mentioning-it-in-replies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;enabled&lt;/a&gt; users to call out xAI’s Grok and ask questions on different things. The move was &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/AravSrinivas/status/1895184011871621520&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;similar to Perplexity&lt;/a&gt;, which has been running an automated account on X to offer a similar experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Soon after xAI created Grok’s automated account on X, users started experimenting with asking it questions. Some people in markets including India began asking Grok to fact-check comments and questions that target specific political beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Fact-checkers are concerned about using Grok — or any other AI assistant of this sort — in this manner because the bots can frame their answers to sound convincing, even if they are not factually correct. Instances of &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/04/elon-musks-grok-keeps-making-up-fake-news-based-on-x-users-jokes/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;spreading fake news&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/12/twitter-ai-bot-grok-election-misinformation&quot;&gt;misinformation&lt;/a&gt; were seen with Grok in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;In August last year, five state secretaries &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://casmi.northwestern.edu/news/articles/2024/misinformation-at-scale-elon-musks-grok-and-the-battle-for-truth.html&quot;&gt;urged&lt;/a&gt; Musk to implement critical changes to Grok after the misleading information generated by the assistant surfaced on social networks ahead of the U.S. election. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Other chatbots, including OpenAI’s ChatGPT and Google’s Gemini, were also seen to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/ai-chatbots-inaccurate-misleading-responses-us-elections-threaten-keep-voters-from-polls/article67894453.ece&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;generating inaccurate information&lt;/a&gt; on the election last year. Separately, disinformation researchers found in 2023 that AI chatbots including ChatGPT could easily be used to produce &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/02/08/technology/ai-chatbots-disinformation.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;convincing text with misleading narratives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“AI assistants, like Grok, they’re really good at using natural language and give an answer that sounds like a human being said it. And in that way, the AI products have this claim on naturalness and authentic sounding responses, even when they’re potentially very wrong. That would be the danger here,” Angie Holan, director of the International Fact-Checking Network (IFCN) at Poynter, told TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image aligncenter size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;1188&quot; height=&quot;1314&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2982816&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png 1188w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=136,150 136w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=271,300 271w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=768,849 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=615,680 615w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=1085,1200 1085w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=1157,1280 1157w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=389,430 389w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=651,720 651w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=814,900 814w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=723,800 723w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=604,668 604w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=339,375 339w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=558,617 558w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-19-at-1.23.04AM.png?resize=480,531 480w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1188px) 100vw, 1188px&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;wp-element-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wp-element-caption__text&quot;&gt;Grok was asked by a user on X to fact-check on claims made by another user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Unlike AI assistants, human fact-checkers use multiple, credible sources to verify information. They also take full accountability for their findings, with their names and organizations attached to ensure credibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Pratik Sinha, co-founder of India’s non-profit fact-checking website Alt News, said that although Grok currently appears to have convincing answers, it is only as good as the data it is supplied with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“Who’s going to decide what data it gets supplied with, and that is where government interference, etc., will come into picture,” he noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“There is no transparency. Anything which lacks transparency will cause harm because anything that lacks transparency can be molded in any which way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-could-be-misused-to-spread-misinformation&quot;&gt;“Could be misused — to spread misinformation”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;In one of the responses posted earlier this week, Grok’s account on X &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/grok/status/1901670856658415706&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;acknowledged&lt;/a&gt; that it “could be misused — to spread misinformation and violate privacy.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;However, the automated account does not show any disclaimers to users when they get its answers, leading them to be misinformed if it has, for instance, hallucinated the answer, which is the potential disadvantage of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image aligncenter size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;1072&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2982813&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg 1072w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=150,105 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=300,210 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=768,537 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=680,476 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=430,301 430w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=720,504 720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=900,630 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=800,560 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=668,467 668w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=536,375 536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=882,617 882w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/grok-misinformation.jpg?resize=708,495 708w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1072px) 100vw, 1072px&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;wp-element-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wp-element-caption__text&quot;&gt;Grok’s response on whether it can spread Misinformation (Translated from Hinglish)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“It may make up information to provide a response,” Anushka Jain, a research associate at Goa-based multidisciplinary research collective Digital Futures Lab, told TechCrunch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;There’s also some question about how much Grok uses posts on X as training data, and what quality control measures it uses to fact-check such posts. Last summer, it &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/26/privacy-watchdog-says-its-surprised-by-elon-musk-opting-user-data-into-grok-ai-training/&quot;&gt;pushed out a change&lt;/a&gt; that appeared to allow Grok to consume X user data by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The other concerning area of AI assistants like Grok being accessible through social media platforms is their delivery of information in public — unlike ChatGPT or other chatbots being used privately. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Even if a user is well aware that the information it gets from the assistant could be misleading or not completely correct, others on the platform might still believe it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;This could cause serious social harms. Instances of that were seen earlier in India when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2020/02/21/how-misinformation-whatsapp-led-deathly-mob-lynching-india/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;misinformation circulated over WhatsApp led to mob lynchings&lt;/a&gt;. However, those severe incidents occurred before the arrival of GenAI, which has made synthetic content generation even easier and appear more realistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“If you see a lot of these Grok answers, you’re going to say, hey, well, most of them are right, and that may be so, but there are going to be some that are wrong. And how many? It’s not a small fraction. Some of the research studies have shown that AI models are subject to 20% error rates… and when it goes wrong, it can go really wrong with real world consequences,” IFCN’s Holan told TechCrunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-ai-vs-real-fact-checkers&quot;&gt;AI vs. real fact-checkers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;While AI companies including xAI are refining their AI models to make them communicate more like humans, they still are not — and cannot — replace humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;For the last few months, tech companies are exploring ways to reduce reliance on human fact-checkers. Platforms including X and Meta started embracing the new concept of crowdsourced fact-checking through so-called Community Notes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Naturally, such changes also cause concern to fact checkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Sinha of Alt News optimistically believes that people will learn to differentiate between machines and human fact checkers and will value the accuracy of the humans more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“We’re going to see the pendulum swing back eventually toward more fact checking,” IFCN’s Holan said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;However, she noted that in the meantime, fact-checkers will likely have more work to do with the AI-generated information spreading swiftly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“A lot of this issue depends on, do you really care about what is actually true or not? Are you just looking for the veneer of something that sounds and feels true without actually being true? Because that’s what AI assistance will get you,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;X and xAI didn’t respond to our request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/x-users-treating-grok-like-a-fact-checker-spark-concerns-over-misinformation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/x-users-treating-grok-like-a-fact-checker-spark-concerns-over-misinformation/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:23:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sequoia shutters D.C. office, lets go of policy team</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/GettyImages-1258486979.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Sequoia will shutter its D.C. office as well as part ways with the policy team there at the end of March, TechCrunch has confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The news comes — and is somewhat in contrast — with the other prominent VC firms in Silicon Valley strengthening their ties with Capitol Hill and the new Trump administration. Andreessen Horowitz, for example, has been leaning into its policy team as several of its partners nab roles in the White House. It recently, for instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/26/a16z-hires-former-republican-congressman-patrick-mchenry-as-advisor/&quot;&gt;hired former Republican congressman&lt;/a&gt; Patrick McHenry as an advisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Sequoia opened its D.C. office five years ago to support companies with regulatory issues and deepen its relationship with policymakers. In a statement to TechCrunch, a Sequoia spokesperson said that thanks to the “strategic guidance and efforts,” of the policy team on the matter of bolstering relationships and knowledge, “Sequoia is now well-positioned to carry these relationships in the U.S. and Europe forward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“To that end, we are sunsetting the dedicated policy function and closing our D.C. office at the end of March. We are grateful to the team for their contributions and impact,” the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The changes impact the policy fellows at the firm, as well as three full-time employees, sources tell &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://fortune.com/2025/03/18/sequoia-capital-cut-policy-team-dc-trump/&quot;&gt;Fortune,&lt;/a&gt; which was first to report this news. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Though Sequoia is typically politically neutral, its partners have previously expressed political views. Notably, Shaun Maguire, a partner at the firm, is an outspoken supporter of President Trump and is reportedly helping screen candidates for DOGE.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/sequoia-shutters-d-c-office-lets-go-of-policy-team/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/sequoia-shutters-d-c-office-lets-go-of-policy-team/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenAI research lead Noam Brown thinks AI ‘reasoning’ models could’ve arrived decades ago</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/openAI-spiral-rose.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Noam Brown, who leads AI reasoning research at OpenAI, says certain forms of “reasoning” AI models could’ve arrived 20 years earlier had researchers “known [the right] approach” and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“There were various reasons why this research direction was neglected,” Brown said during a panel at &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/storyline/nvidia-gtc-2025-live-updates-blackwell-ultra-gm-partnerships-and-two-personal-ai-supercomputers/&quot;&gt;Nvidia’s GTC conference&lt;/a&gt; in San Jose on Wednesday. “I noticed over the course of my research that, OK, there’s something missing. Humans spend a lot of time thinking before they act in a tough situation. Maybe this would be very useful [in AI].”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Brown was referring to his work on game-playing AI at Carnegie Melon University, including Pluribus, which defeated elite human professionals at poker. The AI Brown helped create was unique at the time in the sense that it “reasoned” through problems rather than attempting a more brute-force approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Brown is one of the architects behind o1, an OpenAI AI model that employs a technique called&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/23/openais-o3-suggests-ai-models-are-scaling-in-new-ways-but-so-are-the-costs/&quot;&gt;test-time inference&lt;/a&gt; to “think” before it responds to queries. Test-time inference entails applying additional computing to running models to drive a form of “reasoning.” In general, so-called reasoning models are more accurate and reliable than traditional models, particularly in domains like mathematics and science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Brown was asked during the panel whether academia could ever hope to perform experiments on the scale of AI labs like OpenAI, given institutions’ general lack of access to computing resources. He admitted that it’s become tougher in recent years as models have become more computing-intensive, but that academics can make an impact by exploring areas that require less computing, like model architecture design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“[T]here is an opportunity for collaboration between the frontier labs [and academia],” Brown said. “Certainly, the frontier labs are looking at academic publications and thinking carefully about, OK, does this make a compelling argument that, if this were scaled up further, it would be very effective. If there is that compelling argument from the paper, you know, we will investigate that in these labs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Brown’s comments come at a time when the Trump administration is making &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-03-03/trump-s-funding-cuts-threaten-america-s-ai-competitiveness?embedded-checkout=true&quot;&gt;deep cuts&lt;/a&gt; to scientific grant-making. AI experts including Nobel Laureate Geoffrey Hinton have criticized these cuts, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/03/trump-administration-cuts-may-threaten-ai-research-efforts/&quot;&gt;saying that they may threaten AI research efforts both domestic and abroad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Brown called out AI benchmarking as an area where academia could make a significant impact. “The state of benchmarks in AI is really bad, and that doesn’t require a lot of compute to do,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;As we’ve written about before, popular AI benchmarks today tend to test for&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/03/07/heres-why-most-ai-benchmarks-tell-us-so-little/&quot;&gt;esoteric knowledge, and give scores that correlate poorly to proficiency&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on tasks that most people care about. That’s led to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/19/this-week-in-ai-maybe-we-should-ignore-ai-benchmarks-for-now/&quot;&gt;widespread&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/02/22/did-xai-lie-about-grok-3s-benchmarks/&quot;&gt;confusion&lt;/a&gt; about models’ capabilities and improvements. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated 4:06 p.m. Pacific: An earlier version of this piece implied that Brown was referring to reasoning models like o1 in his initial remarks. In fact, he was referring to his work on game-playing AI prior to his time at OpenAI. We regret the error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/openai-research-lead-noam-brown-thinks-ai-reasoning-models-couldve-arrived-decades-ago/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/openai-research-lead-noam-brown-thinks-ai-reasoning-models-couldve-arrived-decades-ago/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:13:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nvidia reportedly acquires synthetic data startup Gretel</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GettyImages-1272953815-nvidia.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Nvidia has reportedly acquired Gretel, a San Diego-based startup that’s developed a platform to generate synthetic AI training data. Terms of the acquisition are unknown. The price tag was said to be nine figures, exceeding Gretel’s most recent valuation of $320 million,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/nvidia-gretel-acquisition-synthetic-training-data/&quot;&gt;according to Wired&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Gretel and its team of roughly 80 employees will be folded into Nvidia, where its tech will be deployed as part of the former’s suit of generative AI services for developers, Wired reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Gretel was &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/02/20/gretel-nsa-amazon-github-data/&quot;&gt;founded in 2019&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Watson, Laszlo Bock, John Myers, and Ali Golshan, who also serves as the company’s CEO. The startup fine-tunes models, adds proprietary tech on top, and then packages these models together to sell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Gretel raised more than $67 million in venture capital from investors including Anthos Capital, Greylock, and Moonshots Capital prior to its exit, according to Crunchbase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Nvidia’s acquisition is strategic — and timely. Tech giants like Microsoft, Meta, OpenAI, and Anthropic are already using synthetic data to train flagship AI models as they &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/08/elon-musk-agrees-that-weve-exhausted-ai-training-data/&quot;&gt;exhaust sources of real-world data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/nvidia-reportedly-acquires-synthetic-data-startup-gretel/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/nvidia-reportedly-acquires-synthetic-data-startup-gretel/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:34:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>AWS generative AI exec leaves to launch startup</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/IMG_4752.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Raj Aggarwal is leaving AWS after nearly three years as the company’s GM of generative AI and revenue acceleration, according to a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7308177031609925632/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn post&lt;/a&gt; Aggarwal published Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“I’m proud of the pioneering work our team did in generative AI from its earliest days,” Aggarwal said in his post. “We built what might be the world’s first large-scale generative AI products — launched to tens of thousands of sellers, used hundreds of thousands of times, driving a 4.9% increase in pipeline generation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Aggarwal played a notable role in AWS’ recent push into generative AI. In the LinkedIn post, he mentioned his contributions to AWS’s AI foundation models, Bedrock AI development platform, and Amazon’s business-focused generative AI assistant Amazon Q.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Aggarwal plans to “return to his roots” and launch a new company, he said in his post — but didn’t provide any specific details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Aggarwal is no stranger to entrepreneurship. He launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2014/02/04/localytics-raises-16m-to-help-complete-the-picture-for-mobile-marketers/&quot;&gt;Localytics&lt;/a&gt;, a mobile analytics and messaging platform, in 2009, prior to joining AWS. Localytics &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/localytics&quot;&gt;raised more than $69 million&lt;/a&gt; in venture funding before Upland BlueVenn acquired it in 2020. Aggarwal left the company in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Aggarwal later founded &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2020/09/17/demand-sage-seed-funding/&quot;&gt;Demand Sage&lt;/a&gt;, an AI-driven sales analytics platform, in 2018. Demand Sage &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/demand-sage#financials&quot;&gt;went on to raise $3 million&lt;/a&gt; in venture capital before exiting to Snap in April 2021. Aggarwal remained at Snap as head of product and growth in the R&amp;amp;D group before leaving to join AWS in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;TechCrunch has reached out to Aggarwal for more information and AWS for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/aws-generative-ai-exec-leaves-to-launch-startup/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/aws-generative-ai-exec-leaves-to-launch-startup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:15:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Group co-led by Fei-Fei Li suggests that AI safety laws should anticipate future risks</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/maxresdefault_f665d6.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;In a new report, a California-based policy group co-led by Fei-Fei Li, an AI pioneer, suggests that lawmakers should consider AI risks that “have not yet been observed in the world” when crafting AI regulatory policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cafrontieraigov.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Draft_Report_of_the_Joint_California_Policy_Working_Group_on_AI_Frontier_Models.pdf&quot;&gt;41-page interim report&lt;/a&gt; released on Tuesday comes from the Joint California Policy Working Group on Frontier AI Models, an effort organized by Governor Gavin Newsom following &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/29/gov-newsom-vetoes-californias-controversial-ai-bill-sb-1047/&quot;&gt;his veto of California’s controversial AI safety bill, SB 1047&lt;/a&gt;. While Newsom found that &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/09/17/governor-newsom-on-california-ai-bill-sb-1047-i-cant-solve-for-everything/&quot;&gt;SB 1047 missed the mark&lt;/a&gt;, he acknowledged last year the need for a more extensive assessment of AI risks to inform legislators. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;In the report, Li, along with co-authors UC Berkeley College of Computing Dean Jennifer Chayes and Carnegie Endowment for International Peace President Mariano-Florentino Cuéllar, argue in favor of laws that would increase transparency into what frontier AI labs such as OpenAI are building. Industry stakeholders from across the ideological spectrum reviewed the report before its publication, including staunch AI safety advocates like Turing Award winner Yoshua Benjio as well as those who argued against SB 1047, such as Databricks Co-Founder Ion Stoica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;According to the report, the novel risks posed by AI systems may necessitate laws that would force AI model developers to publicly report their safety tests, data acquisition practices, and security measures. The report also advocates for increased standards around third-party evaluations of these metrics and corporate policies, in addition to expanded whistleblower protections for AI company employees and contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Li et al. write there’s an “inconclusive level of evidence” for AI’s potential to help carry out cyberattacks, create biological weapons, or bring about other “extreme” threats. They also argue, however, that AI policy should not only address current risks, but anticipate future consequences that might occur without sufficient safeguards. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“For example, we do not need to observe a nuclear weapon [exploding] to predict reliably that it could and would cause extensive harm,” the report states. “If those who speculate about the most extreme risks are right — and we are uncertain if they will be — then the stakes and costs for inaction on frontier AI at this current moment are extremely high.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The report recommends a two-pronged strategy to boost AI model development transparency: trust but verify. AI model developers and their employees should be provided avenues to report on areas of public concern, the report says, such as internal safety testing, while also being required to submit testing claims for third-party verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;While the report, the final version of which is due out in June 2025, endorses no specific legislation, it’s been well received by experts on both sides of the AI policymaking debate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Dean Ball, an AI-focused research fellow at George Mason University who was critical of SB 1047, said in a post on X that the report was &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/deanwball/status/1902154214068928688&quot;&gt;a promising step&lt;/a&gt; for California’s AI safety regulation. It’s also a win for AI safety advocates, according to California State Senator Scott Wiener, who introduced SB 1047 last year. Wiener said in a press release that the report builds on “urgent conversations around AI governance we began in the legislature [in 2024].”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The report appears to align with several components of SB 1047 and Wiener’s follow-up bill, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/03/the-author-of-sb-1047-introduces-a-new-ai-bill-in-california/&quot;&gt;SB 53&lt;/a&gt;, such as requiring AI model developers to report the results of safety tests. Taking a broader view, it seems to be a much-needed win for AI safety folks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/01/2024-the-year-silicon-valley-stifled-the-ai-doom-movement/&quot;&gt;whose agenda has lost ground in the last year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/group-co-led-by-fei-fei-li-suggests-that-ai-safety-laws-should-anticipate-future-risks/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/group-co-led-by-fei-fei-li-suggests-that-ai-safety-laws-should-anticipate-future-risks/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:27:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Substack rival Ghost is now connected to the fediverse</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/ghost.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;br&gt;  
&lt;p id=&quot;speakable-summary&quot; class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Newsletter platform &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, an open source competitor to Substack, is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://activitypub.ghost.org/social-web-beta/&quot;&gt;now connected to the fediverse, &lt;/a&gt;also known as the open social web. Federated apps &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/06/25/welcome-to-the-fediverse-your-guide-to-mastodon-threads-bluesky-and-more/&quot;&gt;run on the protocol ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt;, which powers apps like &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/07/24/what-is-mastodon/&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/14/decentralized-instagram-alternative-pixelfed-launches-mobile-apps/&quot;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/07/what-is-instagrams-threads-app-all-your-questions-answered/&quot;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/08/13/flipboard-users-can-now-follow-anyone-in-the-fediverse-including-those-on-threads/&quot;&gt;Flipboard&lt;/a&gt;, and others, allowing posts published on one app to be seen and engaged with by those on other federated platforms. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Ghost &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2024/04/22/substack-rival-ghost-confirms-it-will-join-the-fediverse-in-2024/&quot;&gt;said last year&lt;/a&gt; that it was working on an integration with ActivityPub, which would allow its publishers to share their blog posts with the broader open social web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The company expected the integrations to go live last year. However, Ghost this week &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://activitypub.ghost.org/social-web-beta/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the launch of its social web beta, which now allows any site running on its Ghost Pro subscription to try out the new ActivityPub integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;The beta feature is still in active development, the company notes in its help &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ghost.org/help/social-web/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, but is expected to ship in a more finalized state in the Ghost 6.0 release. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image aligncenter size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;1619&quot; height=&quot;1107&quot; src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?w=680&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2983613&quot; srcset=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png 1619w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=150,103 150w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=300,205 300w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=768,525 768w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=680,465 680w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=1200,821 1200w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=1280,875 1280w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=430,294 430w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=720,492 720w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=900,615 900w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=800,547 800w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=1536,1050 1536w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=668,457 668w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=548,375 548w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=902,617 902w, https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/activitypub-beta-1.png?resize=708,484 708w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1619px) 100vw, 1619px&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;wp-element-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;wp-block-image__credits&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Image Credits:&lt;/strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;When Ghost Pro users connect their blog or newsletter to the fediverse, others across the open social web will be able to follow their account’s handle. This handle is a combination of “@index,” representing the home page of the publication, followed by the domain name (@yoursite.com). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Ghost says users will soon be able to customize the @index part of their @index@yoursite.com handle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Users on federated apps will then be able to follow the Ghost publisher’s posts, as well as interact with them by liking, replying, or reposting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;marfeel-experience-inline-cta wp-block-tc23-marfeel-experience&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;To help Ghost publishers also participate in the fediverse and build their readership, Ghost also launched a social web reader. Here, users can browse a “feed” of the short-form content shared across the fediverse, including posts from services like Mastodon and Threads. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;In a separate area called the “Inbox,” Ghost users can keep up with long-form content, like articles published on Ghost or WordPress, the popular publishing platform that &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2023/09/14/wordpress-blogs-can-now-be-followed-in-the-fediverse-including-mastodon/&quot;&gt;integrated with the fediverse in 2023.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;“Think of the&amp;nbsp;Inbox&amp;nbsp;screen like your email inbox. When you follow other publications on the social web, new articles they publish will show up here,” Ghost’s help page explains. “Clicking on a post will open an inline reader view, right inside Ghost, and when you get to the end you’ll be able to like, repost or reply.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;With the integration of these two feeds into Ghost’s admin, Ghost will also now allow its publishers to directly post short-form content to the fediverse, helping them to build their reputation and following on the open social web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Ghost’s Reader also alerts users of interactions like follows, replies, likes, and reposts in its “Notifications” section. Plus, users can customize their Profile page to offer a preview of their social web account, following/followers, and their content, both short and long-form. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Later, the company hopes to more deeply integrate users’ social web profiles with Ghost memberships, but for now, they operate independently from one another. Other coming features include tools to block, report, and mute people or add images or media to notes and replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;There are some compatibility issues with the Ghost Reader as well, most notably with Meta’s Threads. The company says that Ghost users can search for and find Threads users’ profiles, but no interactions work because Threads blocks them. (The issue is on Threads’ side and Ghost suggests that users mention Instagram head Adam Mosseri to fix it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;To try the Ghost social web beta, Pro subscribers can head to the Ghost Admin and then enable the beta under Settings and then Labs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;Today, Ghost is used by several notable &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://ghost.org/publishers/&quot;&gt;publications&lt;/a&gt; including Casey Newton’s Platformer, 404 Media, David Sirota’s The Lever, Tangle, Jason Calacanis’s Inside, SFist, and others. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wp-block-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/substack-rival-ghost-is-now-connected-to-the-fediverse/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/03/19/substack-rival-ghost-is-now-connected-to-the-fediverse/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:25:33 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>