<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Markets | Latest News &amp; Analysis | The Australian Financial Review | AFR</title><link>https://www.afr.com/markets</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.pseudoyu.com/afr/navigation/markets" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>The latest Markets news, events, analysis and opinion from The Australian Financial Review - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://www.afr.com/apple-touch-icon-1024x1024.png</url><title>Markets | Latest News &amp; Analysis | The Australian Financial Review | AFR</title><link>https://www.afr.com/markets</link></image><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:23:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Don’t be fooled by the sudden burst of tariff bullishness</title><description>&lt;p&gt;American exceptionalism is back – for a few days at least.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US dollar rose on Monday night. The benchmark 10-year US bond yield fell. The S&amp;amp;P 500 rose 1.4 per cent, and has now risen 2.5 per cent over the two trading days. The correction that shook global markets still looms large in the rearview mirror. But at least we’re back to basically flat since election day in early November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/7462e5d313abe3f4ebe82b0df90833245ad803da&quot; alt=&quot; &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monday night’s gain was all about better news on the market’s big obsession: tariffs. A series of reports suggesting that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/world/north-america/trump-advisers-backpedal-on-tariffs-before-liberation-day-20250323-p5llsf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;US President Donald Trump would narrow the package of reciprocal tariffs&lt;/a&gt; that are scheduled to be announced on April 2 – or “Liberation Day” as Trump has taken to calling it – were seemingly confirmed by the man himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/world/north-america/trump-may-give-a-lot-of-countries-breaks-on-tariffs-20250325-p5lm80&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;“I may give a lot of countries breaks,” Trump told reporters&lt;/a&gt; on Monday in the Oval Office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the outbreak of hope that has greeted this signalling looks to be built on shifting sands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Hardly a big backdown&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump’s comments came hours after he said the US would impose a 25 per cent tariff on any country that buys oil or gas from Venezuela. And Trump says this new tariff could come on top of the 20 per cent tariff he levied on China this year, suggesting China faces 45 per cent tariffs if it continues to buy oil from Venezuela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Trump said he would announce tariffs soon on cars, aluminium and pharmaceuticals. It hardly sounds like a big backdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The buying on Wall Street was also supported by a string of more upbeat assessments from analysts and strategists who are becoming tactically more positive after the S&amp;amp;P 500 sell-off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley strategist Michael Wilson says the market looks oversold, and although he’s watching the US labour market, activity indicators and earnings revisions closely, there is an argument that the S&amp;amp;P 500 can find support around 5500 points. It closed at 5768 points on Monday night. Even the earnings downgrades among the magnificent tech stocks appear to have bottomed, Wilson says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Stoltzfus, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer Asset Management, is even more upbeat. He says hard economic data and earnings in the December quarter “point to resilience strong enough to weather the current levels of uncertainty driven by concerns tied to tariff policy, reduction of the size of government, as well as other concerns about Fed monetary policy, which rank high among a laundry list of items with outcomes unknown at present”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He’s putting his faith in the artificial intelligence boom as the next catalyst for the rally to regain momentum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In our view, bears have found catalysts in negative interpretations of economic data, company-specific earnings results and guidance to take profits without FOMO [fear of missing out] in what may once again be thought of in hindsight as a secular (long-term) bull market supported by innovation that could well benefit companies in all eleven sectors and likely across market capitalisations and style once the proverbial smoke clears.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;April 2 should provide certainty&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most bullish of all is Julian Emanuel, strategist at Evercore ISI, who is sticking with his view that the S&amp;amp;P 500 can hit 6800 points – or at least 17.5 per cent from here – by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The typical bull market killers – recession, runaway long-end yields, FOMO/exuberance, an unco-operative Fed – remain absent,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His view is that the tariff announcements on April 2 are a good thing, as they will provide certainty for business, even if tariffs are rising.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evercore’s view is that this announcement will essentially be a jumping off point for Trump to start negotiating with trading partners, so how that equates to certainty isn’t exactly clear. But it’s evidence that many parts of Wall Street believe Trump is bluffing, and that he’ll soon pull back from his trade war and apparent lack of concern about pushing America into recession.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Playing with fire&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This read could well be right. As BCA Research strategist Marko Papic says, Trump is playing with fire: causing a recession over trade and rebuilding American manufacturing is a huge political risk, given most Americans care little about trade or have any remote interest in working on an assembly line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Papic notes consumer sentiment has plunged by the most for any new president since 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Pretty astonishing when one considers that Barack Obama had to deal with the GFC and Biden was elected amidst a global pandemic.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are all sorts of conspiracy theories doing the rounds of the macro hedge fund world at present. They include the idea that Trump is using tariffs as part of a grand plan – known as the Mar-a-Lago Accord – to devalue the US dollar and make the rest of the world pay for the big tax cuts he wants to deliver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Two possible paths for Trump&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other theory is that by engineering a recession, Trump can get bond yields to drop to a point where he can force his big tax costs through without attracting the ire of the so-called bond vigilantes who worry about the size of the US budget deficit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there’s a problem with the latter plan, Papic says: bond yields aren’t coming down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yes, US long-dated bond yields normally fall in a recession. But that is when US treasuries are normally seen as a safe haven by global investors who have come to expect a certain level of decorum by US policymakers, behaviour that does not include asking the world to pay for petty tax cuts.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Papic sees two paths for Trump: he backs off from the tariff war and lets the US dollar depreciate gently, or he causes a full on “dollar market riot” by demanding the world pay for massive US tax cuts regardless of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Papic says either outcome will lead to a “secular dollar bear market and an unwinding in US dollar assets such as big tech”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The ‘comeuppance trade’ – comeuppance for the orgy of procyclical fiscal stimulus since 2017 – is upon us and there is no going back. The only question is whether the unwinding happens softly or dramatically.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that doesn’t sound bullish at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/chanticleer/don-t-be-fooled-by-the-sudden-burst-of-bullishness-20250325-p5lm95</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/chanticleer/don-t-be-fooled-by-the-sudden-burst-of-bullishness-20250325-p5lm95</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:45:01 GMT</pubDate><author>James Thomson</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/7462e5d313abe3f4ebe82b0df90833245ad803da" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Chanticleer</category><category>Opinion</category><category>Sharemarket</category><category>Investing</category><category>Trump diplomacy</category><category>Trade wars</category><category>International affairs</category><category>Global economy</category><category>USA</category></item><item><title>ASX rises as tech, banks rally; Gold Road soars 10pc</title><description>&lt;h2&gt;Avoid ‘buggy whip businesses’ amid volatility: Blackstone &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blackstone chief operating officer Jon Gray says investors need to have patience despite the sharemarket volatility caused by the Trump administration and stay focused on the long-term game in artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gray told the Asia Pacific Financial and Innovation Symposium in Melbourne on Tuesday that investors needed to avoid “buggy whip businesses” like call centres, low-level coding, or translation services, as much as they went into things like data centres.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think it’s important to look at the broader backdrop, which is economic growth is generally in the US is pretty healthy,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The most important thing is what’s happening in technology. What this AI is going to fundamentally do, it feels to me a little bit like going from horses and buggies to automobiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The world is going to change. And I think companies, the margins they can produce, the productivity, I think that’s going to be dramatically different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The news of the day sort of draws you in, causes people to freeze or pull back. If you set back a longer-term picture … I have a view that most of this will settle. There will be difficult negotiations, but the bigger picture is not so bad.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regal slashes value of Opthea holding by two-thirds&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regal has written down the value of its investment in biotech Opthea to 20¢ per share after the hedge fund revealed unfavourable results of its phase three clinical trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The writedown is equivalent to two-thirds of the value of Opthea which last changed hands at 60¢ in the dollar before trading was halted last Monday ahead of the trial outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regal owned 30 per cent of the Opthea a stake that was valued at $222 million, but shares in the fund manager slid 15 per cent as investors fretted about the consequences of the soured bet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opthea had told investors collapse because a negative trial result could force it to repay more than $1 billion in development funding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regal’s disclosures were made to investors of two listed funds, the $434 million G1 Global Investors, or VG1 and the $302 million Regal Asian Investments, or RG8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The net asset value was VG1 as a result of the writedown, and other market moves was $1.95, compared to Friday’s closing value of $2.01, a 3 per cent fall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For RG8 the net asset value was marked at $2.19 compared to Friday’s closing value of $2.37, an 8 per cent decline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;ASX rises on tariff optimism; tech, banks rally&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australian shares opened higher on Tuesday after US equities rallied on reports that the Trump administration is planning a more targeted approach to reciprocal tariffs set to be imposed on April 2, including “breaks” for certain countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 rose 0.6 per cent, or 50.1 points, to 7987 at the open, extending gains into a fourth day. The All Ordinaries also added 0.6 per cent. Eight of 11 sectors were in the green with technology leading the gains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ASX tracked a broad rally in US equities after President Donald Trump told reporters he could give “a lot of countries breaks” from tariffs. The comments spurred a rotation out of US government securities back into stocks as perceived economic risks eased.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Risk assets leapt. The technology-heavy Nasdaq rallied 2.3 per cent and Tesla surged 11.9 per cent, posting its strongest day this year with imminent tariffs on US automobile imports also boosting confidence in the stock. The VIX volatility index fell to its lowest in more than a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US tech rally spilled onto the ASX. &lt;strong&gt;WiseTech&lt;/strong&gt; added 1.4 per cent and &lt;strong&gt;Xero&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5 per cent. Banks extended Monday’s gains with &lt;strong&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/strong&gt; rising 1.2 per cent. &lt;strong&gt;Westpac&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;NAB&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;ANZ&lt;/strong&gt; all rose more than 1 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, &lt;strong&gt;James Hardie&lt;/strong&gt; dragged the materials sector lower, shedding 3.5 per cent in early trading and extending Monday’s 14.5 per cent plunge. Investors fled the stock on concerns the $14 billion it will pay to acquire Azek is excessive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Stocks on the move&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Road Resources&lt;/strong&gt; leapt 8.6 per cent after rejecting an unsolicited $3.3 billion bid from rival Gold Fields. The hostile bid also has implications for &lt;strong&gt;Northern Star&lt;/strong&gt;’s &lt;x-placeholder id=&quot;eb64b1b9412221bea95da3c4aeead91a645e985e&quot;&gt;&lt;/x-placeholder&gt; to buy out smaller rival &lt;strong&gt;De Grey Mining&lt;/strong&gt;, given that Gold Road owns a 17.3 per cent stake in the latter. Northern Star slipped 0.5 per cent and De Grey was flat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ampol&lt;/strong&gt; shares were flat after it forecast $35 million worth of repair costs from ex-tropical cyclone Alfred after incurring damage to a crude storage tank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Hope Corporation&lt;/strong&gt; slipped 1.5 per cent after downgrading the conversion price on $300 million worth of convertible bonds for the second time, from $6.55 a share to $6.24.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helia&lt;/strong&gt; bounced back from Monday’s steep plunge to rise 1.7 per cent. That was despite Morningstar downgrading its fair value price estimate for the stock after Commonwealth Bank further threw its existing contact with Helia in to question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atlas Arteria&lt;/strong&gt; sank 3.4 per cent after it went ex-dividend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Nickel Industries posts 20pc jump in earnings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nickel Industries is forecasting a quarter-on-quarter jump in earnings despite high rainfall and widespread flooding affecting its Indonesian operations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The nickel producer said earnings for the March quarter would fall in the range of $US85 million and $US90 million, up around 20 per cent on the December quarter. Its Mengjaya mine delivered 2.6 million wet metric tonnes over the period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That heavy rainfall led to the closure of Oracle Nickel electric furnaces for three days, though Nickel Industries said on Tuesday the furnaces had since been restarted with no significant damage. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Morningstar tips 20pc jump in Codan’s shares&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morningstar has set its price estimate for Codan’s shares at a 20 per cent premium to their current value, arguing the market is ignoring the growth outlook for Codan’s Zetron command centre software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The research house initiated coverage on Codan with a $19.50 fair value price estimate, higher than Codan’s $16.12 closing price on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analyst Esther Holloway called Codan’s “about 17 per cent undervalued”, forecasting low double-digital-sales growth from the communications software manufacturer’s fastest growing business, Zetron. The business operates 911 command centre operators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We think the market has not fully factored in the considerable growth trajectory for its Zetron command centre software,” Holloway said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We estimate low-double-digit sales growth as Codan sells more modules to existing customers, gains new customers, enters new segments, and introduces new products from acquisitions and internal development.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;New Hope lowers conversion price on $300m worth of bonds&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Hope Corporation has downgraded the conversion price on $300 million worth of convertible bonds from $6.55 a share to $6.24.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The downgrade applies to New Hope’s senior convertible notes due in 2029 and is the second downward revision of the notes’ conversion price. It comes as a result of New Hope paying an extraordinary cash dividend of 19¢ to shareholders on 25 March. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversion price on a convertible bond is the price per share at which it can be converted to common equity. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;EBR grows net loss&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;EBR systems’ net loss grew by 16 per cent in 2024 as higher expenses heaped pressure on the $732.8 million biotech. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; EBR’s net loss rose to $US40.8 million ($64.9 million), up from a loss of $US35 million the prior year, owing to higher administrative and expenses, it said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Higher fees from audit, legal, regulatory and tax-related services weighed as the company expanded its workforce, while interest expenses due to an additional $US20 million borrowed over the period. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Net cash fell to $US67 million, down from $US73.4 million the prior year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EBR did not pay any dividends. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Morningstar downgrades Helia as CBA contract in doubt&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morningstar has downgraded its fair value price estimate for Helia Group after Commonwealth Bank announced it was in exclusive talks with another mortgage services provider, throwing its existing contact with Helia in to question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The research house lowered its fair value estimate by 14 per cent to $3.60 after factoring in a significant drop in gross written premiums to its share price should Helia lose the contract. Helia shares lost a quarter of their value on Monday, tanking 25.6 per ent and closing at $3.61 a share,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Losing the contract will mean Helia shrinks materially,” analyst Nathan Zaia said in a note. Commonwealth Bank accounted for 44 per cent of Helia’s gross written premiums in 2024, according to Morningstar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In the past 10 years, Westpac, Macquarie, and National Australia Bank ended agreements with Helia for various reasons,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Citi downgrades New Hope, upgrades Deterra&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Citi has downgraded New Hope to “neutral” and cut its price target to $4.20 after the broker lowered its thermal coal price forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Citi also upgraded Deterra Royalties to “buy” and kept its price target unchanged at $4.50.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The broker also cut its price target on Fortescue to $17.50, Iluka Resources to $5.10, Stanmore Resources to $3.10 and Whitehaven to $7.40. Citi also lowered its price target on Mineral Resources to $28 due to lower lithium prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ampol warns of $35m cost hit from Cyclone Alfred&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ampol has forecast $35 million worth of repair costs from damage inflicted by ex-tropical cyclone Alfred, including $20 million to repair a crude storage tank and $15 million in increased demurrage costs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around half of the total cost would be recovered through insurance, Ampol said. The petroleum producer lost around 10 days of production and incurred damage to a crude storage tank floating roof. Clean up and emptying of the storage tank is ongoing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tesla posts best gain this year&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tesla leapt 11.9 per cent in US trading after US President Donald Trump paved the way for a less severe approach to reciprocal tariffs, boosting US equities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tesla shares closed at $US278.39, notching their best day of gains this year. That was after Trump told reports he “may” be flexible on levies on some countries’ exports and some sector-specific tariffs, and said he would announce tariffs on automobile imports in the coming days. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-rise-wall-st-rises-on-narrower-tariff-bet-20250325-p5lm7b</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-rise-wall-st-rises-on-narrower-tariff-bet-20250325-p5lm7b</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:49:31 GMT</pubDate><author>Nicola Blackburn</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/fb23c19518edea4c31ee0f372778541d859046d8" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Markets Live</category><category>Sharemarket</category><category>Investing</category><category>Before the Bell</category></item><item><title>UBS says the market is too pessimistic about Fortescue after 11pc fall</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The surprising resilience in iron ore prices despite an uncertain outlook for the key steelmaking ingredient has brokers at UBS reconsidering their outlook for Fortescue, one of the country’s largest producers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a note to clients, the investment bank upgraded the Andrew Forrest-chaired company and removed a recommendation to sell shares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lachlan Shaw, the lead UBS analyst, said he believed the outlook for iron ore prices and the discounts Fortescue needed to put in place were not as dire as first thought. Fortescue shares have fallen 11 per cent over the year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is far deeper than its larger iron ore producing rivals BHP and Rio Tinto, although both of those companies have diversified to other minerals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/032eb6faf80d7a9530ac3543dc3ca8aff5daaf22&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some investors have avoided Fortescue&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/fund-managers-and-brokers-turn-bullish-on-bombed-out-fortescue-20240819-p5k3ig&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; in favour of larger competitors like BHP and Rio Tinto&lt;/a&gt; primarily due to Fortescue’s lower-quality iron ore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sean Sequeira, a portfolio manager at Australian Eagle, said the quality of Fortescue’s iron ore – historically lower than BHP and Rio – had been improving as the company brought on new mines like Iron Bridge, the Pilbara operation that moved into production in the middle of 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iron Bridge is an important part of Fortescue’s strategy to raise the iron content of its product suite to achieve better profit margins on each tonne.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“[The quality] has been improving, particularly with the inclusion of the new magnetite ore,” said Sequeira, whose fund owns a small position on Fortescue. “As that ramps up, the quality of the iron ore should get closer and closer to that of Rio and BHP. For it to be more attractive than BHP and Rio, there needs to be a better valuation discount.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sequeira said he was waiting for Fortescue’s share price to fall to about $15 before he would potentially look to increase his stake in the miner. On Monday, it closed at $16.30, up more than 3 per cent or 51¢ after the UBS upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS’ Shaw described the sell-off in Fortescue shares this year as “overdone”. He expects iron ore prices to stabilise between $US90 and $US100 per tonne over the next five years. This is particularly significant for iron ore pure play Fortescue, as its financial performance is closely tied to iron ore prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This forecast is underpinned by steady demand and supply constraints due to weather-related disruptions, which UBS believed would help avoid an oversupply. UBS is comparatively more optimistic than other brokers and fund managers, such as Perennial’s resources investor Sam Berridge, who earlier this month tipped the commodity to decline to $US80 per tonne.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, iron ore futures on the Singapore Exchange rose by 1.5 per cent reaching $101.35 per tonne on the April contract. Fortescue tracked the higher commodity price, rising 3.2 per cent to $16.30 at the closing bell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS analysts also revised their 12-month price targets, reflecting changes to its earnings-per-share forecasts to 2027, lowering its expectations by 3 per cent to 6 per cent. As a result, the broker’s forecast for the company’s share price over the next year was reduced to $16.70 apiece from $17.30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS also noted that the market’s expectations for discounts on lower-grade iron ore are likely overstated. Although potential steel curtailments could affect the overall market, UBS has only marginally increased its forecast discount to 16 per cent, from the previous 15 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This increase reflects the uncertainty around the possibility of Chinese steel curtailments, which could affect iron ore prices by widening discounts for lower-grade ores.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/ubs-says-the-market-is-too-pessimistic-about-fortescue-after-11pc-fall-20250324-p5lm1g</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/ubs-says-the-market-is-too-pessimistic-about-fortescue-after-11pc-fall-20250324-p5lm1g</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 08:23:17 GMT</pubDate><author>Joanne Tran</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/032eb6faf80d7a9530ac3543dc3ca8aff5daaf22" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Sharemarket</category><category>Fortescue Metals Group</category></item><item><title>These are the four big roadblocks to a proper ASX bounce back</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Strategists at Morgan Stanley are warning there are a number of big risks to a market rebound after recession fears in the United States triggered a major slide in global shares, sending the ASX to the verge of a correction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 followed Wall Street lower over the last month after US President Donald Trump’s aggressive tariff policies created anxiety about inflation and a broader trade war, offsetting optimism from the Reserve Bank of Australia’s first rate cut in more than four years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/b7c0bdb544722635aa9620830955a418039023da&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the local market – which briefly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/recession-risks-roil-markets-as-investors-dump-stocks-bitcoin-20250311-p5likm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;fell into correction territory&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month, defined as a 10 per cent drop from its recent peak – has rebounded nearly 2 per cent in the last week, analysts at the Wall Street investment bank said there were several challenges ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a note to clients on Monday, Morgan Stanley’s equity strategist Chris Nicol said much of the improved sentiment after the RBA rate cut was “arguably based on an expectation of more of the same to come”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We see several catalysts or scenarios that could challenge expectations and potentially stunt the green shoots investors are focused on.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A shallow easing cycle&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consumers have responded positively to the start of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/wealth/investing/why-the-rba-rate-cut-is-a-very-big-deal-20250221-p5le3f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the RBA’s easing cycle&lt;/a&gt;, with confidence bouncing off lows, house price expectations climbing and auction clearance rates lifting. While business sentiment has been more muted, Morgan Stanley noted that references to lower interest rates increased significantly in the February results season, highlighting the importance of monetary policy to corporate outlooks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/6c667ab2b7728b9d78c726f960534218a31463ead7b66952d06a589e141857f5&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But some strategists believe financial markets will need to wait until May for another rate cut. “To some cries of ‘why wait?’, the RBA would have an increased understanding of tariffs, and Australia’s first quarter CPI due April 30,” said Chris Weston, head of research at broker Pepperstone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley is also forecasting just one more rate cut in May and then another 0.75 of a percentage point worth of easing in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bond markets imply a 72 per cent chance of a rate cut in May and are fully priced for a reduction in July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The risk of a minority government&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most recent opinion polls suggest the coming federal election could end in minority government, with neither Labor nor Coalition winning enough seats to govern in their own right. Morgan Stanley says this could cause a sharp deceleration in spending, cutting a key driver of the local economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the investment bank told clients that it also believes this degree of government-backed growth was unsustainable over the medium term and expects the amount of new public spending over the next year to slow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/a9c99d2e784a8d2800af1af967945ab1557056e38e2f79eaec1d8f49f6f2f51a&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A lack of fiscal pulse would take steam out of the economy and a potential air pocket should private sector activity continue to lag,” Nicol said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley pointed to the minority government in 2010 where difficulty in passing legislation resulted in essentially no government spending growth over the term of government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The dollar battles to make it&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian dollar briefly fell below US61¢ last month as Trump ramped up tariff threats, making the price of goods from overseas more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That triggered a spike in references to the currency in the February reporting season which Morgan Stanley said could be a precursor to a reflation in goods prices. Indeed, consumer companies warned of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/debt-markets/why-a-battered-a-is-a-double-edged-sword-for-asx-stocks-20250227-p5lfop&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;price rises&lt;/a&gt; later this year should the Aussie dollar remain weak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commonwealth Bank has warned that Trump’s next wave of tariff announcements on April 2 will intensify the trade war and cause traders to flock to the US dollar for safety. “The Aussie and New Zealand dollars are at most downside risk from the US imposing a 20 per cent tariff on all imports and a softer outlook for the global and Chinese economies,” said CBA’s head of international economics Joseph Capurso.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National Australia Bank believes the Australian dollar will trade in the US62¢ to US64¢ range until Trump’s next round of levies is revealed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Worsening tariff sentiment&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At first glance, Australia has been one of the least affected by Trump’s tariff threats, given the country’s trade deficit and alliance with the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Morgan Stanley warned Australia would still suffer from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/policy/economy/trump-s-big-trade-shock-is-coming-for-australia-20250318-p5lkf5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;levies on sectors such as steel and aluminium&lt;/a&gt;, while agriculture and pharmaceuticals will potentially be affected too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/b1bc72d5dde7f29d9e6f052b562d113385c9fe71336677f5043a68b0c39f0133&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the financial contribution of those industries to the broader economy is arguably modest, especially compared to mining, tourism and education, Morgan Stanley said potential tariffs will still hit sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The visibility to communities and regions across the country is high and could depress confidence with far greater impact relative to ultimate aggregate economic hit,” Nicol said.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/four-key-challenges-to-an-asx-rebound-20250324-p5llz0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/four-key-challenges-to-an-asx-rebound-20250324-p5llz0</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 03:29:03 GMT</pubDate><author>Alex Gluyas</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/b7c0bdb544722635aa9620830955a418039023da" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Sharemarket</category><category>Investing</category></item><item><title>Deal sinks James Hardie; Teal’s husband accused; ‘Peak fear’ day looms</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to get this in your inbox at lunchtime every weekday? &lt;em&gt;Financial Review&lt;/em&gt; subscribers can sign up for &lt;a href=&quot;http://join.afr.com/thebrief&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;The Brief newsletter here&lt;/a&gt;. Plus start your day with our &lt;a href=&quot;http://join.afr.com/beforethebell&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Before the Bell newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and read a full wrap of the day’s news in &lt;a href=&quot;http://join.afr.com/marketwrap&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Market Wrap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In today’s news, James Hardie’s shares plunge after it announces a $14 billion merger, Monique Ryan’s husband is filmed removing a Liberal sign, and “peak fear day” is coming for markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Making news&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-fall-despite-tariff-relief-hopes-budget-in-focus-20250321-p5lljw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASX drops; James Hardie sinks 13pc on AZEK deal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The sharemarket started the week lower as Donald Trump’s tariff turns kept traders cautious. James Hardie dived, while Helia shed a quarter of its value. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-fall-despite-tariff-relief-hopes-budget-in-focus-20250321-p5lljw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Follow live updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/politics/federal/canada-s-pm-calls-snap-election-as-trump-looms-over-campaign-20250324-p5llvm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kremlin dials down Trump hopes of Ukraine ceasefire by Easter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Vladimir Putin and the US president appear at odds over peace talks; Prime Minister Anthony Albanese accuses the opposition of lacking its own policies.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/politics/federal/canada-s-pm-calls-snap-election-as-trump-looms-over-campaign-20250324-p5llvm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; Follow live updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/politics/federal/if-labor-s-campaign-is-that-i-m-horrible-they-ll-lose-in-a-landslide-20250214-p5lc45&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘If Labor’s campaign is that I’m horrible, they’ll lose in a landslide’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Peter Dutton has long been underestimated. He hopes to use that to his advantage, he tells AFR Magazine in an exclusive interview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/companies/manufacturing/james-hardie-shares-sink-after-14b-deal-to-acquire-american-giant-20250324-p5llvw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Hardie shares sink after $14b deal to acquire American giant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the building material group’s shares plunged, chief executive Aaron Erter rejected concerns it had overpaid in its deal to buy the Chicago-based company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/politics/federal/monique-ryan-s-husband-filmed-removing-liberal-sign-20250324-p5llyn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monique Ryan’s husband filmed removing Liberal sign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;A man with a striking resemblance to the teal independent MP’s husband, Peter Jordan, was challenged about removing a campaign poster from someone’s property.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/property/residential/this-house-sold-for-4-2m-and-then-for-3-9m-a-week-later-20250320-p5ll0o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This house sold for $4.2m – and then for $3.9m a week later&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The first buyer of a luxury property – with a question mark hanging over it – ghosted the agent. That forced the vendor to set their sights lower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Around the world&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/world/north-america/musk-to-clinch-lucrative-new-us-deals-in-horrifying-power-grab-20250324-p5llvn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk to clinch lucrative new US deals in ‘horrifying power grab’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The billionaire’s company, SpaceX, is set to secure federal government contracts partly because his allies now hold government jobs. Supporters say he has the best tech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/world/north-america/he-wants-to-break-us-canada-s-pm-calls-election-to-take-on-trump-20250324-p5llw4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘He wants to break us’: Canada’s PM calls election to take on Trump&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;New prime minister Mark Carney asked for a mandate “to take on President Trump” as he announced a five-week campaign before voting on April 28.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/world/asia/china-prepared-for-shock-of-trade-war-says-premier-li-20250323-p5llta&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China prepared for ‘shock’ of trade war, says premier Li&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Countries should open up markets in the face of growing economic fragmentation, he told a gathering of global business leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/companies/sport/piastri-delivers-perfect-f1-race-to-win-shanghai-grand-prix-20250324-p5llvi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oscar Piastri delivers perfect F1 race to win Shanghai Grand Prix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Australian coasted to victory in China, sending a warning to his main rivals that he is up for the fight in this year’s world championship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Matter of opinion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/chanticleer/peak-fear-day-is-coming-for-markets-our-super-sector-is-exposed-20250324-p5llws&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Peak fear day’ is coming for markets. Our super sector is exposed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Donald Trump calls it “liberation day” but the date of his next big reveal on tariffs comes at a risky time for Australia’s large superannuation funds, writes &lt;strong&gt;Chanticleer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/politics/federal/chalmers-fiscal-irresponsibility-has-outdone-cairns-and-frydenberg-20250324-p5llwg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jim Chalmers’ fiscal irresponsibility has outdone Cairns and Frydenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;This budget will underline the sobering truth that Australia’s current policy direction leads to even more economic and social hardship, write &lt;strong&gt;Dimitri Burshtein&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Peter Swan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Business life&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/life-and-luxury/health-and-wellness/cycling-helps-this-coo-to-leave-her-work-stress-out-on-the-pavement-20250310-p5ligj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cycling helps this COO to leave her work stress out on the footpath&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;From off-road mountain biking to indoor pedal sessions, Cash Converters’ Lisa Stedman has never tried a mode of cycling she didn’t love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/life-and-luxury/fashion-and-style/the-woman-who-wants-to-see-every-one-of-us-in-an-akubra-20250217-p5lco1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The woman who wants to see every one of us in an Akubra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Australian hat brand is 149 years old and wants to get back to its city roots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/life-and-luxury/cars-bikes-and-boats/after-more-than-a-decade-bmw-has-perfected-the-art-of-ev-variants-20250224-p5leru&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After more than a decade, BMW has perfected the art of EV variants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Savvy, ambidextrous design tactics mean you can enjoy the look and feel of a several BMW models retooled to be electric, including the iX2 xDrive30.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/deal-sinks-james-hardie-teal-s-husband-accused-peak-fear-day-looms-20250324-p5lm0d</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/deal-sinks-james-hardie-teal-s-husband-accused-peak-fear-day-looms-20250324-p5lm0d</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 01:16:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/76090a246e2ff263ffaedcf5fec97f4631c3c53b" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>The Brief</category><category>Subscriber exclusive</category><category>James Hardie Industries</category><category>Monique Ryan</category><category>Sharemarket</category><category>Superannuation</category><category>Investing</category><category>Donald Trump</category><category>Elon Musk</category><category>Anthony Albanese</category><category>Peter Dutton</category><category>SpaceX</category><category>Mark Carney</category><category>Shares</category><category>China</category><category>Jim Chalmers</category><category>Ukraine</category></item><item><title>‘Peak fear day’ is coming for markets. Our super sector is exposed</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s kiss the ring week for Australia’s superannuation sector. A month after Treasurer Jim Chalmers and Australia’s ambassador to the United States, Kevin Rudd, hosted a series of meetings for super industry leaders in Washington and New York, the big dogs of American capital are making the long trek Down Under for the second annual Asia Pacific Financial and Innovation Symposium in Melbourne on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blackstone heavyweight Jon Gray, Apollo Global Management president Jim Zelter and private equity legend Henry Cornell are among the big US names who will appear at the summit, which is the brainchild of Hostplus and the Victorian government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/3dc216a60b797773cd24404be7845b4972f63098&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The timing of this year’s event is exquisite. Australia’s $4 trillion super sector is as exposed to the US market as it has ever been, with allocations to international shares hovering around 30 per cent for most large funds. The fact the big US private capital giants are pressing the flesh Down Under this week tells you there are plenty of Australian savings tied up in American unlisted assets and alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming into 2025, with global markets dancing to the tune of American exceptionalism, the super sector’s positioning looked pretty smart, even if veterans such as AustralianSuper chief investment officer Mark Delaney and UniSuper’s CIO John Pearce were cautious about over-extended valuations and the way US equity markets had been concentrated around a handful of very large, very expensive tech companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in the two short months since Donald Trump’s inauguration as US president, the big bet global investors placed on America is suddenly looking shaky. The S&amp;amp;P 500 has entered correction territory, the tech growth story has been rocked by Chinese artificial intelligence upstart DeepSeek, and Trump’s tariff war has rained uncertainty over everything from credit markets, private equity and M&amp;amp;A to the poor old Federal Reserve, which essentially admitted last week it has little faith in its ability to forecast what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bank of America strategist Michael Hartnett expects this uncertainty to ratchet even higher as we approach the key date of April 2, when the Trump administration is due to announce its program of reciprocal tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“April 2nd is going to be liberation day for America. We’ve been ripped off by every country in the world, friend and foe,” Trump said in the Oval Office on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Harnett has a very different label, arguing April 2 will be “peak fear day”. And even with the endless column inches and commentary dedicated to trying to understand Trump’s next moves and motives, investors are still extremely exposed to potential bad news on the tariff front.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hartnett says positioning tells the tale. Yes, the Bank of America fund manager survey last week suggested that one of the biggest increases in cash allocations since the panic of March 2020 when the COVID-19 crisis hit. But Hartnett says we should watch what investors do, not just what they say – last week heralded the biggest inflows to US and global equities for the year, suggesting professional managers are buying the dip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Investors are going to have a hell of a lot to chew on over the next week or so.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foreign investors – including our super funds – are selling, but they haven’t really started to unwind the $US16 trillion ($26 trillion) position they have built up in US stocks. Hartnett says that for every $100 of inflows into the US market since Trump’s election victory last November, there has been less than $1 of outflows in recent weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Global investors are not anywhere close to short US or global equities,” Hartnett says. “Bad news could have bigger impact than good news.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, bad news on tariffs on April 2 – and the Bank of America view is that tariffs jump from an average of 2 per cent or 3 per cent to about 10 per cent – is still not priced into markets, even after the S&amp;amp;P 500 correction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investors are going to have a hell of a lot to chew on over the next week or so. A well-sourced Bloomberg report on Sunday suggested the reciprocal tariffs could be more targeted than the market fears, with some exemptions possible for countries that Trump doesn’t think “cheat” on America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Trump and his inner circle are still talking about raising trillions of dollars from tariffs over the next decade, and tariffs do appear to be a part of a broader plan to use a combination of sticks and carrots to reduce the US budget deficit by re-imagining America’s position in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Australian super investors meet with US heavyweights this week, they should consider the words of Greg Jensen, co-chief investment officer at Ray Dalio’s hedge fund giant, Bridgewater Associates, in the &lt;i&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt;. “It’s a dangerous time to be overexposed to US assets, and almost everyone is.”&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/chanticleer/peak-fear-day-is-coming-for-markets-our-super-sector-is-exposed-20250324-p5llws</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/chanticleer/peak-fear-day-is-coming-for-markets-our-super-sector-is-exposed-20250324-p5llws</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 22:48:48 GMT</pubDate><author>James Thomson</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/3dc216a60b797773cd24404be7845b4972f63098" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Chanticleer</category><category>Opinion</category><category>Superannuation</category><category>Trump&#39;s America</category><category>Trade wars</category><category>Trump&#39;s White House</category></item><item><title>ASX lifts as banks rally; MinRes up 7pc as Onslow haulage resumes</title><description>&lt;h2&gt;ASX edges higher as banks rally; MinRes jumps 7pc&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sharemarket closed marginally higher on Monday, but traded in a narrow range as investors cautiously awaited more details of US President Donald Trump’s next onslaught of trade tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 Index edged up 0.1 per cent, or by 5.7 points, to 7936.9 at the close. The All Ordinaries was down 0.8 points. Just three of the index’s 11 sectors were in the green.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The index seesawed between small gains and losses, with sentiment bearish as investors gear up for sweeping reciprocal and sector-specific tariffs on April 2. US officials on Friday hinted these tariffs would be targeted, but provided no further details. Uncertainty around the impact of Trump’s trade policies on growth and inflation has sparked volatility in financial markets and kept investors cautious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We can make assumptions on how hawkish the tariff headlines and public statements from Trump will be and the possible impact on consumption, inflation and business confidence. However, the reality won’t be truly realised in the data for a period,” Pepperstone head of research Chris Weston said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Profit-taking took place across the ASX. Stock transfer agency &lt;b&gt;Computershare &lt;/b&gt;fell 2.5 per cent to $39.64 and toll road operator &lt;b&gt;Transurban &lt;/b&gt;2.7 per cent to $12.94. Supermarket &lt;b&gt;Woolworths&lt;/b&gt; slid 1.7 per cent to $29.43, and &lt;b&gt;Coles&lt;/b&gt; 2.1 per cent to $19.06.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Index bellwether &lt;b&gt;James Hardie Industries&lt;/b&gt; was a significant detractor, plunging 14.5 per cent to $40 after striking a $14 billion deal to merge with NYSE-listed Azec. The latter’s shareholders will receive around 26 per cent of the combined company’s stock.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The big banks were a bright spot, buoyed by last week’s softer-than-expected labour market data and support for US banks ahead of their earnings season. &lt;strong&gt;NAB &lt;/strong&gt;rose 2.2 per cent to $33.91, while &lt;b&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Westpac&lt;/b&gt; both added more than 1 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miners were a mixed bag, even as iron ore futures rallied 1.7 per cent to $US101.60 a tonne. Index heavyweight &lt;strong&gt;BHP&lt;/strong&gt; slipped 0.6 per cent to $39.32. &lt;strong&gt;Mineral Resources&lt;/strong&gt; rallied 6.9 per cent to $24.33 after work safety authorities deemed it safe to reopen the miner’s crucial Onslow Iron haul road. And &lt;strong&gt;Fortescue&lt;/strong&gt; advanced 3.2 per cent to $16.30, buoyed by higher iron ore prices and UBS upgrading the stock to “neutral”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stocks in focus&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In corporate news,&lt;b&gt; Helia&lt;/b&gt; plummeted 25.6 per cent to $3.61 after warning investors its current contract with &lt;b&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/b&gt; may not run beyond December 31 as the banking giant courts alternative mortgage insurers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Synlait Milk&lt;/b&gt; slumped 12.1 per cent to 81¢ as the milk producer’s latest result failed to impress investors. That was despite Synlait swinging into the black and posting a 105 per cent increase in profit to $4.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And&lt;b&gt; South32&lt;/b&gt; retreated 1.2 per cent to $3.49 after UBS downgraded the stock to “neutral”, citing the stock’s recent outperformance and some risks from its commodity price exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Four key challenges to an ASX rebound&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investment strategists say the Australian sharemarket remains delicately poised after dipping into correction territory this month, despite early signs of optimism fuelled by the Reserve Bank’s first interest rate cut in more than four years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 was swept up in a sell-off on Wall Street as uncertainty about US President Donald Trump’s aggressive trade policies reignited anxiety about inflation and a potential recession in the world’s largest economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the local sharemarket briefly &lt;x-placeholder id=&quot;f083e7305cfa8d32304c64c2615fa058964e4d97&quot;&gt;&lt;/x-placeholder&gt; earlier this month – defined as a 10 per cent drop from its recent peak – the bourse rebounded nearly 2 per cent last week, helped by data that indicates the RBA’s rate cut last month has boosted sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Morgan Stanley warned that several challenges are looming that could abruptly reverse the sharemarket’s recovery and cause the benchmark index to resume its decline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;x-placeholder id=&quot;a31f0461d3443b3e99862b47e863c20247605913&quot;&gt;&lt;/x-placeholder&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Investors pile into MinRes as iron ore haulage resumes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mineral Resources’ shares jumped almost 6 per cent on Monday after the diversified miner resumed haulage on its crucial Onslow Iron haulage network, just days after a sixth truck crash on its road, following discussions with work safety authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shares were 5.9 per cent higher, at $24.10, at 3.22pm. MinRes said on Monday its previously announced repair works to update the haul road were ongoing, and scheduled to be completed in the first quarter of financial year 2026. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversified miner’s shares have been battered in the past year, shedding 65.7 per cent amid concerns around its mounting debt, problems with its $3 billion Onslow project and allegations of offshore tax evasion lobbed at managing director Chris Ellison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This $14b US bet just got whacked by Aussie scepticism&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to understand the difference between Australians and Americans, the analyst call held to discuss James Hardie’s $US8.75 billion ($14 billion) acquisition of New York-listed AZEK, which makes alternatives to timber decking, was a pretty good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite being dragged to a conference call on a Sunday evening, the US analysts came across as chipper and broadly supportive of a deal that crystallises an impressive five-year run for AZEK. The company listed in June 2020 at $US23 a share and is &lt;x-placeholder id=&quot;1c42d873a464b556763e639eba1b59cd5d59fedd&quot;&gt;&lt;/x-placeholder&gt; after delivering solid revenue growth and margin expansion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;x-placeholder id=&quot;f0d3a92e47c5854d39d7f570a27cb3a5fa44f3aa&quot;&gt;&lt;/x-placeholder&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;ASX seesaws; banks and consumer stocks rise&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sharemarket swung between gains and losses on Monday afternoon as a rally in financial and consumer discretionary stocks sparred with wider losses across the bourse. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 Index edged up less than 0.1 per cent briefly after 2pm, before slipping back. It was down 3.3 points, or 0.04 per cent, to 7927.9 at 2.21pm. The All Ordinaries was down 7 points. Three of the index’s 11 sectors were in the green. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Index bellwether &lt;strong&gt;James Hardie Industries &lt;/strong&gt;pushed the bourse lower, shedding 12.9 per cent after striking a deal to merge with NYSE-listed AZEK in a deal worth $US8.8 billion ($14 billion) that will AZEK shareholders own about 26 per cent of the combined company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cautious sentiment drove wider losses across the bourse as investors gear up for America’s next wave of tariffs on trade partners on April 2. On Friday, Trump’s hint at some flexibility to the reciprocal and sector-specific tariffs provided a brief boost to US equities, but the S&amp;amp;P 500 closed just 0.1 per cent higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock transfer agency &lt;strong&gt;Computershare&lt;/strong&gt; edged 1.9 per cent lower and toll road operator &lt;strong&gt;Transurban &lt;/strong&gt;fell 2.9 per cent. Profit-taking also affected &lt;strong&gt;Woolworths&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Coles&lt;/strong&gt;, which slid 1.1 per cent and 1.6 per cent respectively, after the findings of a long-awaited ACCC report into the supermarkets on Friday spurred a buying spree.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consumer discretionary and financial stocks were a bright spot. Index heavyweights &lt;strong&gt;Wesfarmers&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Aristocrat Leisure&lt;/strong&gt; posted notable gains, adding 1.2 per cent and 1.4 per cent. Among the banks, &lt;strong&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/strong&gt; added 1.1 per cent and &lt;strong&gt;Westpac&lt;/strong&gt; 1.3 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Stocks on the move&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In corporate news,&lt;strong&gt; Helia&lt;/strong&gt; plummeted 26.2 per cent after warning investors its current contract with &lt;strong&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/strong&gt; may not run beyond December 31 as the banking giant courts alternative mortgage insurers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mineral Resources&lt;/strong&gt; jumped 4.5 per cent after reopening its Onslow Iron haul road. A sixth truck crash had forced the miner to close the haulage network early last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iron ore miner &lt;strong&gt;Fortescue&lt;/strong&gt; gained 1.9 per cent after UBS upgraded it to “neutral” from its prior sell rating, arguing that the outlook for iron ore prices and low-grade discounts are less gloomy than feared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synlait Milk&lt;/strong&gt; slumped 8.2 per cent as the milk producer’s latest result failed to impress investors. That was despite Synlait swinging into the black and posting a 105 per cent increase in profit to $4.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And&lt;strong&gt; South32&lt;/strong&gt; retreated 1.7 per cent after UBS downgraded the stock to “neutral”, citing the stock’s recent outperformance and some risks from its commodity price exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;ASX swings into the green&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sharemarket swung into the green on Monday afternoon as financial and consumer discretionary stocks extended the morning’s gains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ASX 200 was just 1.4 points higher at 1.49pm, buoyed by the consumer discretionary sector, up 1.2 per cent. US futures have partially buoyed sentiment, with contracts spanning all three US indexes opening higher on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Index heavyweights Wesfarmers and Aristocrat Leisure posted notable gains, adding 1.5 per cent and 2.2 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks were also behind the move. Commonwealth Bank added 1.3 per cent and Westpac 1.2 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gold near record high with Trump aiding demand&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gold was steady — after two days of declines — as economic and geopolitical risks supported haven demand, despite signs that the next wave of US tariffs may be more targeted than expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bullion traded around $US3,022 an ounce, near a record high reached on Thursday. US President Donald Trump’s so-called reciprocal tariffs are likely to be less punitive than he had earlier threatened. The White House is set to exclude some countries and is not currently planning sector-specific trade barriers, aids and allies familiar with the matter said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese Premier Li Qiang said Asia’s largest economy is still prepared for tariff shocks and Australian Treasurer Jim Chalmers warned about the “seismic” impact of US policies on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;UBS downgrades South32 on commodity price outlook, valuations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS has downgraded South32 to “neutral” from buy owing to the stock’s recent outperformance and some risks from its commodity price exposure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investment bank pointed out that South32 had outperformed BHP by around 20 per cent, saying this indicated the risk-reward was now balanced, particularly with its pivot to organic growth from cash returns and a restructuring. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“South32’s operational performance has improved and its balance sheet is strong, but its growth is long-dated &amp;amp; offset by depletion [from its Cannington mine],” analyst Lachlan Shaw said, adding that the miner’s cash returns over the next 2 years were “not compelling”. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS also called the miner’s commodity risk “balanced”, with alumina prices and manganese ore to come under pressure into 2026, according to its forecasts. Copper prices are set to increase around 15 per cent, and aluminium and zinc are expected to be stable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS also lowered its price target to $3.70 a share, from $4. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;UBS upgrades Fortescue to ‘neutral’&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;UBS has upgraded Fortescue to “neutral” from its prior sell rating, arguing that the iron ore price outlook and low-grade discounts are less gloomy than feared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investment bank expects the iron ore price to hold between $US90 and $US100 a tonne for the next five years, pointing to firmer-than-expected prices because of weather disruption and stable demand keeping oversupply risks at bay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prices would hold at that level even if supply growth put downward pressure on prices in the coming years, UBS said. Fortescue is leveraged to the iron ore price due to its single-exposure commodity portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calling low-grade iron ore discount forecasts “overdone”, UBS also acknowledged the impact of steel curtailments, leading it to marginally increase its discount forecast to 16 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That drove a small downward revision in UBS’ Fortescue price target to $16.70 from $17.30.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shares in the iron ore miner were 2 per cent higher at 12.38pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;ASX slips, James Hardie slumps; CBA up 1pc&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sharemarket opened lower on Monday, as Donald Trump’s back-and-forth approach to tariffs kept traders cautious and a steep sell-off in James Hardie Industries weighed on the bourse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 slipped 0.1 per cent, or 5.2 points, to 7926 at lunchtime. The All Ordinaries Index fell 0.2 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Hardie Industries&lt;/strong&gt; shed 13.2 per cent after striking a deal to merge with NYSE-listed AZEK in a cash and share transaction worth $US8.8 billion ($14 billion). Under the deal, AZEK shareholders will receive stock and cash valued at $US56.88 and own about 26 per cent of the combined company, which will be listed on the New York Stock Exchange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cautious sentiment drove wider losses across the bourse as investors geared up for America’s next wave of tariffs on trade partners on April 2. On Friday, Trump’s hint at some flexibility to the reciprocal and sector-specific tariffs provided a brief boost to US equities, but the S&amp;amp;P 500 closed just 0.1 per cent higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Anticipation and pre-positioning ahead of Trump’s ‘Liberation Day’ on 2 April and the impending deluge of tariff-related announcements that will follow … will be a growing factor that drives price action, sentiment and liquidity in markets this week,” said Pepperstone head of research Chris Weston.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Profit-taking hit index bellwethers across various sectors.&lt;strong&gt; BHP &lt;/strong&gt;dropped 1 per cent. Stock transfer agency &lt;strong&gt;Computershare&lt;/strong&gt; edged 1.5 per cent lower and toll road operator &lt;strong&gt;Transurban &lt;/strong&gt;fell 2.9 per cent. Profit-taking also affected &lt;strong&gt;Woolworths&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Coles&lt;/strong&gt;, which slid 1.3 per cent and 1.2 per cent respectively, after the findings of a long-awaited ACCC report into the supermarkets on Friday spurred a buying spree.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Index bellwether &lt;strong&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/strong&gt; was a bright spot, rising 1.1 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Stocks on the move&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In corporate news,&lt;strong&gt; Helia&lt;/strong&gt; plummeted 25.4 per cent after warning investors its current contract with &lt;strong&gt;Commonwealth Bank&lt;/strong&gt; may not run beyond December 31 as the banking giant courts alternative mortgage insurers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opthea&lt;/strong&gt;’s shares will remain suspended from trading as the biotech scrambles to secure its future following the disappointing results of a clinical trial involving its flagship drug, OPT-302.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kelsian&lt;/strong&gt; climbed 0.7 per cent after it commenced negotiations with Transport NSW over its provision of public bus services to Sydney’s inner west for a further year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synlait Milk&lt;/strong&gt; slumped 9.3 per cent as the milk producer’s latest result failed to impress investors. That was despite Synlait swinging into the black and posting a 105 per cent increase in profit to $4.8 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And an Australian engineering and logistics company has accused diversified miner &lt;strong&gt;South32&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;x-placeholder id=&quot;37fb594f3fe0134cf1ef3d24edd24b7e8e9d18eb&quot;&gt;&lt;/x-placeholder&gt; by using information gathered over the course of a contract to copy its products. The miner’s shares slipped 2.2 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Drakes to open 69th store at former Coles site in South Australia&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drakes Supermarkets, the largest independent grocery retailer in Australia, will open its 69th store, located at the former Coles site in Mount Gambier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drakes has partnered with Leyton Property in a joint purchase and development project that will create over 150 new job opportunities for the region, it said. The store is set to open in late 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drakes managing director and founder Roger Drake managed the same Coles store in Mount Gambier more than 50 years ago, before leaving to open his own shop in 1974.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“South Australia doesn’t just end at Adelaide, and the Blue Lake City has been neglected for far too long. We’ve heard the people loud and clear, and we are excited to be bringing the Drakes offer to Mount Gambier,” said John-Paul “JP” Drake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m so happy Coles told Dad he would never make it in this very store. Amazing what some hard work and support from the people around you can do.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drakes has stores across South Australia and Queensland, which employs more than 6000 staff and has an annual turnover in excess of $1 billion.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-fall-despite-tariff-relief-hopes-budget-in-focus-20250321-p5lljw</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-fall-despite-tariff-relief-hopes-budget-in-focus-20250321-p5lljw</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 20:48:47 GMT</pubDate><author>Nicola Blackburn</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/06c8c317fa37d0cf0e7dcafd8ab513db49ea00992ae6c296a1bd6f4e980daba8" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Markets Live</category><category>Investing</category><category>Commodities</category><category>Cryptocurrencies</category></item><item><title>Here are four ASX stocks that are tipped to go on a tear</title><description>&lt;p&gt;For Deana Mitchell, the wild moves in financial markets since United States President Donald Trump has returned to the White House offer prime opportunities to buy low and ride the rebound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past two months, Trump’s swift and unpredictable tariff policies have rattled the sharemarket as investors around the world balance his pro-business agenda against a potential trade war and looming recession in the world’s largest economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/c64a0a24c1f1660d0366dd4fa8e4e50f2f36bd0f&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Australia, market jitters sent the S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 tumbling to its lowest point since August. After briefly entering a correction, the benchmark index recovered some ground but with Trump threatening to impose new tariffs on April 2, uncertainty lingers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Mitchell, who manages Australian Ethical’s $2 billion Australian Shares Fund, it’s a fertile ground for stock picking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’ve seen stocks overshoot and undershoot in terms of their share price movements and that’s what we’ve been actively looking for,” says Mitchell, who took over running the 30-year-old fund in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She notes that 20 per cent of the stocks that posted results during last month’s earnings season experienced a 10 per cent price swing in either direction, making it the most volatile reporting period on record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Timely reserves&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitchell’s approach is to exploit the substantial price moves driven by momentum traders reacting to changes in earnings forecasts – when a company beats expectations the stock tends to rise, while a shortfall usually results in a drop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So after building up the fund’s cash reserves to 8 per cent when it concluded late last year that stock valuations had got too elevated, Mitchell has been busy buying up stocks at favourable prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s been an opportune time to deploy more capital into the market,” she says of the extra cash in the portfolio. The fund usually holds between 5 per cent and 10 per cent in cash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking advantage of the volatility from the earnings season and Trump’s unpredictable trade agenda, she started buying shares in CSL in February despite the biotech giant reporting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/companies/healthcare-and-fitness/csl-says-on-track-for-double-digit-growth-but-vaccine-sales-weak-20250210-p5lb0u&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;a decline in flu shots in the US&lt;/a&gt; after the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/companies/healthcare-and-fitness/csl-says-on-track-for-double-digit-growth-but-vaccine-sales-weak-20250210-p5lb0u&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitchell is confident in CSL’s core business – blood plasma products – which she says continues to perform well. The ASX heavyweight had not been included in the fund for years because of its lofty price tag, but after trading at its cheapest valuation in 15 years, she snapped it up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another stock pick is SiteMinder, a hotel booking company that went public on the ASX in 2021. It was another valuation call along with expectations of strong growth as the company introduces new products that are still in the investment phase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitchell particularly likes SiteMinder’s adhesion to the “rule of 40”, meaning that a company’s combined annual growth rate and free cash flow margin should exceed 40 per cent. And despite a 22 per cent collapse in the share price this year, Mitchell says management will deliver on these growth prospects, pushing the stock significantly higher from here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another more recent addition is private health insurer NIB, which the team started buying up in September only for the company to issue a profit warning in November amid rising losses in its New Zealand business,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We saw the stock as oversold as it had pushed it to 12 to 13 times its price-to-earnings ratio, well below its historical average of 18 times and a material discount to its nearest rival, Medibank,” Mitchell says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitchell doubled the fund’s holdings in January and has watched the stock shoot up 21 per cent this year to $6.66. Mitchell is tipping even more upside on the stock after it was unfairly punished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for the broader market, Mitchell is not overly concerned about the impact of Trump’s erratic policymaking on the companies she owns. The most exposed stock in the portfolio is metals recycling giant Sims, but she believes the business will actually benefit from the proposed tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise, she isn’t losing sleep over the possibility of an even deeper sell-off in the sharemarket that could possibly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/macquarie-warns-of-bear-market-as-us-spending-collapses-20250317-p5lk22&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;push equities into a bear market&lt;/a&gt;, which is defined by a 20 per cent drop from peak to trough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She says Australian Ethical, which manages $13 billion in assets, follows a long-term investment philosophy that focuses on companies with strong structural growth. It’s for this reason they are overweight in industries such as renewables, healthcare and technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;‘Negative’ sectors&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the name would suggest, it steers clear of “negative” sectors such as fossil fuels, tobacco, and even nuclear energy. Founded in 1986, the firm invests in companies based on their impact on people, the planet and animals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the fund’s inception, it has paid an average of 12.5 per cent and has outperformed the 9.8 per cent return of its blended benchmark that includes the ASX 100 and the Small Ordinaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past 12 months, the fund returned 12.3 per cent versus the benchmark’s 9.1 per cent, and while it has lagged over three years, it has edged the benchmark over five and 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Mitchell, this proves that ethical investing doesn’t mean sacrificing returns. And while noting that a similar portfolio with less stringent investment criteria has also beaten the ASX, Mitchell says investing with an ethical mindset brings a sense of satisfaction and has a positive impact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what about the risk of Trump’s freezing billions of dollars in clean energy projects in the US? Mitchell is confident it will not affect her investments in the space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s because the fund’s renewables focus is primarily in New Zealand, where 85 per cent of the country’s electricity comes from clean sources, positioning it among the most advanced nations in the energy transition. It owns Contact Energy and Mercury, both of which have fallen more than 5 per cent this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere in the portfolio, Mitchell owns Cuscal, a payment provider that went public on the ASX last year. Trading at 12 times its forward earnings, with a 4.5 per cent fully franked dividend yield, Cuscal is a dominant player in the payments’ infrastructure for non-bank institutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitchell likes the management team and is expecting growth through acquisitions. As the company meets its earnings targets, she believes the stock could be re-rated after already soaring 20 per cent this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the shares that the fund sold this year is real estate website Domain, after it received a takeover bid from US property conglomerate CoStar last month. The fund still retains a stake in Domain, which is owned by Nine Entertainment, the publisher of this masthead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mitchell is a self-confessed number enthusiast and joined Australian Ethical in 2018 from Macquarie where she was head of ESG research and deputy head of small caps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She says the best part of the job is stock picking – investing in promising companies and then seeing investment ideas come to fruition. “We do the work as if we were the owners for 10 years,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/here-are-four-asx-stocks-that-are-tipped-to-go-on-a-tear-20250314-p5ljjn</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/here-are-four-asx-stocks-that-are-tipped-to-go-on-a-tear-20250314-p5ljjn</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Cecile Lefort</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/c64a0a24c1f1660d0366dd4fa8e4e50f2f36bd0f" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Monday fundie</category><category>CSL Limited</category><category>Investing</category><category>Shares</category><category>Sharemarket</category></item><item><title>ASX to slip before budget, US tariffs jitters</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Australian sharemarket will open weaker on Monday as investors brace for the federal budget and more uncertainty about US President Donald Trump’s tariff agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The S&amp;amp;P/ASX 200 futures indicate the index will decline 41 points, or 0.5 per cent, after the sharemarket posted its strongest weekly gain this past week. The benchmark is still down almost 3 per cent this year, having briefly entered a correction, defined by a 10 per cent drop from peak to trough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/388ba051d1ed4c367e06ef9b61208bd0012706f3&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump’s chaotic trade policies, just two months into his presidency,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/debt-markets/why-the-prospect-of-a-trumpcession-is-starting-to-grow-20250307-p5lhq1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt; have created uncertainty for businesses and the economy&lt;/a&gt;, leading to turmoil in financial markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investors are awaiting the US president’s detailed plans regarding reciprocal and sector-specific tariffs, set to take effect next month. On Friday, Trump suggested he might show flexibility. His comments bolstered Wall Street, with all three major US stock indexes reversing losses. The Dow Jones and the S&amp;amp;P 500 ended 0.1 per cent higher and the Nasdaq was up 0.5 per cent, paced by Apple and Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, fund managers doubt that wild swings in financial markets are over. “If the tariff ‘flexible’ feels scattergun, on-again-off-again, it could lead to more uncertainty, which markets may like less than the tariff themselves,” said Matt Wacher, Morningstar’s chief investment officer for Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a more balanced approach to tariffs allowing businesses and countries to plan around it could be cheered by investors, despite the possibility of some short-term pain, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Boubouras, head of research at K2 Asset Management, anticipates more frequent but shorter-lived spikes as Trump’s administration moves his agenda to deregulation and lower taxes, which he pledged during his election campaign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Electricity subsidies&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Australia, the federal budget on Tuesday will take centre stage even though most details have already been flagged by the Labor government, including an $8.5 billion allocation for Medicare bulk billing, ahead of a national election, which must be held by May 17.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treasurer Jim Chalmers is expected to unveil an underlying cash deficit of about $20 billion this year, widening to more than $40 billion for 2025-26. Analysts anticipate there will be about $8 billion in additional stimulus such as extending electricity rebates to help households cope with the high cost of living.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/3cd9abd758c214cb19e59ff589b7fba81d3ac3dc3fe57d70d1fab0658c32f56b&quot; alt=&quot; &quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As is typical of pre-election budgets, we expect a boost to discretionary spending,” said &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/markets/debt-markets/meet-the-most-accurate-economic-forecaster-of-2024-20250131-p5l8os&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Paul Bloxham, chief economist for Australia at HSBC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While such an energy package will lower the headline consumer price index, the measure is only a temporary relief.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, headline core inflation, the Reserve Bank’s preferred measure of the gauge, slowed sharply to an annual pace of 3.2 per cent in the December quarter, from 3.6 per cent. Yet, the central bank forecasts it will accelerate to 3.7 per cent later this year when the first round of electricity rebates expires.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Treasury has previously said rebates were “not expected to add to broader inflationary pressures”, but economists are more circumspect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Clever giveaways, such as further electricity subsidies can help keep inflation expectations in check. Equally, they free up income which can be spent elsewhere, and likely complicate life for the RBA,” said Andrew Ticehurst, a rate strategist at Nomura.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared with major central banks which started reducing interest rates in 2024, the RBA only joined the easing tide early this year after gaining more confidence that price rises were heading back sustainably to its 2 per cent to 3 per cent target.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/RD5LF/3/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market will analyse Wednesday’s monthly inflation indicator for February for clues on the consumption pulse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Financial markets imply a total of 68 basis points of cuts this year, which is equivalent to between two and three quarter-of-a-point reductions. Meanwhile, traders ascribe a three-in-four chance the central bank will further reduce the cash rate in May to 3.85 per cent and are fully priced for a move by July. The RBA lowered the policy rate last month for the first time in almost five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nomura forecasts Australia’s underlying budget deficit to widen to 1.7 per cent of GDP by June 2026, from 0.8 per cent this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, Ticehurst is not worried about the rising debt and bond issuance levels because they remain “enviably low” by global standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investors will gain more insights on the national debt on Wednesday when the Australian Office of Financial Management, the financing arm of the government, releases its borrowing plans. Last December, the agency revised its funding program for this financial year ending in June to $95 billion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With almost $1 trillion of government debt in circulation, Australia is one of only 11 countries with a top-notch AAA rating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In international markets, investors will await, on Thursday, the final take on fourth-quarter GDP in the world’s largest economy. Personal consumption expenditures, the Federal Reserve’s preferred measure of inflation, will follow on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-slip-ahead-of-federal-budget-us-tariffs-jitters-20250322-p5lloe</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/asx-to-slip-ahead-of-federal-budget-us-tariffs-jitters-20250322-p5lloe</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 03:18:57 GMT</pubDate><author>Cecile Lefort</author><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/388ba051d1ed4c367e06ef9b61208bd0012706f3" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Investing</category><category>Shares</category><category>Wall Street</category><category>Federal budget</category></item><item><title>Private versus public markets? The debate is just heating up</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Australian sharemarket listings have slowed as capital flowing to unlisted assets has surged. Now, the country’s corporate regulator wants to get to the bottom of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian Securities and Investments Commission wants to look at the role of private markets, if they are reducing the quality of opportunities in public markets, and how they can be better regulated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pundits have until April 28 to share their views on the continued growth of superannuation funds, what market integrity looks like as private capital raising dominates, and whether greater harmonisation is needed in the regulation of public and private companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.ffx.io/images/9ec9ca0f0129b84a4fec3ac08bccd1fb97b718e1&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a parent of two children, I’m often reminded of how fraught comparison exercises can be. In that spirit, let me diplomatically say both public and private markets have their place. We all want both to succeed in an efficient capital market (and we love you both very much).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, without playing favourites, we can talk about individual strengths.&lt;br&gt;Public markets allow for easy entry to markets for less sophisticated investors. It’s easily tradeable, with ample information and regulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I note superannuation funds still only average about a fifth of their capital in private markets due to member liquidity requirements. There will always be an ongoing need for public markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Private markets are more suited for “patient capital”, generating returns over longer periods, making them well-suited to institutional investors. Here, although correlated, returns are driven by additional risk&lt;br&gt;factors, providing diversification benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both have a place in an efficient portfolio, hence the rise of democratisation to make private markets more accessible. Over the past five years, there has been a pronounced shift in where companies go to find capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between December 2022 and 2024, the number of listed companies fell by 145, due to fewer new listings (66) and more de-listings (211). The ratio is pretty stark historically, but ASIC thinks it’s too early to call this a structural trend. But if we consider the drivers of this shift, I think it’s perplexing not to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take the growth of superannuation. Savings are held efficiently in large pools by qualified investment managers who can aggregate and efficiently invest in private markets to reap the benefits. Whereas 30 years ago, long-term savings were more in the hands of individual investors and were disaggregated into smaller amounts – thus preferencing listed markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ASIC is of course right in highlighting some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/companies/financial-services/asic-puts-defensive-150b-private-capital-sector-on-notice-20250224-p5ler0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;potential concerns with private markets&lt;/a&gt;, particularly as they become more accessible. Lack of liquidity, fees, opacity, conflicts of interest, amounts of leverage&lt;br&gt;and valuations were all issues raised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To tackle the first one – illiquidity is a characteristic investors want in private markets, as they get paid for taking on the risk that you can’t sell an asset immediately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Is it fair?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As long as this is understood, illiquid assets warrant an important place in a portfolio – rewarding those who are patient, allowing a company to grow through its “J-curve” and potentially allowing the owner to have more control of management (or employ an asset manager to do this).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The question for managers is whether this illiquidity premium is fair? Not, should we have illiquid assets or not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for some of the other concerns, such as valuations, it is important to consider the entire Australian regulatory framework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian Prudential Regulation Authority has recently wrapped up a review of superannuation trustee’s valuations and liquidity, and made recommendations. Fee disclosure is also heavily regulated for this investor base. In a bid to not over-regulate, consideration of the current framework is vital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, ASIC is also concerned about retail investors in private markets along with other regulators around the world. Retail investment in private markets via managed investment schemes are currently mainly regulated by the Corporations Act – arguably too generic for the risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We see a broad church of approaches from managers in disclosure and transparency, and note that many schemes are already managed by sophisticated managers. However, we would support a clearer standard in the industry to ensure retail investors appreciate &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.afr.com/companies/financial-services/sqm-issues-warning-on-private-credit-after-uptick-in-bad-loans-20250320-p5lla0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;the risks involved&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the public versus private markets debate is unlikely to subside after April, every effort to ensure Australia’s capital markets remain attractive and meet future economic needs is welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We do encourage a considered response that recognises the sophistication of institutional investors and the level of regulation and scrutiny they are already under. Recent APRA reviews should alleviate a lot of ASIC’s concerns for this cohort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are staunch believers in illiquidity premia and the important place it holds for portfolio management – but recognise that it can never be a dominant holding when these funds can be drawn upon immediately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To that end, keeping our public markets attractive for investment against a market that is innovating at a faster pace is a worthy enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Katrina King is the general manager of client solutions and capital, for QIC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.afr.com/markets/debt-markets/private-versus-public-markets-the-debate-is-just-heating-up-20250323-p5llqh</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.afr.com/markets/debt-markets/private-versus-public-markets-the-debate-is-just-heating-up-20250323-p5llqh</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 22:19:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.ffx.io/images/9ec9ca0f0129b84a4fec3ac08bccd1fb97b718e1" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>Private credit</category><category>Opinion</category><category>Bonds</category><category>Sharemarket</category><category>Investing</category><category>ASIC</category></item></channel></rss>