<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>LMU Academic Staff Job Openings</title><link>https://www.lmu.de/en/about-lmu/working-at-lmu/job-portal/academic-staff/</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.henry.wang/lmu/jobs" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>LMU Academic Staff Job Openings - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:08:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>14</ttl><item><title>Doctoral researcher in Plant Science (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Biology&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-15T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Biocenter at LMU Munich invites applications for a PhD position within the DFG funded Transregional Collaborative Research Center TRR175, under the supervision of PD Dr. Serena Schwenkert (chair molecular plant biology • Prof. Dr. Dario Leister). The collaborative research project focuses on elucidating the molecular mechanisms of plant acclimation to changing environmental conditions.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Master’s degree in Biology or Biochemistry, or a related field&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experience with molecular laboratory methods and/or data analysis is beneficial&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;High level of motivation and scientific curiosity&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Proficiency in English (both written and spoken).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A dynamic and interdisciplinary research environment within the TRR175 consortium&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Access to state-of-the-art research facilities, including proteomics, metabolomics and microscopy platforms&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Participation at international conferences&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Opportunity to join the graduate school Life Science Munich (LSM)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Remuneration according to the collective agreement for the public service of the federal states (TV-L) in &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;E13&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lmu.de/en/about-lmu/working-at-lmu/additional-services/corporate-benefits/&quot;&amp;gt;In addition, you can benefit from the various LMU corporate benefits&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please send your application (including CV, academic transcripts and contact details of two academic referees) via e-mail to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:serena.schwenkert@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;Dr. Serena Schwenkert&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; with the subject line &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&amp;amp;quot;PhD Application – TRR175&amp;amp;quot;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;. For further inquiries, feel free to contact &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:serena.schwenkert@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;Dr. Serena Schwenkert&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/fdc977b35d86a9e3c6a563abe9fe791e336e35df0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/fdc977b35d86a9e3c6a563abe9fe791e336e35df0</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:01:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral position in Neuroscience (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Biology&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-15T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The newly established group of &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annaschroederlab.com/&quot;&amp;gt;Prof. Dr. Anna Schroeder&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; at LMU Munich is seeking an excellent candidate for a postdoctoral position in neuroscience.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Our lab investigates the neural circuits underlying emotions, motivations, and physiological needs, focusing on how these internal states shape behavior in dynamic environments. Specifically, we study the subthalamic circuits of the zona incerta, an enigmatic brain region that integrates internal states, external sensory cues, and past experiences to adapt behavior flexibly. To dissect the neural circuit mechanisms driving behavior, we employ cutting-edge methodologies including:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;In vivo&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; calcium imaging with 2-photon microscopy or Miniscopes&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Whole-cell patch-clamp electrophysiology&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Single-cell RNA sequencing&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Optogenetics&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Chemogenetics&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Viral circuit tracing&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;State-driven behavioral paradigms&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Transgenic mouse models&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Advanced machine learning techniques&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Our ultimate goal is to advance understanding of brain function and develop novel therapeutic strategies for psychiatric disorders through neuromodulation. Prof. Dr. Schroeder is deeply committed to training, mentorship and career development for lab members. The lab offers state-of-the-art neuroscience in a very supportive environment.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For more information, visit &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://www.annaschroederlab.com&quot;&amp;gt;Schroeder Lab&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Ph.D. or equivalent in a relevant field (e.g., biology, psychology, medicine, physics)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A proven track record (including peer-reviewed publications or pre-prints)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Relevant experience with at least one advanced circuit technology (e.g., in vivo calcium imaging, electrophysiology, optogenetics)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Competence in quantitative data analysis and scientific programming&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Proficiency in English&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Beneficial qualifications:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Practical experience with rodents (e.g., stereotactic surgeries, behavioral experiments)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;The best environment for neuroscience in Germany:
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;LMU Munich is often ranked as the best university in Germany and is consistently ranked among the top 50 universities worldwide, both overall and for life sciences specifically&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;According to the Nature Index, LMU Munich is the top academic institution in Germany for neuroscience&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Advanced neuroscience research with cutting-edge tools in state-of-the-art facilities&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Collaborative and inclusive environment, including partnerships with leading local institutions (e.g., Max Planck Institutes, DZNE, Helmholtz Institutes, TU Munich) all connected via the Munich Center for Neurosciences&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Mentorship and career development support from Prof. Dr. Schroeder, a young and highly motivated PI who is genuinely invested in the success of her team members&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Opportunity to live in Munich, a vibrant, international city near lakes and mountains with one of the world&#39;s strongest neuroscience communities and a high quality of life&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Remuneration according to the collective agreement for the public service of the federal states (TV-L) in &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;E13&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lmu.de/en/about-lmu/working-at-lmu/additional-services/corporate-benefits/&quot;&amp;gt;In addition, you can benefit from the various LMU corporate benefits&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Applications must provide the following and can be sent to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:anna.schroeder@bio.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;Prof. Dr. Schroeder&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; by e-mail:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cover letter detailing prior research experience, future career goals and why you’d like to join the Schroeder lab&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;CV&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Names and contact details for two or three referees&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A copy of a publication (or pre-print) you authored&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/045968231fd156fd29a97912586041d15a6a9e1a0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/045968231fd156fd29a97912586041d15a6a9e1a0</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 11:36:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-Doc - Biophysical characterization of intercellular adhesion (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Medicine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-03-31T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We, the group around the W2 professorship for anatomy and intercellular adhesion, focus on research in the regulation of desmosomal adhesion in the skin. We dedicate our work to the characterization of desmosomal adhesion using biophysical techniques and investigate mechanisms that contribute to loss of intercellular adhesion in the bullous autoimmune disease pemphigus. With this, we would like to contribute to a more concise understanding of how desmosomes adhere while we aim to identify novel therapeutic approaches to treat desmosomal diseases. For our team we search for an enthusiastic and highly motivated researcher (m/f/d).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For more insights into our research focus, please also visit our &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ls1.anatomie.med.uni-muenchen.de/forschung/ag_vielmuth/index.html&quot;&amp;gt;homepage&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;University degree in medicine (human medicine/ animal medicine/ dentistry) or life sciences with subsequently a doctoral degree&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Strong commitment to basic science and interest in teaching anatomy&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Communication skills in German and English&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;You are a team player and work structured and precise&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Beneficial: professional experience in the above mentioned research techniques/ teaching&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Beneficial: experience in scientific writing&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Motivated team of the Anatomische Anstalt, LMU, Lehrstuhl 1 (Campus Innenstadt)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Access to modern research techniques (confocal and STED microscopy, AFM, STED-AFM, TEM, …)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fascinating research in the field of desmosomal adhesion&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Excellent opportunities for career development with the possibility to be trained as Fachanatom/Fachanatomin of Anatomische Gesellschaft/ Facharzt/Fachärztin für Anatomie (m/f/d)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Compatibility of family and research (e.g. family service of LMU)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Employee benefits of LMU such as retirement plan, workplace health promotion and job-ticket for public services&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Our institute is located in the city center of Munich and is embedded in the excellent research environment of LMU with outstanding methodological facilities and a plethora of opportunities for advanced training and professional career development.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Women are encouraged to apply.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We look forward to your application by e-mail (motivation letter, CV, certificates) to:  &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Anne.Kustermann@med.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;Anne.Kustermann@med.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Prof. Franziska Hartig-Vielmuth&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Anatomische Anstalt – Lehrstuhl 1&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Pettenkoferstraße 11&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
80336 München&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Further questions can be directed to: Prof. Franziska Hartig-Vielmuth, phone: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;tel:089218072700&quot;&amp;gt;+49 89 2180 72700&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; or e-mail: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:franziska.vielmuth@med.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;Franziska.Vielmuth@med.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/4b4f16db5ce2b0d512640161ab01e1252fbddfd30</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/4b4f16db5ce2b0d512640161ab01e1252fbddfd30</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 10:39:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Research Associate (Pre- or Postdoc), DFG Project &quot;Sound Art History&quot; with Focus on the Middle Ages (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of History and the Arts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-03T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Art History Department at LMU Munich is one of the largest art historical teaching and research institutions in the German-speaking world, covering periods from the Middle Ages to the present. Research focuses include European, North American, and Islamic art, as well as questions of their global interconnections. The Art History Department at LMU hosts several major third-party funded projects. It cooperates closely with the Central Institute for Art History Munich and other art and cultural institutions in Munich and beyond.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The DFG-funded project (directed by Prof. Dr. Joanna Olchawa) is dedicated, on the one hand, to the study of European pulpits in the triadic understanding of seeing, hearing, and speaking, and on the other hand, aims to establish a new methodological approach, a &#39;Sound Art History&#39;. This includes analyses of audiovisual interdependencies, as well as medialization strategies of the voice and other sounds (including music, noises, signals). This art historical approach should - beyond pulpits - be opened up for other applications and groups of works, and increase the visibility of art historical research within interdisciplinary Sound History / Sound Studies.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Requirements include a completed university degree (MA) in art history, outstanding scientific potential, high communicative and social competencies, as well as organizational and teamwork skills.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The position is classified as &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lff.bayern.de/themen/arbeitnehmer/entgelttabellen/&quot;&amp;gt;TV-L E13&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. We offer an interesting and responsible workplace with good further education and development opportunities.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can expect exciting and varied work in a collegial environment with flat hierarchies and regular exchange, appreciation, and a friendly and productive working atmosphere.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Your workplace is centrally located in Munich and is easily accessible by public transportation.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will have full access to the GraduateCenter of LMU with a wide range of qualification offers and support in the form of individual counseling and coaching. Additional benefits include:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Mobile working&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Flexible working hours&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Support with childcare (e.g., holiday and emergency care services)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Health promotion offers&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Opportunity to purchase a job ticket (discounted use of public transport)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;LMU Munich is an equal opportunity employer and committed to enhancing the diversity of its faculty.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please send your detailed application documents (motivation letter, CV, list of publications if applicable, copies of certificates), a writing sample (e.g., a chapter of your master&#39;s thesis or a publication), and an exposé of your planned project (max. 5 pages) &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;by April 3, 2025 at the latest&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; (exclusively one PDF, max. 5 MB) to: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joanna.olchawa@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;joanna.olchawa@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
School of Arts&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Department of Art History&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Prof. Dr. Joanna Olchawa&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Zentnerstr. 31&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
D - 80798 Munich&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The applicant who is shortlisted will be invited to an (online) interview. The selection interviews are expected to take place &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;in the second week of April 2025 (CW 15)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;. If you have any questions, please contact Prof. Dr. Joanna Olchawa (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joanna.olchawa@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;joanna.olchawa@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/790e3e7e66cac9d9ae7264e9ff118597db197e880</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/790e3e7e66cac9d9ae7264e9ff118597db197e880</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 13:21:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Funded Doctoral Position in Anthropology (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Languages and Literatures&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-03-31T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;MA in anthropology or a related discipline;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fluency in English, with strong English writing skills;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Ability to work well in a team;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experience conducting ethnographic fieldwork;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Commitment to conduct 12 months of fieldwork, as well as shorter follow-up visits (funds for travel and field expenses are available).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Preferred Qualifications&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Prior field experience in one of the locations under study or similar ones;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experience working with children or families;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experience conducting video ethnography;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Proficiency in a relevant local language;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Background in linguistic and/or psychological anthropology.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The RCC is one of the largest center for advanced study in the environmental humanities in the world and hosts numerous international scholars. Its working language is English. The RCC offers an attractive compensation package, based on the tariff contracts for public service (65% of level &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;E13&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, commensurate with experience) and 30 days paid vacation. Working hours are flexible, and the RCC offers a family-friendly working environment. The RCC may also assist, if necessary, with work permits and visas. As the candidate will be a state employee, they are required to have German health insurance and make contributions to the German tax and social welfare system.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Inquiries prior to the application deadline can be directed to: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:changingchildhoods@carsoncenter.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;changingchildhoods@carsoncenter.lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;To apply, please submit your application, including the following documents compiled into a single PDF file, to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jobs@rcc.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;jobs@rcc.lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;by 31 March 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A cover letter/letter of motivation (max. two pages), including a statement about current and past research interests and how they may be relevant to the project&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A short CV (max. two pages)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Copies of university degree(s)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A writing-sample, such as a final thesis or other single-authored text (term paper, peer-reviewed article, book chapter, etc.)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Contact information of two references&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Applicants who wish to apply to conduct ethnographic research at a location that is distinct from the two field sites mentioned should also submit a brief description of their proposed site, detailing how it meets the abovementioned criteria.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Interviews will take place in the second week of April via Zoom. We welcome applications from qualified individuals with disabilities, people of diverse backgrounds, and gender identities. We are particularly interested in candidates from the communities or regions envisioned in this study. We may also be able to support individual doctoral projects related to the research described above through applications to separate funding mechanisms. Please &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:changingchildhoods@carsoncenter.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;e-mail us&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:changingchildhoods@carsoncenter.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;changingchildhoods@carsoncenter.lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;) to discuss.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/1dea733e232470bbef16415de328e9bc73173a7b0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/1dea733e232470bbef16415de328e9bc73173a7b0</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 05:35:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Research fellow (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Business Administration - Munich School of Management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-05-15T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;At the Chair of Digital Services and Sustainability, we research digital innovation and sustainable business. Our aim is to harness the potential of new technologies such as artificial intelligence, digital platforms, blockchain and the metaverse for companies. We create knowledge that works - and bring it into practice, politics and society. With a clear focus on digitalization, management and responsibility, we are actively shaping the future.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Enthusiastic about economic and technical developments and contexts in the digital economy&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Excellent analytical and conceptual skills in combination with openness, critical and structured thinking and creativity&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Motivation for top international research&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;(Very) well completed Master&#39;s degree at university level in the fields of economics, business informatics, industrial engineering, economics, computer science or related disciplines&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Very good written and spoken English&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Independent, results-driven and self-structured&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;High level of team and communication skills, as well as social competence.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Varied and exciting range of activities in research and teaching projects&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Inspiring working environment through intensive exchange and collaboration with companies and leading international scientists&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Excellent preparation for a career in science or practice&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Individual and structured support&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Diverse personal development opportunities and early personal responsibility&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Great potential for personal initiative, creative work and the acquisition of new knowledge and skills&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Participation in training programs and conferences around the world&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Integration into an agile, ambitious and research-oriented team&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Attractive, flexible and pleasant working environment in a central Munich location.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please e-mail your application documents (cover letter, CV, copy of academic degrees) in &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;one pdf file (max. 5MB)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; by &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;15.05.2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; to: Tina Flemmerer (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dss@som.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;dss@som.lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Questions can be directed to Prof. Dr. Johann Kranz (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kranz@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;kranz@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/7def4d07ed5054009333bd33b532ea798a2eb1810</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/7def4d07ed5054009333bd33b532ea798a2eb1810</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 13:29:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Researcher and lecturer in the field of energy science (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Geosciences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-03-31T21:59:59+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Department of Geography of the LMU is a globally recognized institution with innovative approaches in sustainability science. There, the newly established chair for physical geography and nexus research assesses the complex interactions between water security, food production, energy security and nature. Our group develops knowledge and tools to understand, monitor, and simulate the behaviour, features and evolution of the nexus as a complex system. In this framework, we have designed an area devoted to energy security and sustainable energy.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Master degree in Geography, Geosciences, Energy Science, Energy Technics, Renewable Energy, Engineering in Electrotechnics, or similar&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Willingness to learn and further develop the model &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geo.lmu.de/geographie/de/forschung/physische-geographie-und-nexusforschung/forschung/lpjml/&quot;&amp;gt;LPJmL&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; as well as analysing modelling outputs&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A high level of competence in oral and written English&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Post-doc experience, experience in interdisciplinary work and PhD degree are a plus&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Structured and goal-oriented thinking&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Creativity and openness to new approaches&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Reliability and a high level of motivation&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Willingness to travel for work (project meetings, workshops etc.)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Capacity for teamwork and excellent communication skills, including the willingness to build a productive scientific network.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;It is a &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;E13 TV-L&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; position with a possibility to do a habilitation (German qualification as university lecturer). This is organized for three years and its prolongation for three more years after positive evaluation and fulfilment of official requirements.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A stimulating working environment in a dynamic team&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Working in an interdisciplinary milieu, focusing on questions relevant for society, economics and politics&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Personal development through the LMU qualification program&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Support in relocating to Munich through the&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lmu.de/en/about-lmu/working-at-lmu/additional-services/lmu-gateway/&quot;&amp;gt; LMU Gateway&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; service&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Support for child care (for example emergency care, holiday programme)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Living in one of the most prosperous cities in Germany, Munich, with beautiful landscapes nearby and numerous cultural, sport and leisure events&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Workplace health promotion&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Theater and culture: special events, discounts and vouchers&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Mobility: job tickets and discounted membership with Share Now (car sharing).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We seek to increase the share of women in scientific positions and therefore explicitly encourages women to apply.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please fill in the &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.geographie-muenchen.de/en/job-application/researcher-energy-nexus/&quot;&amp;gt;application template&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;before March 31st 2025.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
For questions regarding the application please contact Prof. Dr. Marianela Fader: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:M.fader@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;M.fader@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/d64567ed05db324daf8900db84960a22a056be1c0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/d64567ed05db324daf8900db84960a22a056be1c0</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 13:50:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Researcher (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Social Sciences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-06T21:59:59+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;An excellent dissertation in the area of party research and/or electoral politics broadly defined (completed or close to completion).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Advanced skills in quantitative data analysis.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experience in the design and implementation of cross-country (qualitative or quantitative) content analyses.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Excellent organizational skills and the ability to work independently and in teams.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fluency in English and (at least) high proficiency in Spanish. &amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Prior experience of working in cross-national, comparative projects is desirable.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please submit the following (in English):&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cover letter that explains why you want to work in the project and what qualifies you for the post&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;CV&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Diplomas&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;One single-authored paper or chapter (published or not) that displays methods skills relevant to the project&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Contact data for two referees (referees will be contacted only at the interview stage).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Pay is based on &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;TV-L, Entgeltgruppe E 13&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. The workload is 40,1 hours a week.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;The post ought to be filled no later than 1 October 2025 and is restricted to a duration of 2.5 years (probation six months).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;Your workplace will be in the center of Munich and is well connected through public transport. The application of women is encouraged.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;submission deadline is&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;6 April 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;. Please submit your application per e-mail (in one single PDF file, max. 5MB) to: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sekretariat.bolleyer@gsi.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;sekretariat.bolleyer@gsi.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität Munich&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Chair for Comparative Political Science, Ms. Zwerger&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Interviews are planned to take place in Munich on the 14 and 15 of May 2025.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you have any questions, please get in touch with Prof. Dr. Nicole Bolleyer: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:n.bolleyer@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;n.bolleyer@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; or PD Dr. Martin Gross: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:martin.gross@gsi.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;martin.gross@gsi.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/13590f501364d17edca97e5fdfec84041ad9ee100</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/13590f501364d17edca97e5fdfec84041ad9ee100</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 11:14:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Research fellow for ecosystem-climate interactions (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Geosciences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-06T21:59:59+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Chair for Physical Geography and Land Use Systems (Prof. Julia Pongratz) at LMU’s Department of Geography investigates the interactions between humans, ecosystems and climate. Our group develops and applies the latest generation of carbon cycle, land surface and climate models and integrates them with Earth observations. We investigate the fate of ecosystems under the pressures of land-use and climate change; Earth system feedbacks that emerge through energy, water and biogeochemical cycles; and the role that vegetation and soils can play for greenhouse gas emissions reduction and CO2 removals in support of the Paris Agreement. The team is strongly involved in large national and international collaborations such as the &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://globalcarbonbudget.org/&quot;&amp;gt;Global Carbon Project&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipcc.ch/assessment-report/ar6/&quot;&amp;gt;IPCC&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://cdrterra.de/en&quot;&amp;gt;CDRterra&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and several Horizon Europe projects such as &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://rescue-climate.eu/&quot;&amp;gt;Rescue&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forestnavigator.eu&quot;&amp;gt;ForestNavigator&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.climate-tipping-points.eu&quot;&amp;gt;ClimTip&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;You hold a Ph.D., or will soon finish your Ph.D., in a natural science subject (geography, environmental science, physics or similar).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a track record of effectively communicating research results (appropriate to career stage)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;good programming skills (such as python or R)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;very good communication skills in English (our working language)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;ability to teach – eventually in German – in the study programs of the Department of Geography.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;the opportunity to be part of a dynamic, internationally connected team working at the forefront of Earth system science&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;E13 TV-L position&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, commensurate with work experience, for three years with the possibility to extend to a maximum of six years, based on performance, and to acquire a postdoctoral lecturer qualification (“Habilitation”)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;career development through the LMU qualification program&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a stimulating working environment at one of Germany’s top-ranked universities. Our institute is located in the heart of the vibrant and internationally diverse city of Munich with excellent public transportation links.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;organizational assistance from the LMU Gateway service for relocation to Munich.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please send an application outlining your fit for the position (including a cover letter sketching out your ideas in at least one of the topics mentioned above, a CV, copies of scientific degrees, and the names and contact information of two references) by e-mail (one PDF-attachment with max. 5MB including all documents) with &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;subject &amp;amp;quot;ecosys-2025LMU&amp;amp;quot;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:climate.jobs@geographie.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;climate.jobs@geographie.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Applications received prior to April 6, 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, will receive full consideration, but the position will remain open until filled.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The starting date is negotiable between May and August 2025. For further information please contact Prof. Dr. Julia Pongratz (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:julia.pongratz@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;julia.pongratz@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/9f89107ce2bf333f5571be8c07b4878f648e1a570</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/9f89107ce2bf333f5571be8c07b4878f648e1a570</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 16:15:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Postdoctoral researcher for terrestrial carbon cycle modeling (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Geosciences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-06T21:59:59+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Chair for Physical Geography and Land Use Systems (Prof. Julia Pongratz) at LMU’s Department of Geography investigates the interactions between humans, ecosystems and climate. Our group develops and applies the latest generation of carbon cycle and climate models and integrates them with Earth observations. In support of the EU&#39;s climate and sustainability targets we open a position in the Horizon Europe project &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/101184989&quot;&amp;gt;NextGenCarbon&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. NextGenCarbon will develop a novel framework to improve our understanding and quantification of greenhouse gas budgets, incorporating enhanced ecosystem data, advanced modeling, scenario predictions, and climate policy support. This way, substantial knowledge gaps impeding predictive capabilities and the ability to evaluate the EU&#39;s climate policy targets will be closed. A core component will be delivering more accurate estimates of CO2 emissions and removals related to land-use activities, which play a crucial role in the annual &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://globalcarbonbudget.org/&quot;&amp;gt;Global Carbon Budgets&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and are increasingly important for cross-validating national greenhouse gas budgets.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;You hold a Ph.D., or will soon finish your Ph.D., in a natural science subject (geography, environmental science, physics or similar).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a track record of effectively communicating research results (appropriate to career stage)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;good programming skills (such as Python or R)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;very good communication skills in English (our working language).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;the opportunity to be part of a dynamic, internationally connected team working at the forefront of Earth system science&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;E13 TV-L position&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, commensurate with work experience, for three and a half years&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;career development through the LMU qualification program. To support career development, some teaching at the Department of Geography can be arranged.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a stimulating working environment at one of Germany’s top-ranked universities. Our institute is located in the heart of the vibrant and internationally diverse city of Munich with excellent public transportation links.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;organizational assistance from the LMU Gateway service for relocation to Munich.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please send an application outlining your fit for the position (including a cover letter sketching out your ideas in at least one of the topics mentioned above, a CV, copies of scientific degrees, and the names and contact information of two references) by e-mail (one PDF-attachment with max. 5MB including all documents) with &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;subject &amp;amp;quot;NextGenC-2025LMU&amp;amp;quot;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:climate.jobs@geographie.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;climate.jobs@geographie.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Applications received prior to April 6, 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;, will receive full consideration, but the position will remain open until filled.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The starting date is negotiable. For further information please contact Prof. Dr. Julia Pongratz (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:julia.pongratz@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;julia.pongratz@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/6be893b57ba4de35308581a2d767ddb080c1f1280</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/6be893b57ba4de35308581a2d767ddb080c1f1280</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:37:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctoral researcher (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty for the Study of Culture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-01T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The ERC-funded project &amp;amp;quot;Buddhism’s Early Spread to Tibet&amp;amp;quot; (BEST), led by Prof. Dr. Jonathan A. Silk and based in the Institute of Indology and Tibetology at the Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität Munich (LMU), is advertising two PhD positions, for a period of 4 years. The Institute is a major hub of learning and research in the fields of Indian and Tibetan Studies. With five professors and over twenty members, it boasts a broad expertise in the languages, literatures, religions and philosophies of South Asia and Tibet, and works closely with colleagues in Sinology. Doctoral students working for the project will further be integrated within the cross-faculty and interdisciplinary Doctoral Programme in Buddhist Studies.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;You have an excellent MA (completed, or to be complete by the beginning of your tenure at LMU) in a relevant field, which may include, but is not necessarily limited to, Buddhist Studies, Tibetology and/or Sinology (Classical China).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;You have a high level of knowledge in Classical Tibetan and/or Classical Chinese, and a good familiarity with pre-modern Buddhism.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;For non-native speakers, proof of a high-level knowledge of spoken and written English is required. A writing sample (MA thesis or other academic writing) in English must be submitted with the application.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;After passing our first round of evaluations, you will be asked to respond to the full BEST project proposal (to be provided) with a written statement of how you see your place in the project.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This will be followed by an online interview.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Your workplace will be in the center of Munich and is well connected through public transport.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;You will be paid a salary, at the payscale 0.65 fte of &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://oeffentlicher-dienst.info/c/t/rechner/tv-l/allg?id=tv-l-2025&amp;amp;amp;matrix=1&quot;&amp;gt;TV-L E13&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. For one explanation of this scheme, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://fastepo.com/phd-and-postdocs-salary/phd-students-and-postdocs-salary-germany/&quot;&amp;gt;see here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;LMU has signed the “Charter of Diversity” and is committed to the diversity of its employees. We actively promote equality between women and men.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;More information on the Family Service of LMU can be found &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lmu.de/en/about-lmu/working-at-lmu/additional-services/diversity/being-family-friendly/family-service/index.html&quot;&amp;gt;here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;,&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please submit the following in English:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cover letter explaining your motivation to do your PhD embedded in the BEST project (max. two pages). See below for a short outline of the project.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;CV&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A writing sample (MA thesis or other academic writing) in English. If this is not available, indicate this with your application, along with the reason for its absence.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Copies of your diploma(s), including BA; if MA is not yet awarded, include a letter from your supervisor certifying the expected date of degree conferal.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Contact data for two referees (who will be contacted only at the interview stage). Combine all of these items into one PDF file with the file name as YOUR FAMILY NAME_Your Given Name_the date (eg: SILK_Jonathan_29 January 2025).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Applications should be submitted by &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;1 April 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;E-mail the application to: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sekretariat.indologie@lrz.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;sekretariat.indologie@lrz.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Indicate in the subject line of the e-mail: BEST PhD application&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Your tenure in the position should begin preferably by 1 October 2025 Although a later date is possible, employment must begin on or before 1 January 2026.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For more information, contact Prof. dr. Silk: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Jonathan.Silk@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;Jonathan.Silk@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The BEST project in outline:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Modern scholarship follows emic accounts in situating the origins of Tibetan Buddhism squarely in India, tacitly accepting Tibet’s claim to be heir to the orthodox tradition. This oversimplifies the complex history of Buddhism’s two transmissions to Tibet, in the 7th and 11th centuries, eliding the formative early contributions of Sinitic sources, principally impart-ed from the Silk Road oasis of Dunhuang, a crucial locus of interaction between Tibetan and Chinese cultures in the 8th-11th centuries. Manuscripts preserved in the Dunhuang caves evi-dence this Sino-Tibetan nexus in native compositions and translations from Chinese into Ti-betan. Efforts to trace Chinese and Sino-Tibetan influences on the formation of Tibetan Bud-dhism have been largely impressionistic, but state-of-the-art tools such as Handwritten Text Recognition to digitize manuscripts allow their systematic analysis, and others permit us to identify “fingerprints” of Tibetan translations from Chinese. BEST will locate scriptures and other materials of Sinitic origin, and trace their impact on Tibetan Buddhism. Starting with an examination of the reasons for the prominence of Dunhuang, we will uncover the conditions permitting the site to become such a multicultural center, cradle to a high level of Buddhist scholarship. Identifying Sinitic sources introduced into Tibet in the early period, we will probe their later importance, challenging the tradition&#39;s polemical historiography which re-presses such recognition. We will produce studies of individual Tibetan translations from Chi-nese, linguistic studies of the Chinese-Tibetan lexical interface, studies on the most prominent Dunhuang monk-translator, Chos grub, investigations of later Tibetan historiographical works, and a database of Tibetan Dunhuang manuscripts, all contributing to a fundamental revaluation of formative influences on early Tibetan Buddhism.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/b2e78f7a2ec0c3c24fa0403d77e3608d64849f360</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/b2e78f7a2ec0c3c24fa0403d77e3608d64849f360</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 10:51:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Assistant Professorships (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Social Sciences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; BesGr A13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-03-21T22:59:59+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Chair of Empirical Political Research and Policy Analysis (Prof. Dr. Paul W. Thurner) at LMU Munich&#39;s &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.en.gsi.uni-muenchen.de/index.html&quot;&amp;gt;Geschwister-Scholl-Institute of Political Science&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is advertising, with possible start dates of &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;1 October 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;1 April 2026&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; two (2) positions of&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;An excellent dissertation related to quantitative political science methods (Methods &amp;amp;amp; IR or Comparative Politics), completed or close to completion.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Skills to teach multivariate methods in R, special methods skills in one or more specific areas (e.g. NLP, Machine Learning, Causal Designs etc.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Research interests related to &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.en.gsi.uni-muenchen.de/chairs/analysis/index.html&quot;&amp;gt;research interests of the chair&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (conflict studies, electoral research, survey research etc.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Publication in peer-reviewed journals or strong indications of the potential to place publications competitively.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fluency in English. Good German skills are desirable.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Excellent organizational skills and the ability to work independently and in teams.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Pay is based on, Entgeltgruppe A13, “BeamtIn auf Zeit”.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;The posts ought to be filled by 1 October 2025 and 1 April 2026 and is restricted to a duration of 3 years (probation 6 months). The positions can be extended for 1-2 more years.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;The Geschwister-Scholl-Institute of Political Science (GSI) is one of the most renowned political science institutes across Europe.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Your workplace will be centrally located in Munich and can be easily reached by public transport.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;More information on the Family Service of LMU can be found &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lmu.de/en/about-lmu/working-at-lmu/additional-services/diversity/being-family-friendly/family-service/index.html&quot;&amp;gt;here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;LMU has signed the &amp;amp;quot;Charter of Diversity&amp;amp;quot; and is committed to the diversity of its employees. We therefore actively promote equality between women and men.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please submit the following (in English):&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cover letter&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;CV&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Diplomas&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Contact data for two referees (referees will be contacted only at the interview stage)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;One writing sample of an article or a chapter representative of your research agenda (preferably single-authored)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The submission deadline &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;is 21 March 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;. Please submit your application per Email (in one PDF, max. 10MB) to&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität Munich&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.en.gsi.uni-muenchen.de/chairs/analysis/index.html&quot;&amp;gt;Empirical Political Research and Policy Analysis&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Ms. Hopp, &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sekretariat.thurner@gsi.uni-muenchen.de&quot;&amp;gt;sekretariat.thurner@gsi.uni-muenchen.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/8cb3725922012073eb43835dabcf2806353cebd10</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/8cb3725922012073eb43835dabcf2806353cebd10</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:07:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>PhD student position for the study of human ion channels using cryo-electron microscopy (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Medicine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-30T21:59:00+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.med.lmu.de/wsi/en/workgroups/neuberger-lab/&quot;&amp;gt;Our lab&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; is based at the Walther Straub Institute of Pharmacology &amp;amp;amp; Toxicology, right in the center of Munich. The institute belongs to the Faculty of Medicine of LMU Munich.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Our lab at LMU Munich has openings for prospective PhD students.  Join us to study ion channel structure and function using a combination of cryo-electron microscopy and other biophysical methods. We are looking for hard-working scientists to join our lab – ideally with prior experience in mammalian cell culture work, molecular biology, protein biochemistry and/or structural biology (of any sort).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We are a newly established lab with easy access to any needed cryo-EM preparation tool (provided by our lab) as well as to cryo-EM screening (on our lab&#39;s own cryo-TEM) and collection facilities (short public transport ride away). Live in one of&amp;nbsp;Europe&#39;s most vibrant cities whilst&amp;nbsp;conducting research at the top-ranked university&amp;nbsp;in Germany (ARWU Shanghai Ranking 2024). The compensation is based on TV-L group 13 (see also &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tdl-online.de/fileadmin/downloads/TV-L/TV-L_Anlagen/Allgemeine_Entgelttabelle__Anlage_B___g%C3%BCltig_ab_01.12.2022.pdf&quot;&amp;gt;Entgelttabelle des Tarifvertrags der Länder&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, with levels to be determined based on applicant’s expertise).&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For a quick overview of the PI’s previous work:  &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7744-6559&quot;&amp;gt;ORCID.org&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;  and  &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&amp;amp;amp;user=ZufZ4T0AAAAJ&amp;amp;amp;view_op=list_works&amp;amp;amp;sortby=pubdate&quot;&amp;gt;Google Scholar&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Happy to answer any questions.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Deadline for applications is &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;April 30th, 2025&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;; however, &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;applications are being reviewed on a rolling basis&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Interested candidates should submit a CV, motivation letter, and contact details of at least two referees to&amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:neuberger@lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;neuberger@lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Incomplete applications will not be considered.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/cdfc7de0f67a1cc152ad7ed0ad61e7ed2bb557d10</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/cdfc7de0f67a1cc152ad7ed0ad61e7ed2bb557d10</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:08:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctoral researcher/ Ph.D. student (m/f/x)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Faculty of Medicine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remuneration:&lt;/strong&gt; TV-L E13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-04-30T21:59:12+00:00&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your qualifications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;We are seeking a highly motivated young researcher, who would like to perform a Ph.D. thesis in an interdisciplinary and international environment. We anticipate applicants with an excellent previous scientific training, very good communication skills, and the ability to work independently and as part of a team. We offer an excellent research environment, access to a wide variety of techniques, and the possibility to participate in the structured graduate program of MvPI and LMU, including focused lectures, seminars, and skills courses.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Applicants with a completed undergraduate degree (Master or equivalent) in the life sciences, biomedical or natural sciences will be considered.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experience in microbiology, ideally human pathogens, molecular biology/biochemical methods and bioinformatics skills will all be beneficial for successfully conducting the project, but can also be acquired as part of the PhD project.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The position will be available from May 2025 or later at the &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mvp.uni-muenchen.de/en/&quot;&amp;gt;Max von Pettenkofer Institute&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; (located in Munich city center).We offer an excellent research environment, access to a wide variety of techniques, and the possibility to participate in the structured graduate program of MvPI and LMU, including focused lectures, seminars, and skills courses.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Detailed information about the Max von Pettenkofer Institute, the PhD program, and the Suerbaum lab are available &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mvp.uni-muenchen.de/en/&quot;&amp;gt;online&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. Applications should be submitted, if possible, as one single pdf file not exceeding 10 MB.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Please e-mail your complete application documents, including your CV and complete transcripts of records, letter of motivation, and two references to: &amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:PhD.Infection@mvp.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;++PhD.Infection@mvp.lmu.de++&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Max von Pettenkofer Institute&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Ludwig Maximilians-Universität München&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Lehrstuhl, Medizinische Mikrobiologie und Hygiene&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Pettenkoferstr. 9a&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
80336 München&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For specific scientific questions, please contact Prof. Dr. Sebastian Suerbaum (&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:suerbaum@mvp.lmu.de&quot;&amp;gt;suerbaum@mvp.lmu.de&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/5a4b4c811f2c84cff90a49983dae1615c6dc536b0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://job-portal.lmu.de/jobposting/5a4b4c811f2c84cff90a49983dae1615c6dc536b0</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:14:20 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>