<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0"><channel><title>Gist Latest Articles</title><link>https://grist.org/articles</link><atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:1200/grist" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Latest Articles on grist.org - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:34:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Power companies would rather not clean their toxic messes. Trump’s EPA is granting their wish.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On January 15, a group of utility companies wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/policy-regulation/power-companies-pressure-trump-epa-to-roll-back-rules-on-toxic-coal-ash&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; to Lee Zeldin, then president-elect Donald Trump’s nominee to lead the Environmental Protection Agency. “We provide the electricity for millions of homes, businesses, and institutions across the U.S., create thousands of good-paying jobs, and drive economic progress and American prosperity,” the letter stated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;After the polite opening, they got right to their main request: “Two matters in particular call for immediate action: (1) regulations on greenhouse gas (‘GHG’) emissions from existing coal-fired and new natural-gas power plants that mandate a carbon capture technology that has not been adequately demonstrated and (2) the unprecedented expansion of the federal regulation of coal combustion residuals (‘CCR’).”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The companies contend that the federal government has overstepped its authority in its enforcement of these two areas of regulation. The letter asked Zeldin to go easy on them — by delivering the regulatory authority back to states and rescinding a 2024 rule that mandated cleanup of coal ash at inactive power plants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;What the power companies call “coal combustion residuals,” and describe as “a natural byproduct of generating electricity with coal … used for beneficial purposes in U.S. construction and manufacturing,” is known more colloquially as coal ash — a toxic mixture of heavy metals like arsenic and mercury, which, because coal plants are usually built near bodies of water, often comes in contact with groundwater when it is buried in an unlined pit. Over the last &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=62444&quot;&gt;century and a half&lt;/a&gt; of American coal power generation, power companies have dumped coal ash at hundreds of active and inactive power plants &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthjustice.org/feature/coal-ash-map-sites-legacy-inactive-regulated&quot;&gt;across the country&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/caught-off-guard-epa-proposes-to-fire-hundreds-of-scientists/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;EPA Administrator Lee Zeldin&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1599w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=1536%2C865&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1599&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/caught-off-guard-epa-proposes-to-fire-hundreds-of-scientists/&quot;&gt;‘Caught off guard’: EPA proposes to fire hundreds of scientists&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/naveena-sadasivam/&quot;&gt;Naveena Sadasivam&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;       &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/tik-root/&quot;&gt;Tik Root&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Zeldin is now the administrator of the EPA, and it appears the power companies are getting their wish. Amid a barrage of press releases that, on March 12, proposed 31 deregulatory actions, were two that seem designed to significantly weaken enforcement of coal ash regulations, environmental attorneys told Grist.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Zeldin called it “the greatest day of deregulation our nation has seen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the first, the EPA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-announces-swift-actions-coal-ash-program-coal-combustion-residuals&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it will encourage states to take over permitting and enforcement of the coal ash rule. When states are delegated the authority by the EPA to issue their own coal ash disposal permits, they are supposed to adhere to standards at least as stringent as the federal rules, but in some cases state environmental agencies have simply gone rogue and flouted this requirement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Georgia, which received the authority to issue its own permits for coal ash disposal in 2019, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/georgia-psc/georgias-coal-ash-cleanup-controversies-explained/&quot;&gt;controversially approved plans&lt;/a&gt; at several coal plants for the utility Georgia Power to permanently store millions of tons of coal ash in unlined landfills that are partially submerged in groundwater, despite being notified by EPA that this violates the federal rule. In neighboring Alabama, state regulators sought the same delegated authority that their counterparts in Georgia had been granted, but last year the EPA &lt;a href=&quot;https://insideclimatenews.org/news/23052024/epa-denies-alabama-coal-ash-waste-plan/&quot;&gt;denied their application&lt;/a&gt; because they planned to issue permits to Alabama Power that violated the federal rules &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gpb.org/news/2023/08/25/feds-rejected-alabamas-toxic-waste-disposal-plan-what-means-for-georgias-coal-ash&quot;&gt;in the same manner&lt;/a&gt; as Georgia’s.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Alabama’s was the first application for a state-run coal ash program that the EPA has denied; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/coalash/permit-programs-coal-combustion-residual-disposal-units&quot;&gt;so far&lt;/a&gt;, only Georgia, Texas, and Oklahoma have been approved. But new approvals may be coming soon: “EPA will propose a determination on the North Dakota permit program within the next 60 days,” the release said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The EPA also said it would be “reviewing” a rule it finalized in 2024, under President Joe Biden, that &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/regulation/epa-closes-coal-ash-loophole/&quot;&gt;closed a long-standing loophole&lt;/a&gt; by extending coal ash regulations to cover so-called “legacy” coal ash ponds at shuttered power plants — which weren’t covered by a landmark 2015 rule that regulated coal ash disposal only at power plants in active use.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The EPA’s review of the 2024 legacy coal ash rule will focus on whether to extend the deadlines for compliance with the rule. Lisa Evans, senior counsel at Earthjustice, said the time frames in the rule as written were already far more lenient than was necessary. “Industry already got major concessions from the Biden EPA to establish deadlines that are far in the future,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Because coal ash’s peak contamination levels aren’t reached until some 70 years after waste is dumped, longer deadlines can only mean less effective cleanup. “The longer you ignore those sites, the worse the pollution gets,” Evans said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the second announcement related to coal ash, the EPA said it will revise a list of its top enforcement priorities that was announced in 2023 and applied to the fiscal years 2024 through 2027. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/enforcement/national-enforcement-and-compliance-initiatives&quot;&gt;The list&lt;/a&gt; of National Enforcement and Compliance Initiatives, or NECI, included six “priority areas” for action, one of which was&amp;nbsp;“Protecting Communities from Coal Ash Contamination.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The EPA now intends to “align” the agency’s enforcement priorities with President Trump’s executive orders. It said this would be accomplished by “immediately” revising the NECI list “to ensure that enforcement does not discriminate based on race and socioeconomic status (as it has under environmental justice initiatives) or shut down energy production and that it focuses on the most pressing health and safety issues.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;No further details were provided regarding what this meant for the agency’s actual enforcement actions. But a fuller picture is found in an internal agency memo, which was sent by Jeffrey Hall, the acting head of the agency’s enforcement and compliance division. The memo, seen by Grist, outlines the ways in which the NECI list was to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Hall’s memo said that the priorities are under review “to ensure alignment between the NECIs and the Administration’s directives and priorities,” and it laid out a series of directions that applied “in the interim” to all EPA enforcement and compliance actions. These include a blanket directive that “environmental justice considerations shall no longer inform EPA’s enforcement and compliance assurance work” and another declaring that “enforcement and compliance assurance actions shall not shut down any stage of energy production (from exploration to distribution) or power generation absent an imminent and substantial threat to human health or an express statutory or regulatory requirement to the contrary.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;With respect to coal ash, the memo argues that the NECI priority list “focuses in large part on perceived noncompliance with current performance standards and monitoring and testing requirements and is motivated largely by environmental justice considerations, which are inconsistent with the President’s Executive Orders and the Administrator’s Initiative.” Accordingly, the memo stipulates that “enforcement and compliance assurance for coal ash at active power plant facilities shall focus on imminent threats to human health.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Due to the wording of the memo, Evans said in an email that “it would be entirely possible for EPA to justify avoiding any enforcement whatsoever of the coal ash rule under the NECI.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This would be a dramatic reversal of the heightened enforcement that ramped up under the Biden administration. In 2024 — the first year of the coal ash NECI priority —&amp;nbsp;the EPA conducted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/enforcement/national-enforcement-and-compliance-initiative-protecting-communities-coal-ash&quot;&gt;107 compliance assessments&lt;/a&gt; of coal ash sites across 18 states. While only five enforcement cases (orders or agreements by which EPA requires companies to take certain actions) were filed in that year, Evans said it is likely that EPA will find reason for enforcement action at many of the other sites if the investigations are allowed to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Evans said the requirement that enforcement only take place in cases of an imminent threat to human health effectively restricts the agency from enforcing aspects of the coal ash rule designed to “prevent ‘imminent threats’ by requiring proper management and monitoring of toxic waste sites before damage and spills occur.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For instance, Evans said, the directive would prohibit the EPA from requiring a utility to repair a faulty groundwater monitoring system. “Utilities have gamed the system at some plants by designing monitoring systems that intentionally miss detecting leakage from a coal ash dump,” she said, citing a 2022 &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthjustice.org/press/2022/new-report-most-power-plants-violating-federal-rules-mandating-cleanup-of-toxic-coal-ash-dumps&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by Earthjustice and the Environmental Integrity Project that alleged a widespread practice among power companies of manipulating monitoring data to downplay the extent of contamination.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Power companies are supposed to dig wells to assess the groundwater quality at coal ash dumps, and in order to gauge their contamination level they compare it to what should be uncontaminated water samples nearby. But the 2022 report documented examples like coal plants in Texas, Indiana, and Florida where the EPA found that the “background” wells used for the purpose of providing baseline samples of water quality were dug in contaminated areas near the coal ash dump. The report also documented the practice of “intrawell” monitoring, or simply analyzing the data from each well in isolation, in order to assess changes in contamination levels over time, rather than contrasted with uncontaminated wells. This method doesn’t work unless the wells aren’t contaminated to begin with, and is prohibited by EPA guidelines — but the report found it was in use at 108 coal plants nationwide.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;These practices could essentially be given a free pass under the new enforcement guidance.&amp;nbsp; “While these are very significant violations (because contamination is not discovered and cleanup not triggered), they may not rise to an ‘imminent threat,’ especially if there are no data revealing toxic releases,” Evans said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The section of the memo dealing with coal ash also stipulated that “any order or other enforcement action that would unduly burden or significantly disrupt power generation” requires “advance approval” from the assistant administrator of the Office of Enforcement and Compliance Assurance — the politically appointed position temporarily being held by Hall.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The memo justifies this requirement on the basis of the Trump administration’s stated intention of “unleashing American energy.” But to Nick Torrey, a senior attorney at the Southern Environmental Law Center, it has little to do with energy production —&amp;nbsp;and more to do with utilities’ bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“There’s nothing about cleaning up coal ash that affects power generation; those are two separate activities,” Torrey noted. “So what it sounds like is they’re prioritizing polluters’ interests over people’s drinking water.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/health/coal-ash-epa-lee-zeldin-trump/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/health/coal-ash-epa-lee-zeldin-trump/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Gautama Mehta</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/AP22011575725673-e1742591076437.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Health</category><category>Regulation</category></item><item><title>Environmentalists in Israel and Palestine fight to save cross-border water resources</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Wadi Gaza is the estuary of Nahal Besor, a stream mentioned in the Bible. It flows west from Hebron in the West Bank, through Israeli territory and on through Gaza into the Mediterranean Sea. Today, after 18 months of war, Wadi Gaza is characterized by “pollution from debris, wastewater, corpses, ammunition, and explosives,” in the words of Nada Majdalani, the Palestinian director of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ecopeaceme.org/&quot;&gt;EcoPeace Middle East&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Nevertheless, spring is still the migration&lt;a href=&quot;https://whc.unesco.org/en/tentativelists/5722/&quot;&gt; season&lt;/a&gt; in Israel and Palestine. This region forms a narrow land bridge joining Europe, Asia, and Africa, marking one of the world’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://allisrael.com/the-great-migration-israel-is-a-crossroads-for-500-million-birds-annually&quot;&gt;busiest flight paths&lt;/a&gt; for an estimated 500 million birds. Many of them — flamingos, herons, storks, cranes — land in Wadi Gaza, one of the few natural preserves in the Gaza Strip, which grew into one of the most densely populated areas in the world over the last two decades because of Israeli restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGazaGetty2-1244567219.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;White birds against greenery near a body of water.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Birds seen in the Gaza valley in 2022. Migration season in Israel and Palestine can draw millions of bird, many landing near the Wadi Gaza.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ahmed Zakot / SOPA Images / LightRocket via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Birds seen in the Gaza valley in 2022. Migration season in Israel and Palestine can draw millions of bird, many landing near the Wadi Gaza.
 &lt;cite&gt;Ahmed Zakot / SOPA Images / LightRocket via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This is the driest region in the world for the number of people it supports, and water scarcity is getting worse because it’s also warming around twice as fast as the global average. Eighty percent of Israel’s drinking water comes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eib.org/en/essays/wastewater-resource-recovery&quot;&gt;ocean desalination&lt;/a&gt;. In Gaza, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arava.org/caed/environmental-humanitarian-impacts-gaza-war/&quot;&gt;seawater intrusion&lt;/a&gt; has contaminated once-abundant underground reservoirs because of overpumping. While Israel and other powers in the region continue to practice resource hoarding and ecological destruction, there is also a small, stubborn movement of transboundary environmentalist peacebuilders, who have persisted throughout the current war.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Organizations like EcoPeace, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arava.org/&quot;&gt;Arava Institute for Environmental Studies&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alandforall.org/english/?d=ltr&quot;&gt;A Land For All&lt;/a&gt; — all three with shared Palestinian and Israeli leadership — have been working collectively for decades toward a vision that centers fair, shared stewardship of natural resources and sustainable development as the basis of lasting peace. And they persevere even now, after Israel violated a several-week ceasefire in March with another round of bombings, killings, and cutting off of aid to Gaza, and when the prevailing political messaging, according to Arava’s Barak Talmor, “has gotten so polarized that cultivating empathy or sympathy between the sides is increasingly challenging.”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Water-based environmental and health risks travel across borders, just like Nahal Besor. Yasmeen Abu Fraiha, an Israeli citizen and doctor of Palestinian descent, advises A Land For All, a political group that advocates for a two-state confederation. She was working at a hospital in southern Israel in the first few months of the war. There, she treated Israeli soldiers suffering from dysentery and rare fungal infections attributable to drinking the water in Gaza. “In Israel and Palestine, what we see is that our lives are so intertwined with each other,” she said. “The health of Palestinians affects the health of Israelis and vice versa. And the best example is water.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1082 1082w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1443 1443w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gaza_Damage_972.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A 2024 map showing proximity of water infrastructure to damage sites in Gaza&quot; data-caption=&quot;A 2024 map showing proximity of water infrastructure to damage sites in Gaza
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Elaine Donderer / Arava Institute for Environmental Studies&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A 2024 map showing proximity of water infrastructure to damage sites in Gaza
 &lt;cite&gt;Elaine Donderer / Arava Institute for Environmental Studies&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This fact can sometimes force compromise. The environmental nonprofit EcoPeace Middle East was able to leverage the health-water connection to bring modern wastewater treatment to Gaza before the war. EcoPeace had Israeli beaches tested just north of Gaza, and found e.coli contamination in the sand. A technician at the lab also tipped them off that untreated solid waste from Gaza was clogging and shutting down an Israeli desalination facility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“[Prime Minister Benjamin] Netanyahu himself quoted one of our reports in a statement in 2014, saying that if the sewage crisis of Gaza threatens Israel’s water security, we have to deal with it,” said Gidon Bromberg, EcoPeace’s Israeli co-founder and co-director. Four plants ultimately opened in Gaza by 2022, enabling Gazans and Israelis alike to more safely swim in the ocean; they sustained severe damage during the war.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Even after the October 7 attack of Hamas on Israel, Bromberg said, they were able to invoke the same principle of shared health destiny after Israel shut off the three water pipes supplying Gaza’s highest-quality drinking water. EcoPeace got leading Israeli public health experts to sign a letter saying, “You’re going to see lots of disease, and it’s not going to just stop in Gaza.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“That was very effective,” he said. “It broadens the zero-sum thinking into an understanding that this is lose-lose.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Within the first week, one drinking water pipeline was reopened, and eventually all three. (More recently, in March 2025, Israel cut power to two of Gaza’s desalination plants, once again imposing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2025-03-13/ty-article/.premium/israels-power-cutoff-will-cut-gaza-water-supply-drastically/00000195-8bf4-dfff-afbd-ebf4d8cb0000&quot;&gt;water scarcity&lt;/a&gt; as a weapon; EcoPeace is responding by lobbying the government).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gazainlinebromberg.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;a man in glasses standing next to a wall of documents&quot; data-caption=&quot;Gidon Bromberg of EcoPeace Middle East in his office in Tel Aviv. As environmentalists, he said, “We’re all coming from a technical position where we strongly understand that borders are man-made.”
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Anya Kamentz / Grist&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Gidon Bromberg of EcoPeace Middle East in his office in Tel Aviv. As environmentalists, he said, “We’re all coming from a technical position where we strongly understand that borders are man-made.”
 &lt;cite&gt;Anya Kamentz / Grist&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The environmental situation today in Gaza is worse than ever. The war has left an estimated 40 million tons of rubble and 900,000 tons of toxic waste from demolished buildings in Gaza, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://arava.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Environmental-Humanitarian-Impacts-of-War-in-Gaza_reduced.pdf&quot;&gt;recent report&lt;/a&gt; from the Arava Institute; not to mention, once again, a growing amount of raw sewage. The World Health Organization warns that infectious disease, arising from water scarcity, could kill more Gazan people than Israeli bombs, and researchers are concerned about new strains of antibiotic-resistant bacteria that thrive where soap and water washing is scarce.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Barak Talmor is the project manager of Arava Institute’s Jumpstarting Hope in Gaza project, one attempt to respond to these conditions. The educational and research institute, in its first foray into direct humanitarian aid, raised money and convened a coalition to bring some of the off-grid sustainable technologies developed there and elsewhere into Gaza. These include Laguna, a solar-powered water treatment unit the size of a large dumpster that uses algae to filter sewage; WaterGen, machines that pull potable water out of the air; off-grid desalination units, and a biodigester that turns sewage gas into cooking gas. These were designated to supply a refugee camp in Khan Younis and a hospital. But approval took months, and the donated equipment is currently sitting in warehouses and at the border thanks to yet another stop on aid. “If I have any gray hair, it’s from the past year,” Talmor said.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Despite these harsh realities, members of EcoPeace, Arava, and A Land For All say that their shared commitment to sustainability has enabled them to keep cross-border relationships strong. This is itself a challenge when any hint of “normalization” or Israeli-Palestinian dialogue is denigrated by what Bromberg calls “spoilers” on both sides.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Abdullah Khateeb is part of a new generation of Palestinian environmentalist peacebuilders, and he said it’s a lonely path, especially since the war. “I cannot tell my family that I’m meeting Israelis. I cannot tell the Israeli people that my community wants to throw you to the sea. It’s kind of living two lives, basically, and you have to hide it perfectly in order to survive.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/the-future-of-gazas-recovery-may-rely-on-solar-power/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Palestinians walk by a solar panel, used by some to produce electricity in the refugee camps in Rafah.&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/the-future-of-gazas-recovery-may-rely-on-solar-power/&quot;&gt;The future of Gaza’s recovery may rely on solar power&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/saqib-rahim/&quot;&gt;Saqib Rahim&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Khateeb had never left the West Bank three years ago when he was accepted for a semester at Arava Institute, studying environmental science in the south of Israel alongside fellow Palestinians, Israeli, and Jordanian students. He said he applied solely to get past the checkpoints and see a little more of the world. “I didn’t care about the environment, about peace, about anything like that. Arava attracted me with the free food, the swimming pool. And once I was there, miracles happened.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Khateeb, by chance, recognized one of his Israeli classmates. She had once been a soldier guarding his village. Through the Arava Institute’s moderated weekly dialogue sessions, they listened to each others’ experiences and forged a friendship. Now, he’s traveled to Northern Ireland and to England to engage in dialogue alongside Israeli peace activists. And after earning degrees in civil and water engineering, he now interns with Laguna, which has two of its off-grid sewage treatment units installed in the West Bank. He’s working on better methods for converting the solids into cooking gas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Water apartheid” is visible here in the West Bank in the storage tanks seen only on Palestinian roofs; they are forced to purchase drinking water, while nearby Israelis in illegal settlements copiously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2017/10/21/how-israel-engages-in-water-apartheid&quot;&gt;irrigate&lt;/a&gt; their crops. &amp;nbsp; For Khateeb, “Peacebuilding is not only about dialogue. It’s also political, financial, educational, and technological. That’s why I work on water and environment. It offers opportunities. Everyone likes new innovations.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Bromberg, an attorney, founded EcoPeace alongside Jordanian, Egyptian, and Palestinian environmentalists in the mid-1990s. Back then, their plan was to team up to prevent rapid overdevelopment that was expected in the wake of the Oslo Accords bringing peace and with it, increased tourism to the region. Needless to say, that did not come to pass, and EcoPeace’s mission pivoted from pursuing environmentalism post-peace, to modeling peace through environmentalism. (The Egyptians pulled out in the late 1990s under pressure from President Hosni Mubarak.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As environmentalists, he said, “We’re all coming from a technical position where we strongly understand that borders are man-made. We have to look at watersheds and water basins. There, borders just get in the way.” During the second Intifada in the early 2000s, they launched the Good Water Neighbors project. Ultimately, 28 communities on either side of rivers and streams in Israel, Gaza, the West Bank, and Jordan, cooperated in campaigns to preserve the bodies of water that both divided and united them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/international/project-prosperity-israel-war-gaza-landmark-mideast-climate-deal/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=330%2C220&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1067&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/international/project-prosperity-israel-war-gaza-landmark-mideast-climate-deal/&quot;&gt;How Israel’s war on Gaza unraveled a landmark Mideast climate deal&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/saqib-rahim/&quot;&gt;Saqib Rahim&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;After October 7, Bromberg and his counterparts in Jordan and Palestine made a pact to talk every day, to combat the misinformation that was inundating all sides. “We had staff in all of our offices lose family members in the war. One of our Ramallah staff lost 100 members of his extended family.” he said. They also lost a colleague in Gaza, a consultant. “It’s been a nightmare.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;One that has recently resumed. “Every day you open your eyes, and you wonder whether you’re on the right track or not,” said Nada Majdalani, the Palestinian director of EcoPeace. “But then we confront ourselves with — if this is not the way to do it, then what else? We don’t accept the status quo. And we need to bring out a different narrative to each other. What we all really want for us and for our children in the future is peace and stability.” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;What keeps her going, she said, are the thousands of students, teachers, young professionals, and other stakeholders that are “walking the path” alongside them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Their educational programs are more popular than ever. And all three EcoPeace directors were in Washington, D.C. in a March meeting with the State Department and members of Congress about sustainable development plans for a railway, expanded renewable energy, and a new Gaza port.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We share the understanding that this war will end and we all have a responsibility to ensure we stop the suffering,” said Bromberg. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While she doesn’t like many of the statements of the Trump administration in relation to Gaza, Majdalani said, “The important part is not to shut down the opportunity for communication. But try to find an opening where we can actually put on the table ideas which bring interest to all parties.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/international/environmentalists-in-israel-and-palestine-fight-to-save-cross-border-water-resources/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/international/environmentalists-in-israel-and-palestine-fight-to-save-cross-border-water-resources/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Anya Kamenetz</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WadiGaza1.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Health</category><category>International</category><category>Oceans</category><category>Politics</category><category>Solutions</category></item><item><title>The Trump administration’s climate policies jeopardize research in disaster-prone Puerto Rico</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Professor Maritza Barreto Orta had planned to complete two federal funding applications crucial for her research on coastal erosion in Puerto Rico. However, these funding opportunities “disappeared” from the websites of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) due to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/putting-america-first-in-international-environmental-agreements/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;new policies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;imposed by U.S. President Donald Trump. These policies limit funding for&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/feb/21/trump-scientific-research-climate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;academic research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Research on sea level rise, coastal erosion, coral bleaching, renewable energy, heatwaves, climate-related diseases like dengue, and extreme weather events like hurricanes is at risk under Trump’s climate policies, which have withdrawn the United States from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/putting-america-first-in-international-environmental-agreements/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Paris Agreement&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and international climate financing plans. Studies examining the climate’s influence on cancer rates in Puerto Rico are also jeopardized.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://periodismoinvestigativo.com/2025/02/puerto-rico-climate-crisis-impact-report/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico ranks sixth&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;among the countries most affected by the climate crisis, according to the latest Climate Risk Index published by the international organization&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.germanwatch.org/en/93013&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Germanwatch&lt;/a&gt;. This index measures the impact of extreme weather, climate, and hydrological events on people and the economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In line with Trump’s executive orders, the National Institutes of Health (NIH) have begun mass cancellations of research grants, cutting funding to active scientific projects that “do not align with the agency’s priorities.” These cuts target studies focused on environmental justice, climate change, transgender populations, gender identity, diversity, equity, and inclusion, as well as any research perceived as discriminatory based on race or ethnicity, according to a report by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-00703-1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;magazine in early March.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico currently has&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reporter.nih.gov/search/mdLqDVZkdESc7AiHgaYs8A/projects?org=PONCE%20SCHOOL%20OF%20MEDICINE;UNIVERSIDAD%20CENTRAL%20DEL%20CARIBE;GRUPO%20NEXOS%20INC.;LIFEGENE-BIOMARKS,%20INC.;INTER%20AMERICAN%20UNIVERSITY/PUERTO%20RICO;SAN%20JUAN%20BAUTISTA%20SCHOOL%20OF%20MEDICINE;SISTEMA%20UNIVERSITARIO%20ANA%20G.%20MENDEZ,%20INCORPORADO;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO%20MED%20SCIENCES;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO%20RIO%20PIEDRAS;COMPREHENSIVE%20CANCER%20CENTER/%20UNIV/PR;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO%20MAYAGUEZ;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO%20AT%20AGUADILLA;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PR%20CAYEY%20UNIVERSITY%20COLL;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO%20AT%20HUMACAO;UNIVERSITY%20OF%20PUERTO%20RICO%20PONCE&amp;amp;states=PR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;107&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;active NIH-funded grants totaling $78.5 million. Of these, 91 (85 percent) are led by University of Puerto Rico (UPR) scientists, while&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reporter.nih.gov/search/mdLqDVZkdESc7AiHgaYs8A/projects?org=PONCE%20SCHOOL%20OF%20MEDICINE;UNIVERSIDAD%20CENTRAL%20DEL%20CARIBE;GRUPO%20NEXOS%20INC.;LIFEGENE-BIOMARKS,%20INC.;INTER%20AMERICAN%20UNIVERSITY/PUERTO%20RICO;SAN%20JUAN%20BAUTISTA%20SCHOOL%20OF%20MEDICINE;SISTEMA%20UNIVERSITARIO%20ANA%20G.%20MENDEZ,%20INCORPORADO&amp;amp;states=PR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;are housed at private institutions, though none of the latter focus on climate and health intersections.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/21-05-07-Erosion-Costera-Elevada-Yabucoa-18-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Coastal erosion has led to the loss of infrastructure, as seen on this beach in Yabucoa.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Nahira Montcourt / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Coastal erosion has led to the loss of infrastructure, as seen on this beach in Yabucoa.
 &lt;cite&gt;Nahira Montcourt / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Coastal Research and Planning Institute (CoRePI), led by Barreto Orta, is affiliated with the UPR’s School of Planning at the Río Piedras campus. Amid funding cuts to the university, the professor and her team rely on federal grants to conduct their studies and keep CoRePI operational. With current resources, the institute can operate only until April 2026 unless it secures new funding to continue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Barreto Orta acknowledged that “the opportunity to seek more external funding has diminished.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Currently, CoRePI has two main active projects, one funded by the United States Geological Survey (USGS) amounting to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upr.edu/subvencion-de-2-442-millones-para-la-upr-rp-para-ganar-tiempo-contra-el-mar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;$2.4 million&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to assess erosion in coastal municipalities, and another&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uprrp.edu/2024/12/relanzamiento-del-instituto-de-investigacion-y-planificacion-costera-de-puerto-rico-adscrito-a-la-escuela-graduada-de-planificacion/&quot;&gt;$500,000&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;project funded by CDBG grants from the Department of Housing, aimed at training for coastal erosion studies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;According to a survey done by the&amp;nbsp; NOOA in 2006, Puerto Rico has an estimated 700 miles of coastline (1,126 kilometers).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Our last project will conclude in April 2026, and I’m unsure where I’ll be able to submit new proposals to keep the center running, which not only evaluates the state of coastal erosion but also provides mentorship and funding to students,” Barreto Orta explained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53%E2%80%AFPM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-1.38.53 PM.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A chart showing NIH research funds for Puerto Rico&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot; data-credit=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Scientists from the public university system interviewed by the Centro de Periodismo Investigativo (CPI) said this uncertainty about the immediate future of climate crisis research in Puerto Rico has spread among UPR researchers, warning that these measures halt the search for solutions to face and anticipate natural disasters by limiting students’ academic training.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Studies on renewable energy, agriculture, and planning are also faltering. At the Río Piedras campus, professors Jorge Colón Rivera, from the Chemistry Department, and José Hernández Ayala, from the School of Planning, are also battling the avalanche of restrictions imposed by the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Colón Rivera leads research on renewable energy, an essential field for Puerto Rico’s energy future, while Hernández Ayala studies the effects of heat waves on the island’s schools. Both fear their projects will be cut short if they cannot secure grants to continue their studies in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Colón Rivera said the U.S. Department of Energy removed all information related to the Reaching a New Energy Sciences Workforce (RENEW) program from its website, from which funds for studies conducted in collaboration with researchers from UPR in Humacao, Ana G. Méndez University, and Cornell University in New York originate. The chemist expressed concern about potential program cancellations that support research on finding renewable solutions for generating electricity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Colón Rivera is part of four active investigations: two with grants from the National Science Foundation (NSF) and two with RENEW funds from the U.S. Department of Energy, exploring how solar energy can “generate green hydrogen, a clean and renewable fuel.” The four grants total $43.6 million distributed among all institutions collaborating on the studies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;He added that the program would not only be affected by its focus on identifying renewable energy sources but also because it sought to support institutions serving underrepresented communities in the sciences. Another of Trump’s policies, in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-illegal-discrimination-and-restoring-merit-based-opportunity/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of January 21, seeks to cancel all federal government diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) programs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=779&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/3-DIA-CPI-2254-1170x779-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Executive orders by President Donald Trump threaten the research at the Coastal Research and Planning Institute led by Professor Maritza Barreto Orta.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;José E. Rodríguez / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Executive orders by President Donald Trump threaten the research at the Coastal Research and Planning Institute led by Professor Maritza Barreto Orta.
 &lt;cite&gt;José E. Rodríguez / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We are concerned that there may not be as many programs to fund climate science proposals, and perhaps programs will be eliminated. In the case of renewable energy, we worry that when we renew proposals, we may no longer be attractive for having students from an area of the population that is not the typical one participating in other programs,” he noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The UPR has ongoing research evaluating the environment from various academic perspectives and receiving federal funds from the NIH, NOAA, NSF, USGS, NASA, and CDBG funds awarded by the U.S. Department of Housing, among others.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The interim president of the UPR, Miguel Muñoz, told the CPI that the university administration has not received official notifications about the closure of any of these studies. However, he acknowledged that they have faced instability issues on some federal agency websites, limiting the possibility for some researchers to submit their progress reports.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We have found that, on some occasions, the website or the agency’s page where the researcher has to submit their progress reports was closed one week, but the next week it opened, and the researcher could submit their progress reports. That continuity has been maintained, with very rare exceptions of one or two proposals (studies) where we have not been able to establish that contact, but we are hopeful that everything will normalize,” Muñoz said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;He could not specify which agencies or specific researchers he was referring to.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Amid the uncertainty about the future of their research, Hernández Ayala expressed concern that his investigation might stagnate because it focuses on climate change topics. A few weeks ago, he submitted a pre-proposal to the NSF to study the impact of heat on Puerto Rico’s public schools day to day operations, and although he was told his topic was promising and suggested which call for proposals he could apply to, he now fears the proposal will not be approved.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fiona-001-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A blue house and car sit in floodwaters&quot; data-caption=&quot;According to the latest Climate Risk Index, Puerto Rico ranks sixth among the jurisdictions most affected by the climate crisis.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ricardo Arduengo / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;According to the latest Climate Risk Index, Puerto Rico ranks sixth among the jurisdictions most affected by the climate crisis.
 &lt;cite&gt;Ricardo Arduengo / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Of the $&lt;a href=&quot;https://nsf-gov-resources.nsf.gov/files/puerto_rico_factsheet.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;26.6 million&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;the NSF has awarded in Puerto Rico in fiscal year 2023, $18.6 million (70 percent) was awarded to the UPR. In its latest update on how Trump’s executive orders are being implemented, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/executive-orders&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;NSF&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;indicated that it maintains the agency’s usual practices focused on “evaluating the merit of the proposals they are considering” without ignoring federal standards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The review criteria remain consistent. Guidance on reviews and panel summaries has not changed. Program directors do not comment on activities outside of the purview of the panel. The reviews and panel summaries are advisory to NSF. As has always been the practice at NSF, we will consider this advisory material in conjunction with agency-wide guidance and applicable federal standards when making funding decisions,” the agency states on its website.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At the University of Puerto Rico, Mayagüez Campus (known as RUM), agricultural economics professor Héctor Tavárez faces the possibility of not being able to access funds from the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) for his studies on sustainable and resilient agricultural practices because his work includes the term “climate change,” which contradicts the public policy decreed by Trump.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Many of the proposals we fill out are to directly or indirectly address climate change. We are quite concerned that in the future, they will tell us: ‘no, this proposal is not authorized’ or ‘this proposal is not a priority.’ When just a year ago, it was precisely the type of proposal with the highest priority for the [federal] government,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Tavárez, like other researchers, fears that the restriction on research addressing climate change and its impact will lead to the loss of this type of agricultural study.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=731&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/PREM-1-Grupo-de-estudiantes-participantes-de-proyecto-investigativo-NSF-PREM-UPR-Recinto-de-Rio-Piedras-Featured-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;The National Science Foundation is one of the scientific entities that could see its research work diminished due to the Trump administration’s denial of climate change reality.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy photo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The National Science Foundation is one of the scientific entities that could see its research work diminished due to the Trump administration’s denial of climate change reality.
 &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy photo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Imagine running an agricultural research project on eggplant or coffee, only to have your funding suddenly frozen. We aren’t necessarily talking about future projects, but projects that are running. If you receive a budget cut because the study has to do with climate change, it’s not that the project is altered for a while, it’s that it is basically destroyed because we’re working with living beings,” warned the professor, who between 2022 and 2024 obtained $479,355 from three USDA grants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA suspended more than $100 million in grants to the University of Maine in March, which was put under investigation by the Trump administration for not complying with the president’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;prohibiting the participation of girls and transgender women in women’s sports. The cancellation of funds occurred after the state’s governor, Janet Mills, had a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/mundo/articles/cly2g5de2ywo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;confrontation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with Trump at the White House in February when the president threatened to withdraw funds from the Maine government if they did not comply with the executive orders related to gender.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA also canceled a $10,000 grant this semester to the Inter American University, Barranquitas Campus, intended to train 100 Puerto Rican farmers in “climate-smart” agricultural practices, according to Rector Juan Negrón. “The main idea of the project was to improve food production, and in this case, it focused on the necessity of considering environmental conditions when practicing agriculture,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Negrón noted that the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) also canceled the evaluation of a proposal submitted to access $10 million for an environmental justice project in the communities of Orocovis. This project would have included analyses of river pollution in the area and community adaptation to disasters such as hurricanes. Researchers from the Mayagüez Campus and the University of Puerto Rico, Río Piedras Campus, were also set to participate in the project, the biochemist explained.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Trump’s public policy against climate change also wreaks havoc at UPR in Humacao, where the U.S. Forest Service put on hold a funding request submitted by the Transdisciplinary Institute for Research and Social Action (ITIAS, in Spanish) of the Department of Social Sciences to create a community climate justice network in eastern Puerto Rico, environmental sociologist Alejandro Torres Abreu claimed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/FIONA-LOIZA-26-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Ongoing research in Puerto Rico on renewable energy could also be affected.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;José Reyes / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ongoing research in Puerto Rico on renewable energy could also be affected.
 &lt;cite&gt;José Reyes / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Torres Abreu said the proposal would allow ITIAS to access $300,000 from the U.S. Forest Service, complemented by $500,000 from the UPR program Sea Grant Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Due to Trump’s policy, federal agencies like the U.S. Forest Service comply with that policy, and since [the funding request] was under evaluation and the agency had not signed it, the process was halted until it is clarified what will happen and what the guidelines are regarding those funding processes. So, it affects me because of the way I planned the project’s development,” said Torres Abreu, who directed ITIAS from 2016 to 2023.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-anticipating-a-gag-on-scientific-innovation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anticipating a “gag” on scientific innovation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The elimination of scientific research calls for proposals and the penalization of investigations that include terms like “climate change,” “race,” “diversity,” or “climate justice” could generate self-censorship and disinterest among researchers in submitting proposals for federal funds or even preferring to focus on other lines of research to avoid the pressure imposed by Trump, warned Professor Manuel Valdés Pizzini, director of the Interdisciplinary Center for Coastal Studies (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uprm.edu/cienciassociales/ciel/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;CIEL&lt;/a&gt;, in Spanish) established 19 years ago at the RUM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s a gag on innovation, integrity, and creativity in the scientific community,” he stated.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Valdés Pizzini is part of the Puerto Rico Adapted Flood Maps research project conducted by the Graduate School of Planning at the Río Piedras campus, in collaboration with the federal Sea Grant Puerto Rico Program and CIEL, with a $750,000 NOAA grant valid until 2027.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Presidente-UPR-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A man in a cap and gown stands at a podium&quot; data-caption=&quot;Miguel Muñoz Muñoz, interim president of the University of Puerto Rico.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Photo taken from Facebook&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Miguel Muñoz Muñoz, interim president of the University of Puerto Rico.
 &lt;cite&gt;Photo taken from Facebook&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Projects related to observing how the ocean behaves, if they are subject to cuts, we will no longer have that important data. An entire scientific component would be eliminated, which also has an educational component because we do all these projects to train a whole new crop of researchers. We will lose an entire cadre of people who will not enter these fields because there are no funds to work on research,” warned Valdés Pizzini.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For climatologist Rafael Méndez Tejeda, a physics professor at UPR in Carolina, climate research will also be limited by cuts,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/us/memo-says-mass-layoffs-veterans-affairs-will-begin-early-june-2025-03-09/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;layoffs&lt;/a&gt;, and censorship experienced by federal agencies like NOAA in their operations, as the agencies will no longer have the capacity to collect information and data consulted by other scientists.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Regardless of whether they don’t affect us yet, research will be limited because the executive orders are penalizing agencies like NOAA, FEMA, or NASA, which generate databases. If we have fewer people generating databases, and if [for example] we don’t have data from NOAA’s buoys and satellites, our research will be affected,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Meteorologist Ada Monzón warned that the National Weather Service (NWS), which is under NOAA, would not be launching “radiosonde” instruments with the usual frequency due to “staff limitations” in its offices. “These instruments provide information on the atmosphere’s vertical profile and are the data that feed the models meteorologists use to make forecasts,” Monzón explained in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1NGxXcNxLH/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Hector-S-Tavarez-Vargas-UPRM-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 960w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Héctor S. Tavárez Vargas, professor of the Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology at the College of Agricultural Sciences at UPR Mayagüez campus.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy photo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Héctor S. Tavárez Vargas, professor of the Department of Agricultural Economics and Rural Sociology at the College of Agricultural Sciences at UPR Mayagüez campus.
 &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy photo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;However, meteorologist Ernesto Morales from the NWS assured that the services that the agency provides for data collection and dissemination, at least in Puerto Rico, remain unchanged for now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“There is a restructuring of the agency, and it’s not clear what will happen, but what is known is that services and the ways we collect information through satellites, weather stations, or radars will not be affected in the short term as part of this restructuring,” he told the CPI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Trump administration has cut&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/27/politics/noaa-federal-workers-firings/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;at least 800 positions at NOAA&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;at the central level, including critical duties at the National Hurricane Center and the Storm Prediction Center, as well as cuts at the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Climate Prediction Center&lt;/a&gt;, which, among other things, provides critical weather data across&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/products/international/africa/africa.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and tracks the El Niño-La Niña phenomenon, as well as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov/#page=ovw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Weather Prediction Center&lt;/a&gt;, focused on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wpc.ncep.noaa.gov/international/intl2.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;South America&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opinions clash over “adjustment” of language in research proposals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Among the researchers that the CPI interviewed, there are differing opinions about adjusting the language of their research proposals to dodge Trump’s restrictive policies on climate change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Some, like Professor Tavárez from the RUM, consider modifying terms like “climate change” or “global warming” in their funding applications a necessary strategy to secure federal funding and move projects forward, while others argue that preserving the language is the way to maintain scientific integrity and honesty in their project proposals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Unfortunately, writing the words ‘climate change,’ ‘global warming,’ and ‘gender equity’ puts me at a disadvantage. Even if I feel uncomfortable and think it’s not ethically correct, I will have to do it [omit those words] because I think they wouldn’t approve the proposals,” said the agricultural economics professor.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image alignfull js-breaks-column&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Jardines-Metropolitanos-1Rio-Piedras-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Rainfall floods are becoming more powerful and damaging, but climate change research will be limited by cuts, layoffs, and censorship in federal agencies.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Gabriel López Albarrán / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Rainfall floods are becoming more powerful and damaging, but climate change research will be limited by cuts, layoffs, and censorship in federal agencies.
 &lt;cite&gt;Gabriel López Albarrán / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The director of Sea Grant in Puerto Rico, Ruperto Chaparro, also agrees with adjusting the language to evade funding limitations. He said the focus in proposal writing should prioritize the impacts caused by the environment, such as floods or heatwaves, and not on “umbrella” concepts like the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“There is a list of words that should not be used. Instead of talking about ‘climate change,’ you can talk about the impacts. You have to play the game and change the title and put something related that doesn’t mention those words. Here in Puerto Rico, we are used to the gag law because we are a (US) colony. When you learn to play the game, the outcome is what matters,” Chaparro said. Sea Grant operates with $2 million in funds awarded by NOAA, matched 50 percent by UPR.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Professor Pablo Méndez Lázaro, principal investigator of the Caribbean Climate Adaptation Network at the UPR Medical Sciences Campus, believes that other concepts like “climate oscillation” can be used if it becomes impossible to use the concept of climate change to apply for federal funds. The researcher is part of a study measuring the intersection between climate and cancer incidence in Puerto Rico with a $1.1 million NIH grant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Although Hernández Ayala acknowledged that this situation would lead to having to “dress up” proposals to try to move them forward, he positioned himself against omitting concepts because “they are not to the liking of the current administration.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“As a scientist, I cannot deny the reality of what we are experiencing globally and in Puerto Rico. I cannot deny climate change. No matter how much I want to say that extreme heat does not exist and is not related to climate change, it would be irresponsible of me to have to adjust my research just because this administration is uncomfortable with those words because they don’t align with their economic interests,” the planner said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Barreto Orta stood on the same side, stating that she will continue to use the term climate change in her studies and research proposals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Personally, I will continue working on the topic of climate change. Even if there are people who do not favor that approach, I will not hide something I know is true. I have a responsibility as a researcher, although I may have to change strategies to convey the messages,” she said, referring to focusing more on communicating how these situations will impact people’s quality of life, such as those who cannot insure their homes because they are in flood zones, rather than the impact on the habitat.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interim UPR president downplays the issue and its implications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The CPI learned from two separate sources that, at least in the UPR campuses of Río Piedras and Humacao, professors have been meeting to discuss how to address censorship by the Trump administration on academia, and according to the sources, there are positions for and against adjusting the language.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Although he sees no problem in adjusting the language of proposals to avoid funding cuts, the interim president of the UPR was not clear in saying whether that will be the university’s official stance on how to handle the public policy imposed by the Trump administration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Mendez-Tejeda-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Professor Rafael Méndez Tejeda said it is urgent for the university administration to take clear positions on the application of executive orders.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ricardo Rodríguez / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Professor Rafael Méndez Tejeda said it is urgent for the university administration to take clear positions on the application of executive orders.
 &lt;cite&gt;Ricardo Rodríguez / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“When a call for proposals comes, it comes with specific guidelines and objectives. Saying there is an ethical conflict because one changed a proposal title, I don’t see any conflict. That proposal goes to a committee of colleagues who evaluate them (…) I think it’s an issue that is exaggerated in how it manifests because you respond to a proposal call. If I had an ethical conflict in terms of submitting a proposal, the decision is up to the researcher not to submit it,” Muñoz noted.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In this scenario, Méndez Tejeda said it is urgent for the university administration to take clear positions on how Trump’s executive orders will be applied, as he said these measures will not only affect research in natural sciences but also because climate change directly affects society, studies looking at climate intersections with social sciences could also be reduced.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We are going back almost to the 60s or 70s if we continue with the limitation and censorship of a series of things that were already believed to be overcome. It’s censorship that will limit academia because if I can’t work on diversity, race, and inclusion topics, all those topics will be affected, not only in natural sciences but also in social sciences that will not be able to access proposals,” he warned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Barreto Orta pointed out that in the scenario promoted by Trump’s policies, denial of climate change will increase, and advances in ecological awareness generated among citizens will be rolled back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ernesto-002-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A man stands in boots in the street in muddy floodwaters&quot; data-caption=&quot;The National Weather Service could also be affected due to staff cuts at NOAA, particularly those working with instruments measuring atmospheric conditions.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ricardo Arduego / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The National Weather Service could also be affected due to staff cuts at NOAA, particularly those working with instruments measuring atmospheric conditions.
 &lt;cite&gt;Ricardo Arduego / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The scenario is bad because, even without Trump’s policies, coastal erosion was not accepted as a threat to people. In recent years, there have been some small changes, and we have seen progress. Here the question is what the universities’ stance on these new positions will be because scientists will not stop,” she concluded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;All the researchers interviewed told the CPI that they have not received any official communication from the university administration instructing them on the course to follow with research that would be contrary to federal government orders. They agree they don’t&amp;nbsp; know how the UPR will adopt Trump’s executive orders or what measures are being taken to identify funds that allow the institution and its research to continue operating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The interim president denied the lack of communication and said that in his first meeting with the rectors of the 11 campuses after taking office on February 18, one of the main instructions he gave was for professors to keep following the guidelines of federal agencies regarding Trump’s executive orders.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I was surprised by that comment because in my first meeting with all the rectors, this was one of the issues mentioned, and the rectors are constantly receiving those communications, and the researchers too. But since you bring up the issue, maybe what it tells me is that I have to reaffirm my instructions regarding that,” he told the CPI.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=780&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Chaparro-1-1170x780-min.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A balding man with a gray beard sits and listens&quot; data-caption=&quot;Ruperto Chaparro, director of Sea Grant in Puerto Rico.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ricardo Rodríguez / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ruperto Chaparro, director of Sea Grant in Puerto Rico.
 &lt;cite&gt;Ricardo Rodríguez / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In his first&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25562402-informe-presidente-interino-upr-27-feb-2025/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/live/_VtjWi0xZNM?si=8v8IWcMNLKDPPdxF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;UPR Board of Governors&lt;/a&gt;, Muñoz indicated that continuous follow-up is given to the guidelines and changes coming from federal agencies, but there is no specific process to notify the university community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Professor Colón Rivera, meanwhile, warned that “if these projects are canceled after being peer-reviewed and approved by the agencies, and they still have four, two, or one year to go, and suddenly the money is blocked, I would think that one way Puerto Rico can continue doing research and helping students is to find a way to complement with local government funds&amp;nbsp; And how can that be done? Either the Puerto Rico Government addresses it, or the Fiscal Control Board [JCF] must release the money it has taken from the UPR, or the Science and Technology Trust seeks to allocate something to prevent everything from falling apart. It would be disastrous for all research to fall apart.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Puerto Rico Science and Technology Trust did not respond to a request for comments from the CPI to learn if Trump’s restrictions have affected the research they conduct or the flow of funds..&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salt on the wound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The elimination of studies funded by federal funds for climate change research represents an additional challenge for UPR’s finances, which since 2017 has faced a 48 percent cut in its operating budget due to measures by the Fiscal Control Board (JCF).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The UPR also faces the possibility of losing another $5.4 million in health research funds if Trump’s proposal to limit up to 15 percent of funds for administrative and operational expenses of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://history.nih.gov/display/history/A+Short+History+of+the+National+Institutes+of+Health&quot;&gt;NIH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;grants is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/2024-04-12-Panel-1-Caribe-Fest-6.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Pablo A. Méndez Lázaro, professor and researcher at the UPR Medical Sciences Campus.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Brandon González Cruz / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Pablo A. Méndez Lázaro, professor and researcher at the UPR Medical Sciences Campus.
 &lt;cite&gt;Brandon González Cruz / Centro de Periodismo Investigativo&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The University expects early-career professors like me — this is my first year at UPR — to submit proposals and secure research funding, but now it’s tougher. From the University, we must think about how we can reduce dependence on these funds and make the University receive funds from the Puerto Rico government or other global or nonprofit entities again,” said Professor Hernández Ayala.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Amid this scenario, Muñoz said that although several forums demand the reinstatement of the formula applied by law, which granted 9.6 percent of the Puerto Rican Government’s General Fund to the University, this measure is not viable due to the fiscal crisis facing the Puerto Rican Government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The reality is that thinking they will reinstate the formula is not a feasible reality. We have to take measures with the budget we have, use it with the greatest effectiveness and efficiency, and comply with a university restructuring,” Muñoz said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story is made possible through a collaboration between the Centro de Periodismo Investigativo and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opencampus.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open Campus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This translation was generated with the assistance of AI and thoroughly reviewed by our editorial team to ensure accuracy and clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/extreme-weather/the-trump-administrations-climate-policies-jeopardize-research-in-disaster-prone-puerto-rico/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/extreme-weather/the-trump-administrations-climate-policies-jeopardize-research-in-disaster-prone-puerto-rico/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Víctor Rodríguez Velázquez, Centro de Periodismo Investigativo</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Portada-CPI-Fiona-Salinas.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Extreme Weather</category></item><item><title>Gutting clean energy incentives would drive up electric bills</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Trump administration insists that renewables are making energy more expensive and that more fossil-fueled power will reduce utility bills. But those claims are false — and if congressional Republicans succeed in repealing key tax credits supporting the growth of clean energy, Americans will suffer the consequences in higher electric bills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;So finds a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://energyinnovation.org/report/inflation-reduction-act-repeal-harms-state-economies-raises-consumer-costs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;report released Thursday&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by think tank Energy Innovation warning lawmakers of the costs of repealing the clean-energy tax credits created by the&amp;nbsp;2022&amp;nbsp;Inflation Reduction Act, the Biden administration’s signature climate law.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The fate of those tax credits&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/7262600/how-trump-is-trying-to-undo-the-inflation-reduction-act/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;remains highly uncertain&lt;/a&gt;. Some Republican lawmakers have voiced support for keeping them in place, but others have criticized the incentives, which could channel&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/policy-regulation/what-climate-law-tax-credits-will-be-in-and-out-under-trump-2-0&quot;&gt;hundreds of billions of dollars&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to solar and wind power, batteries, electric vehicles, and other carbon-free technologies over the next decade. President Donald Trump has also vowed to repeal the&amp;nbsp;IRA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Key members of the Trump administration have disparaged clean energy as a&amp;nbsp;wasteful distraction while praising fossil gas and coal. Last week at an industry event, Energy Secretary Chris Wright said wind and solar have&amp;nbsp;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/10/climate/energy-secretary-climate-change-fossil-fuels.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;obvious scale and cost problems&lt;/a&gt;,” and dismissed their prospects for serving more than a&amp;nbsp;fraction of the country’s power&amp;nbsp;needs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But Energy Innovation’s report repeats findings from a&amp;nbsp;series of studies over the past months that forecast major downsides to repealing the tax credits, including lost jobs, hundreds of billions of dollars of foregone investment — and significantly more expensive electricity for U.S. businesses and households.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Energy-Innovation-IRA-repeal-March-20-household-cost-increase-graph.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A bar chart showing rising annual energy costs per household&quot; data-caption=&quot;Energy Innovation projects that energy costs for U.S. households will rise if key IRA clean energy tax credits are repealed and other federal climate funding disappears.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Energy Innovation&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Energy Innovation projects that energy costs for U.S. households will rise if key IRA clean energy tax credits are repealed and other federal climate funding disappears.
 &lt;cite&gt;Energy Innovation&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We looked at a&amp;nbsp;state-by-state level at energy bills as well as jobs and economic growth,” said Robbie Orvis, Energy Innovation’s senior director of modeling and analysis.&amp;nbsp;“Across the board, repealing the&amp;nbsp;IRA&amp;nbsp;is going to make it more expensive for the average household — and in some states, dramatically.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The report modeled electricity costs in two scenarios — one in which current incentives and federal funding are kept in place, and one in which they are repealed this year. Under the&amp;nbsp;“repeal” scenario, annual consumer energy bills would be more than $6&amp;nbsp;billion higher for U.S. households in&amp;nbsp;2030&amp;nbsp;and more than $9&amp;nbsp;billion higher in&amp;nbsp;2035. Translated to individual households, energy costs would increase by an average of $48&amp;nbsp;per year in&amp;nbsp;2030&amp;nbsp;and $68&amp;nbsp;per year in&amp;nbsp;2035, and continue to rise in future years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Some states will see relatively low increases, Orvis said.&amp;nbsp;“But when you look out over&amp;nbsp;2035, most households are over $100&amp;nbsp;per year in energy expenditures.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The findings are consistent with other recent studies on the same&amp;nbsp;topic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last month, The Brattle Group published a&amp;nbsp;report, commissioned by conservative environmental advocacy group ConservAmerica, that found repeal of the clean energy tax credits would&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brattle.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/A-Wide-Array-of-Resources-is-Needed-to-Meet-Growing-US-Energy-Demand.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;increase residential electric bills&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;nationwide by an average of $83&amp;nbsp;per year by&amp;nbsp;2035, and up to $152&amp;nbsp;per year in California, New England, and much of the upper Midwest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;And&amp;nbsp;NERA&amp;nbsp;Economic Consulting projected in a&amp;nbsp;February report commissioned by the Clean Energy Buyers Association trade group that repealing the tax credits would&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cebuyers.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/CEBA_Electricity-Price-Impacts-of-Technology-Neutral-Tax-Incentives-With-Incremental-Electricity-Demand-From-Data-Centers_February-2025.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;drive average U.S. electricity prices up&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;nearly&amp;nbsp;10 percent by&amp;nbsp;2029, and by more than&amp;nbsp;30 percent for commercial and industrial electricity customers in certain states.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;The silhoutte of a woman against the night sky and a power grid.&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1598w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?resize=1200%2C676&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?resize=768%2C433&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?resize=1536%2C865&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1598&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/&quot;&gt;Utilities are shutting off power to a growing number of households&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/akielly-hu/&quot;&gt;Akielly Hu&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Republican leaders have committed to slashing federal spending to pay for the cost of extending the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.budget.senate.gov/chairman/newsroom/press/extending-trump-tax-cuts-would-add-46-trillion-to-the-deficit-cbo-finds&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;multi-trillion-dollar tax cut&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;passed during the first Trump administration, which primarily benefits corporations and wealthy individuals. Cutting clean energy incentives could be on the chopping block as a&amp;nbsp;result, although they’d only cover a&amp;nbsp;fraction of the tax breaks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But most of the investment in clean energy facilities and factories spurred by the law has been in states and congressional districts&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/interactive/2024/climate-bill-biden-clean-energy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;represented by Republicans&lt;/a&gt;, potentially making the path to repealing the Inflation Reduction Act’s clean energy incentives more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last week,&amp;nbsp;21&amp;nbsp;GOP&amp;nbsp;Congress members wrote a&amp;nbsp;letter&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/10/house-republican-clean-energy-tax-breaks-00218126&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;demanding to preserve&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;those tax credits, saying they’re critical to growing the economy and achieving the Trump administration’s&amp;nbsp;“energy dominance” agenda. They also warned that repealing them&amp;nbsp;“would increase utility bills the very next&amp;nbsp;day.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-why-clean-power-is-cheaper-power&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why clean power is cheaper power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The reason repealing these tax credits would drive up costs is simple, Orvis said. Solar and wind energy can supply U.S. power grids with electricity at lower long-term cost than alternatives such as coal, gas, and nuclear power plants. The more of it that can be built, the more it can supplant those costlier resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Over the past decade, solar and wind power have become the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/news/rapid-rollout-of-clean-technologies-makes-energy-cheaper-not-more-costly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;cheapest source of new electricity generation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;across the majority of the world, according to the International Energy Agency. Those cost advantages have been driven primarily by technology improvements and economies of scale of production as well as the deployment of solar panels, lithium-ion batteries, and wind turbines, although&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.mit.edu/ask-mit/how-much-do-government-subsidies-affect-price-fossil-fuel-energy-how-about-renewable-energy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;government subsidies have played an important role&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the U.S., newly built solar and wind farms can provide power at a&amp;nbsp;cheaper rate than&amp;nbsp;99 percent of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/fossil-fuels/clean-energy-is-cheaper-than-coal-across-the-whole-us-study-finds&quot;&gt;the country’s remaining coal plants&lt;/a&gt;. Even fossil gas, the workhorse of the U.S. grid, struggles to compete with new clean energy. A&amp;nbsp;study from think tank&amp;nbsp;RMI&amp;nbsp;found that portfolios of solar, wind, and batteries paired with utility energy-efficiency investments can&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-energy/with-new-tax-credits-clean-energy-beats-gas-plants-almost-every-time&quot;&gt;serve grid needs at a&amp;nbsp;lower cost&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;than newly built gas-fired power plants.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/florida-is-now-a-solar-superpower-heres-how-it-happened/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A sea of solar panels stretches out on a flat field&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/florida-is-now-a-solar-superpower-heres-how-it-happened/&quot;&gt;Florida is now a&amp;nbsp;solar superpower. Here’s how it happened.&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/alexander-c-kaufman/&quot;&gt;Alexander C. Kaufman&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;What’s more, the cost of solar and wind power isn’t tied to fluctuations in the price of fossil gas, which has driven significant electricity price increases in the past several years, Orvis said. That lack of fuel cost, along with lower operations and maintenance costs, make wind and solar a&amp;nbsp;long-run winner financially.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Energy developers and utilities are following the money. Last year,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-energy/chart-96-percent-of-new-us-power-capacity-was-carbon-free-in-2024&quot;&gt;solar, batteries, and wind made up more than&amp;nbsp;90 percent&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;of the&amp;nbsp;56&amp;nbsp;gigawatts of power capacity built in the U.S. The U.S. Energy Information Administration predicts solar will&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-energy/chart-solar-batteries-to-lead-us-power-plant-construction-in-2025&quot;&gt;lead power plant construction&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/energy-storage/chart-us-is-set-to-shatter-grid-battery-records-this-year&quot;&gt;battery installations will break records&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;again in&amp;nbsp;2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Wind and solar farms&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=63485&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;do cost more to build&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;than the equivalent gas power plants, however. That makes the pace and scale of their growth more dependent on the cost of capital, which is influenced by interest rates, and on incentives to reduce those up-front costs. In the U.S., the Inflation Reduction Act supercharged federal tax credits that have supported the industry for decades, delivering the law’s single biggest boost to reducing greenhouse gas emissions while helping to finance cheaper electricity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Cutting off those tax credits would curtail that growth and leave the country more reliant on fossil-fueled power plants that would not only create planet-warming emissions and harmful local air pollution but cost U.S. consumers more money. That would add roughly $20&amp;nbsp;billion in additional fuel, operations, and maintenance costs to U.S. electricity prices per year in&amp;nbsp;2030&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;2035, according to Energy Innovation’s analysis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An&amp;nbsp;‘energy emergency’ — false claims versus real solutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Trump administration has moved to undo decades of federal policy seeking to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, fight climate change, and protect the environment. It has also declared a&amp;nbsp;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/declaring-a-national-energy-emergency/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;national energy emergency&lt;/a&gt;” that casts renewable energy as a&amp;nbsp;threat to grid reliability and calls for expanded use of fossil fuels as the solution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Energy Secretary Wright, a&amp;nbsp;longtime gas industry executive who&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/mar/10/chris-wright-climate-fossil-fuels#:~:text=Wright%20has%20been%20called%20a,climate%20realist%2C%E2%80%9D%20he%20said.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;has denied that climate change is a&amp;nbsp;crisis&lt;/a&gt;, attacked solar and wind power in his&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.gov/articles/secretary-energy-chris-wright-delivers-keynote-remarks-ceraweek-2025&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;keynote address&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;at the CERAWeek by S&amp;amp;P Global conference in Houston last week.&amp;nbsp;“Everywhere wind and solar penetration have increased significantly, prices on the grid went up and stability of the grid went down,” he&amp;nbsp;said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But that assertion is&amp;nbsp;“not borne out by the data at all,” Orvis said. Rising risks of grid outages and emergencies are&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/utilities/why-are-blackouts-looming-blame-extreme-weather-not-wind-and-solar&quot;&gt;primarily driven by increasingly extreme weather&lt;/a&gt;, which is linked to global warming. And while the variability of wind and solar power generation is intimately tied to weather, traditional power plants have proven to be far less reliable than their backers have claimed, particularly during winter cold snaps like those that led to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/policy-regulation/the-texas-energy-system-faces-a-winter-reckoning-again&quot;&gt;massive grid outages in Texas in&amp;nbsp;2021&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/fossil-fuels/natural-gas-is-the-pillar-of-the-us-electric-grid-its-also-unreliable&quot;&gt;across the U.S. Southeast in&amp;nbsp;2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As for clean energy’s relationship to rising electricity prices, an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/utilities/dont-blame-clean-energy-for-rising-electric-bills&quot;&gt;Energy Innovation report last year&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;highlighted that surging electric utility costs in recent years are linked not to renewables but other factors, including spikes in fossil gas prices following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and the increasing cost of expanding and maintaining utility power&amp;nbsp;grids.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=722&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ember-March-2025-US-electricity-price-not-correlated-with-renewables-uptake.webp?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Ember&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ember&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A report out last week from think tank Ember reiterated&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/us-electricity-2025-special-report/power-generation-in-context/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;the absence of data&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to correlate reliance on clean energy and utility electricity costs.&amp;nbsp;“Some states with high wind and solar penetration — such as Iowa, South Dakota and Kansas — have some of the lowest electricity prices in the country,” the report notes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Other states with aggressive clean-energy mandates, such as California and Massachusetts, also have some of the country’s most expensive electricity, the report says. But those costs are more closely driven by aging infrastructure,&amp;nbsp;“expensive imported fossil fuels” in the case of Massachusetts, or in California,&amp;nbsp;“natural disaster damage” — namely, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/utilities/californias-utility-bill-crisis-is-clear-to-all-the-solution-not-so-much&quot;&gt;massive costs of wildfires&lt;/a&gt;, many caused by utility grid failures, and the investments meant to prevent more of&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;More broadly speaking, the cost of electric utility service is primarily tied to rising investments in utility transmission and distribution grids and the cost of fuel to power their generation, said Paul DeCotis, a&amp;nbsp;senior partner at consultancy West Monroe. And&amp;nbsp;“if people are concerned about the high cost of fuel, the federal government has made tax credits available for decades for renewable energy, which brings down the cost of electricity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In his speech at CERAWeek, Wright also mocked the idea that wind, solar, and batteries could completely replace fossil fuels for providing reliable round-the-clock generation capacity. But the U.S. isn’t facing that problem in the near term. Instead, it must cheaply and quickly build new capacity to meet the country’s growing power needs — and clean energy and batteries are best positioned to do that, according to energy industry analysts and executives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The U.S. is experiencing a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/transmission/suddenly-us-electricity-demand-is-spiking-can-the-grid-keep-up&quot;&gt;first-in-decades boom in demand&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for electricity, driven by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/utilities/data-centers-are-driving-us-power-demand-to-hard-to-reach-heights&quot;&gt;new data centers and factories&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the short term, and in the longer term by the push to shift from fossil-fueled to electric vehicles and building heating. A&amp;nbsp;number of utilities are proposing to build gigawatts of new gas-fired power plants to meet that demand. But as of today, manufacturers of gas turbines say they’re unable to supply power plants not already in planning until&amp;nbsp;2028&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;2029.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“If we’re really in this energy security and energy supply scenario this administration has talked about, we’re not going to be able to meet it with gas, because we’re tapped out on building it,” Orvis&amp;nbsp;said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;New solar, wind, and battery projects can be built in roughly half that time, making them a&amp;nbsp;vital near-term solution to rising power demand, NextEra Energy&amp;nbsp;CEO&amp;nbsp;John Ketchum&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/17/climate/renewable-energy-trump-electricity.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;told The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;at CERAWeek, adding that&amp;nbsp;“if you take renewables and storage off the table, we’re going to force electricity prices to the&amp;nbsp;moon.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/energy/gutting-clean-energy-incentives-would-drive-up-electric-bills/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/energy/gutting-clean-energy-incentives-would-drive-up-electric-bills/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Jeff St. John, Canary Media</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/WindTurbinesCA.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Energy</category></item><item><title>A court ordered Greenpeace to pay a pipeline company $660M. What happens next?</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A jury in North Dakota ordered Greenpeace to pay more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/climate/greenpeace-energy-transfer-dakota-access-verdict.html&quot;&gt;$660 million&lt;/a&gt; in damages to Energy Transfer, the company behind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nrdc.org/stories/dakota-access-pipeline-what-you-need-know#what-is&quot;&gt;Dakota Access Pipeline&lt;/a&gt;. Energy Transfer &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/general-news-c86795a2c7a64cb1b5c1f7e42c649dba&quot;&gt;sued Greenpeace in 2019&lt;/a&gt;, alleging that it had orchestrated a vast conspiracy against the company by organizing historic protests on the Standing Rock Sioux reservation in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2017/02/22/us/dakota-access-pipeline-evacuation-order/index.html#:~:text=Oceti%20Sakowin%20was%20the%20main,as%20many%20as%2010%2C000%20people.&quot;&gt;2016 and 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In its lawsuit, Energy Transfer Partners accused three Greenpeace entities — two in the U.S. and one based in Amsterdam&amp;nbsp;— of violating North Dakota trespassing and defamation laws, and of coordinating protests aimed to stop the 1,172-mile pipeline from transporting oil from North Dakota’s Bakken oil fields to a terminal in Illinois. Greenpeace maintained it played only a minor supporting role in the Indigenous-led movement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This was obviously a test case meant to scare others from exercising their First Amendment rights to free speech and peaceful protest,” said Deepa Padmanabha, a senior legal adviser for Greenpeace USA. “They’re trying to buy silence; that silence is not for sale.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Legal and Indigenous experts said the lawsuit was a“textbook” example of a “strategic lawsuit against public participation,” known colloquially as a SLAPP suit, a tactic used by corporations and wealthy individuals to drown their critics in legal fees. They also criticized Energy Transfer for using the lawsuit to undermine tribes’ treaty rights by exaggerating the role of out-of-state agitators.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The three Greenpeace entities named in the lawsuit —&amp;nbsp;Greenpeace Inc., a U.S.-based advocacy arm; Greenpeace Funds, which raises money and is also based in the U.S.; and Greenpeace International, based in the Netherlands — are now planning their next moves, including an appeal to the North Dakota Supreme Court and a separate countersuit in the European Union.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As part of a previous appeal to move the trial more impartial court, Greenpeace submitted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://climatecasechart.com/wp-content/uploads/case-documents/2025/20250227_docket-20250065-_petition.pdf&quot;&gt;33-page document&lt;/a&gt; to the state Supreme Court explaining that the jurors in Morton County, North Dakota —&amp;nbsp;where the trial occurred — would likely be biased against the defendants, since they were drawn from the same area where the anti-pipeline protests had taken place and disrupted daily life.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The request included results from a 2022 survey of 150 potential jurors in Morton County conducted by the National Jury Project, a litigation consulting company, which found 97 percent of residents said they could not be a fair or impartial juror in the lawsuit. Greenpeace also pointed out that nine of the 20 final jurors had either “direct personal experience” with the protests, or a friend or family member with direct personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/deepa-greenpeace.png?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of Greenpeace staff attorney Deepa Padmanabha wearing a suit, with lawyers in the background and a three-story building.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Deepa Padmanabha, a Greenpeace staff attorney, outside the Morton County Memorial Courthouse in North Dakota.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Stephanie Keith / Greenpeace&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Deepa Padmanabha, a Greenpeace staff attorney, outside the Morton County Memorial Courthouse in North Dakota.
 &lt;cite&gt;Stephanie Keith / Greenpeace&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Pat Parenteau, an emeritus professor at the Vermont Law and Graduate School, said the chances that the North Dakota Supreme Court will overturn the lower court’s verdict are “probably less than 50 percent.” What may be more likely, he said, is that the Supreme Court will reduce the “outrageous” amount of money charged by the Morton County jury, which includes various penalties that doubled the $300 million in damages that Energy Transfer had originally claimed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The court does have a lot of discretion in reducing the amount of damages,” he said. He called the Morton County verdict “beyond punitive. This is scorched Earth, what we’re seeing here.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Depending on what happens at the North Dakota Supreme Court, Parenteau also said there’s a basis for appealing the case to the U.S. Supreme Court, based on the First Amendment free speech issues involved. But, he added, the move could be “a really dangerous proposition,” with the court’s conservative supermajority and the precedent such a case could set. A federal decision in favor of Energy Transfer could limit any organizations’ ability to protest nationwide —&amp;nbsp;and not just against pipelines.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Amsterdam-based Greenpeace International, which coordinates 24 independent Greenpeace chapters around the world but is legally separate from them, is also fighting back. It countersued Energy Partners in the Netherlands in February, making use of a new anti-SLAPP directive in the EU that &lt;a href=&quot;https://commission.europa.eu/news/new-eu-rules-protect-against-strategic-lawsuits-against-public-participation-enter-force-2024-05-03_en&quot;&gt;went into effect in May 2024&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Greenpeace International is only on the hook for $132 million of the more than $600 million charged against the three Greenpeace bodies by the Morton County jury. Its countersuit in the EU wouldn’t change what has happened in U.S. courts. Instead, it seeks to recover costs incurred by the Amsterdam-based branch during its years-long fights against the Morton County lawsuit and an earlier, federal case in 2017 that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courthousenews.com/judge-tosses-900m-suit-over-greenpeace-pipeline-protests/&quot;&gt;eventually dismissed&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;If the damages awarded against Greenpeace International in U.S. courts aren’t overturned through appeals, then it can potentially claim those same millions back from Energy Transfer in the EU case.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Greenpeace International’s trial will begin in Dutch courts in July and is the first test of the EU’s anti-SLAPP directive. According to Kristen Casper, general counsel for Greenpeace International, the branch in the EU has a strong case because the only action it took in support of the anti-pipeline protests was to sign an open letter — what she described as a clear case of protected public participation. Eric Heinze, a free speech expert and professor of law and humanities at Queen Mary University of London, said the case appeared “black and white.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Normally I don’t like to predict,” he said, “but if I had to put money on this I would bet for Greenpeace to win.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While Greenpeace’s various entities may have to pay damages as ordered by U.S. courts, the result of the case in the EU, Casper said a victory would send an international message against “corporate bullying and weaponization of the law.” Padmanabha said that regardless of the damages that the Greenpeace USA incurs, the organization isn’t going away any time soon. “You can’t bankrupt the movement,” she said. “What we work on, our campaigns and our commitments — that is not going to change.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In response to request for comment, Energy Transfer said the Morton County jury’s decision was a victory for the people of Mandan and “for all law-abiding Americans who understand the difference between the right to free speech and breaking the law. That Greenpeace has been held responsible is a win for all of us.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Nick Estes, an assistant professor of American Indian studies at the University of Minnesota and member of the Lower Brule Sioux Tribe who wrote a book about the Dakota Access Pipeline protests, said the case was about more than just punishing Greenpeace — it was a proxy attack on the water protectors at Standing Rock and the broader environmental justice movement. He said it showed what could happen “if you step outside the path of what they consider as an acceptable form of protest.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“They had to sidestep the actual context of the entire movement, around treaty rights, land rights, water rights, and tribal sovereignty because they couldn’t win that fight,” he said. “They had to go a circuitous route, and find a sympathetic court to attack the environmental movement.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Janet Alkire, the chair of the Standing Rock Sioux Tribe, said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.standingrock.org/2025/03/03/standing-rock-sioux-tribal-chairwoman-janet-alkire-statement-on-the-energy-transfer-lawsuit-against-greenpeace/&quot;&gt;March 3 statement&lt;/a&gt; that the Morton County case was “frivolously alleging defamation and seeking money damages, designed to shut down all voices supporting Standing Rock.” She said the company also used propaganda to discredit the tribe during and after the protests.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Part of the attack on our tribe is to attack our allies,” Alkire wrote. “The Standing Rock Sioux Tribe will not be silenced.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story has been updated to include additional information from Greenpeace.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/indigenous/a-court-ordered-greenpeace-to-pay-a-pipeline-company-660m-what-happens-next/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/indigenous/a-court-ordered-greenpeace-to-pay-a-pipeline-company-660m-what-happens-next/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 21:49:48 GMT</pubDate><author>Sachi Kitajima Mulkey, Joseph Winters</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/standing-rock-flags.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Indigenous Affairs</category></item><item><title>The EPA wants to roll back a rule that’s essential for protecting you from chemical disasters</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A little past 4 a.m. on June 21, 2019, workers at the Philadelphia Energy Solutions oil refinery in Philadelphia noticed a leak from a corroded pipe, and were immediately on high alert. The leak had originated in Unit 433, known among workers as the “bogeyman” because it contained the highly explosive chemical hydrofluoric acid, or HF. When released in large quantities, the chemical can form a dense, toxic vapor cloud that hugs the ground and can travel many miles. Contact with this cloud can be deadly; if it ignites, it could cause a massive explosion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Sure enough, a vapor cloud materialized and ignited, causing three large explosions and a massive fire that sent smoke “pouring into the sky.” Pieces of equipment the size of cars flew through the air, miraculously landing in the Schuylkill River without hitting any homes. The force of the explosions threw workers back, injuring five, but ultimately did not cause any fatalities. Workers remembering the incident years later agreed that it could have been much worse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“You figure you ain’t going home,” one former worker told Grist of the moment he saw the fire in Unit 433. “You figure this is it.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Shortly after the incident, the company filed for bankruptcy and shut down, leaving &lt;a href=&quot;https://whyy.org/articles/pes-refinery-explosion-five-years-former-employees/&quot;&gt;around 1,000 workers jobless&lt;/a&gt; and without severance pay.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Refineries that use HF are regulated under the EPA’s Risk Management Program, or RMP, a regulation designed to improve chemical accident prevention at large petrochemical facilities — but for reasons that have little to do with knowhow and capacity, RMP regulations have been glaringly ineffective. Indeed, few regulations have been subject to the yo-yo of successive presidential administrations, and their political whims, like the RMP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The RMP program was established in 1990 following a series of infamous chemical disasters in the 1980s, most notably the chemical leak at Union Carbide’s plant in Bhopal, India, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/dec/08/bhopals-tragedy-has-not-stopped-the-urban-disaster-still-claiming-lives-35-years-on&quot;&gt;poisoned roughly 500,000 people&lt;/a&gt;, around 20,000 of whom died in the hours and years afterwards due to health complications from the exposure. Another leak at a Union Carbide facility in West Virginia the following year &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1985/08/12/us/toxic-cloud-leaks-at-carbide-plant-in-west-virginia.html&quot;&gt;caused&lt;/a&gt; eye, throat, and lung irritation for at least 135 residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The first iteration of the rule came into effect in 1994, during the Clinton administration, but lacked several important protections such as independent auditing for regulated facilities, public information provisions, and the requirement that companies complete a “safer technology and alternatives analysis” to determine whether there are any safer ways to conduct their operation. A series of chemical disasters in 2013 — including a massive explosion at the West Fertilizer Company in west Texas that &lt;a href=&quot;https://stateimpact.npr.org/texas/tag/west-fertilizer/&quot;&gt;killed 15 people and damaged 350 homes&lt;/a&gt; — brought these deficiencies to the attention of regulators.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/caught-off-guard-epa-proposes-to-fire-hundreds-of-scientists/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;EPA Administrator Lee Zeldin&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1599w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=1536%2C865&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1599&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/caught-off-guard-epa-proposes-to-fire-hundreds-of-scientists/&quot;&gt;‘Caught off guard’: EPA proposes to fire hundreds of scientists&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/naveena-sadasivam/&quot;&gt;Naveena Sadasivam&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;       &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/tik-root/&quot;&gt;Tik Root&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In January 2017, the Obama EPA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/rmp/final-amendments-risk-management-program-rmp-rule&quot;&gt;finalized&lt;/a&gt; amendments to the Accidental Release Prevention Requirements of the RMP, which included measures to enhance emergency preparedness requirements and ensure that local emergency response officials and residents had access to information to better prepare for potential chemical disasters. But the provisions never went into full effect: In May 2018, the Trump EPA proposed amendments to remove third-party audits and incident investigations, among other protections. The Trump rule was finalized in December of 2019 — six months before the explosion at the Pennsylvania refinery.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When Biden took office, in 2021, the EPA began working on a new set of amendments for the RMP rule. Unions like U.S. Steelworkers and advocates at organizations like the Union of Concerned Scientists pushed for better public disclosure provisions, the inclusion of more types of facilities in the safer technologies alternatives assessment requirements, and the freedom for workers to stop work that they deem unsafe.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Many communities that are vulnerable to chemical accidents are in overburdened and underserved areas of the country,” said former EPA Administrator Michael Regan in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-finalizes-stronger-safety-standards-protect-risk-communities-chemical-accidents&quot;&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt; announcing the final rule last March. It was slated to go into effect in 2027.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the past few years, several chemical disasters have disrupted life in the country’s industrial corridors. In August 2023, a large fire at Marathon Petroleum’s refinery in St. John the Baptist Parish, Louisiana in August 2023 burned for seven hours, causing residents to flee for safety. But in the days following the incident, &lt;a href=&quot;https://lailluminator.com/2023/08/25/fire-at-marathon-refinery-in-st-john-parish-burns-for-seven-hours/&quot;&gt;neither the company nor state and federal environmental regulators&lt;/a&gt; responded to locals’ questions about what chemicals the air was being tested for. And in 2024, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/pemexs-deer-park-oil-refinery-scales-back-operations-after-fatal-accident-2024-10-12/&quot;&gt;hydrogen sulfide leak&lt;/a&gt; at Pemex’s refinery in Deer Park, Texas killed two contract workers and injured 35 others.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/zeldin.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Lee Zeldin&quot; data-caption=&quot;EPA Administrator Lee Zeldin
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;EPA Administrator Lee Zeldin
 &lt;cite&gt;Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In January, a group of industry trade associations sent Lee Zeldin a letter congratulating him on his appointment to the position of EPA Administrator and asking him to take swift action against the “misguided and illegal new requirements” of Biden’s RMP rule. In their letter, the trade groups argued that the new rule represents an overextension of the EPA’s authority and fails to provide a durable solution to facility safety, though they did not explain how the rule falls short in this regard. They singled out &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdxapps.epa.gov/olem-rmp-pds/&quot;&gt;an interactive map&lt;/a&gt; that the agency published last year separate from the rulemaking process showing where RMP facilities are located around the country, along with other basic public information such as compliance history and the types of chemicals stored onsite.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In a statement &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-announces-reconsideration-risk-management-plan-boost-safety-competitiveness&quot;&gt;announcing the EPA’s decision&lt;/a&gt; to revisit the RMP rule earlier this month, Zeldin seemed to buy industry’s argument.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The Biden EPA’s costly Risk Management Plan rule ignored recommendations from national security experts on how their rule makes chemical and other sensitive facilities in America more vulnerable to attack,” Zeldin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-announces-reconsideration-risk-management-plan-boost-safety-competitiveness&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;. The press release also notes that Biden’s RMP rule makes domestic oil refineries and chemical facilities less competitive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It took years to come to the rule that was finalized last year,” said Darya Minovi, a senior analyst at the Union of Concerned Scientists. “To see that rolled back simply because of a letter sent by industry trade associations is really frustrating and shows what little regard this administration has for communities they say they care about.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Minovi told Grist that the rhetoric about national security is overblown. The public data tool does not contain sensitive information, she said, and when the Department of Homeland Security reviewed the rule last year, they flagged no concerns with the public information disclosure requirements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We’re not happy about it,” the U.S. Steelworkers representative told Grist about the Trump administration’s reconsideration of the RMP rule. As for Zeldin’s concerns about making domestic oil and gas companies competitive, “I think that putting workers and communities at greater risk of catastrophic injuries is not good for the economy.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/regulation/epa-lee-zeldin-risk-management-program/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/regulation/epa-lee-zeldin-risk-management-program/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Lylla Younes</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/philly_refinery_fire.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Regulation</category></item><item><title>Farmers and small business owners were promised financial help for energy upgrades. They’re still waiting for the money.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This coverage is made possible through a partnership between&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bpr.org/&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt;BPR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a public radio station serving western North Carolina,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wbez.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wabe.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;WABE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wbez.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;, Atlanta’s NPR station, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;WBEZ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, a public radio station serving the Chicago metropolitan region, and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.interlochenpublicradio.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interlochen Public Radio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; in Northern Michigan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Trump administration’s freeze on funding from the Inflation Reduction Act, or IRA, the landmark climate law from the Biden era, has left farmers and rural businesses across the country on the hook for costly energy efficiency upgrades and renewable energy installations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The grants are part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rd.usda.gov/programs-services/energy-programs/rural-energy-america-program-renewable-energy-systems-energy-efficiency-improvement-guaranteed-loans&quot;&gt;Rural Energy for America Program&lt;/a&gt;, or REAP, originally created in the 2008 farm bill and supercharged by funding from the IRA. It provides farmers and other businesses in rural areas with relatively small grants and loans to help lower their energy bills by investing, say,&amp;nbsp; in more energy-efficient farming equipment or installing small solar arrays.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;By November 2024, the IRA had awarded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usda.gov/about-usda/news/press-releases/2024/11/14/biden-harris-administrations-inflation-reduction-act-tops-1-billion-clean-energy-investments-nearly&quot;&gt;more than $1 billion for nearly 7,000 REAP projects&lt;/a&gt;, which help rural businesses in low-income communities reduce the up-front costs of clean energy and save thousands on utility costs each year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But now, that funding is in limbo. Under the current freeze, some farmers have already spent tens of thousands of dollars on projects and are waiting for the promised reimbursement. Others have had to delay work they were counting on to support their businesses, unsure when their funding will come through — or if it will.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;REAP is administered by the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Secretary Brooke Rollins said the agency is “coming to the tail end of the review process” of evaluating grants awarded under the Biden administration.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“If our farmers and ranchers especially have already spent money under a commitment that was made, the goal is to make sure they are made whole,” Rollins told reporters in Atlanta last week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But it’s not clear when the funds might be released, or whether all the farmers and business owners awaiting their money will receive it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For Joshua Snedden, a REAP grant was the key to making his 10-acre farm in Monee, Illinois, more affordable and environmentally sustainable. But months after installing a pricey solar array, he’s still waiting on a reimbursement from the federal government — and the delay is threatening his bottom line.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I’m holding out hope,” said Snedden, a first-generation farmer in northeast Illinois. “I’m trying to do everything within my power to make sure the funding is released.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In December, his five-year old operation, Fox at the Fork, began sourcing its power from a new 18.48 kilowatt solar array which cost Snedden $86,364. The system currently offsets all the farm’s electricity use and then some.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;REAP offers grants for up to half of a project like this, and loan guarantees for up to 75 percent of the cost. For Snedden, a $19,784 REAP reimbursement grant made this solar array possible. But the reimbursement, critical to Snedden’s cash flow, was frozen by Trump as part of a broader review of the USDA’s Biden-era commitments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Fox-at-the-Fork-Josh-raking-leaves.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A man rakes leaves in a field.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Joshua Snedden is a first-generation farmer who said he will continue whether or not he gets the federal funding for solar. 
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Joshua Snedden&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Joshua Snedden is a first-generation farmer who said he will continue whether or not he gets the federal funding for solar. 
 &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Joshua Snedden&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Snedden grows the produce he takes to market — everything from tomatoes to garlic to potatoes — on about an acre of his farm. He also plans to transform the rest of his land into a perennial crop system, which would include fruit trees like pears, plums, and apples planted alongside native flowers and grasses to support wildlife.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A solar array was always part of his plans, “but seemed like a pie in the sky” kind of project, he said, adding he thought it might take him a decade to afford such an investment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The REAP program has been a lifeline for Illinois communities struggling with aging infrastructure and growing energy costs, according to Amanda Pankau with the Prairie Rivers Network, an organization advocating for environmental protection and climate change mitigation across Illinois.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“By lowering their electricity costs, rural small businesses and agricultural producers can put that money back into their business,” said Pankau.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;That’s exactly what Snedden envisioned from his investment in the solar power system. The new solar array wouldn’t just make his farm more resilient to climate change, but also more financially viable, “because we could shift expenses from paying for energy to paying for more impactful inputs for the farm,” he said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;He anticipates that by switching to solar, Fox at the Fork will save close to $3,200 dollars a year on electric bills.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Now, Snedden is waiting for the USDA to hold up their end of the deal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The financial strain hurts,” said Snedden. “But I’m still planning to move forward growing crops and fighting for these funds.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorCarolinaReap1.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Man and woman stand closely to each other.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Jon and Brittany Klimstra are both scientists who are originally from western North Carolina. They returned to the area to start a farm and an orchard and are waiting for solar funds they were promised.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Jon Klimstra&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Jon and Brittany Klimstra are both scientists who are originally from western North Carolina. They returned to the area to start a farm and an orchard and are waiting for solar funds they were promised.
 &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Jon Klimstra&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At the start of the year, Jon and Brittany Klimstra were nearly ready to install a solar array on their Polk County, North Carolina farm after being awarded a REAP grant in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As two former scientists who had moved back to western North Carolina 10 years ago to grow apples and be close to their families, it felt like a chance to both save money and live their values.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We’ve certainly been interested in wanting to do something like this, whether it be for our personal home or for our farm buildings for a while,” said Jon. “It just was cost prohibitive up to this point without some type of funding.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;That funding came when they were awarded $12,590 from REAP for the installation. But, after the Trump administration’s funding freeze, the money never came.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We were several site visits in, several engineering conversations. We’ve had electricians, the solar company,” said Brittany . “It’s been a very involved process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Since the grant is reimbursement-based, the Klimstras have already paid out-of-pocket for some costs related to the project. Plus, the farm had been banking on saving $1,300 in utilities expenses per year. In a given month, their electricity bill is $300-$400.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/NorthCalREAP2.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;red apples in a gray wooden box&quot; data-caption=&quot;Apples from the orchard run by Jon and Brittany Klimstra. They were ready to install a solar array when the federal funding was frozen.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Jon Klimstra&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Apples from the orchard run by Jon and Brittany Klimstra. They were ready to install a solar array when the federal funding was frozen.
 &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Jon Klimstra&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Across Appalachia, historically high energy costs have made the difference between survival and failure for many local businesses, said Heather Ransom, who works with Solar Holler, a solar company that serves parts of Virginia, West Virginia, Kentucky, and Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We have seen incredible rate increases across the region in electricity over the past 10, even 20 years,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Through Solar Holler, REAP grants also passed into the hands of rural library systems and schools; the company installed 10,000 solar panels throughout the Wayne County, West Virginia school system. About $6 million worth of projects supported by Solar Holler are currently on hold.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In other parts of the region, community development financial institutions like the Mountain Association in eastern Kentucky combatted food deserts through helping local grocery stores apply for REAP.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Solar Holler also works in coal-producing parts of the region, where climate change discussions have been fraught with the realities of declining jobs and revenue from the coal industry. The program helped make the case for communities to veer away from coal and gas-fired energy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“What REAP has helped us do is show people that it’s not just a decision that’s driven by environmental motives or whatever, it actually makes good business sense to go solar,” Ransom said. In her experience, saving money appeals to people of all political persuasions. “At the end of the day, we’ve installed just as much solar on red roofs as we do blue roofs, as we do rainbow roofs or whatever.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/MichiganREAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A man with gray hair and a blue ball cap walks along a field wearing a brown vest and holding a cup of coffee.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Jim Lively has a local food market just minutes from the Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore in northern Michigan. He’s waiting for the federal money he was promised so he can put solar on the roof and offset the costs of opening up a campsite for RVs in this field. 
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Izzy Ross / Grist&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Jim Lively has a local food market just minutes from the Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore in northern Michigan. He’s waiting for the federal money he was promised so he can put solar on the roof and offset the costs of opening up a campsite for RVs in this field. 
 &lt;cite&gt;Izzy Ross / Grist&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore in northern Michigan draws over 1.5 million visitors every year. Jim Lively hopes some of those people will camp RVs at a nearby site he’s planning to open next to his family’s local food market. He wants to use solar panels to help power the campsite and offset electric bills for the market, where local farmers bring produce directly to the store.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lively helped promote REAP during his time at an environmental nonprofit, where he’d worked for over two decades. So the program was on his mind when it came time to replace the market’s big, south-facing roof.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We put on a metal roof, and worked with a contractor who was also familiar with the REAP program, and we said, ‘Let’s make sure we’re setting this up for solar,’” he said. “So it was kind of a no-brainer for us.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;They were told they had been approved for a REAP grant of $39,696 last summer — half of the project’s total cost — but didn’t feel the need to rush the solar installation. Then, at the end of January, Lively was notified that the funding had been paused.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Lively2REAP.jpeg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;The interior of a grocerys tore with shelves of food and the back of a woman stocking the shelves.&quot; data-caption=&quot;The interior of the Lively NeighborFood Market, where owner Jim Lively likes to feature local produce. He was hoping to install a solar roof this year, but the funding has been stalled.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Izzy Ross / Grist&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;The interior of the Lively NeighborFood Market, where owner Jim Lively likes to feature local produce. He was hoping to install a solar roof this year, but the funding has been stalled.
 &lt;cite&gt;Izzy Ross / Grist&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The property runs on electricity, rather than natural gas, and Lively wants to keep it that way. But those electric bills have been expensive — about $2,000 a month last summer, he said. When they get the RV site up and running, he expects those bills to approach $3,000.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Selling local food means operating within tight margins. Lively said saving on energy would help, but they won’t be able to move ahead with the rooftop solar unless the REAP funding is guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Continuing to power the property with electricity rather than fossil fuels is a kind of personal commitment for Lively. “Boy, solar is also the right thing to do,” he said. “And it’s going to be difficult to do that without that funding.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The grants aren’t only for solar arrays and other renewable energy systems. Many are for energy efficiency improvements to help farmers save on utility bills, and in some cases cut emissions. In Georgia, for instance, one farm was awarded just under $233,000 for a more efficient grain dryer, an upgrade projected to save the farm more than $16,000 per year. Several farms were awarded funding to convert diesel-powered irrigation pumps to electric.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA did not directly answer Grist’s emailed questions about the specific timeline for REAP funds, the amount of money under review, or the future of the program. Instead, an emailed statement criticized the Biden administration’s “misuse of hundreds of billions” of IRA and bipartisan infrastructure law (BIL) funds&amp;nbsp; “all at the expense of the American taxpayer.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“USDA has a solemn responsibility to be good stewards of the American people’s hard-earned taxpayer dollars and to ensure that every dollar spent goes to serve the people, not the bureaucracy. As part of this effort, Secretary Rollins is carefully reviewing this funding and will provide updates as soon as they are made available,” the email said.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/trump-climate-funding-freeze-ira-bil-biden/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;President Trump silhouetted against a cloudy sky&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?resize=330%2C220&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/trump-freeze-funding-power.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1067&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/trump-climate-funding-freeze-ira-bil-biden/&quot;&gt;Trump is freezing climate funds. Can he do that?&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/jake-bittle/&quot;&gt;Jake Bittle&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Two federal judges have already ordered the Trump administration to release the impounded IRA and BIL funds. Earthjustice, a national environmental law organization, filed a lawsuit last week challenging the freeze of USDA funds on behalf of farmers and nonprofits.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The administration is causing harm that can’t be fixed, and fairness requires that the funds continue to flow,” said Jill Tauber, vice president of litigation for climate and energy at Earthjustice.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Rollins &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usda.gov/about-usda/news/press-releases/2025/02/20/secretary-rollins-releases-first-tranche-funding-under-review#:~:text=Washington%2C%20D.C.%2C%20Feb.%2020,Inflation%20Reduction%20Act%20(IRA)&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; the first tranche of funding February 20 and announced the release of additional program funds earlier this month. That did not include the REAP funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA announced Wednesday it would expedite funding for farmers under a different program in honor of National Agriculture Day, but as of March 20 had not made an announcement about REAP.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rahul Bali of WABE contributed reporting to this story. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Earthjustice is an advertiser with Grist. Advertisers have no role in Grist’s editorial decisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/farmers-and-small-business-owners-were-promised-financial-help-for-energy-upgrades-theyre-still-waiting-for-the-money/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/farmers-and-small-business-owners-were-promised-financial-help-for-energy-upgrades-theyre-still-waiting-for-the-money/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Emily Jones, Katie Myers, Juanpablo Ramirez-Franco, Izzy Ross</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/REAPChicago.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Accountability</category><category>Business</category><category>Economics</category><category>Food and Agriculture</category><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>The climate movement is talking about carbon all wrong, a new book argues</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Burning oil, gas, and coal — literal &lt;em&gt;fossil&lt;/em&gt; fuels, made from the compressed remains of ancient plants and plankton — has released carbon into Earth’s atmosphere, where it traps heat and alters the climate. That process has caused massive destruction and loss of life, and it will continue to do so. As a result, carbon came to be seen as something to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weforum.org/stories/2015/09/fighting-emissions-from-space/&quot;&gt;fight&lt;/a&gt;,” “&lt;a href=&quot;https://abc6onyourside.com/news/local/columbus-ohio-grow-tree-canopy-combat-carbon-emissions-enhance-neighborhoods-environment-trees-nature&quot;&gt;combat&lt;/a&gt;,” and “capture.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Paul Hawken, the author of the new book &lt;em&gt;Carbon: The Book of Life&lt;/em&gt;, argues that the climate movement is thinking about its work, and messaging, all wrong. “Those who call carbon a pollutant might want to lay down their word processor,” Hawken writes. Carbon, he notes, is after all the building block of life, the animating force behind trees, rhinos, eyelashes, hormones, bamboo, and so much more. Without it, Earth would just be a lonely, dead rock. So much for decarbonizing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Hawken has come to believe that treating carbon as something to tackle, liquefy, and pump into geological formations not only reflects the same mindset that caused climate change in the first place, but also further alienates people from the living world. There is no “climate crisis,” he argues, but a crisis of human thinking and behavior that’s degrading the soil, wiping out entire species, and changing the weather faster than people can adapt. “From a planetary view,” he writes in &lt;em&gt;Carbon&lt;/em&gt;, “the warming atmosphere is a response, an adjustment, a teaching.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken_Inline.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Viking / Jasmine Scaelsciani Hawken&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Viking / Jasmine Scaelsciani Hawken&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The book records a shift in his thinking. In 2017, Hawken published &lt;em&gt;Drawdown: The Most Comprehensive Plan Ever Proposed to Reverse Global Warming&lt;/em&gt;, a book that ranked 100 climate solutions by how much they could reduce carbon emissions, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://drawdown.org/solutions/refrigerant-management&quot;&gt;refrigerant leaks&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://drawdown.org/solutions/reduced-food-waste&quot;&gt;food waste&lt;/a&gt;. The nonprofit &lt;a href=&quot;https://drawdown.org/&quot;&gt;Project Drawdown&lt;/a&gt;, which he launched, continues to implement these kinds of fixes around the world. But now, Hawken is forgoing straightforward metrics to focus on what he sees as a deeper cultural problem. “The living world is a complex interactive system and doesn’t lend itself to simple solutions,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The new book frames carbon as a flow — a cycle that moves through the atmosphere, oceans, soil, with the element absorbed by growing plants and exhaled in every animal breath. Hawken’s book is a lesson in what’s sometimes called “unlearning,” or letting go of old assumptions, like the idea that nature is something to fix or control. The book explores ways to repair a broken relationship with the natural world, drawing inspiration from Indigenous cultures and new scientific discoveries. Hawken marvels at how much remains unknown about carbon, which he dubs “the most mysterious element of all.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The book’s poetic language offers a stark contrast to &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/climate/the-war-on-climate-the-climate-fight-are-we-approaching-the-problem-all-wrong/&quot;&gt;the warlike terms&lt;/a&gt; climate advocates tend to use to describe carbon. Hawken argues that the typical metaphors are not only inaccurate — how exactly do you battle an element? — but also provide fuel for right-wing narratives that carbon has been unfairly demonized. Last week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eenews.net/articles/trumps-next-climate-move-show-global-warming-benefits-humanity/&quot;&gt;E&amp;amp;E News reported that the Trump administration is planning a federal report&lt;/a&gt; making the case that a warming world would be a good thing, a pretext for weakening climate regulations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Carbon dioxide is not an evil gas,” David Legates, a former Trump official, said in a recent video put out by the Heartland Institute, a conservative think tank. “Rather, it’s a gas beneficial to life on Earth. It’ll increase temperatures slightly, and warmer temperatures are certainly better than colder temperatures.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/project/indigenous/klamath-river-dam-removal-tribe-pacificorp-salmon/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;An illustrative medley of tirbal leaders, Warren Buffet, money, and paperwork against the backdrop of a dam and salmon&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/klamath-dam-removal-social.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/project/indigenous/klamath-river-dam-removal-tribe-pacificorp-salmon/&quot;&gt;How the Klamath Dams Came Down&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/anita-hofschneider/&quot;&gt;Anita Hofschneider&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;       &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/jake-bittle/&quot;&gt;Jake Bittle&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Hawken wants a broad shift in how people talk about the natural world, though, not just a rethinking of the climate movement’s metaphors. He points to how financial institutions &lt;a href=&quot;https://indoeden.substack.com/p/goldman-sachs-biodiversity-fund-the?utm_campaign=post&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&quot;&gt;increasingly refer to nature as a commodity&lt;/a&gt;. In January, BlackRock, the world’s largest asset manager, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackrock.com/corporate/literature/publication/blk-commentary-engagement-on-natural-capital.pdf&quot;&gt;declared “natural capital” an investment priority&lt;/a&gt;. In February, Goldman Sachs launched a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esgdive.com/news/goldman-sachs-launches-biodiversity-bond-fund-to-support-sdgs/741533/&quot;&gt;“biodiversity bond fund”&lt;/a&gt; turning ecosystems into investment products. The jargon used in scientific reports and global climate conferences also creates a sense of detachment that dulls the living things it refers to. Hawken describes the word “biodiversity” as “a bloodless term” and “carbon neutrality” as an absurd “biophysical impossibility.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We are numbed by the science, puzzled by jargon, paralyzed by predictions, confused about what actions to take, stressed as we scramble to care for our family, or simply impoverished, overworked, and tired,” Hawken writes. “Most of humanity doesn’t talk about climate change because we do not know what to say.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Even plainspoken terms like “nature” are suspect, in Hawken’s view: The concept only seems to exist to mark a separation between humans and the rest of the world. He points out that the Chicham language of the Achuar people in the Amazon doesn’t have a word for nature, nor do other Indigenous languages. “Such words would only be needed if the Achuar experienced nature as distinct from the self,” he writes. English, by contrast, he describes as a “rootless” language, borrowing terms from so many places that it struggles to teach the kind of deep, reciprocal relationships that are born from living in one place and caring for it over many generations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Hawken hopes to mend that separation by helping people discover the flow of carbon in their daily lives and kindle a sense of wonder about it. &lt;em&gt;Carbon&lt;/em&gt; delves into mind-bending scientific discoveries about the kind of marvels that carbon makes possible. Bees, with their two-milligram brains, appear able to count, learn by observation, feel pain and pleasure, and even recognize their own knowledge. The rye plant senses the world around it with more than 14 million roots and root hairs, a network that one plant neurobiologist described as a type of brain. Hawken’s book is a reminder that carbon — despite all the problems caused by releasing too much of it into the atmosphere — is actually a gift.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The goal of &lt;em&gt;Carbon&lt;/em&gt; isn’t to map out a plan for saving the Earth, but to rekindle a sense of relationship with it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Where Hawken lives in California, his community recently restored a salmon stream, breaking down a concrete barrier under a bridge that had blocked the fish on their final journey up the stream to spawn. “The core of it is about care, and kindness, and connection, and compassion, and generosity,” Hawken said. “That’s where regeneration starts.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/language/paul-hawken-book-climate-movement-carbon/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/language/paul-hawken-book-climate-movement-carbon/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:15:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Kate Yoder</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Climate_Carbon_Hawken.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Culture</category><category>Language</category></item><item><title>‘Caught off guard’: EPA proposes to fire hundreds of scientists</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The mood was grim at a town hall meeting called by the Environmental Protection Agency on Tuesday. The gathering came one day after The New York Times reported&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/17/climate/trump-eliminates-epa-science.html&quot;&gt; a bombshell&lt;/a&gt; — Lee Zeldin, the agency’s administrator, plans to dismantle its Office of Research and Development, eliminating 50 to 75 percent of its 1,500 or so chemists, toxicologists, biologists, and other experts. The department, which conducts essential research to inform federal policies, plays a critical role in the agency’s mission to safeguard public health and the environment. Laying off most of its staff, many of whom are career scientists, would leave the EPA without the independent and rigorous science needed to develop effective regulations. No one consulted the office’s leaders about the plan.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Maureen Gwinn, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/aboutepa/organization-chart-office-research-and-development-ord&quot;&gt;who leads the &lt;/a&gt;Office of Research and Development, or ORD, is not a political appointee, and her team learned about the specifics of the proposal when they read about it in the Times. Managers quickly set up an all-hands with the department staff to discuss it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“There was no preparation,” Holly Wilson, an EPA employee and president of the union that represents its employees, told Grist. “They were caught off guard, and acting as good leaders, wanted to bring their folks together and add some context around what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Employees from all over the country dialed into the call, which lasted about 30 minutes. They wanted to know when the layoffs would begin, how they would be notified if they were being terminated, and whether buyouts would be offered. One person asked if they could publish their research after being fired. Management had few specific answers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Times’ reporting was based on documents the EPA provided to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. The proposal, which was submitted to the White House last week and could change in the coming days, calls for dissolving the research office, firing most of its employees, and reassigning those who remain to other roles. Under the plan, the agency would seek a waiver to halve the standard notice period for a “reduction in force” from 60 to 30 days.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We don’t know which jobs, which pieces are going to go away and which ones stay,” said Wilson. “The uncertainty is what’s causing a lot of the angst.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It is the latest assault on the agency. Over the last two months, the Trump administration has fired more than 400 of its probationary workers, only to reinstate them after a court mandated it. The agency also &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/regulation/the-end-of-the-epas-fight-to-protect-overpolluted-communities/&quot;&gt;shuttered its Office of Environmental Justice&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/trump-zeldin-epa-citi-greenhouse-gas-reduction-fund/&quot;&gt;froze funding for various&lt;/a&gt; climate &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/trump-zeldin-epa-citi-greenhouse-gas-reduction-fund/&quot;&gt;programs&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;EPA employees had been bracing for these changes. In implementing President Donald Trump’s executive order to reduce the federal workforce, the Office of Management and Budget has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opm.gov/policy-data-oversight/latest-memos/guidance-on-agency-rif-and-reorganization-plans-requested-by-implementing-the-president-s-department-of-government-efficiency-workforce-optimization-initiative.pdf&quot;&gt;required agencies to submit phase two&lt;/a&gt; of their “reduction in force” plans by April 14. The Office of Research and Development is the largest department within the agency, and often the subject of presidential efforts to rein it in or expand it. Project 2025, the conservative blueprint for Trump’s second term, specifically foreshadowed the current events. It recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_FULL.pdf&quot;&gt;eliminating “several ORD offices and programs,”&lt;/a&gt; and called the department “bloated, unaccountable, closed, outcome-driven, hostile to public and legislative input, and inclined to pursue political rather than purely scientific goals.”&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/regulation/the-end-of-the-epas-fight-to-protect-overpolluted-communities/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?resize=330%2C220&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?resize=1536%2C1023&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1066&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/regulation/the-end-of-the-epas-fight-to-protect-overpolluted-communities/&quot;&gt;The end of the EPA’s fight to protect overpolluted communities&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/lylla-younes/&quot;&gt;Lylla Younes&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Still, the scale of the proposed rollbacks has caught almost everyone off guard. “What’s new is the extreme nature of this,” said a senior EPA official, who requested anonymity given the sensitivity of the topic. “This is not designed to cut expenses, it’s designed to destroy” the department.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Democrats have pushed back, arguing that the office’s functions are protected by federal law and eliminating it is illegal. “Every decision EPA makes must be in furtherance of protecting human health and the environment, and that just can’t happen if you gut EPA science,” Representative Zoe Lofgren (D-CA), ranking member of the House Science, Space, and Technology Committee, said in a statement to Grist. “Donald Trump and Elon Musk are putting their polluter buddies’ bottom lines over the health and safety of Americans.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Republican members of the committee did not respond to requests for comment. Neither did the Heritage Foundation, a major backer of Project 2025, or the EPA.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Office of Research and Development supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/research/national-research-programs&quot;&gt;six research programs&lt;/a&gt; through offices &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/aboutepa/about-office-research-and-development-ord&quot;&gt;in 10 facilities&lt;/a&gt;. It works alongside EPA offices that oversee air and water quality, chemical safety, toxic chemicals, and children’s health, and its research division is responsible for answering key questions that others within the agency rely on to develop policies. This split of duties has allowed its researchers to produce independent science detailing, among other things, the health impacts of algal blooms, soot exposure, and toxic chemicals such as hexavalent chromium, &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/ethylene-oxide-georgia-medical-supply-warehouses-worker-health/&quot;&gt;ethylene&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/ethylene-oxide-puerto-rico-chemical-salinas-worker-health/&quot;&gt;oxide&lt;/a&gt;, formaldehyde, and chloroprene.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This work provides the foundation for many of the environmental and public health regulations safeguarding people nationwide. For instance, its work was central to regulation of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, a class of compounds abbreviated as &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food/here-are-the-chances-your-water-supply-is-contaminated-by-forever-chemicals/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tooltipsall tooltipsincontent classtoolTips4&quot;&gt;PFAS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and nicknamed “forever chemicals” because they do not easily degrade in the environment. Nearly two decades ago, EPA researchers collected water samples along the Cape Fear River in North Carolina where &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/un-declares-pfas-pollution-in-north-carolina-a-human-rights-violation/&quot;&gt;a chemical facility was discharging its waste&lt;/a&gt;. They found these chemicals in the samples, and in the drinking water supply for the nearby city of Wilmington. This research made the ubiquity of PFAS clear and established that the public was being exposed to it through drinking water.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the years since, the Office of Research and Development helped develop methods to identify and measure PFAS in the environment, understand the risks of human exposure, and develop the technologies that would destroy them, said Jennifer Orme-Zavaleta, who worked at the EPA for 40 years and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.environmentalprotectionnetwork.org/about/board-of-directors/&quot;&gt;led the research office during part of President Trump’s first term&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, the agency finalized the &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/epa-finalizes-the-nations-first-pfas-limits-in-drinking-water/&quot;&gt;first rules governing PFAS levels in drinking water&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The office has “played a huge role in characterizing and opening our awareness of the contamination of our environment by PFAS compounds,” Orme-Zavaleta said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Without the research office, it’s unclear where the EPA might turn for scientific analysis. To a degree, officials could increasingly classify decisions as policy rather than science-based and minimize, or skip, research altogether. Some functions could shift to other parts of the agency, like the Office of Chemical Safety and Pollution Prevention, which is now headed by Nancy Beck, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eenews.net/articles/epa-walks-back-nancy-becks-chemical-office-powers/&quot;&gt;a former chemical industry lobbyist&lt;/a&gt;. The government also could simply rely upon science funded by the very industries it regulates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“That’s the fox guarding the hen house,” said the senior official. “The EPA makes critical decisions that determine our public health. Do you want those informed by industry hearsay or real facts?”&lt;br&gt;Eliminating the Office of Research and Development is the most drastic proposal from the Trump administration to reshape the EPA — but it’s unlikely to be the last. The research office accounts for just 10 percent of the agency’s resources, according to Orme-Zavaleta, a short way toward &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eenews.net/articles/zeldin-65-percent-epa-budget-cut-is-a-low-number/&quot;&gt;Zeldin’s stated goal&lt;/a&gt; of eliminating 65 percent of the agency’s spending. As Orme-Zavaleta puts it, “many more shoes are going to be dropping.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/politics/caught-off-guard-epa-proposes-to-fire-hundreds-of-scientists/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/politics/caught-off-guard-epa-proposes-to-fire-hundreds-of-scientists/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 16:42:45 GMT</pubDate><author>Naveena Sadasivam, Tik Root</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2204326341.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Politics</category><category>Regulation</category><category>Science</category></item><item><title>Gavin Newsom delayed his own ‘nation-leading’ plastic policy. Why?</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Three years ago, California Governor Gavin Newsom, a Democrat, signed off on &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/regulation/california-new-legislation-fights-plastic-pollution/&quot;&gt;the country’s strongest plastic reduction policy&lt;/a&gt;. The legislation, known as SB 54, gave the state recycling agency until 2025 to write rules to dramatically slash sales of single-use plastic. At the time, Newsom called the law “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.ca.gov/2022/06/30/governor-newsom-signs-legislation-cutting-harmful-plastic-pollution-to-protect-communities-oceans-and-animals/&quot;&gt;nation-leading&lt;/a&gt;,” and said he was “holding polluters responsible and cutting plastics at the source.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;California’s recycling agency, CalRecycle, has been crafting rules around the law’s implementation since 2022, negotiating the specifics with industry groups and environmental advocates and &lt;a href=&quot;https://calrecycle.ca.gov/Laws/Rulemaking/SB54Regulations/&quot;&gt;incorporating public feedback&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier this month, however, the governor’s office unexpectedly rejected CalRecycle’s proposed rules. He told the agency to go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/environment/story/2025-03-07/newsom-fails-to-greenlight-landmark-plastic-legislation&quot;&gt;back to the drawing board&lt;/a&gt;, leaving California no closer to addressing its plastic waste management problem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s kind of like we just got slapped with a wet fish,” said Shira Lane, founder and CEO of a zero-waste organization in Sacramento called Atrium 916. Lane said she’d participated in two years of long, complicated meetings with CalRecycle officials to provide input on the regulations, and that it was unclear why the governor had now decided to reject them. His office’s statements on the issue pointed only vaguely to concerns about fairness and “minimizing costs for small businesses and working families.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Newsom’s one-eighty arrived as plastics industry groups — many of which claim publicly to support the legislation —&amp;nbsp;ramped up complaints behind closed doors about the potential impact of the law. In the absence of a clear explanation from the governor, many environmental groups suspect that he responded to industry pressure. “A lot of people were hurt,” Lane said, describing the good-faith effort they had put into shaping the rules only for them to be rejected for unclear reasons.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When it passed in 2022, SB 54 was hailed as the United States’ “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.santacruzworks.org/news/monterey-bay-aquarium-cheers-enactment-of-senate-bill-54-the-ca-plastic-pollution-producer-responsibility-act&quot;&gt;most comprehensive policy for reducing sources of plastic waste&lt;/a&gt;,” and a “&lt;a href=&quot;https://oceanconservancy.org/news/sb54-california-ocean-conservancy-win/&quot;&gt;huge win&lt;/a&gt;” in the fight against ocean plastic pollution. It gave companies until 2032 to reduce their in-state sales of single-use plastic packaging and foodware,&amp;nbsp;both by weight and by the number of items, by 25 percent. It also required them to achieve significantly higher recycling rates for plastic products, finance a $500 million annual fund to clean up existing pollution, and make all of their single-use packaging and foodware — even if it wasn’t made of plastic —&amp;nbsp;recyclable or compostable by 2032.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;CalRecycle was in charge of writing more specific rules to enforce the law, like delineating which products it applied to. Another body, known in industry parlance as a “producer responsibility organization,” would coordinate companies’ cooperation, requiring plastic producers to become paying members, managing the $500 million fund, and making sure the industry was complying with the law. An existing organization called Circular Action Alliance, composed of plastics industry representatives, was designated as the producer responsibility organization for SB 54.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;SB 54 had gained ground in the California legislature thanks to the threat of a more aggressive &lt;a href=&quot;https://oag.ca.gov/system/files/initiatives/pdfs/19-0028A1%20%28Recycling%20Products%20%29.pdf&quot;&gt;ballot initiative&lt;/a&gt;, which would have given plastic producers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sacbee.com/news/politics-government/capitol-alert/article262783748.html&quot;&gt;less control&lt;/a&gt; over the implementation of plastic reduction targets, placed a 1-cent-per-item tax on plastic producers and distributors, and banned polystyrene food packaging outright.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/overflowing-trashcan.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Trash overflowing&quot; data-caption=&quot;A trash can overflowing with plastic and other waste.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A trash can overflowing with plastic and other waste.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Supporters of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sos.ca.gov/administration/news-releases-and-advisories/2021-news-releases-and-advisories/sw21038&quot;&gt;referendum&lt;/a&gt;, which had received the requisite 623,212 signatures to be included on the ballot, mostly included grassroots environmental groups. The initiative’s three sponsors &lt;a href=&quot;https://calmatters.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Statement-from-Linda-Escalante-Caryl-Hart-PhD-Michael-J.-Sangiacomo.pdf&quot;&gt;agreed to withdraw it&lt;/a&gt; in exchange for the passage of SB 54, which was seen as preferable by business and industry groups. The American Chemistry Council, for instance — a plastics and petrochemical trade group — said in 2022 that SB 54 was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanchemistry.com/chemistry-in-america/news-trends/press-release/2022/american-chemistry-council-comments-on-sb-54-and-the-outstanding-anti-plastics-ballot-measure&quot;&gt;not the optimal legislation to drive California toward a circular economy&lt;/a&gt;,” but that it was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanchemistry.com/chemistry-in-america/news-trends/press-release/2022/acc-statement-on-california-ballot-initiative-withdrawal&quot;&gt;better outcome&lt;/a&gt; than the withdrawn ballot initiative. The group pledged to “work constructively with lawmakers and CalRecycle to support appropriate implementation of SB 54.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The California Chamber of Commerce similarly said that the policy would ensure “&lt;a href=&quot;https://advocacy.calchamber.com/2022/06/30/calchamber-issues-statement-on-sb-54/&quot;&gt;long-term policy certainty around recycling and packaging&lt;/a&gt;.” The Plastics Industry Association declined to endorse SB 54 but said it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plasticstoday.com/legislation-regulations/california-passes-nation-s-toughest-law-targeting-single-use-plastics&quot;&gt;better than the ballot initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Still, industry groups appeared to hold out hope in 2022 that unidentified changes would be made to the legislation. The American Chemistry Council vowed to “support subsequent legislation to make the necessary improvements to help ensure the intent of SB 54 is carried out effectively.” The California Chamber of Commerce’s president noted that the bill “allows the Legislature to make changes to the proposal in the future,” and the president of the California Business Roundtable said in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://calmatters.org/commentary/2022/11/plastic-advanced-recycling-california-turf/&quot;&gt;CalMatters op-ed&lt;/a&gt; that lawmakers should “come back to the conversation prepared to make changes that can open doors for a more circular economy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;After the passage of the law, CalRecycles held &lt;a href=&quot;https://calrecycle.ca.gov/packaging/packaging-epr/pastevents/&quot;&gt;several information sessions&lt;/a&gt; and workshops about its forthcoming rules, with opportunities for participation from the public and plastic producers. The agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.calrecycle.ca.gov/PublicNotices/Details/5387&quot;&gt;began the formal rulemaking process&lt;/a&gt; for SB 54 on March 8, 2024 and held two comment periods, during which industry groups provided feedback, over the course of that year. CalRecycles finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://resource-recycling.com/plastics/2024/11/06/sb-54-draft-rules-spark-debate-over-rates-review/&quot;&gt;drafting the regulations&lt;/a&gt; in the fall, and in September began &lt;a href=&quot;https://calrecycle.ca.gov/packaging/packaging-epr/&quot;&gt;notifying industry groups&lt;/a&gt; that they would soon be going into effect. The rules were set to be adopted one year from the start of rulemaking, on March 8, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Ben Allen, a Democratic senator who represents parts of Los Angeles and who sponsored SB 54, learned that industry groups objected to the rules less than a week before the March 8 deadline. He sat down with Circular Action Alliance and came up with what he called a “roadmap” to address their concerns: If industry groups would not object to CalRecycle’s regulations moving forward on schedule, then he and other lawmakers would pass legislation to make minor changes to the law itself and to empower CalRecycle to make slight adjustments to the rules it had spent so long working on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The proposed changes, laid out in a letter shared with Grist, included exemptions for biosciences packaging, less frequent reporting from packaging companies, and a more lenient timeline for plastic producers to become members of the producer responsibility organization. Allen said he had nearly reached a compromise by the time the governor’s office made its announcement. “People were not expecting the governor to pull back the drafted regulations,” Allen said. “That was a surprising development.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Newsom’s office declined to say whether it had held meetings with business or industry groups, and emphasized that the rulemaking delay would not change “the timeline” for SB 54, presumably referring to the statutory deadlines for plastic companies to reduce the amount of packaging they sell and meet certain recycling rates. When asked to elaborate on its cost concerns, a spokesperson for the governor pointed Grist to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://calrecycle.ca.gov/laws/rulemaking/sb54regulations/&quot;&gt;regulatory impact assessment&lt;/a&gt; published by CalRecycle last October, which estimated SB 54-related compliance costs for California businesses and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Ben-Allen.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Senator Allen (right) hands papers to a colleague (left)&quot; data-caption=&quot;California state Senator Ben Allen, right, confers with Senator Mike McGuire in 2023.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;AP Photo / Rich Pedroncelli&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;California state Senator Ben Allen, right, confers with Senator Mike McGuire in 2023.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;AP Photo / Rich Pedroncelli&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For businesses that sell more than $1 million of products covered by SB 54 each year, the annual costs would average about $791,000, the report found. The typical small businesses would see increased expenses of just $309. Households could end up paying a mean of $329 a year by 2032, though the report said this number would likely be mitigated by increases in personal income, as well as health and environmental benefits totaling more than $40 billion over 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Allen objected to Newsom’s characterization of the bill’s toll on entrepreneurs and families. The whole point of the bill, he said, was to address an “untenable” rise in the cost of waste collection and pollution management in California, as cities are being &lt;a href=&quot;https://lbpost.com/news/city/trash-rates-increase-long-beach-organic-waste&quot;&gt;forced&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.berkeleyside.org/2023/05/22/berkeley-trash-collection-bill-rate-hike&quot;&gt;manage&lt;/a&gt; ever-increasing amounts of plastic garbage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We knew that there might be some modest increases in consumer costs, but they would be more than made up for in ratepayer benefits on the back end,” he added.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Of the six business and industry groups that Grist reached out to, only Circular Action Alliance elaborated on its specific concerns over CalRecycle’s proposed rules for SB 54. A spokesperson said these had involved “clarifying producer obligations, compiling data to build the program plan, and fixing timing and sequencing issues.” The group said it had “actively engaged with interested parties” including the governor’s office, CalRecycle, and Allen “to address any feasibility concerns and ensure the successful implementation of the legislation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We look forward to continued engagement with all parties to move SB 54 forward,” the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Two groups —&amp;nbsp;the American Chemistry Council and California Chamber of Commerce —&amp;nbsp;sent Grist statements affirming their support for SB 54. The California Business Roundtable, the California Retailers Association, and the Plastics Industry Association did not respond to Grist’s requests for comment, though Plastics Industry Association President and CEO Matt Seaholm released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plasticsindustry.org/newsroom/plastics-industry-association-responds-to-governor-newsoms-directive-to-restart-sb-54-regulatory-negotiations/&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; calling for policymakers “to craft practical, effective regulations that drive economic growth, foster innovation, and enhance circularity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In the absence of clearer information about Newsom’s intentions, environmental advocates are concerned that business and industry groups are trying to claw back parts of the statute, despite their nominal support for it in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The more they can delay the implementation, the more they can make a case for the deadlines being unreasonable,” said Jennifer Savage, associate director of California policy for the nonprofit Surfrider.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Plastic makers and business groups are already seizing on the SB 54 kerfuffle to argue that similar legislation shouldn’t be pursued in other jurisdictions. Last weekend, more than 100 companies and groups signed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/f/?id=00000195-8220-d055-affd-a3367d740000&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; obtained by Politico opposing a proposed New York bill on the grounds that it would “go beyond the California statute in key areas, … indicating that the impacts of New York’s proposal would be even more severe.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Allen said the governor’s office wants to move “expeditiously” to complete CalRecycle’s revisions by this summer. That includes initiating another 45-day public comment period, incorporating any changes, and submitting final documents to the state’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://oal.ca.gov/&quot;&gt;Office of Administrative Law&lt;/a&gt; to make sure they are clear and legal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Nick Lapis, director of advocacy for the nonprofit Californians Against Waste, said his organization will be ready to participate however possible, whether by engaging in a public workshop or by submitting written comments on a draft of the new rules. He also hinted that the ballot initiative that environmentalists withdrew when SB 54 was passed may still be on the table.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We remain committed to reevaluating all possible avenues,” Lapis said, “including reviving the initiative to let voters decide on this.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/regulation/newsom-delays-nation-leading-sb-54-plastic-policy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/regulation/newsom-delays-nation-leading-sb-54-plastic-policy/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Joseph Winters</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/gavin-newsom.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Politics</category><category>Regulation</category></item></channel></rss>