<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0"><channel><title>Gist Latest Articles</title><link>https://grist.org/articles</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.henry.wang/grist" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Latest Articles on grist.org - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:05:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>14</ttl><item><title>Alaska Natives want the US military to clean up its toxic waste</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In June 1942, Japan’s invasion of the Aleutian islands in Alaska prompted the U.S. military to activate the Alaska territorial guard, an Army reserve made up of volunteers who wanted to help protect the U.S. So many of the volunteers were from Alaska’s Indigenous peoples —&amp;nbsp;Aleut, Inupiak, Yupik, Tlingit, and many others —&amp;nbsp;that the guard was nicknamed the “Eskimo Scouts.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When World War II ended and the reserve force ceased operations in 1947, the U.S. approached the Indigenous Yupik people of Alaska with another ask: Could the Air Force set up “listening posts” on the island of Sivuqaq, also known as St. Lawrence Island, to help with the intelligence gathering needed to win the Cold War?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Viola Waghiyi, who is Yupik from Sivuqaq, said the answer was a resounding yes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Our grandfathers and fathers volunteered for the Alaska territorial guard,” she said. “We were very patriotic.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But that trust was abused, Waghiyi said. The U.S. military eventually abandoned its Air Force and Army bases, leaving the land polluted with toxic chemicals such as fuel, mercury, and polychlorinated biphenyls, or PCBs, that are known as “forever chemicals” because they persist so long in the environment. The contamination was &lt;a href=&quot;https://dec.alaska.gov/spar/csp/sites/st-lawrence/&quot;&gt;largely due&lt;/a&gt; to spilled and leaking fuel from storage tanks and pipes, both above ground and below ground. More chemical waste came from electrical transformers, abandoned metals and 55-gallon drums.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Now, Waghiyi is the environmental health and justice program director at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akaction.org/&quot;&gt;Alaska Community Action on Toxics&lt;/a&gt;, an organization dedicated to limiting the effects of toxic substances on Alaska’s residents and environment. Last week, the organization filed a complaint to the United Nations special rapporteur on toxics and human rights, in partnership with the U.C. Berkeley Environmental Law Clinic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Their complaint calls for the United Nations to investigate how military waste on Sivuqaq continues to violate the rights of the people who live there, such as the right to a clean and healthy environment and Indigenous peoples’ right to free, prior, and informed consent to what happens on their land.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“By exposing the Yupik people of Sivuqaq to polluted drinking water sources, air, and soil, and by contaminating local native foods; by causing pervasive human exposure to hazardous chemicals through multiple routes; by toxifying the broader ecosystem; and by not cleaning up contamination sufficiently to protect human health and the environment, the U.S. Air Force and Army Corps of Engineers violated human rights long recognized in international law,” the complaint says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;This submission from Alaska is part of a larger, global effort to raise awareness of military toxic waste by the United Nations. The U.N. special rapporteur on toxics and human rights is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohchr.org/en/calls-for-input/2025/call-input-military-activities-and-toxics&quot;&gt;collecting public input on military activities and toxic waste&lt;/a&gt; until April 1. The information collected will be used in a report presented to the U.N. General Assembly in October.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The two shuttered bases in Sivuqaq, Alaska, are now classified as “formerly used defense,” or FUD, sites, overseen by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, and more than $130 million has been spent to remove the contamination. John Budnick, a spokesman for the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers in Alaska, said the cleanup is considered complete but that the agency is reviewing the site every five years “to ensure the selected remedies continue to be protective of human health and the environment.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We have completed the work at Northeast Cape, but additional follow-up actions may result from the monitoring phase of the Formerly Used Defense Sites Program,” he said. The last site visit occurred last July and an updated review report is expected to be released this summer.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The federal Environmental Protection Agency, or EPA, similarly concluded in 2013 that an additional EPA cleanup wouldn’t significantly differ from what the Army Corps of Engineers is doing and declined to place the sites on the EPA’s list of hazardous waste cleanup priorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A 2022 study found that so far, federal cleanup efforts have been inadequate. “High levels of persistent organic pollutants and toxic metals continue to leach from the Northeast Cape FUD site despite large-scale remediation that occurred in the early 2000s,” the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9078153/#:~:text=.%2C%202016).-,Sivuqaq%20(St.,be%20contaminated%20with%20these%20contaminants.&quot;&gt;authors concluded&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The persisting pollution has garnered the attention of Alaska’s state &lt;a href=&quot;https://dec.alaska.gov/spar/csp/sites/st-lawrence/&quot;&gt;Dept. of Environmental Conservation&lt;/a&gt; which oversees the cleanup of contaminated sites. Stephanie Buss, contaminated sites program manager at the agency, said her office has asked the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to do additional cleanup at Northeast Cape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“These active contaminated sites have not met closure requirements,” she said. The second former base, Gambell, was classified as completed but still lacks land use controls, she noted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“DEC takes community health concerns seriously and will continue to provide oversight of the conditions at its active sites in accordance with the state’s regulatory framework to ensure an appropriate response that protects human health and welfare,” Buss said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;That same 2022 study found that 89 percent of the fish around the Northeast Cape base contained mercury exceeding the levels the EPA deemed appropriate for people who rely on subsistence fishing. “All fish sampled near the FUD site exceeded the EPA’s PCB guidelines for cancer risk for unrestricted human consumption,” the researchers further found. Waghiyi said the contamination displaced 130 people, and has left her friends and family with a lasting legacy of illness.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s not a matter of if we’ll get cancer, but when,” Waghiyi said. Her father died of cancer. Her mother had a stillborn child. Waghiyi herself is a cancer survivor and has had three miscarriages.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We feel that they have turned their back on us,” Waghiyi said of the U.S. military. “We wanted our lands to be turned back in the same condition when they turned over.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The U.S. military has a long history of contaminating lands and waters through military training and battles sites, including on Indigenous lands. Citizens of the Navajo Nation in Arizona and&amp;nbsp; Yakama Nation in Washington continue to raise concerns about the ongoing effects of military nuclear testing on their lands and health. In the Marshall Islands, fishing around certain atolls is discouraged due to high rates of toxicity due to nuclear testing and other military training. On Guam, chemicals from an active Air Force base have contaminated parts of the islandʻs sole-source aquifer that serves 70% of the population. Last year, a federal report found that climate change &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/indigenous/decades-after-the-us-buried-nuclear-waste-abroad-climate-change-could-unearth-it/&quot;&gt;threatens to unearth&lt;/a&gt; even more U.S. military nuclear waste in both the Marshall Islands and Greenland.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In 2021, the Navy in Hawaiʻi poisoned 90,000 people when jet fuel leached from aging, massive underground storage tanks into the drinking water supply after the Navy ignored years of warning to upgrade the tanks or remove the fuel. The federal government spent hundreds of millions of dollars to remove unexploded ordnance from the island of Kahoʻolawe, a former bombing range in Hawaiʻi, but the island is still considered dangerous to walk on because of the risk of more ordnance unearthing due to extensive erosion.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The complaint filed last week by the Alaska Community Action on Toxics calls for the United Nations to write to U.S. federal and state agencies and call upon them to honor a 1951 agreement between the U.S. government and the Sivuqaq Yupik people that prohibited polluting the land.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The agreement said that the Sivuqaq Tribes would allow the Air Force to construct surveillance sites to spy on the Soviet Union, but they had four conditions, including allowing Indigenous peoples to continue to hunt, fish and trap where desired and preventing outsiders from killing their game. Finally, the agreement said that “any refuse or garbage will not be dumped in streams or near the beach within the proposed area.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The import of the agreement was clear: The military must not despoil the island; must protect the resources critical to Indigenous Yupik inhabitants’ sustenance; and must leave the island in the condition they found it, which ensured their health and well-being,” the Alaska Community Action on Toxics wrote in their complaint.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This is a burden we didn’t create,” Waghiyi said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/indigenous/alaska-natives-want-the-u-s-military-to-clean-up-its-toxic-waste/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/indigenous/alaska-natives-want-the-u-s-military-to-clean-up-its-toxic-waste/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Anita Hofschneider</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Alaska-Photo-Formatted.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Indigenous Affairs</category></item><item><title>You rely on this agency’s data for weather and climate forecasts. DOGE is decimating its workforce.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Late last month, Rebecca Howard was fired from her dream job. With less than two hours’ notice, the research biologist was told to leave her position with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or NOAA, surveying Alaskan shellfish and pollock populations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Howard is one of the more than 1,000 employees affected by the recent layoffs at NOAA. As a science branch of the Department of Commerce, the agency plays a crucial role in climate research, ecosystem restoration, and oversight of commercial fisheries. The National Weather Service, which provides the data that powers weather apps on phones and informs local meteorologists, is an agency within NOAA.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As part of the Trump administration’s effort to slash the federal budget across various departments, over the last month the agency has fired hundreds of probationary employees — staff that were hired or promoted to a new position in the last year — regardless of their duties.&amp;nbsp; The agency is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/noaa-job-cuts-weather-forecasts-trump-doge-musk-7e35e9d5d757d8fc3f0f50b2bd71c87d&quot;&gt;reportedly preparing to lay off an additional 1,029 employees&lt;/a&gt;, representing a cumulative 20 percent reduction of its workforce. Last week, federal judges in California and Maryland ordered the Trump administration to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-judge-extend-block-trump-administration-ordering-mass-firings-2025-03-13/&quot;&gt;rehire&lt;/a&gt; probationary staffers who were let go.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Howard was one of the probationary employees affected by the first round of layoffs, and said the fisheries management projects she was involved in were being conducted by understaffed teams. As researchers like her leave, she said it’s not clear how the work will continue.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“We need these types of data to know how many fish and crabs we can catch each year, where those populations are going as the oceans change, and to keep track of environmental trends,” Howard said during a press conference organized by Senator Patty Murray, a Democrat representing Washington. Howard pointed out that when a survey of shellfish in the Bering Sea was missed in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic, Alaska’s $200 million snow crab fishery &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/feature-story/snow-crab-collapse-due-ecological-shift-bering-sea#:~:text=NOAA%20Fisheries%20scientists%20attribute%20the,well%20suited%20to%20Arctic%20conditions.&quot;&gt;collapsed&lt;/a&gt; the following year. “Firing people like me will make it incredibly hard for NOAA Fisheries to fulfill its mission,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Department of Government Efficiency, the budget-cutting entity spearheaded by Elon Musk, has also proposed terminating leases for 19 properties used by NOAA for its operations. Separately, the General Services Administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/statement-regarding-gsas-disposal-of-noncore-assets-03042025&quot;&gt;designated an additional 13 buildings&lt;/a&gt; owned by the agency as “not core to government operations.” The buildings include law enforcement offices for fisheries, a control room that oversees a fleet of 15 weather satellites, and an information center that houses more than a century of climate data archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Climate scientists are also worried about the possible closure of an office that supports the Mauna Loa Observatory, which supplies the longest-running record of atmospheric carbon dioxide measurements. The research station supplies the data behind the Keeling Curve, a graph that shows how much of the planet-warming gas has accumulated in the atmosphere since it was established in 1958.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Political leadership in this administration doesn’t know the agency’s mission, and they don’t care,” said Richard Spinrad, the former NOAA chief who led the agency during the Biden administration, during the press conference. “These actions are not the strategic moves of a government looking out for its pockets. They are the unnecessary and malicious acts of a shambolic administration.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;NOAA’s $9.8 billion budget represents just &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/7267889/climate-cost-of-trump-staff-cuts-noaa-nasa/&quot;&gt;0.097 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all federal spending, and its employees represent less than 0.5 percent of the entire federal workforce. But because of the agency’s wide-ranging duties and the indiscriminate nature of the cuts, Spinrad says the damage will be felt through virtually “every business sector, every geographic region of the country, and every component of American society.” And as extreme weather services — like flood forecasts, hurricane outlooks, tsunami warnings, and wildfire monitoring — are compromised, American lives will be threatened, he said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The reduction in staff is already hampering operations. The agency has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wxxinews.org/2025-03-12/national-weather-service-suspends-vital-ny-weather-monitoring-after-trumps-staffing-cuts&quot;&gt;suspended the launch of some weather balloons&lt;/a&gt;, which are a key tool in recording atmospheric conditions and real-time storm tracking. NOAA launches these balloons daily to collect crucial data, and without it, weather forecasts could become less accurate over time. The agency has also canceled its long-standing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/13/noaa-cancels-global-warming-briefings-cuts&quot;&gt;monthly briefings&lt;/a&gt; with reporters about seasonal forecasts and global climate conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The cuts already have been hugely disruptive, and the impacts are growing,” Daniel Swain, a climate scientist at the University of California, told Grist. “Some of [the problems] will manifest during extreme events, and then some of them will probably just take some time to show themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Swain pointed to the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/15/g-s1-54089/tornadoes-wildfires-south-missouri-oklahoma&quot;&gt;deadly outbreak of tornadoes and wildfires&lt;/a&gt; as examples of when “the 24/7 life-saving duties of the National Weather Service are on full display.” A spate of&amp;nbsp; wildfires torched nearly 300 homes in Oklahoma, and at least 40 were left dead after a surge of tornadoes and dust storms tore through the Midwest and South. During these types of extreme weather events, NOAA meteorologists provide real-time updates to first responders, issue public alerts, and help local authorities track storms as they develop. But key hubs for this work, such as The Storm Prediction Center in Norman, Oklahoma, are among the NOAA facilities that DOGE is &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/noaas-storm-prediction-center-facility-planned-doge-cuts/story?id=119882272&quot;&gt;considering&lt;/a&gt; closing. Local news outlets reported that there may not be enough staff left to adequately &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oudaily.com/news/national-weather-center-service-ou-meteorology-students-national-oceanic-and-atmospheric-administration-layoffs-cuts/article_4272b898-f572-11ef-9c52-5bb9d5af94c9.html&quot;&gt;respond to tornado events&lt;/a&gt; due to layoffs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This is the kind of moment where you might start to see the tangible, real-world, and genuinely life-threatening impacts of these staffing gaps,” Swain said. “These people, despite being in lifesaving roles, were fired without notice or justification.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On Monday, some NOAA probationary employees who were fired, including Howard, the fisheries research biologist, were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/17/climate-energy-agencies-probationary-employees&quot;&gt;rehired&lt;/a&gt; as mandated by federal court orders. Howard said the reinstatement email she received placed her on administrative leave, and that there’s been “no indication” when she will be allowed to return to work. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I had been working toward a career in marine science since I was a child,” she said. “Being put back in that stressful situation is not something I would look forward to, but this is what I wanted to do with my career.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/politics/you-rely-on-this-agencys-data-for-weather-and-climate-forecasts-doge-is-decimating-its-workforce/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/politics/you-rely-on-this-agencys-data-for-weather-and-climate-forecasts-doge-is-decimating-its-workforce/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:19:25 GMT</pubDate><author>Sachi Kitajima Mulkey</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2202648720.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Utilities are shutting off power to a growing number of households</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Electric utilities across the United States are shutting off power to a growing number of households, according to a recent report that also found most shutoffs happened during last year’s record-hot summer, a reminder that &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/how-climate-change-drives-hotter-more-frequent-heat-waves/&quot;&gt;climate change&lt;/a&gt; fuels more intense, frequent, and prolonged heat waves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Shutoffs can be deadly, especially during extreme freezes and blistering heat. And while health issues are the most worrisome risk, there are other threats to daily life such as losing access to phone, internet, medical equipment, and food storage. Basic physical comfort can prove impossible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biologicaldiversity.org/programs/energy-justice/pdfs/Powerless_Report_2025.pdf?_gl=1*hpe2sd*_gcl_aw*R0NMLjE3MzY4NzA5NDguQ2owS0NRaUFzNWk4QmhEbUFSSXNBR0U0eEh3cml0RnBhekQ5M1o3V2hWTHVtQkpUdjFXZEZrUzdGRU1fS01VMEF1SDhOM1FqTkpEZXdNTWFBbm1JRUFMd193Y0I.*_gcl_au*MTc4MTAyMzI3NC4xNzM2ODcwOTQ4&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by the nonprofit Center for Biological Diversity revealed that six investor-owned utilities disconnected customers between January and September 2024 more than 662,000 times, an over 20 percent jump from the same period in 2023. Those companies included Georgia Power, DTE Energy, Duke Energy, Ameren Corporation, Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric, and Arizona Public Service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But all shutoffs, and the harms they cause, are avoidable, said Selah Goodson Bell, lead author of the report. States and local governments have the power to protect customers by enacting policies like comprehensive shutoff bans during extreme heat and reining in utility rate hikes. While most states already ban shutoffs during cold weather, more and more are starting to ban it during heat waves. “It’s going to be up to cities, municipalities, and states to remedy ongoing energy injustices and hold these utility companies accountable,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It’s hard to know the true extent and nature of shutoffs because only &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;a patchwork of data&lt;/a&gt; exists nationwide. Twenty-two states don’t require utilities to report disconnections at all, and among the ones that do, only 20 states and Washington, D.C., have up-to-date data. Report authors analyzed the six power companies because they provide current disconnection data and collectively serve more than 200 million customers, spanning most regions of the U.S. from California to the Carolinas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Georgia, the state’s largest electric utility Georgia Power disconnected customers for nonpayment over 180,000 times from January to September 2024 — a more than 20 percent increase from the same period in 2023. Duke Energy in North and South Carolina also increased shutoffs by nearly 20 percent last year. DTE Energy in Michigan disconnected customers more than 150,000 times, and Ameren in Illinois and Missouri shut off power more than 120,000 times, with both raising shutoff rates in the past few years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric in California and Phoenix-based Arizona Public Service cut off power to fewer customers than the other utilities, the report still found a steady growth in shutoffs since 2022.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lingering inflation, rate hikes, and climate change have all contributed to the rise in shutoffs, the report found. But the core issue is an “antiquated and broken” utility business model that effectively punishes low-income customers by aggressively raising rates, and then cutting off power when households can’t pay, said Goodson Bell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As shutoffs increased, the six utilities analyzed in the report also netted $10 billion in profits between January and September 2024, a more than 20 percent increase from the same period in 2023. Less than 2 percent of their shareholder dividends would have prevented all shutoffs last year, the report found. “Customers are losing access to an essential service they need to survive while shareholders line their pockets with lavish returns,” Goodson Bell said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Besides using more electricity to cope with extreme temperatures, customers are also paying for the mounting costs of repairing and hardening the grid after disasters like wildfires or hurricanes. Yet the report documents efforts by utilities that would worsen climate-driven costs: Almost all the utilities mentioned in the report have worked to expand gas infrastructure and fossil fuel energy supply, and lobbied to weaken rooftop solar and other climate policies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;digital collage of a Black hand turning off a light switch, an electric meter, and the logo for Xcel Energy&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;A lack of data hampers efforts to fix racial disparities in utility cutoffs&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/akielly-hu/&quot;&gt;Akielly Hu&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Representatives from Ameren, Arizona Public Service, DTE Energy, and PG&amp;amp;E told Grist that disconnection is a last resort, and that the utilities offer a range of energy assistance and flexible payment plans. “We recognize that higher costs, including energy bills, can be a challenge for customers,” said PG&amp;amp;E spokesperson Mike Gazda. Duke Energy and Georgia Power did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For most of the utilities in the report, shutoffs peaked in the summer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While 42 states already ban shutoffs during cold weather, 23 have now passed heat-based shutoff bans, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.leg.wa.gov/billsummary?BillNumber=1329&amp;amp;Year=2023&amp;amp;Initiative=false&quot;&gt;Washington state in 2023&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lis.virginia.gov/cgi-bin/legp604.exe?241+sum+HB906&quot;&gt;Virginia in 2024&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilga.gov/legislation/publicacts/fulltext.asp?Name=103-0019&quot;&gt;Illinois strengthened an existing ban&lt;/a&gt; by lowering the previous threshold of 95 degrees Fahrenheit to 90. That change appears to have already had a measurable impact: According to the Center for Biological Diversity’s report, summertime shutoffs in Illinois were 13 percent lower in 2024 than in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But in Michigan and California, which both have temperature-based shutoff bans for extreme heat, disconnections by DTE Energy and PG&amp;amp;E still peaked during the summer. Temperature-based shutoff bans in those states fail to adequately protect customers because they don’t require utilities to automatically restore power to households that get disconnected prior to a heat event, said Goodson Bell. That means that even if a household gets their power shut off right before a ban takes effect, if they can’t pay in time, “They will be forced to endure harsh conditions without access to electricity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Arizona Public Service, on the other hand, has avoided a summertime spike in shutoffs by using a date-based shutoff moratorium from June 1 to October 15. The policy was &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/arizona-heat-death-legacy-3fce53af423293d9fb15d7889dee9e13&quot;&gt;introduced by state regulators&lt;/a&gt; after Arizona Public Service cut off power to a 72-year-old woman who owed $51 on her electricity bill, resulting in her death in 2018. But even date-based protections may not be enough because extreme heat is increasingly happening on days outside summer months, Goodson Bell pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;States should instead use both temperature and date-based restrictions to widen the period of time customers are protected, and ban shutoffs completely for certain customers such as those with medical conditions, he said. Such measures are small steps to address widespread harms, said Sanya Carley, a professor at the University of Pennsylvania who studies utility disconnections. “When it comes to disconnections, I think states need to adopt as many protections as they possibly can.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Akielly Hu</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Climate &amp;amp; Energy</category><category>Economics</category><category>Extreme Heat</category></item><item><title>‘Our people are hungry’: What federal food aid cuts mean in a warming world</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Every Friday, as he’s done for the last year and a half, Mark Broyles hops in his truck and drives 20 minutes from his home in Big Stone Gap to Duffield, Virginia, to pick up two boxes of free food. Though their contents are always a surprise, as the retired mechanic describes it, he’s able to get “fresh produce and stuff that a lot of us can’t afford because of the price of groceries.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On any given week, the boxes, which are provided by Appalachian Sustainable Development, a local nonprofit food hub that also helps small farmers sell fresh goods to public schools and grocery stores, are filled with lean meat, half a gallon of milk, and an assortment of seasonal produce.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It’s been a lifeline for Broyles, who injured his shoulder in 2022 and has been unable to work since. His mother, who broke an arm and is unable to cook, relies on him for meals. Given the variety of ingredients available to him through the food boxes, the 57-year-old has been expanding his cooking repertoire, whipping up chicken, broccoli, and rice casseroles, apple dump cobbler, and roasted butternut squash. The food ends up feeding Broyles’ family of four, his mother, and her husband. Sometimes, if there were unclaimed boxes at the end of the distribution period, Broyles would pick them up and share them with his neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Not only is it food that you can put on the table, but it’s good food that you can put in your body,” said Broyles. “And it’s good food that can build bonds in the community.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Big Stone Gap is in the mountainous southwest corner of the state, wedged between Kentucky and Tennessee. At the 2020 census, the town recorded a population of 5,254. Nestled in the heart of coal country, more than 80 percent of the residents in the area voted for President Donald Trump in November.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Just last month, the region was hit hard by torrential rain and flash floods. While Broyles escaped the brunt of it, his home is in a floodway, and surging water from the river nearby flooded parts of his yard. “I’m dreading that it’s going to flood again,” said Broyles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A couple of weeks later, the team at Appalachian Sustainable Development learned that the USDA funding they relied on to be able to afford this farm-to-donation work was going to be delayed and they may only end up being reimbursed a portion of a $1.5 million grant that was supposed to last them through July. Then, one of those programs they were counting on for future funding was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/10/usda-cancels-local-food-purchasing-for-schools-food-banks-00222796&quot;&gt;suddenly terminated by the USDA&lt;/a&gt;. So, about a week ago, Appalachian Sustainable Development &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/asdevelop/posts/1215974407201502&quot;&gt;shuttered the food box program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Director of development Sylvia Crum described the situation as “heartbreaking” for the thousands of people throughout Central Appalachia they feed and the 40 farmers they work with that will now lose income. “We don’t have the money,” said Crum. It costs them roughly $30,000 to fill the 2,000 or so boxes that, up until March 7, they distributed every week.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Food insecurity has long been a widespread problem across the region, where residents in parts of Kentucky, for one, grapple with rates of food insecurity that &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10401894/&quot;&gt;more than double the national average&lt;/a&gt;. In the last year alone, a barrage of devastating disasters has magnified the issue, said Crum, causing local demand for the nonprofit’s donation program to reach new highs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“[This region] has really dealt with so much, with the recent hurricanes and mudslides and tornadoes. And our farmers are hurting, and our people are hurting, and our people are hungry,” she said. “It’s an emotional roller coaster for everybody.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Appalachia-Lions-Club-picking-up-food-boxes-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A group of people pack a truck with fresh vegetable food boxes for donation&quot; data-caption=&quot;Volunteers pick up Appalachian Harvest Food Box program donations to distribute throughout the region. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Appalachian Sustainable Development&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Volunteers pick up Appalachian Harvest Food Box program donations to distribute throughout the region. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Appalachian Sustainable Development&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For decades, the USDA has funded several programs that are meant to address the country’s rising food insecurity crisis — a problem that has only worsened as climate change has advanced, the COVID-19 pandemic led to layoffs, and grocery prices have skyrocketed. A network of nonprofit food banks, pantries, and hubs around the country rely extensively on government funding, particularly through the USDA. The Appalachian Sustainable Development is but one of them. The first few months of the Trump administration have plunged the USDA and its network of funding recipients into chaos.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The agency has &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/trump-funding-freeze-usda-us-farms/&quot;&gt;abruptly canceled contracts&lt;/a&gt; with farmers and nonprofits, froze funding for other long-running programs even as the courts have mandated that the Trump administration release funding, and fired thousands of employees, who were then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/trump-administration/usda-ordered-temporarily-reinstate-thousands-fired-employees-rcna194992&quot;&gt;temporarily reinstated as a result of a court order&lt;/a&gt;. Trump’s funding freeze and the USDA’s subsequent gutting of local food system programs has left them without a significant portion of their budgets, money they need to feed their communities. Experts say the administration’s move to axe these resources leaves the country’s first line of defense against the surging demand for hunger relief without enough supply.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA disperses funding for food aid groups through multiple programs. Some of them were established &lt;a href=&quot;https://ask.usda.gov/s/article/when-and-why-did-the-emergency-food-assistance-program-start#:~:text=The%20Temporary%20Emergency%20Food%20Assistance,under%20the%201990%20farm%20bill.&quot;&gt;decades ago&lt;/a&gt;, while others are recent additions to the maze of hunger prevention programs shepherded by the agency. Among the more prominent programs are the Resilient Food Systems Infrastructure Program, Local Food Purchase Assistance Program, Local Food for Schools Cooperative Agreement Program, and The Emergency Food Assistance Program. Although each program has a separate mandate, combined, they help nonprofits and community groups purchase food goods from small and mid-sized farms, distribute them to those in need, and bolster local and regional food supply chains.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Over the last few weeks, the USDA has upended that order, cutting billions of dollars for food assistance programs. To get a more comprehensive understanding of the fallout from the chaos, Grist reached out to the state agriculture departments for nine states. Here’s what we learned.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA has ended future rounds of funding for the Local Food Purchase Assistance Program and the Local Food for Schools Cooperative Agreement Program. The two programs were slated to dole out $1.13 billion throughout the ongoing fiscal year to states, tribes, and territories, which would then distribute funding to emergency food providers, childcare centers, and schools. Additionally, farm and food programs like the Working Lands Conservation Corps as well as seven other programs have had funding frozen while another three have had individual contracts canceled, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://civileats.com/food-policy-tracker/#usda-unfreezes-20-million-in-conservation-funds&quot;&gt;Civil Eats&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At least two major food banks based in the Midwest and Northeast — the Northern Illinois Food Bank and the Central Pennsylvania Food Bank, both of which are part of the Feeding America network — have lost critical funds through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fns.usda.gov/tefap/fy25-ccc-funding#:~:text=The%20CCC%20funds%20are%20being,Foods%20for%20distribution%20through%20TEFAP.&quot;&gt;The Emergency Food Assistance Program&lt;/a&gt;, or TEFAP, which was established in 1981 to provide direct food assistance to low-income families. It is a primary way that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fns.usda.gov/tefap/allocation-disaster-supplemental-appropriations&quot;&gt;states and the federal government&lt;/a&gt; have distributed food to local communities in the aftermath of a climate-fueled disaster like a &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/hunger-was-already-bad-enough-then-beryl-hit/&quot;&gt;hurricane or heatwave&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The USDA stopped the flow of some of the money that pays for products like meats, eggs, and vegetables that are termed “bonus commodities” through TEFAP. Normally, those bonus commodities are distributed to charitable food organizations where they show up as monthly shipments. (The first Trump administration initiated this additional funding in 2018 as part of an effort to bailout farmers suffering from retaliatory tariffs in the U.S.-China trade war.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Robert Desio, a senior manager of public policy and benefits at the Northern Illinois Food Bank, said that without those shipments the quantity and quality of food they will be able to serve will be greatly reduced. About 570,000 residents depend on Northern Illinois; since October, the food bank has distributed roughly 3.1 million meals made up of bonus commodities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The loss of that program is now compounding with the loss of future Local Food Purchase Assistance funding, a “significant chunk of money” that, for Northern Illinois, Desio said would have amounted to an estimated $1.5 million. They’re also waiting on $165,000 in reimbursements they already spent against the grant this year — before the USDA began freezing and rescinding funds — that they aren’t sure they’ll get back.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We are already serving more neighbors than ever,” said Desio. An even bigger issue, he said, is that nobody — from the state to the USDA — seems to know exactly what’s going on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/its-demoralizing-trumps-climate-funding-freeze-has-left-tribes-and-community-groups-in-limbo/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2196460551.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;activists holding sign that says unfreeze the federal funds now&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2196460551.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2196460551.jpg?resize=330%2C220&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2196460551.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-2196460551.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/its-demoralizing-trumps-climate-funding-freeze-has-left-tribes-and-community-groups-in-limbo/&quot;&gt;‘It’s demoralizing’: Trump’s climate funding freeze has left tribes and community groups in limbo&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/naveena-sadasivam/&quot;&gt;Naveena Sadasivam&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Policy analyst Teon Hayes of the Center for Law and Social Policy said the funding freeze and corresponding food and farm program terminations are going to “send a shockwave” throughout the nation, given the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2024/11/28/food-insecurity-banks-holiday-season&quot;&gt;growing demand&lt;/a&gt; for charitable food donations. “A federal funding freeze of this magnitude definitely amplifies this strain, and the reduction in funding of these programs … is definitely going to weaken local food systems,” said Hayes. All of this is compounding with an ongoing push by Congressional Republicans to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/02/12/congress/house-gop-budget-targets-snap-cuts-00203872&quot;&gt;drastically reduce nutrition program funding&lt;/a&gt; in the farm bill and the budget reconciliation bill, she said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The team at the Central Pennsylvania Food Bank is also scrambling amid all the uncertainty, said CEO Joe Arthur. Earlier this month, their bonus commodities-funded shipments and Local Food Purchase Assistance funding, which amounts to about 12 percent of their food budget every month, were canceled, too.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The sudden dearth of federal funding has forced them to pull the plug on a farm-to-donation acquisition program. That money allowed them to source fresh goods like milk, eggs, and meat directly from local farmers, which was then donated to hungry families across 27 counties statewide.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We’re hustling like crazy to raise food from our food donors and money from our financial donors. But these two sources are substantial, and you just really can’t make them up privately,” said Arthur.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The state agricultural departments that Grist reached out to said they receive tens of millions in funding for food aid from the USDA. A spokesperson for the Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture said the agency has been awarded more than $55 million through five USDA programs to fight hunger and promote resilient food systems in the state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Federal funding from the USDA is critical to our ability to serve Pennsylvanians who struggle with food insecurity, including vulnerable seniors and families with children,” the spokesperson said. “Frozen or reduced funding will hurt these families.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Neither Feeding America nor the USDA responded to Grist’s requests for comment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k21W82bOup8&amp;amp;t=354s&quot;&gt;interview last week with Fox News&lt;/a&gt;, USDA secretary Brooke Rollins said, “We will use every tool that we have as we move into the next few months, the next year, and beyond to ensure that our farmers are protected.” Much of her pitch for helping “family farmers” had to do with incentivizing international trade for their products. So far, though, the Trump administration has imposed harsh tariffs on the U.S.’s biggest trade partners, which has only resulted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/what-trumps-escalating-trade-wars-mean-for-your-grocery-bill/&quot;&gt;counter tariffs that overwhelmingly target American farmers&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When asked to justify the funding cuts, Rollins responded, “We spend billions and billions and billions of dollars on nutrition programs for lower income and socioeconomically disadvantaged kids, but the Biden administration used that to often push money out, taxpayer dollars out, that is not reaching its intended target. … We’re pulling that back.” Rollins continued, “As we have always said, if we are making mistakes, we will own those mistakes and we will reconfigure.” Without specifying which discontinued food programs she was referring to, Rollins reiterated that the cuts were limited to “nonessential” programs, or what she termed, “an effort by the left to continue spending taxpayer dollars that were not necessary.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-81678111.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A sign in a grocery store asks people to &amp;quot;please donate food&amp;quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Food banks across the U.S. are seeking increased donations while the demand for food handouts are increasing. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Justin Sullivan / Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Food banks across the U.S. are seeking increased donations while the demand for food handouts are increasing. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Justin Sullivan / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The termination of some USDA programs and the funding standstill of others isn’t merely preventing food banks and pantries from getting the supplies they need to feed the hungry. It has also forced some businesses to cut internal operations. Because of the USDA’s abrupt decisions, 4P Foods, a food hub in Warrenton, Virginia, is out of roughly $4 million, or some 25 percent of the work they had planned for the year. As a result, founder Tom McDougall has had to tell five members of his team he can no longer afford to keep them on payroll.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We work with Virginians, with families with children who’ve been with us for years, who don’t deserve to be laid off, but they are going to be because we will not have food to put into places and deliver it the way that we had planned,” said McDougall.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Still, he’s “cautiously optimistic” that the administration and USDA will reverse course on the decision to pull the plug on these programs that McDougall says are necessary lifelines for communities like his after a disaster strikes — a reality increasingly likely for more people as warming makes many types of extreme weather events more frequent and severe.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“When, not if, &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; the next disaster hits, we’re going to need to turn back to what we did during COVID, which was local and regional supplied [food] webs,” he said. “The next hurricane, who’s going to have food available? We’re going to have food available. We’re going to be able to get into these communities again and again and again. This is a conversation not just about the economy, but about resiliency.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For aid recipients like Broyles, the end of Appalachian Sustainable Development’s food box program means rethinking how to feed his family. For now, he has frozen produce that he can rely on, but in the long term, Broyles said he will either turn to other food programs in the region, even though none of them provide fresh produce, or scour grocery aisles for deals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Mountain folk are very proud people,” Broyles said. “Mountain folk don’t usually ask for help, but sometimes when help is offered, we reluctantly go to get it. … I hope our president and our representatives can see how crucial this program is. Instead of using a broad axe approach to cut some of these programs, that they would go more with the scalpel and trim off the fat.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/our-people-are-hungry-usda-federal-food-aid-cuts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/our-people-are-hungry-usda-federal-food-aid-cuts/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 08:15:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Ayurella Horn-Muller, Naveena Sadasivam</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/ASD-staff-member-stacking-a-food-box-edited.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Food and Agriculture</category><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Trump repeals America’s first-ever tax on greenhouse gases before it goes into effect</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In late February, Republicans in the House and Senate &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/methane-fee-repeal-epa-oil-gas-drilling-4844558bece1e683da9246ee226c57b5&quot;&gt;voted along party lines&lt;/a&gt; to repeal a Biden-era rule implementing a federal tax on &lt;span class=&quot;tooltipsall tooltipsincontent classtoolTips3&quot;&gt;methane&lt;/span&gt; pollution. President Donald Trump &lt;a href=&quot;https://subscriber.politicopro.com/article/eenews/2025/03/17/trump-signs-resolutions-to-undo-methane-fee-offshore-drilling-rules-00232305&quot;&gt;signed the measure into law on Friday&lt;/a&gt; — putting the country’s climate goals further out of reach. Since taking control of the White House and both chambers of Congress this year, Republicans have set about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/02/climate/trump-us-climate-policy-changes.html#:~:text=Trump%20has%20gutted%20federal%20climate,the%20burning%20of%20fossil%20fuels.&quot;&gt;systematically dismantling Biden-era advancements on climate change&lt;/a&gt;, no matter the size or projected economic impact of the policy, with varying degrees of success.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Methane is a powerful but fast-acting greenhouse gas — it packs a big punch in the short term and weakens over time. Studies show methane is responsible for &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/methane/?intent=121&quot;&gt;20 to 30 percent&lt;/a&gt; of global warming since the Industrial Revolution. U.S. oil and gas operations are collectively responsible for emitting &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2024/03/methane-emissions-major-u-s-oil-gas-operations-higher-government-predictions&quot;&gt;more than 6 million metric tons of methane&lt;/a&gt; every year — the equivalent of 10 percent of the country’s annual CO2 emissions, if you’re looking at a greenhouse gas’s first 20 years in the atmosphere. Methane is the primary component of natural gas, which often &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/accountability/the-epas-new-methane-rule-includes-an-innovative-way-to-stop-super-emitters/&quot;&gt;leaks out of drilling sites, pipelines, and storage facilities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;When Joe Biden was elected president in 2020, he made it clear that he intended to become the &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/joe-biden-climate-change-legacy/&quot;&gt;first president in American history&lt;/a&gt; to successfully take on climate change — a goal that necessarily included targeting methane emissions. In 2022, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/16/business/biden-climate-tax-inflation-reduction.html&quot;&gt;signed the Inflation Reduction Act&lt;/a&gt;, or IRA — legislation that offered hundreds of billions of dollars in incentives, loans, and grants to households, utilities, and industries to cut their greenhouse gas emissions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The IRA also amended the Clean Air Act to include a provision that directed the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a methane fee for major producers of oil and gas —&amp;nbsp;essentially, taxing fossil fuel companies for every ton of the greenhouse gas they emitted above a certain threshold. The legislation included subsidies to help producers who emitted methane over the legal limit to install gas-trapping technology to reduce their emissions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The rule the EPA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-finalizes-rule-reduce-wasteful-methane-emissions-and-drive-innovation-oil-and-gas&quot;&gt;finalized in November last year&lt;/a&gt;, technically called the Waste Emissions Charge, would have applied to facilities that produce volumes of methane that exceed the equivalent of 25,000 tons of carbon dioxide. The fee started at $900 per ton of methane in 2024 and would have risen to $1,200 per ton in 2025 and $1,600 in 2026 and every year beyond that. Most big oil and gas companies already meet the standards laid out in Biden’s fee, which means they wouldn’t have had to pay anything. The EPA was supposed to start tallying up fees this year based on 2024 emissions data, but Republicans repealed it before the agency could start collecting penalties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The fee, had it taken effect, would have been the first-ever federal tax directly imposed on a greenhouse gas. It would have applied to roughly a third of the methane emissions that come from oil and gas infrastructure in the U.S. and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-finalizes-rule-reduce-wasteful-methane-emissions-and-drive-innovation-oil-and-gas#:~:text=Also%2C%20as%20directed%20by%20Congress,statutorily%20specified%20methane%20intensity%20levels.&quot;&gt;diverted 1.2 metric tons of methane through 2035&lt;/a&gt; — the equivalent of taking nearly 8 million gas-powered cars offline for a year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Shell, BP, and other oil majors &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/117/meeting/house/112766/documents/HMKP-117-IF00-20210610-SD006.pdf&quot;&gt;supported the initiative&lt;/a&gt;. But other parts of the oil and gas industry, and Republicans in Congress, opposed it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=685&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/GettyImages-1384645555.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Natural gas is flared off during an oil drilling operation in the Permian Basin oil field on March 12, 2022 in Midland, Texas.&quot; data-caption=&quot;Natural gas is flared during an oil drilling operation in the Permian Basin in Andrews, Texas, in 2022. &lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Joe Raedle / Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Natural gas is flared during an oil drilling operation in the Permian Basin in Andrews, Texas, in 2022. &lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Joe Raedle / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“No one wants to do business when the federal government creates regulations that will put them out of business, which is what this natural gas tax is doing,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oaoa.com/local-news/methane-fees-repeal-needs-only-trumps-signature/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; Republican August Pfluger of San Angelo, Texas, the Congressman who wrote the measure that Trump signed on Friday. Pfluger’s district overlaps with the Permian Basin, the highest producing oil field in the U.S. “In reality this rule has only stifled American energy production, discouraged investment, and increased energy prices across America,” he said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Pfluger’s pessimistic view of the health of America’s oil and gas industry is at odds with what official reports say. America’s fossil fuel producers are on a winning streak by every measure. The U.S. is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=61683&quot;&gt;largest exporter of natural gas in the world&lt;/a&gt;, and crude oil and natural gas production &lt;a href=&quot;https://energy.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/oil-and-gas/us-crude-oil-and-natural-gas-output-hit-record-highs-in-december/118643376#:~:text=US%20crude%20oil%20production%20reached,its%20highest%20since%20October%202024.&quot;&gt;hit record highs in December&lt;/a&gt;. The Texas oil and gas industry &lt;a href=&quot;https://texasborderbusiness.com/texas-oil-and-natural-gas-industry-breaks-new-production-records/&quot;&gt;broke new production records&lt;/a&gt; on Monday.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s hard to imagine how a country that’s breaking records for production is being somehow constrained,” said Jon Goldstein, associate vice president of the Environmental Defense Fund’s energy transition program. “I don’t think that argument really holds water.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;However, the tax tackled only a sliver of U.S. methane emissions. The American agricultural and waste sectors &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/article/food-is-a-huge-source-of-methane-emissions-fixing-that-is-no-easy-feat/&quot;&gt;produced almost twice as much methane&lt;/a&gt; as fossil fuel production between 2010 and 2019. But clamping down on emissions from those sectors is challenging. Methane emissions from agriculture come from myriad decentralized sources, like cows and manure storage facilities, making them difficult to regulate. And the amount of methane agriculture produces depends in large part on consumer eating habits, which are hard for the government to control.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Despite its limited impact, the methane fee was a step in the right direction, experts said. “There’s an order of operations in which we need to implement climate solutions,” said Daniel Jasper, the policy director for the climate solutions nonprofit Project Drawdown. “Methane is something we call an emergency brake, because we’ve got to do it now.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The fee is one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/26/climate/republicans-california-waiver-electric-cars.html&quot;&gt;seven climate and environment policies&lt;/a&gt; Republicans in Congress are targeting using the Congressional Review Act — a law that gives lawmakers the authority to reverse recently-passed regulations with a simple majority vote. But Republicans only repealed the EPA rule establishing the methane fee — not the IRA provision permitting the application of such a fee in the first place. If that remains intact, a future presidential administration could pick up where Biden left off. However, Republicans in Congress have signaled that they intend to repeal as much of the IRA as possible in the coming months, &lt;a href=&quot;https://democrats-appropriations.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/democrats-appropriations.house.gov/files/FY24%20House%20Republican%20Cuts%20IRA%20and%20IIJA.pdf&quot;&gt;including the portions&lt;/a&gt; that empower the EPA to crack down on greenhouse gas emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/politics/trump-repeals-americas-first-ever-tax-on-greenhouse-gases-before-it-goes-into-effect/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/politics/trump-repeals-americas-first-ever-tax-on-greenhouse-gases-before-it-goes-into-effect/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:45:56 GMT</pubDate><author>Zoya Teirstein</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-612304712-1.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Energy</category><category>Politics</category><category>Regulation</category></item><item><title>The end of the EPA’s fight to protect overpolluted communities</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The first thing Amanda Cronin did when her supervisor offered her a job at the Environmental Protection Agency was buy herself a big piece of chocolate cake. The 25-year old New York native had spent nine months searching for work in environmental advocacy with little luck, until she stumbled upon a posting for a program analyst in the EPA’s Office of Environmental Justice and External Civil Rights, or OEJECR, based in Washington, D.C. When she joined in May 2023, the Biden Administration was in the midst of a historic push to advance environmental justice nationwide, and the office was buzzing with the energy of a start-up company.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I just felt like I was part of something big and special,” Cronin recalled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;She quickly plunged into the world of environmental justice work, helping to coordinate the EPA’s partnerships with tribes and local advocacy groups, and organizing webinars to inform residents from Arizona to Alabama about federal grants they could apply for to fight the pollution in their backyards. Last November, when Donald Trump won the presidential election on a platform that promised to gut environmental regulation in the nation’s industrial corridors, Cronin knew her days in the agency could be numbered.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Sure enough, on February 6, she and 167 other workers in the office &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/06/politics/epa-workers-administrative-leave/index.html&quot;&gt;were placed&lt;/a&gt; on indefinite leave, and locked out of their federal email accounts. A week later, an additional 388 staffers still in the first year of their positions in the agency &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-administration-terminates-388-epa-staff-2025-02-14/&quot;&gt;were terminated&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While on leave, Cronin filled her time with scuba diving and yoga classes and “trying to maintain a healthy balance of staying informed while also not falling into the doomscroll spiral.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last Tuesday, Cronin got some more bad news: The EPA would begin eliminating all environmental justice offices and positions immediately, including jobs in OEJECR and in the environmental justice offices within the EPA’s 10 regional divisions. In an internal memo, EPA Administrator Lee Zeldin said the move was intended to move the agency into compliance with President Trump’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-radical-and-wasteful-government-dei-programs-and-preferencing/&quot;&gt;January 20 executive order&lt;/a&gt; titled “Ending Radical and Wasteful Government DEI Programs and Preferencing.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While diversity, equity, and inclusion, or DEI, have traditionally been understood as guiding principles for hiring and admissions within corporations and universities, the Trump administration has repeatedly conflated such initiatives with efforts to advance environmental justice, which the agency has, since 2020, &lt;a href=&quot;https://19january2021snapshot.epa.gov/environmentaljustice/ej-2020-glossary_.html&quot;&gt;defined&lt;/a&gt; as the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race or socioeconomic status, in the development and implementation of the nation’s environmental laws and policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s ironic because our work actually aligns with the administration’s stated priorities, which is uplifting poor, working class communities,” Cronin told Grist.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/what-trumps-escalating-trade-wars-mean-for-your-grocery-bill/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;digital collage of hands holding a grocery receipt surrounded by a bottle of tequila, avocado, maple syrup, lime, beer, and chocolate&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 2000w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trmp-tariffs-groceries-2.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1125&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/what-trumps-escalating-trade-wars-mean-for-your-grocery-bill/&quot;&gt;What Trump’s escalating trade wars mean for your grocery bill&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/ayurella-horn-muller/&quot;&gt;Ayurella Horn-Muller&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Contrary to Trump’s politicized messaging that has tied the concept of environmental justice to Biden and Democrats, the EPA established OEJECR in 1992 during president George H.W. Bush’s administration to fight “disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on minority and low-income populations.” Until recently, the office had only several dozen staffers and sat within the agency’s Office of Policy. In 2022, former EPA Administrator Michael Regan &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/perspectives/epas-new-office-environmental-justice-and-external-civil-rights-moment-history&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that OEJECR would be turned into a national program office on par with the Office of Air and Radiation or the Office of Water, and that its staff size would grow to 200 personnel. The decision was “transformative,” said Margot Brown, the senior vice president of environmental justice and equity at the Environmental Defense Fund.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It elevated the need to ensure that every American has clean air, clean water, and safe land to live on,” she explained. “It made it a national priority.” The EPA Administrator meets weekly with the heads of all the agency’s national programs, she continued, meaning that the OEJECR now had direct and routine access to the EPA’s top decision makers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Another former environmental justice staffer, whom we’ll call Tracy, joined the EPA during OEJECR’s hiring blitz and was also fired after Trump took office. (She asked that her name be withheld for fear of affecting her future employment prospects in the agency.) Her job was to help manage cooperative agreements, a term for a special kind of grant issued with substantial government involvement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It was a dream job,” she told Grist in a phone call. “It allowed me to gain more experience in my area of expertise, a wider reach.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Tracy described an energetic work environment with people from a variety of backgrounds and skill sets who had uprooted their jobs and lives in other parts of the country to be part of the Biden Administration’s push for environmental justice. The team of grant makers she was on worked with historically disadvantaged communities to implement environmental justice programs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We told them that we would do things differently this time, that we would right the wrongs of the past,” Tracy said of the office’s grantees. “We worked really hard to build their trust.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Tracy scoffed at Trump’s and Zeldin’s claims that their office had wasted federal dollars on DEI initiatives. “We don’t just give the money and say come back and see us in six months,” she said. “We’re meeting with them every step of the way.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The news of the imminent closure of the EPA’s environmental justice offices came just one day before Zeldin’s announcement of the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-launches-biggest-deregulatory-action-us-history&quot;&gt;biggest deregulatory action in U.S. history,&lt;/a&gt;” aimed at gutting federal oversight of the automobile and oil and gas industries. The EPA intends to eliminate dozens of environmental regulations, including rules governing petroleum refineries and climate-warming emissions. Also last week, Zeldin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/11/zeldin-terminates-greenhouse-gas-reduction-fund-grants-00225481&quot;&gt;terminated&lt;/a&gt; $20 billion in Biden climate grants, many of which were designated for underserved communities. Altogether, the actions of last week trammel Biden-era efforts to fight pollution in the nation’s industrial corridors and put millions of people at risk of increased exposure to toxic air and water.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last Thursday, two federal judges, one in Maryland and another in California, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/13/nx-s1-5325694/maryland-court-fired-federal-employees-trump&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; the Trump administration’s firing sprees to be unlawful and ordered that thousands of federal employees be reinstated. On Sunday, Tracy received an email from the EPA informing her that her termination had been rescinded; she is now on administrative leave until further notice. The news offered some relief, she said, but not much. She believes her position will be on the chopping block next.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“You know those brownfields?” Tracy asked, referring to toxic sites where former industrial facilities once operated. “The oil companies get to disband and go operate somewhere else. But what about the communities next to those places? What’s going to happen to them?”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/regulation/the-end-of-the-epas-fight-to-protect-overpolluted-communities/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/regulation/the-end-of-the-epas-fight-to-protect-overpolluted-communities/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Lylla Younes</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/protect_the_epa.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Regulation</category></item><item><title>A greener Ramadan: How Atlanta-area mosques are cutting food waste during the Muslim holy month</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;One evening in early March, Nina Ansari frowns as she picks up an untouched plate of rice left on the floor of the masjid she attends near her home in Stone Mountain. “Would anyone like to take this?” she asks a group of women standing nearby. When no one responds, she picks it up. Her hands are already full of the pizza and curry leftovers that her kids didn’t finish. If she doesn’t take the rice home, it will be thrown out. “There’s a lot of waste that happens during Ramadan,” says Nina, 38, who grew up in Georgia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;During the Muslim holy month — a time of spiritual rejuvenation through increased prayer and daylight fasting — masjids may serve hundreds of visitors for iftar, the sunset meal that marks the breaking of the fast. Some also serve a meal in the predawn hours, suhoor, before congregants start their fast.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;That all can add up to a lot of trash, though. At mosques in Atlanta and elsewhere, it’s not uncommon to find garbage cans packed to the top by the end of the night, with some plates and plastic water bottles still half full.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s just not acceptable for us,” says Nina. “My family is conscious of water and food conservation. We eat leftovers — we are not wasting or being snooty about wasting.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;She’s not the only one concerned about the problem. This year, more than two dozen Atlanta-area masjids or Islamic groups are planning environmentally friendly “zero-waste iftars,” aiming to cut down on the amount of discarded food, disposable plates, and water bottles. Food waste is a global and national dilemma — in the U.S.,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feedingamerica.org/our-work/reduce-food-waste&quot;&gt;almost 40 percent of the food supply&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;ends up in the landfill. But the trash generated during the holy month directly conflicts with a religious mandate to not be wasteful, says Marium Masud, who attends Marietta’s Masjid Al Furqan West Cobb Islamic Center: “We are called to be stewards of the Earth. There is a saying from the Prophet Muhammad that all of the Earth is a masjid. So it’s up to us to keep it clean, just like we keep our masjids clean.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1152 1152w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BahadurAliSohani.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A man in a white shirt, black robe, and white head covering and white beard holds plastic bottles in his hand in a mosque&quot; data-caption=&quot;Bahadur Ali Sohani of Lilburn shows off water bottles he has just crushed at Masjid Fatimah in Stone Mountain before recycling them.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Tasnim Shamma&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Bahadur Ali Sohani of Lilburn shows off water bottles he has just crushed at Masjid Fatimah in Stone Mountain before recycling them.
 &lt;cite&gt;Tasnim Shamma&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Masud is part of a “green team” of 17 volunteers that Al Furqan established to help tackle the problem. This past year, Al Furqan’s green team focused on one thing: banning plastic water bottles. In the past, the masjid threw away nearly 300 plastic bottles every night — but this year, hardly any. To prepare for Ramadan, the team added water filling stations, brought in reusable five-gallon water bottles, and had their Cub Scout packs sell recycled aluminum bottles to community members for $10 each. They also accepted donations to give out water bottles for free to anyone who couldn’t afford them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On March 19, Al Furqan — where 200 to 250 people come for iftars each weeknight — will host its first “zero-waste iftar” in partnership with Georgia Interfaith Power and Light, or GIPL, a nonprofit that works with religious groups on environmental justice. The organization provides training, workshops, and grants for reusable or compostable plates and cutlery. At the end of the iftar dinner, GIPL also covers the cost of sending the excess to the Atlanta nonprofit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://livethrive.org/charm/&quot;&gt;CHaRM&lt;/a&gt;, which composts food waste and processes hard-to-recycle items.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Al Furqan’s zero-waste iftar is just one of 24 zero-waste iftars planned across Atlanta-area Islamic centers this Ramadan. At least 15 now have dedicated green teams. That’s a big increase from 2023, when there was only one masjid with a GIPL-certified green team: Roswell Community Masjid, or RCM. RCM, which hosts weekly zero-waste iftar dinners every Saturday, signed a contract with Atlanta-based Goodr in mid-January to handle its composting and provide food waste recovery services year-round.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-monitoring-trash&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring trash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At Masjid Fatimah in Stone Mountain, Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed helps direct trash traffic during Ramadan. He sits in a folding chair for hours each night telling male congregants where to put the recycling, trash, and compost. About 150 people attend their iftar dinners each night.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“People waste so much food. There are half-eaten plates. Sometimes the entire plate. And because they don’t want me to see what they’re throwing away, they take another plate to cover it,” Rasheed says. “I see you! Sometimes I tell them, when you’re grabbing food, get a smaller portion. The food is there. I collected a lot of bread the past two days because people didn’t like it and were trying to throw it away.” (Some local masjids like Masjid Fatimah are working to reduce food waste by having volunteers portion out plates before handing them out to attendees — who tend to pile food on their own plates after fasting all day long.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/organizedtrash.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-caption=&quot;Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed of Masjid Fatimah in Stone Mountain organizes and stacks plates before throwing them away.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed of Masjid Fatimah in Stone Mountain organizes and stacks plates before throwing them away.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Reducing waste isn’t just aligned with religious principles — there’s also a financial incentive. Rasheed estimates that his masjid has saved nearly $1,000 so far because it has not needed to call Gwinnett County to pick up excess trash: Instead of five bags every night, there is now only one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Masjid Fatimah still provides congregants with plastic water bottles. But this year, it’s cutting down on the volume of its recycling by placing permanent markers with instructions on neon-green poster boards near the free bottles. “I put up a message and every day I remind people: Label your bottle, put your initial,” says Rasheed, calling this his personal pilot project. When they’re done drinking, he reminds people to remove the caps from their bottles and crush them so they’ll take up less space in the trash.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;At the end of the night, he sorts through the compost bin and trash to bring home what he can to add to his compost pile and feed his four chickens and red wiggler worms. Rasheed, who grew up gardening in Hyderabad, India, spends two hours a day working with his beehives and tending to his backyard permaculture setup after he returns home from his job as a biologist at the CDC; his garden provides hundreds of pounds of produce each year for his family of four. At the masjid, he shows other gardeners how to use the pizza boxes left over from Ramadan iftars to create easy garden plots and reduce time spent pulling weeds. He says more congregants are following his example and bringing scraps home to feed their backyard chickens as well.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;wp-block-heading&quot; id=&quot;h-khalifas-of-the-earth-or-green-teams&quot;&gt;‘Khalifas’ of the earth, or green teams&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Ayesha Abid is the program coordinator for Georgia Interfaith Power and Light. Informally, she calls herself the Muslim organizer for the nonprofit, and has been working to increase the number of Muslim organizations embracing recycling and reducing energy use and waste since she joined in 2023. “It’s hard to say for sure, since we are in the Bible Belt and we have more churches, but we have about 150 green teams [statewide],” Abid says, explaining that this includes teams across all religious houses of worship. “If there are about 100 masjids and 15 have green teams, I don’t think that’s a bad representation.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Atlanta Masjid of Al-Islam in East Atlanta is composting for the first time this year, and received a grant from GIPL for its zero-waste iftar.&amp;nbsp; The masjid, which opened in 1958, is the largest and oldest Islamic community center in metro Atlanta.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Freshveggies.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;A hand holds tomatoes next to baskets of fresh veggies&quot; data-caption=&quot;Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed shows off some of the produce from his permaculture garden.
&quot; data-credit=&quot;Courtesy of Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed shows off some of the produce from his permaculture garden.
 &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Mohammed Ata Ur Rasheed&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It isn’t that expensive to do composting,” Abid says. “What’s expensive is manpower or volunteers. The biggest thing I was hearing was ‘I don’t have volunteers to take it to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://livethrive.org/charm/&quot;&gt;CHaRM&lt;/a&gt;.’ There was a woman at [Atlanta Masjid of Al-Islam] who just took six to eight bags of compost/recyclable waste in her van. You need community members willing to step up to do that. I think the women in the community are uplifting this the most.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Abid says East Cobb Islamic Center, Al Furqan West Cobb Islamic Center, and Roswell Community Masjid have all called to eliminate single-use plastic bottles and encourage people to bring their own tupperware to take home food so it isn’t thrown out.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I grew up in Georgia and going to masjids, my most significant memory of Ramadan is seeing aunties forget which water bottle is theirs and getting a new one and letting entire bottles of water go to waste,” Abid says. “Volunteers are tired after fasting all day and don’t have energy to empty it into gardens. Muslims are supposed to be ‘khalifas’ [stewards] of the Earth, especially during Ramadan, and I could never make sense of the waste. This disconnect has always stood out to me. A lot of people question it but don’t care about it. But we’re working to fix that.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/a-greener-ramadan-how-atlanta-area-mosques-are-cutting-food-waste-during-the-muslim-holy-month/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/food-and-agriculture/a-greener-ramadan-how-atlanta-area-mosques-are-cutting-food-waste-during-the-muslim-holy-month/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Tasnim Shamma, 285 South</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GardenAtlanta.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Food and Agriculture</category></item><item><title>Florida is now a solar superpower. Here’s how it happened.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last May, Florida enacted a&amp;nbsp;law deleting any reference to climate change from most of its state policies, a&amp;nbsp;move Republican Governor Ron DeSantis&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/GovRonDeSantis/status/1790820306157703505&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;described as&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;“restoring sanity in our approach to energy and rejecting the agenda of the radical green zealots.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;That hasn’t stopped the Sunshine State from becoming a&amp;nbsp;national leader in solar&amp;nbsp;power.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In a&amp;nbsp;first, Florida&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/clean-energy/the-us-smashed-clean-energy-records-last-year-can-it-keep-up-the-pace&quot;&gt;vaulted past&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;California last year in terms of new utility-scale solar capacity plugged into its grid. It built&amp;nbsp;3&amp;nbsp;gigawatts of large-scale solar in&amp;nbsp;2024, making it second only to Texas. And in the residential solar sector, Florida continued its longtime leadership streak. The state has ranked number two&amp;nbsp;behind California for the most rooftop panels installed each year from&amp;nbsp;2019&amp;nbsp;through&amp;nbsp;2024, according to data the energy consultancy Wood Mackenzie shared with Canary Media.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We do expect Florida to continue as number two&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;2025,” said Zoë Gaston, Wood Mackenzie’s principal U.S. distributed solar analyst.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Florida is expected to again be neck and neck with California for this year’s second-place spot in utility-scale solar installations, said Sylvia Leyva Martinez, Wood Mackenzie’s principal utility-scale solar analyst for North America.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Overall, the state&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://seia.org/state-solar-policy/florida-solar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;receives&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;about&amp;nbsp;8 percent of its electricity from solar, according to Solar Energy Industries Association data. The vast majority of its power comes from fossil gas.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/solar-power-trump-culture-wars-american-energy-dominance/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of a barn with a flag behind a row of solar panels&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/solar-panels-flag.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/solar-power-trump-culture-wars-american-energy-dominance/&quot;&gt;Can solar power avoid Trump’s culture wars?&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/kate-yoder/&quot;&gt;Kate Yoder&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The state’s solar surge is the result of weather — both good and bad — and policies at the state and federal level that have made panels cheaper and easier to build, advocates say.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Obviously in Florida, sunshine is extremely abundant,” said Zachary Colletti, the executive director of the Florida chapter of Conservatives for Clean Energy.&amp;nbsp;“We’ve got plenty of&amp;nbsp;it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The state is also facing a&amp;nbsp;growing number of extreme storms. Of the&amp;nbsp;94&amp;nbsp;billion-dollar weather disasters that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/access/billions/state-summary/FL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;federal data shows&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;unfolded in Florida since&amp;nbsp;1980,&amp;nbsp;34&amp;nbsp;occurred in the last five&amp;nbsp;years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Floridians have long understood that not only is solar good for your pocket, it’s also good for your home resilience,” said Yoca Arditi-Rocha, the executive director of The&amp;nbsp;CLEO&amp;nbsp;Institute, a&amp;nbsp;Miami-based nonprofit that advocates for climate action.&amp;nbsp;“In the face of increasing extreme weather events, having access to reliable energy is a&amp;nbsp;big motivator.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/electrification/your-cheat-sheet-to-the-climate-laws-consumer-incentives&quot;&gt;tax credits available&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;under former President Joe Biden’s Inflation Reduction Act, or IRA, have also made buying panels cheaper than ever before, she&amp;nbsp;said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“A lot of people took advantage of that. I’m one of them,” Arditi-Rocha said.&amp;nbsp;“As soon as I&amp;nbsp;saw that the federal government was going to give me&amp;nbsp;30 percent back on my taxes, I&amp;nbsp;decided to make the investment and got myself a&amp;nbsp;solar system that I&amp;nbsp;could pay back in seven years. It was a&amp;nbsp;win-win proposition.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But solar started growing in Florida long before Democrats passed the&amp;nbsp;IRA&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;2022, and that’s thanks to favorable state policies.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/transportation/plan-to-build-a-road-with-radioactive-waste-in-florida-prompts-legal-challenge-against-the-epa/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A large brownish green lake sits among flat land along the water&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1533w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/FLchemicals.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;862&quot; width=&quot;1533&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/transportation/plan-to-build-a-road-with-radioactive-waste-in-florida-prompts-legal-challenge-against-the-epa/&quot;&gt;Plan to build a road with radioactive waste in Florida prompts legal challenge against the EPA&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/amy-green-inside-climate-news/&quot;&gt;Amy Green, Inside Climate News&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Municipalities and counties have little say over power plants, giving the Florida Public Service Commission ultimate control over siting and permitting. Plus, solar plants with a&amp;nbsp;capacity under&amp;nbsp;75&amp;nbsp;megawatts&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://floridadep.gov/water/siting-coordination-office/content/power-plant-siting-act&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;are exempt&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;from review and permitting altogether under the Florida Power Plant Siting Act.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The latter policy in particular has made building solar farms easy and inexpensive for the state’s major utilities, said Leyva Martinez. Companies such as NextEra Energy–owned Florida Power&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Light, the state’s largest electrical utility, have for years patched together gigawatts of solar with small&amp;nbsp;farms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“We’re seeing this wave of project installations at gigawatt scales, but if you look at what’s actually being built, it’s a&amp;nbsp;small&amp;nbsp;74-megawatt [project] here or a&amp;nbsp;74.9-megawatt project there,” she said.&amp;nbsp;“It’s just easier to permit in the state, and developers have realized that they can keep installations at this range and they don’t need to go through the longer process.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The solar buildout has prompted some backlash in rural parts of the state. A&amp;nbsp;bill Republican state Senator Keith Truenow&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/Bill/2025/700/BillText/Filed/PDF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;filed&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;last month proposes granting some additional local control over siting and permitting solar farms on agricultural land.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“You’re starting to see a&amp;nbsp;lot more complaining about the abundance of solar installations in more rural areas,” Colletti said. The legislation, he said,&amp;nbsp;“would add some hurdles and ultimately add costs” but&amp;nbsp;“wouldn’t necessarily reverse the state’s preemption” of local permitting authorities.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/utility-pay-green-grid-ev-electricity/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of two workers installing solar panels on a roof&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?resize=1200%2C808&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?resize=330%2C222&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?resize=768%2C517&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?resize=1536%2C1034&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1747805068d.jpg?resize=150%2C101&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1077&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/utility-pay-green-grid-ev-electricity/&quot;&gt;Utilities may soon pay you to help support a greener grid&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/matt-simon/&quot;&gt;Matt Simon&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;NextEra and Florida Power&amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;&amp;nbsp;Light did not respond to an email requesting comment. Nor did Truenow return a&amp;nbsp;call.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While the bill is currently making its way through the Legislature, DeSantis previously vetoed legislation that threatened Florida’s solar buildout.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In&amp;nbsp;2022, the governor&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/enn/desantis-net-metering-veto-highlights-path-for-solar-in-red-states&quot;&gt;blocked&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;utility-backed bill to end the state’s net metering program, which pays homeowners with rooftop solar for sending extra electricity back to the grid during the&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The governor did the right thing by vetoing that bill that would have strangled net metering and a&amp;nbsp;lot of the rooftop solar industry in Florida,” Colletti said.&amp;nbsp;“I know Floridians are much better off for it because we are able to offset our costs very well and take more control and ownership over our households.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flaseia.org/assets/pdf/Florida+Rooftop+Solar+Poll+Results+-+Feb+2022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;telephone survey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;conducted by the pollster Mason-Dixon in February&amp;nbsp;2022&amp;nbsp;found that among&amp;nbsp;625&amp;nbsp;registered Florida voters,&amp;nbsp;84 percent supported net metering, including&amp;nbsp;76 percent of self-identified Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“It’s not about left or right,” Arditi-Rocha said.&amp;nbsp;“It’s about making sure we live up to our state’s name. In the Sunshine State, the future can be really sunny and bright if we continue to harness the power of the&amp;nbsp;sun.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/energy/florida-is-now-a-solar-superpower-heres-how-it-happened/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/energy/florida-is-now-a-solar-superpower-heres-how-it-happened/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Alexander C. Kaufman</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/SolarPanelsFlorida.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Energy</category></item><item><title>MAGA Teslas? Elon Musk is upending the politics of EVs.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;President Donald Trump, the same man who once said that people promoting electric vehicles should “&lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/Business/wireStory/trump-buying-tesla-harsh-things-evs-years-119680885&quot;&gt;ROT IN HELL&lt;/a&gt;,” bought his own EV this week. He showed off his new Tesla Model S — red, like the Make America Great Again hats — outside the White House on Tuesday, piling compliments on his senior advisor Elon Musk, the CEO of Tesla, and declaring the company’s vehicles “beautiful.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It resembled a sales pitch for Musk’s company, the country’s biggest seller of EVs. Tesla has lost &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2025/03/10/tesla-shares-plunge-14percent-head-for-worst-day-in-five-years.html&quot;&gt;more than half of its value&lt;/a&gt; since December as sales have &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/7266929/heres-how-teslas-sales-have-been-hit-around-the-world/&quot;&gt;plummeted worldwide&lt;/a&gt;. With Musk dismantling parts of the federal government as the head of the new Department of Government Efficiency, aka DOGE, the vehicles have become a toxic symbol for Democrats, a large portion of Tesla owners. Over the past week, protesters have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/crime-courts/tesla-facilities-face-wave-attacks-elon-musk-delves-politics-rcna195458&quot;&gt;vandalized Tesla dealerships&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/10/us/tesla-cybertruck-fire-seattle.html&quot;&gt;set Cybertrucks aflame&lt;/a&gt;, and boycotted the brand. Liberal Tesla drivers have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/03/business/tesla-boycott-elon-musk.html&quot;&gt;slapped stickers on their cars&lt;/a&gt; that read “I bought this before Elon went crazy.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The strong feelings surrounding Musk have already started to scramble the politics around EVs. Trump’s exhibition at the White House on Tuesday was a defense of Musk, who he said had been unfairly penalized for “finding all sorts of terrible things that have taken place against our country.” Yet the bizarre scene of Trump showcasing a vehicle that runs on electricity instead of gas felt almost like a sketch from Saturday Night Live, and not just because the Trump administration has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/trump-administration-begins-effort-reverse-epa-vehicle-rules-2025-03-12/&quot;&gt;trying to reverse Biden-era rules&lt;/a&gt; that would have sped up the adoption of low-emissions vehicles. Here were the two biggest characters in MAGA politics promoting a technology that’s been largely rejected by their right-wing base.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Other prominent Republicans, including House Speaker Mike Johnson and Georgia Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msnbc.com/top-stories/latest/tesla-musk-vandalism-domestic-terrorism-rcna196220&quot;&gt;quickly moved to defend Tesla&lt;/a&gt; against vandalism that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/boston/news/tesla-vandalism-trump-domestic-terrorism-elon-musk/&quot;&gt;Trump is labeling “domestic terrorism.”&lt;/a&gt; Tesla’s sudden shift from Democratic status symbol to Republican icon has some thinking the controversy around Musk could lead to a bipartisan embrace of EVs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“He’s uniquely positioned to and has the power to really shape this debate and help bridge the divide here,” said Joe Sacks, executive director of the American EV Jobs Alliance, a nonprofit trying to prevent “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americanevjobs.org/&quot;&gt;silly partisan politics&lt;/a&gt;” from stopping a manufacturing boom for electric vehicles. “I’m unsure if that’s what he’s going to use his new perch and his role in the administration to do, but it seems like he has the ability to do that.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.evpolitics.org/news/a-political-x-ray-of-elon-musk/&quot;&gt;polling the alliance conducted&lt;/a&gt; after the November election, Republicans have warmed up to Musk, with 82 percent of those polled saying that Musk is a good ambassador for EVs. A solid majority of Trump voters — 64 percent —&amp;nbsp;said they viewed Tesla favorably, compared with 41 percent of those who voted for Kamala Harris. “Republicans are probably inching towards the idea that there shouldn’t be much of a cultural divide on this product category, if the market leader CEO is sitting next to President Trump in the Oval Office during press conferences,” Sacks said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The data aligns with a recent analysis from the financial services firm Stifel, which found that Tesla has become more favorable among Republicans as its popularity plunges with Democrats. Compared to August, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/tesla-losing-traction-with-democrats-but-gaining-with-republicans-stifel-says-3902068&quot;&gt;13 percent more Republicans are willing&lt;/a&gt; to consider purchasing a Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-ups-image-inner&quot;&gt;&lt;img decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=330 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=768 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1200 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=1536 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=160&amp;amp;h=90&amp;amp;crop=1 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=640&amp;amp;h=853&amp;amp;crop=1 640w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=96&amp;amp;h=96&amp;amp;crop=1 96w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=150 150w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Cybertruck.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1024w&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of a Cybertruck painted like a flag with the word Trump over it&quot; data-caption=&quot;A Donald Trump-themed Tesla Cybertruck sits in traffic in Washington, D.C.&lt;br&gt;&quot; data-credit=&quot;Christopher Furlong / Getty Images&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A Donald Trump-themed Tesla Cybertruck sits in traffic in Washington, D.C.&lt;br&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Christopher Furlong / Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Yet there are reasons to suspect that EVs will continue to be a hard sell for Republicans. They are typically tradition-minded people who like big cars, not small cars with new technology they’ve never used before, said Marc Hetherington, a political scientist at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and co-author of the book &lt;em&gt;Prius Or Pickup?&lt;/em&gt; “Conservatives don’t have the sensibility that fits with electric vehicles at all,” he said. “So I don’t think that you’re going to see a spike in Tesla sales among conservatives.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Alexander Edwards, president of the research consultancy Strategic Vision, said that Republicans view gas-powered cars as a more practical purchase for transporting their families from place to place. That’s based on his firm’s surveys, which examine the psychology behind the car choices of about a quarter-million Americans a year. “I think Elon made a bet that I think he’s secretly regretting, that Republicans would come out of the woodwork and say, ‘Yes, we’re going to support you,’” Edwards said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;If they came around to any electric vehicle, however, it might be a Tesla. One of the primary things Republicans care about when it comes to buying a car is that it looks fast and goes fast, and Tesla has seen more Republican buyers for that reason, Edwards said. Democrats have consistently been buying electric vehicles at a rate of 4 to 1 compared to Republicans, but 2 to 1 when it comes to Teslas, according to Edwards’ data. Last year, more Republicans than Democrats bought Teslas for the first time — not because more Republican flocked to the brand, but because Democrats pulled away from it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For Democrats, who had long been criticized &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/culture/herschel-walker-south-park-the-prius-gas-guzzlers/&quot;&gt;as having a smug attitude for driving a Prius&lt;/a&gt;, Teslas offered a cool and desirable alternative with less baggage when they took off in the early 2010s. “Tesla was able to finally give Democratic buyers what they were looking for — a Prius-like image of being thoughtful, combined with the fun and excitement of a real luxury sports car,” Edwards said. That started to change as Musk became a magnet for political controversy, starting with his takeover of Twitter in 2022. A Tesla EV became a symbol of Tesla’s CEO.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Doesn’t matter if you’re Republican or Democrat — when you jump into the Batmobile, you become Batman,” Edwards said. “And the same thing is true with the vehicles we purchase. We often want them to show who we are, what we’ve accomplished, what we stand for.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Of course, there are ways to depolarize electric vehicles that don’t rely on cues from Trump or Musk. Sacks recommends talking about the attributes of electric vehicles: their ability to accelerate faster and brake more crisply, as well as help people &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zeta.org/news/electric-vehicles-continue-to-be-cheaper-than-internal-combustion-engine-vehicles-according-to-zetas-ev-savings-report&quot;&gt;save money for every mile they drive&lt;/a&gt;, since there’s no need to buy gas. When people have friends or family who own an EV, that also helps break down the cultural divide, he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In a way, you could see Trump becoming a salesman for electric vehicles as an example of that very phenomenon, with his &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1856073530137526564&quot;&gt;self-described “first buddy”&lt;/a&gt; convincing him to come around. Just two years ago, Trump complained that EVs &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/trump-electric-vehicles-past-criticism-hoax-d58758e990f13482e0c6e3a79150abbe&quot;&gt;needed a charge every 15 minutes&lt;/a&gt; and would &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2023/06/27/trump-stokes-electric-car-fears-in-mich-ee-00103726&quot;&gt;kill American jobs&lt;/a&gt;. But, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/12/trump-musk-electric-vehicles-00173682&quot;&gt;after Musk endorsed his presidential campaign&lt;/a&gt; last summer and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/01/31/elon-musk-trump-donor-2024-election/&quot;&gt;donated $288 million&lt;/a&gt;, Trump softened his tone, saying that he was in favor of “a very small slice” of cars being electric. “I have to be, you know,” Trump said, “because Elon endorsed me very strongly.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On Tuesday, as Trump climbed into his new electric car for the first time, he seemed surprised by what he saw there. “That’s beautiful,” he said, admiring the dashboard. “This is a different panel than I’ve had. Everything’s computer!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Correction:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; This story originally misidentified the percentage of Harris voters who viewed Tesla favorably.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/politics/elon-musk-tesla-trump-republicans-electric-vehicles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/politics/elon-musk-tesla-trump-republicans-electric-vehicles/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Kate Yoder</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Trump-Musk-Tesla.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Culture</category><category>Politics</category><category>Technology</category></item><item><title>The future of Gaza’s recovery may rely on solar power</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The first time Majd Mashharawi left her native Gaza was in 2017, to visit Tokyo. Her flight landed late at night, and she was struck by the airport’s many glittering lights. Then when she got to the urban core, she was astonished. “This is the life people have outside Gaza?” she thought. “Why don’t we have this life?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Growing up, Mashharawi had been accustomed to life with inconsistent power — as little as three hours a day. “It’s not easy to describe unless you live it,” she said. “Your life is completely messed up. Everything is controlled by others. Your life is controlled by when power is on and off.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Last week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2025/03/09/middleeast/israel-electricity-gaza-intl-latam/index.html&quot;&gt;Israel cut off all electricity to the Gaza Strip&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to strengthen its hand against Hamas in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/12/nx-s1-5325721/israel-hamas-qatar-hostages-mediation&quot;&gt;ceasefire talks&lt;/a&gt;. But in fact, the two parties’ dysfunctional relationship around energy has a long history. In 2007, after Hamas took control of the Gaza Strip, Israel established &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unicef.org/mena/documents/gaza-strip-humanitarian-impact-15-years-blockade-june-2022&quot;&gt;a land and sea blockade&lt;/a&gt;. This included electricity: Israel came to control 10 power lines running into Gaza, as well as the diesel fuel needed to run its one power plant. The blockade also gave Israel gatekeeping power over any materials — cement, steel, batteries — needed for domestic infrastructure, if Israeli authorities judged they could help militants.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Israel’s security establishment thought this hammerlock over Gazan energy meant leverage over Hamas, said Elai Rettig, a lecturer in energy politics at Bar-Ilan University. As for Hamas, many Gazans felt the group was more interested in its crusade against Israel than addressing public works.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For the people of Gaza, the conflict meant energy poverty. The Strip’s combined power resources could at best meet a quarter to a third of demand. This translated to daily power outages averaging 12 to 16 hours a day. Even worse, Mashharawi said, the outages were unpredictable — whenever the power flicked on, you had to scramble. This maddening unreliability landed especially hard on &lt;a href=&quot;https://al-shabaka.org/briefs/confronting-energy-poverty-in-gaza/&quot;&gt;women&lt;/a&gt;, who had to jam all their chores into these fleeting windows of opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But over the last decade, as solar prices tumbled worldwide, more Israeli leaders started thinking that getting solar into Gaza had a strategic benefit. Gaza’s energy dependence wasn’t cheap. Years of Palestinian counterparties failing to pay Gaza’s power bill — for financial and political reasons — had by 2023 racked up a debt to Israel of 2 billion shekels, about $500 million.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In 2016 and 2017, Israel approved about 100,000 solar panels to enter Gaza, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/350385684_Light_at_the_End_of_the_Panel_The_Gaza_Strip_and_the_Interplay_Between_Geopolitical_Conflict_and_Renewable_Energy_Transition&quot;&gt;researchers&lt;/a&gt; at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem. Satellite imagery soon showed solar arrays sprouting on thousands of buildings across the Gaza Strip, especially in crowded areas like refugee camps.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Around the time of Mashhawawi’s trip to Tokyo, she’d been working to start a company that manufactured Gaza’s war rubble into bricks. But her production lines were being constantly kneecapped by the start-stop of the grid. It occurred to her that unreliable power was not just a burden in households, like the one she grew up in. Thousands of businesses across Gaza — restaurants, workshops, bakeries — yearned for a source of energy more reliable than what they had. Mashharawi decided to get into the energy business.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;She started Sunbox, a social enterprise promoting solar power, in 2017, working doggedly with Israeli authorities to get the equipment approved. She started by selling small arrays — 1 kilowatt and up, about enough to power a home with a small fridge — to families. She soon helped supply bigger projects. Sunbox equipped 20 small desalination plants, the engines of Gazan water production, with solar. It set up solar-charged streetlights so girls could feel more confident walking to school in the wee hours.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Large international organizations like the World Bank and U.N. were also getting in the game,&amp;nbsp;decking hospitals and schools in solar. A 7-megawatt system, partly financed by the International Finance Corporation, or IFC, got bolted onto the Gaza Industrial Estate, a manufacturing complex. The IFC said the smoother power supply made it possible to expand output and hire workers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It was a renewable revolution born of political dysfunction. The total number of solar arrays in the Gaza Strip &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/350385684_Light_at_the_End_of_the_Panel_The_Gaza_Strip_and_the_Interplay_Between_Geopolitical_Conflict_and_Renewable_Energy_Transition&quot;&gt;vaulted&lt;/a&gt; from about a dozen in 2012 to 8,760 in 2019, mostly in the form of small rooftop systems. The extraordinary growth &lt;a href=&quot;https://systemschangelab.org/news/these-8-countries-have-scaled-renewable-energy-fastest&quot;&gt;made&lt;/a&gt; the Occupied Palestinian Territories one of the fastest-growing renewable energy markets in the world. By 2023, solar represented 25-40 percent of daytime power generation on the ragged Gazan grid, Rettig, of Bar-Ilan University, estimated.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/international/project-prosperity-israel-war-gaza-landmark-mideast-climate-deal/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=330%2C220&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/water-gaza-tank.jpg?resize=150%2C100&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;1067&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/international/project-prosperity-israel-war-gaza-landmark-mideast-climate-deal/&quot;&gt;How Israel’s war on Gaza unraveled a landmark Mideast climate deal&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/saqib-rahim/&quot;&gt;Saqib Rahim&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Then came October 7, 2023. Mashharawi was abroad at the time on business travel. She spent the first two months of the war calling in favors and trying to get her family to Egypt. Meanwhile, Sunbox’s offices and warehouses were destroyed. Mashharawi is mourning the loss of a dear coworker, Mahmoud Abushawish, who she said was venturing north to help a school set up solar — and find some candy for the kids.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Israel’s military assault on Gaza has taken at least 48,000 lives and left its infrastructure in tatters. In February an interim assessment, led by the World Bank, estimated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/press-release/2025/02/18/new-report-assesses-damages-losses-and-needs-in-gaza-and-the-west-bank&quot;&gt;$53 billion&lt;/a&gt; in reconstruction needs. It said that 80 percent of Gaza’s power infrastructure is wrecked and that Gazans have experienced a “near-total blackout” since the start of the war. Because Gaza’s water supplies depend on energy to pump and purify it, availability has fallen to sub-critical levels. “There is no water and no electricity. It is stunning just how much damage occurred there,” Steve Witkoff, President Donald Trump’s Middle East envoy, told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/01/30/gaza-rebuilding-plans-trump-administration&quot;&gt;Axios&lt;/a&gt; after visiting the territory in January.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;A ceasefire signed in January, which has been roughly observed even as its first phase expired March 1, has paused the bombing for now. But talks to end the war haven’t gained traction, and many sense that Israel’s ultra-right-wing government, emboldened by Trump’s return, wants to resume fighting. Meanwhile, today most of Gaza’s 2.1 million people live in desperate conditions in displacement camps and other makeshift shelters, often exposed to the elements and possessing minimal access to basic services. Humanitarian groups are begging Israel and the international community to preserve the ceasefire and rush aid to improve conditions at these camps — hopefully, as a precursor to reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;With Hamas weakened, world powers are deciding the future of Gaza. In February, Trump whimsically proposed to empty Gaza of Palestinians and redevelop it as a luxury riviera. The idea won plaudits from Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu — and categorical rejection by America’s Arab and Western allies. Trump’s vision is out of step with the majority of governments and experts who think that the reconstruction of Gaza can, and should, be done in a way that empowers Palestinians to live better lives on their land, without posing a threat to Israel.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Energy access is minimal in Gaza today. But solar has become one of the few ways to get it. About half of the electrons Gazans are using today come from solar power, according to a December estimate by the Shelter Cluster, a group that coordinates among aid organizations working in Gaza. The other half is coming from diesel, the customary fuel for post-disaster scenarios, but aid groups say Israel is withholding the necessary supplies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;With virtually no new hardware getting in, Gazans have created an internal economy for used cleantech. Solar units and their peripherals are being ripped from roofs, salvaged from rubble, and sold on Facebook. In the many camps of internally displaced people now dotting the strip, you’ll see solar panels leaning against walls and chairs — facing the sun. Some serve commercial ends. “You can find a guy with one panel, and a table, and his business is actually to charge cell phones and to charge batteries,” said one 55-year-old Gazan whose family has been displaced several times during the war.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The aid groups serving these encampments are hoping the most violent stage of the war is past and that they can switch to establishing basic services: food, water, shelter and critical health care. With diesel supplies scant, some are trying to import solar-powered gear instead. The U.N. Development Programme wants to deploy 1,100 prefab housing units, each equipped with a kilowatt of solar and rudimentary plumbing, as part of a $27 million program. The U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization said in a statement that setting up off-grid photovoltaic systems is crucial to restoring agricultural activities like irrigation and cold storage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Jumpstarting Hope in Gaza, a coalition of Palestinian, Israeli, and international NGOs, is supporting Palestinian-run IDP camps with 12,000 people in the south of Gaza with goods and equipment. The group aspires to set up a suite of solar-powered services — electricity, wastewater treatment, even units that produce drinking water from the air — to make them self-sufficient, dignified places to live during reconstruction, whenever that should begin. But in actuality, only a bit of traditional equipment got in before the ceasefire, and all equipment entries have stopped since then, said David Lehrer, a co-leader of the initiative.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Though the war isn’t formally over, many Gazans are returning to their homes, or the places their homes once stood. Some are beginning the early work of clearing rubble and laying to rest the bodies they find — a glimpse of the immense mourning that lies ahead.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As for the longer term, powerful parties are already competing to advance their respective visions of reconstruction. This month, Egypt, along with the 21 other members of the Arab League, issued a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/aiming-to-stymie-trumps-riviera-vision-arab-leaders-gather-to-endorse-gaza-plan/&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/a&gt; meant to counter Trump’s “riviera” concept. It proposes building 2,500 megawatts of power generation — about 20 times what Gaza had before the war — including solar, wind, and fossil-fuel generation. They’re not alone in envisioning Gaza as a renewable-energy powerhouse. The Palestinian Authority, which hopes to replace Hamas as Gaza’s ruling body, is developing a master plan of infrastructural priorities to be finalized with the World Bank, European Union, U.N., and Arab States. Wael Zakout, the Authority’s Minister of Planning and International Cooperation, has said solar and wind farms across Gaza could make it “the first region in the world to reach zero carbon emissions.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Another idea that’s been mooted — one that Trump endorsed in his first term — is to build a solar farm in the sun-blasted deserts of the Sinai, just across Gaza’s southern border. Proponents say this has twin benefits: It frees up land in Gaza for other uses, and because it’s in Egypt, Israel’s not likely to target it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But renewable energy won’t be the only resource considered for the repowering of Gaza. A modestly sized natural gas field was discovered offshore of Gaza in 2000. Political and economic conditions kept it from being developed, but the U.S., Egypt, and Israel have described it as an untapped energy reserve for Gaza. In November 2023, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/10/us/politics/amos-hochstein-lebanon-israel-biden.html&quot;&gt;Amos Hochstein&lt;/a&gt;, a Middle East envoy for President Joe Biden and a former energy executive, said “as soon as we get to the day after and this horrible war ends, there are companies willing to develop those fields.” Supporters say gas-fired electricity would bolster Gaza’s overall energy supply and enable major new industrial infrastructure, like desalination plants and wastewater treatment, that would improve everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Josef Abramowitz, an Israeli-American solar developer who’s worked with Palestinian partners before, thinks the emphasis on large projects loses the decentralized character that has proven the most successful in Gaza. “The story of Gaza is: big projects that don’t get done,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Abramowitz’s favored model is minigrids: localized networks of solar panels and battery storage, which he said can supply round-the-clock energy at a fraction the cost of gas-fired generation. They’re flexible, sustainable, and — important in the Gazan context of blockade, frequent war, and poor governance — feasible with or without a grand resolution to the Israel-Palestine conflict.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As for Mashharawi, she said her vision for reconstruction involves something a lot more basic than energy: peace and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“One to two years from now, where are we going?” she said. “We don’t want to keep building and rebuilding things that are destroyed.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/energy/the-future-of-gazas-recovery-may-rely-on-solar-power/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/energy/the-future-of-gazas-recovery-may-rely-on-solar-power/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Saqib Rahim</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-1940074014.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Energy</category><category>International</category></item></channel></rss>