<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Psyche | Ideas</title><link>https://psyche.co/ideas</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.isrss.com/psyche/type/ideas" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Psyche | Ideas - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:43:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>For this unsung philosopher, metaphors make life an adventure</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;   &lt;blockquote&gt;Metaphor is the law of growth of every semantic. It is not a development, but a principle.&lt;br&gt;– from &lt;em&gt;Philosophy in a New Key &lt;/em&gt;(1941) by Susanne K Langer&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Words are incorrigible weasels; meanings of words cannot be held to paper with the ink.&lt;br&gt;– from &lt;em&gt;Mind: An Essay on Human Feeling&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Vol III&lt;/span&gt; (1982) by Susanne K Langer&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaphors are double agents. They say one thing and mean another. Their purpose within the symbolic order is to amplify, not deceive – to grow the stock of shared meanings. When we invoke a metaphor, we dislodge words from their literal perch. Our words become ambidextrous, stretched by analogy. We can say new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was among the more important claims made by Susanne K Langer (1895-1985), a neglected American philosopher now experiencing a revival. Langer began her career when the analytic approach was in its formative stages. Women philosophers were rare, and women philosophers specialising in logic were an anomaly. However, the argument she made in her bestselling &lt;em&gt;Philosophy in a New Key&lt;/em&gt; (1941) – that music and the other arts bear logical insights that language, science and mathematics can’t capture – served to marginalise her from a philosophical establishment that was, by then, hostile to women. One of Langer’s students, Arthur Danto, later explained why he rarely cited her: in graduate school he picked up that she was regarded as ‘poison’ to a philosophical career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When interest in metaphor surged in the late &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;20th century,&lt;/span&gt; Langer’s contributions were overlooked. &lt;em&gt;Metaphors We Live &lt;/em&gt;By (1980), George Lakoff and Mark Johnson’s blockbuster, doesn’t mention Langer. Nor does their 600-page sequel &lt;em&gt;Philosophy in the Flesh&lt;/em&gt; (1999). She rarely appears in other serious works on metaphor. Her insights are consigned to the stacks, obscured to students of the subject. She deserves to be unshelved, to win a new readership, for her lucid account of metaphor’s generative power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metaphors, for Langer, are more than just&lt;/strong&gt; the ardour in a poet’s ink. They are the dynamic force of everyday communication, prosaic as well as artful. In their way, metaphors are as important to you and me as they were to Shakespeare and Wordsworth. Some examples, high and low: in 1942, the existentialist Albert Camus evoked the plight of the mythic Sisyphus as a metaphor to convey the absurdities of modern life. The film &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt; (1993) does something similar. Metaphor’s analogical reach also explains why the units of energy of motorboats, lawn tools and cars is still measured in horsepower in the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;21st century.&lt;/span&gt; As Ralph Waldo Emerson explained in ‘The Poet’ (1844): ‘Language is fossil poetry.’ When &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/ideas/let-me-open-a-treasure-chest-to-explain-how-metaphor-works&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;metaphors&lt;/a&gt; enter into common usage, they lose their wings. Their origins tend to be forgotten: so, today, we focus on the power of our machines, and barely notice the horses are still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The etymology of the word ‘metaphor’ is from the Greek ‘transfer’, with the suffix ‘meta’ meaning ‘beyond’ or ‘after’, as in ‘metamorphosis’ or ‘metaphysics’. For Langer, metaphor is the ‘key’ to understanding human evolution and the development of civilisation: religion, science, literature, music and art. She was not the first thinker to claim that metaphor is much more than a figure of speech. German philologists of the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;19th century&lt;/span&gt; appreciated the crucial role that metaphor played in the development of language. Inspired by Emerson’s poetics, Friedrich Nietzsche crafted a theory of knowledge in which truth is a social covenant composed of worn-out metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Langer, the analogic ‘principle’ that metaphor supports allows us to &lt;em&gt;make sense &lt;/em&gt;of our own experience as well as to ‘represent’ that sense in symbols that can transcend time and space. As she explained in &lt;em&gt;Philosophy in a &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Key&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;We play on words, explore their connotations, evoke or evade their associations; we identify signs with our symbols and construct the ‘intelligible world’; we dream our needs and fantasms and construct the ‘inner world’ of unapplied symbols. We impress each other, too, and build a social structure, a world of right and wrong, of demands and sanctions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaphor, for Langer, is language’s law of growth. When there is no word available to express a new thought, we reach for analogy – for familiar language that denotes something similar – and apply it to the new thought. We may send it out on its own or alter it in some way by, for example, adding a prefix or suffix. Our listeners grasp that the word isn’t meant literally – that it serves here as proxy for a new idea or object. The literal meaning is a symbol for the figurative meaning, the ‘thing that has no name of its own’. As the metaphor gets taken up – if it’s used enough – the word will fade to the literal, as ‘horsepower’ has for most of us. Its metaphorical quality dissipates, thereby expanding the language’s denotative stock – so the word can be lent out again to express another novel thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langer illustrates this growth process with a poetic metaphor: a brook that is ‘laughing in the sunlight’. The phrase evokes the idea of laughter to suggest the brook’s unstudied course. It is a live metaphor, in contrast to the sentence ‘The brook runs swiftly.’ The ‘runs’ here was &lt;em&gt;once&lt;/em&gt; a metaphor, but has long since settled into a literal meaning, something like a ‘shallow rippling flow’. As Langer notes, when we hear a ‘rumour runs through the town’, we think ‘neither of leg-action nor of ripples’. The word has come to denote a coursing-through – it has taken on, that is, a general, versatile character. ‘Runs’ is a &lt;em&gt;faded&lt;/em&gt; metaphor, among thousands of others: ‘[O]ur literal language is a very repository of “faded metaphors”,’ she concludes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, language is built up bit by bit, word by word, through slow, metaphoric accretion. Langer held that the analogic motor (or fountain) of metaphor was running at the beginning – even before the prehistoric limen of language. This is a speculative view, of course, but she secured her claims in the early literature of evolutionary anthropology. She encouraged her readers to imagine a frenzy of symbol-making, a ‘sumptuous prodigality of symbols’, as early humans coped with the tumbling currents of raw sensation that wash over us all. For them, the act of perception was (as it is for us) a sorting-through – a selection from the blooming, buzzing confusion. &lt;em&gt;Homo sapiens&lt;/em&gt; made active sense of their world, recognising &lt;em&gt;forms&lt;/em&gt; – basic shapes or patterns – in their sensational stream. Thus, to perceive, for our ancestors, was to conceive: to see one thing (the sensory onrush) in another (the perceptual shape given by the mind and primordial cultures). That is, our predecessors were already &lt;em&gt;abstracting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Abstraction’ may be the most important word, &lt;/strong&gt;and concept, in Langer’s thought. By abstraction she means the process of recognising something in common, something shared, in more than one thing. Perception, in this sense, is spontaneous and natural, as it was even for our language-less forebears – and may also be within the repertoire of the preverbal stage of early childhood. By recognising forms or patterns in the throng of impressions crowding the mind, our ancestors identified things in common – nameless, as yet, but captured in mental imagery. Once unmoored from the original sense-experience, which is to say abstracted, images could act as symbols for other things and states. Aspects of the physical world like fire, registered in imagery, could in turn connote – come to express – ideas like passion and activity. Langer reminds us that dreaming has this quality: ‘madly metaphorical fantasies’ filled with ‘riotous’, and mostly imagistic, symbolism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is that metaphor, as ‘abstractive seeing’, predates language. Every new experience, or novel idea, is apprehended through metaphor – that is, in terms of something else. Once language, as a stock of public meanings, takes initial hold – Langer had her theories here too – its spread and growth is powered by metaphor. With no name to express new thoughts, we reach for a surrogate, a word or phrase with a connotation in common. The word itself, thanks to the extension, takes on a more generic colouring in the process – becomes, that is, more abstract, more widely serviceable. In this way, according to Langer, we are ‘forever laying down a deposit of old, abstracted concepts in an increasing treasure of general words.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the power of seeing one thing in another is how language keeps step with human experience and thought. Metaphor’s ‘true nature’, Langer wrote, is to make us ‘&lt;em&gt;conceive&lt;/em&gt; things in abstraction’, which, in turn, is our ‘greatest mental achievement’. Whenever the pool of felt meanings floods the levee of shared expression, metaphor comes to the rescue: say one thing, mean another, and expect the meaning to be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One by-product of what Langer called ‘metaphorical extension’ is that each word in a living language carries a trace of every meaning it has ever had (‘like an overtone’) and every association it has acquired (‘like an aura’). Even as social convention fixes a word’s general usage in time, the older meanings linger, which can make certain words better fit to express this or that ‘wordless insight’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Langer’s legacies is to help us see that language – to stay fresh, to keep step – &lt;em&gt;needs&lt;/em&gt; words to be ‘incorrigible weasels’, double agents. Words mean more than we can say, which lets us say new things with old words. Metaphor, Langer reminds us, is what makes ‘human life an adventure in understanding’.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/for-this-neglected-philosopher-metaphors-make-life-an-adventure</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/for-this-neglected-philosopher-metaphors-make-life-an-adventure</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Sue Curry Jansen, Jeff Pooley</author></item><item><title>True solidarity requires Burke’s ‘sympathetic revenge’</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Solidarity – the word is in the air. Yet what exactly does it mean? Solidarity once meant that different groups – each facing distinct injustices – laboured together for social, political and economic reforms on each other’s behalf. Supporting the cause of one group – let’s say, Black Americans during the civil rights movement of the 1960s – was not only the right thing to do but a powerful way of affirming a shared sense of humanity through common struggle. Somewhere along the way, solidarity lost this element of labour. It became a matter of declarations. Social media utterances – offered in the name of empathy – came to substitute for the grinding work of political commitment. Digital affirmations work well enough in the performative world of social media, where private lives must partake in public acts of ritual exposure, but they fail to wrestle with the complex moral emotions that shape our real-world responses to injustice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, solidarity appears to be more about the person declaring it than the afflicted stranger they claim to be standing beside. When one declares solidarity – &lt;em&gt;I stand with X&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;I stand with Y&lt;/em&gt; – the statement, however well intentioned, inevitably works as a piece of theatre. That’s not to say such expressions are disingenuous or ineffective. To the contrary, they can be sincere and memorable instances of identification with suffering. But I want to suggest that there is a deeper, more morally demanding form of solidarity that has largely been abandoned in the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;21st century&lt;/span&gt; – one that explains why people sometimes commit themselves, even at great personal cost, to the causes of strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This form of solidarity can be found in an unexpected source: the political thinker Edmund Burke &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;(1729-97).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.aeonmedia.co/user_image_upload/3963/edmund-burke-npg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Painting of a man in 18th-century attire with brown hair and a white cravat against a dark background.&quot; class=&quot;ld-image-block&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;ld-image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detail from a portrait of Edmund Burke (&lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;1769) by the studio of Sir Joshua Reynolds. Courtesy the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npg.org.uk/collections/search/portrait/mw00926&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;National Portrait Gallery, London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burke is commonly remembered as the father of &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/conservatives-cant-claim-edmund-burke-as-one-of-their-own&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;modern conservatism&lt;/a&gt; for his opposition to the French Revolution and its forces of violence. What is forgotten is Burke the ‘badly suppressed rebel’ (as Conor Cruise O’Brien remembered him), whose anger at British abuses of power abroad in India ignited his own visceral experiences of injustice as an Irish-born man. Burke – a member of the UK Parliament practically involved with these questions – thought solidarity was not merely about empathy, about &lt;em&gt;feeling as another feels&lt;/em&gt;. Solidarity, he thought, required confronting a deeper, more unsettling emotion within oneself: what Burke called ‘sympathetic revenge’ – a moral emotion that fuses anger with justice; a human retribution against the agents of injustice, compelled by a sense of the full humanity of their victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sympathetic revenge hinges on a powerful insight:&lt;/strong&gt; that the final spark driving people to take personal and collective action against an injustice is not simply outrage but the recognition that they, themselves, are implicated in the wrong. This sense of self-betrayal arises when people recognise that they are enabling wrongdoing contrary to their own self-declared values, and returns to strangers the moral agency they otherwise lack, protecting their consignment to their own victimhood. More than anything, this anger gets people (seriously) involved in the causes of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For nearly 15 years, Burke tried to reform the East India Company, the private corporation that ruled colonial India with arbitrary power throughout the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;18th century.&lt;/span&gt; His most infamous stand came in his impeachment of Warren Hastings – the head of the East India Company and the British governor of Bengal – whom Burke accused of violating the rights of Indians and betraying Britain’s constitutional ideals. Addressing the Lords and assembled public in a packed Westminster Hall in London, Burke kick-started a moral crisis in the British psyche: &lt;em&gt;If you sympathise with Hastings’s victims, must you hold him accountable for his crimes? And if you credit my account but can’t summon the sympathy for the Indians, what does that say &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;about you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burke sought to cultivate a special kind of guilt within Englishmen: not a paralysing shame, but a righteous anger that turned inward, forcing individuals to come face to face with their own complicity. His anger at the British mimicked the possible or potential anger of the Indians as would-be victims, in a kind of mirroring process. Through sympathising with those who would be understandably angry at what the British had done to them, Burke became angry at his own nation on behalf of the Indians, so joining their angers in mutual protest at the broken relationship they share. Paradoxically, Burke thought this mutual anger could be the first step towards justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we are living through our own age of injustice, with blood spattered across our screens daily. Gaza. Ukraine. Beirut. The Be’eri kibbutz. Sexual violence at home. Racial violence on our streets. These crises demand more than distant expressions of solidarity; they require us to wrestle with our own entanglements. Burke’s idea of sympathetic revenge is a potent means of thinking about solidarity in cases where leaders act on our behalf in ways we find reprehensible. Burke hoped a more capacious kind of solidarity would emerge from Englishmen as part of the British Empire’s response to India – an empire he believed owed Indians more. I have the same hope for many today: for Israelis appalled by the murderous actions of their government in Gaza; for all of us in the West who are complicit in those crimes while reckoning with a vile and recrudescent antisemitism; for men reflecting on how they have failed to be part of the solution to gender inequality; to those who would flagrantly abuse democratic constitutions in the name of popular government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes sympathetic revenge a morally imaginative form of solidarity is its ability to navigate the complex, often contradictory emotions surrounding political and social injustices. Contemporary understandings of solidarity risk reducing these emotions into a simple binary: one is either an oppressor or the oppressed. And yet the reality of emotional life is far more complex – guilt, rage, sympathy, loss, suffering and shame often coexist within us in ways that defy forceful categorisation and easy taming. Sympathetic revenge gathers all these emotions into a ball and rolls them towards a more meaningful form of introspection. If solidarity has traditionally been seen as being about adding one’s voice to the voiceless in their cause, sympathetic revenge mirrors that silent stranger’s anger, keeping this anger real, visible and alive. Burke was aware that such solidarity came with little reward; in a speech to the House of Commons in 1783, he said: ‘In such an attempt you hurt those who are able to return kindness or to resent injury. If you succeed, you save those who cannot so much as give you thanks.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an age of digital activism, where expressions of solidarity often remain abstract and performative, Burke’s example compels us to confront violence in a more immediate, personal way. He insists that solidarity cannot be an art practised at arm’s length. It must be a prompt towards self-reflection – one that, if it leads to self-knowledge, renders contemporary expressions of solidarity comparatively weightless.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/true-solidarity-requires-burkes-sympathetic-revenge</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/true-solidarity-requires-burkes-sympathetic-revenge</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Jack Jacobs</author></item><item><title>How do we start learning to ‘read’ other people’s minds?</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;   &lt;p&gt;‘Would you like some?’ says the child, shaking the red chocolate box to elicit the telltale sound of the treat. Quivering with glee, he watches as his little sister excitedly accepts the gift and opens the box… only to find that the usual contents have been replaced with marbles. The older child giggles uncontrollably. The trick is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how did the older child know the trick would work? Playing a trick like this required him to have a sense of what his sister would be thinking, given the context. His words to her, the recognisable container and the familiar rattle were all cues to make her think she was being offered a real treat. Only when his little sister opened the box, he understood, would &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; know what was clear &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not until the age of four or five that children develop this flexible ‘theory of mind’: the ability to reason about others’ thoughts and feelings. This includes understanding that people’s beliefs can be decoupled from reality (sometimes to comic effect). This ability to ‘read’ other people’s minds is crucial for social interaction. Which direction is that car going to turn? The indicator lets you infer the driver’s intention. Does that attractive acquaintance like you? Their eye contact and flick of the hair might give you a sign. Are we communicating about this topic well? To answer that question, we have to imagine what the reader will need to know in order to follow our train of thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theory of mind has been a topic of intense study since the 1980s, when psychologists first developed ‘false belief’ tasks. These tasks involve asking children to reason about other people’s behaviour in scenarios where those people don’t have full information. For example, Mum leaves her car keys on the kitchen table; when she is gone, Dad puts the car keys in his pocket. Mum comes back to the kitchen – where will she look for her keys? Children under the age of four predict that Mum will look in Dad’s pocket; after all, that’s where the keys are. However, older children understand that Mum will expect the keys to be on the table, and that Dad might be in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An enduring question, one for which we and other scientists are still seeking answers, is what happens around that age to make this critical ability possible. How, exactly, do we become ‘mind readers’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Historically, there are two big ideas&lt;/strong&gt; about how theory of mind works. ‘Simulation theory’ suggests that we routinely read other people’s minds by imagining how we would think and feel in their shoes. So, by this account, you might ask yourself: ‘What would &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; think if I saw this chocolate box and heard it rattle?’ – and if you can correctly work through your own imagined thought processes, you can arrive at what someone else would think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, some psychologists and philosophers have taken the ‘theory’ part of ‘theory of mind’ literally. They argue that people have something genuinely like a scientific theory of others’ minds, which can be understood using theoretical terms like ‘if X, and if Y, then Z’. A concrete example might be: if someone wants X (eg, chocolate), and thinks Y (there is chocolate in this box), then they will do Z (open the box expectantly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As adults, people may use a mixture of these strategies to understand others’ minds – sometimes ‘simulating’ how they would feel or what they would think in another person’s position, and sometimes appealing to what they know about typical behavioural patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent research &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022096524002431?via%3Dihub&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt;, we used the intuitions behind both of these theories to try to uncover the developmental building blocks of theory of mind. As with adults, when a child thinks about what someone else is thinking, they might sometimes imagine how they would think or feel in another’s position, and other times they might instead draw from their knowledge of what others usually do (eg, ‘people look for things where they expect to find them’). However, to grasp that another person can hold a false belief, we hypothesised, a child would first need to have an idea of what a belief, or thought, is. Thus, a child’s ability to introspect about their &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; thoughts – also known as metacognition – could be a developmental building block for the ability to reason about the mental states of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, in itself, might not be enough. We also expected that self-control, which children take time to develop, would be important to the ability to ‘read’ others’ minds. In order to guess what’s happening in someone else’s mind, one has to be able to temporarily put aside one’s own experience of reality, which requires inhibition. This is why young children are typically considered to be egocentric (think of the ‘terrible twos’), a trait that abates &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;with age.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past research has suggested that the first signs of metacognition – for example, reporting feelings of uncertainty – emerge at the end of toddlerhood, around the same time as the first signs of self-control and theory of mind. We wanted to take a closer look at the order in which these skills emerge, to see if what we found would support our hypothesis: that metacognition and self-control are necessary for the development of theory of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw a group of Scottish children three times, over a year and a half, starting when they were three to four years old. Each time, we gave them the same set of assessments, allowing us to see when metacognition, self-control and theory of mind emerged in the same children, and how they related to each other. To examine children’s metacognitive abilities, we asked them to pick out an item (say, a duck) from a pair of blurred pictures, and then asked whether they were ‘sure’ or ‘not so sure’ of their answer. If children tend to say ‘sure’ more often when they’ve got the answer right, it’s a sign that they are sensitive to their own certainty. Our measures of self-control included a version of the popular game Simon Says, in which children were to follow certain instructions but not others. To measure theory of mind, we tested children’s understanding of beliefs, knowledge, intentions and emotions – seeing, for instance, if they could correctly say whether a character knew the contents of a container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across this developmental period, we found that the majority of children first became competent in metacognition, followed by self-control, and then theory of mind. Our results imply that the first two abilities might provide important stepping stones to the ability to reason about other people’s thoughts and feelings. Further, metacognition and self-control were related to each other across time, suggesting that being able to introspect about one’s own thoughts plays a role in the development of self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many of us, then, getting to know our own mental states early in life may be key to other skills. Let’s revisit the chocolate trick: the big brother knows that there are marbles in the chocolate box. However, he has to suppress this knowledge to focus on what his sister will think. He might plan the trick by considering what he would think in his little sister’s shoes, or by predicting an action pattern (people who want chocolates look in chocolate boxes). But, in either case, he must already understand that thoughts – not reality – guide people’s behaviour. The simplest way for a child to arrive at that understanding might be through introspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insights into how theory of mind emerges &lt;/strong&gt;are important from a practical perspective. The development of this ability to reason about other minds can be disrupted by environmental factors, such as a lack of opportunity for social interaction and language development, and by neurodivergence, which is sometimes associated with difficulty in social reasoning. To support children in developing theory of mind, experts might usefully target its developmental building blocks. That could include focusing, in part, on supporting a child’s self-reflection and self-control. For example, while some researchers have sought to help children develop theory of mind with the aid of thought bubbles that illustrate story characters’ thoughts and beliefs, a more accessible starting point for many children might be encouraging them to engage in introspection – perhaps by externalising their own thought processes in this concrete way (eg, within bubbles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is crucial to consider whether the developmental foundations of this skill set are universal. Researchers are currently pulling together to address a pervasive &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/the-problem-with-parenting-interventions-in-the-global-south&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;cultural bias&lt;/a&gt; in developmental psychology: the majority of information we have on child development is based on studies with Western populations. In Western societies, people tend to consider a principal goal of child development to be gaining independence and self-reliance – becoming the ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/why-main-character-syndrome-is-philosophically-dangerous&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;main character&lt;/a&gt;’ in one’s own life. But, in much of the world, a principal goal is to support a child to be interdependent, to fit in with their social surroundings to sustain the greater good. For example, in Japan, developing &lt;em&gt;omoiyari&lt;/em&gt; – a concept similar to empathy and sympathy – is a key goal of child-rearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps surprisingly, given this social focus, research suggests that children growing up in ‘interdependent’ societies tend to develop these abilities differently, demonstrating self-control earlier but theory of mind later than their Western counterparts. This apparent difference could be because standard theory of mind tasks have been developed using a Western lens, focusing on an individual’s intent as the key driver of behaviour. However, it could also be due to substantial cross-cultural variation in the way people mentally represent self and other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings from developmental research, including other &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/desc.13417&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; we’ve done, indicate that there could be significant cultural differences in the stepping stones to theory of mind. In this research, we asked children in Scotland and Japan to complete the tasks described previously. In both groups, we again found that introspective ability was related to self-control. However, neither ability was strongly related to Japanese children’s theory of mind, suggesting that the developmental precursors may differ between independent and interdependent societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this cross-cultural finding holds in future research, how might we explain the difference? It is possible that in interdependent societies, it does not take (as much) self-reflection or self-control to be able to consider another person’s thoughts and feelings, since other people’s perspectives are always closer to the forefront of thought. In cultures with an interdependent focus, children may follow a different set of developmental stepping stones to theory of mind, perhaps through the scaffolding of shared perspectives of reality. In other contexts, however – including in the independence-focused West – a child’s ability to guess at other people’s thoughts and feelings is likely to begin with introspection on &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;their own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/how-do-we-start-learning-to-read-other-peoples-minds</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/how-do-we-start-learning-to-read-other-peoples-minds</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Josephine Ross, Martin Doherty</author></item><item><title>There’s no good reason to love each other – and that’s a relief</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;‘Why do you love me?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many years, I have come to think this is an ill-formed question. Ill-formed for many reasons, not the least of which might be that it has no good answer. ‘Because you are strong; because you are attractive; because you make me laugh; because you are kind; because you will be a great father; because you are (financially or otherwise) stable; because you are great in bed; because you make me feel complete; because you are confident, tranquil, young, fun, creative, smart, composed…’ Ad nauseam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I thought – for a very long time – that there was a very good reason to love one another. And this belief also made me think that the point of life was to make oneself lovable. I would go to the gym – to be lovable. I would write great books – to be loveable. And I would hold myself together, as best as humanly possible – to be loveable. Of course, I should have known that this was a largely futile project. At the end of the (very long) day, I felt out of shape, ugly, poor and vulnerable. Probably, at root, because I had the misguided belief that the question ‘Why do you love me?’ could have an adequate answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do believe that there is a reason to love – trust me, you will spend your life looking for it. And from a man who has been married three times, again believe me, it will destroy any and all chances for true intimacy. If you tacitly think that you have to be a certain way to satisfy love’s conditions, you will dedicate your life to it, and, most likely, waste it in the process. I spent so many hours in the gym, on the treadmill, in the library – thinking that all of this was going to pay off. And I spent so much of my life scrutinising others – most especially my closest intimates – to see whether they measured up. Not realising that love is not a matter of debt and exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can imagine a couple in love – for five or seven years – arriving at dinner one night, on a night without kids or responsibilities, without much to say, and without much to do. The husband says ‘I love you’ in exactly the way that says ‘Do you &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;love me?’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the wife, she smiles broadly. ‘Of course!’ she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She clears her throat to explain: ‘I love you because you are so kind to me in hard times – and &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; there for me when I &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;am sad.’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The husband nods and acts satisfied, but he wouldn’t be. Surely there had to be better (or at least more extensive) reasons than this. This is it? And in the back of his head, he would have the more disturbing thought that his wife was really just lying to him: three days ago, she had swung into an inconsolable mood, a true unspeakable funk, and he… he had been nothing like kind or supportive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, there is probably no good reason his wife could furnish. Because there is no good reason to love him – or me, or you. Because there is no good reason to love. An exhaustive list of love’s conditions cannot be assembled. Just as an exhaustive list of characteristics cannot fully describe yourself, or just as an exhaustive list of possibilities cannot define your future. This is for the best. If you don’t believe me, let’s take a second to consider Elizabeth Barrett Browning’s ode to unreasonable passions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;How do I love thee? Let me count the ways.&lt;br&gt;I love thee to the depth and breadth and height&lt;br&gt;My soul can reach, when feeling out of sight&lt;br&gt;For the ends of being and ideal grace.&lt;br&gt;I love thee to the level of every day’s&lt;br&gt;Most quiet need, by sun and candle-light.&lt;br&gt;I love thee freely, as men strive for right.&lt;br&gt;I love thee purely, as they turn from praise.&lt;br&gt;I love thee with the passion put to use&lt;br&gt;In my old griefs, and with my childhood’s faith.&lt;br&gt;I love thee with a love I seemed to lose&lt;br&gt;With my lost saints. I love thee with the breath,&lt;br&gt;Smiles, tears, of all my life; and, if God choose,&lt;br&gt;I shall but love thee better after death.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poet never says ‘I love you &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; –.’ She doesn’t ask ‘how do I love thee’ and then give extensive reasons. That would be rather dissatisfying, wouldn’t it? Love is not to be earned or bartered, because if it were then it would be something of comparable, and not incomparable, worth. And that’s what we want in love and life and marriage, something of incomparable worth. So we should get it through our heads – there is no reason to love one another. In the words of the monk and poet &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/can-a-vow-of-silence-last-forever-the-paradox-of-thomas-merton&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Thomas Merton&lt;/a&gt;, ‘love is not a package’ to be measured, bartered and exchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be counterintuitive but I promise it will turn out to be more right than not in the end. Because, in the end, we are all extremely unpleasant little beasts. We are unkind and short-tempered and disloyal, and altogether ugly – plus, we grow old, get sick and die – which is about the best reason that one could ever have to avoid loving little creatures like us. We could never, ever, in any number of lifetimes earn something like love. But we do love and are loved, and that unreasonable fact should provide a bit of peace of mind in several different respects, just so long as we take it to be wholly and utterly unreasonable. Loving (and especially getting married) is an unreasonable decision, and it has to be for love to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I was 40, I hopped off a treadmill in the&lt;/strong&gt; gym at the university where I teach. I had just killed myself for nearly an hour, thinking that I was only worth something (in other words, was lovable) by submitting myself to its whirring belt. And then I actually died. The EMTs brought me back to life after a cardiac arrest, and I spent a year going through bypass surgery and convalescing in the most unbecoming of situations. My third (and, I swear, final) wife, Kathleen, had to help me to the bathroom, had to help me use the bathroom, had to help me out of bed, had to put up with my most unbearable mood. And it was the first time that I realised that you don’t love someone for any good reason – because I certainly wasn’t furnishing any. It was the greatest relief of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why making up after an argument can be so incredibly life changing. In this way, you (sometimes) prove that things can actually go to hell, and you still love each other, and that little miracle is so revelatory, so freeing, there are few acts that can embody it: laughing, singing, dancing, crying…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These activities in their purest forms are not forced, and they are neither compelled nor described accurately by any logical process. They are also, interestingly, not chosen, at least not in the typical sense of making a choice with a particular justification. In fact, if I present the reasons – extensive or compelling – for why a joke is so very funny, it becomes immediately less so. Tragic situations become less dire (thank God) in their therapeutic description. Dancing, or other acts that involve rhythm and beat, become mechanical and other-than-themselves when we think too carefully about their supposed rhyme and reason. Description has a way of destroying certain experiences. I take this as instructive. Having reasons is sometimes overrated, and maybe one of these sometimes is being in love. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/it-is-time-for-love-to-become-a-radical-force-in-politics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Hannah Arendt&lt;/a&gt; once said of love, it ‘is killed, or rather extinguished, the moment it is displayed in public.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might say that all of this is so obvious that none of it is worth mentioning. After all, we talk about ‘unconditional love’ like we already know what it means. But I would submit that we often speak with the most confidence about matters we regularly ignore, overlook and know nothing about. To say ‘I love you unconditionally’ frequently means ‘On balance, I will stay with you mostly, no matter what: I have weighed all the reasons that I love you and they will usually outweigh the reasons not to.’ As you can hear, this has everything to do with counting reasons and very little to do with love beyond measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say ‘I love you unconditionally’ is instead simply to say that there is no reason, neither good nor bad, for me to love you at all, that I do it freely without reason, in the same way that I laugh unexpectedly at this situation and not that. In this sense, love is more akin to an act of faith than a rational decision, and continues to be as long as we are ‘in it’. So let’s not forget, and it is easy to forget, the leaping into love or marriage is not a singular act, but rather remains as audacious (and irrational) as the initial fanfare of a wedding. Otherwise, it isn’t love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite poems is Emily Dickinson’s ‘Why Do I Love You, Sir?’ And the answer is just so terse, laconic, unreasonable – and right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;‘Why do I love’ you, Sir?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Because –&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The Wind does not require the Grass&lt;br&gt;To answer – Wherefore when He pass&lt;br&gt;She cannot keep Her place.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Because He knows – and&lt;br&gt;Do not You –&lt;br&gt;And We know not –&lt;br&gt;Enough for Us&lt;br&gt;The Wisdom it be so –&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The Lightning – never asked an Eye&lt;br&gt;Wherefore it shut – when He was by –&lt;br&gt;Because He knows it cannot speak –&lt;br&gt;And reasons not contained –&lt;br&gt;– Of Talk –&lt;br&gt;There be – preferred by Daintier Folk –&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The Sunrise – Sire – compelleth Me –&lt;br&gt;Because He’s Sunrise – and I see –&lt;br&gt;Therefore – Then –&lt;br&gt;I love Thee –&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you fall out of love? It can never, I think, be by discovering that there is no reason left. Maybe we fall out of love when we confuse the conditions of companionship with love itself, which is, for better and for worse, unreasonable. Maybe we fall out of love just by thinking that we have to have the reasons to &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;stay in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is another possibility, which is terrifying and therefore probably true. Maybe love ends as a song does: in its own time. Or as laughter fades, when the time is over. And maybe that is reason enough to be unspeakably grateful for the time that we have left.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/theres-no-good-reason-to-love-each-other-and-thats-a-relief</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/theres-no-good-reason-to-love-each-other-and-thats-a-relief</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>John Kaag</author></item><item><title>Reflections on mortality can help you live well now – here’s how</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;When I was an adolescent, I developed a profound fear of flying. But I also&lt;em&gt; really &lt;/em&gt;loved to travel. To overcome this impasse, I developed a sort of spontaneous ritual. As soon as I got myself situated on the plane – carry-on stowed, seat belt buckled – I would close my eyes and take a few deep breaths. Then I would ask myself a question: ‘If I were to die today on this flight, what would I regret?’ Unwittingly, and knowing nothing of the tradition, I had developed my own &lt;em&gt;memento mori.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.aeonmedia.co/user_image_upload/3947/insert-a-woman-divided-into-two_-representing-life-and-death.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Half woman half skeleton holding a scythe in an oil painting with flowers in the background.&quot; class=&quot;ld-image-block&quot; height=&quot;972&quot; width=&quot;819&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;ld-image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Woman Divided into Two, Representing Life and Death&lt;/em&gt;. Courtesy the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wellcomecollection.org/works/qwfwb7bm/items&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Wellcome Collection, London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For millennia, and all over the world, people have actively cultivated a relationship with death as an important part of a life well lived. One way they have done so is through the use of &lt;em&gt;memento mori&lt;/em&gt; (Latin for ‘remember you must die’). These are practices, objects or artworks created expressly to remind people of their death as a means of encouraging them to live the life they truly want before it’s too late. By forging a relationship with death, many people have found that they were, paradoxically, able to live fuller and more meaningful lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs, the man behind Apple computers and the iPhone, made use of &lt;em&gt;memento mori &lt;/em&gt;in the crafting of a unique and impactful life. In a 2005 commencement speech – soon after he was diagnosed with a rare form of pancreatic cancer – Jobs shared that, since his teens, he would look in the mirror every morning and ask himself: ‘If today were the last day of my life, would I want to do what I am about to do today?’ If he found that the answer to that question was ‘No’ for too many days in a row, then he would make a change. He also told the young graduates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Remembering that I’ll be dead soon is the most important tool I’ve ever encountered to help me make the big choices in life. Because almost everything – all external expectations, all pride, all fear of embarrassment or failure – these things just fall away in the face of death, leaving only what is truly important.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What our ancestors knew so well – and Jobs and I both accidentally discovered – is that contemplating death is a powerful tool that, regardless of your beliefs about God or an afterlife, can transform your life. Its formidable lineage stretches back at least to Socrates, who asserted that the core of philosophy itself was a &lt;em&gt;memento mori&lt;/em&gt;-like contemplation of one’s mortality. In ancient Rome, it was common to encounter a skeleton mosaic on a tavern floor as an exhortation to ‘seize the day’ (&lt;em&gt;carpe diem&lt;/em&gt;); in other words, eat, drink and be merry, for tomorrow you might be dead. Christians used &lt;em&gt;memento mori &lt;/em&gt;as a reminder to resist earthly temptations and to be ready to meet (and be judged by) their maker. &lt;em&gt;Memento mori &lt;/em&gt;were also used by &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/videos/to-tibetan-buddhists-sky-burials-are-sacred-to-tourists-theyre-a-morbid-curiosity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;some Buddhists&lt;/a&gt;, who would visit charnel grounds and meditate on decomposing corpses as a means of overcoming fear of death. Even today, one sometimes finds a human skeleton in a Buddhist meditation space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl Jung (1875-1961), the founder of analytical psychology and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/videos/sex-religion-and-envy-how-freud-and-jungs-frenetic-friendship-tore-itself-apart&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;onetime protégé&lt;/a&gt; of Sigmund Freud, believed that, even for nonreligious people, the contemplation of death is deeply important. He asserted that coming to terms with mortality is one of the most important tasks of life from middle age on, and that developing one’s own personal understanding of it is essential to psychological wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, I have found that keeping reminders of mortality close at hand provides me with the clarity to see what truly matters to me, and the courage necessary to live a life aligned with my values. Because I have, for decades, been asking myself what I would regret if I were to die – &lt;em&gt;and because I made changes in accord with those answers&lt;/em&gt; – I live a rich and fulfilling life that I appreciate every day. Contemplating death has not given me financial security or a generous retirement account, but it &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; allowed me to manifest a life – one filled with travel, learning, beauty, relationships and artistic expression – that will, I hope, leave me with few deathbed regrets and allow me to die with a sense of peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.aeonmedia.co/user_image_upload/3946/insert-1965_235_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A painting of a skull on books with an hourglass candle and papers on a table conveying a vanitas theme.&quot; class=&quot;ld-image-block&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; width=&quot;806&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;ld-image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Memento Mori, ‘To this Favour’&lt;/em&gt; (1879) by William Michael Harnett. Courtesy the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clevelandart.org/art/1965.235&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Cleveland Museum of Art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, I started a project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.morbidanatomy.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Morbid Anatomy&lt;/a&gt;. Devoted to the places where art, death and culture intersect, it began as a blog and has since evolved to include exhibitions, films, books, a research library and various educational programmes. Morbid Anatomy is also a &lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;, a place for people around the world who wish to talk about, or develop a positive relationship with, death and mortality. At the beginning of the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/span&gt; lockdown, I started to teach an online class for Morbid Anatomy called ‘Make Your Own Memento Mori’. I wanted to use that particular historical moment – one in which death was demanding our attention in a way it had not in decades – as an invitation to develop a relationship with our mortality. The class introduced students to a rich variety of ways in which other eras and cultures made sense of, imagined and even celebrated death. They also made their own&lt;em&gt; memento mori,&lt;/em&gt; an object intended to remind them of death so as to make the best use of their time on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/736595/memento-mori-by-joanna-ebenstein/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;new book&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Memento Mori: The Art of Contemplating Death to Live a Better Life &lt;/em&gt;(2024) draws from and expands on my experience teaching this class. It also offers dozens of practical exercises designed to help any of us forge a personal relationship with death, reduce our fear of it and find clarity on what&lt;em&gt;, for us,&lt;/em&gt; makes a life well lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I will share a few of these activities with you, along with their animating principles. Just grab a pen and paper – or speak into the notes app on your phone – and respond to the questions and prompts that follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reflect on your ideas about death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one knows for sure what happens after we die. And, of course, it’s natural to fear the unknown, especially when that unknown is as mysterious, inevitable and personally impactful as death. But another natural response to the unknown is &lt;em&gt;curiosity&lt;/em&gt;. A provocative &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0191886920305882&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by the behavioural scientist Coltan Scrivner and colleagues found that people who possess ‘morbid curiosity’ – those with an interest in topics such as death and the macabre – have greater positive resilience, or the ability to have a positive experience even in threatening or frightening situations. Following individuals during the recent pandemic, they noted that the morbidly curious were able to find this fraught historical moment not only frightening, but also &lt;em&gt;interesting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, see if it is possible for you to get curious about different views on death, to feel a sense of wonder rather than – or at least, in addition to – fear. An important first step towards opening your mind to other ways of thinking and allowing in a sense of curiosity is to uncover your present beliefs and their likely sources. Below are some prompts to get you started. Try to respond as quickly as possible, without overthinking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did your parents think about death and what happens after &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;you die?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is your first memory of death? Was it a pet, a grandparent, a friend? If it was a person, were you invited to the funeral? What was the experience like? How might it have impacted the way you think about death today? How did your family or other adults talk to you &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;about it?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did your culture tell you about death and what happens after? Do these ideas feel true to you? Have such ideas made the world a better place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore less familiar ideas about death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing some reflection about your views on death, I encourage you to learn about some of the ways people living in other cultures or eras have understood it. Many of us today look to science to explain life, death and everything in between. For the vast majority of our ancestors, however, the truths of life and death were to be found in mythology and religion. With rich and fully realised cosmologies – and the near-ubiquitous belief that the death of the body does not mean the end of the person – these stories can offer us, if nothing else, different metaphors for understanding the human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a nonreligious Jewish family. No one told me what they believed (or disbelieved) about God or what happens after we die. As an adult, while researching the history of Jewish belief, I was surprised to learn that some Jews believed in an angel of death who would collect you at your allotted time. I also discovered that some Jewish sects believe that, after death, your soul is given a view of its previous life from a newly acquired spiritual vantage point. The pain one experiences upon seeing one’s own shortcomings acts like a temporary hellfire, purging the soul of its impurities and preparing it for its next destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking to the traditions of another culture can also reshape your view of death. In &lt;em&gt;The Labyrinth of Solitude &lt;/em&gt;(1950), the Nobel Prize-winning author Octavio Paz wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The word death is not pronounced in New York, in Paris, in London, because it burns the lips. The Mexican, in contrast, is familiar with death, jokes about it, caresses it, sleeps with it, celebrates it; it is one of his favourite toys and his most steadfast love.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, in Mexico, images of death are ubiquitous; one sees skulls and skeletons in the paintings of Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera, in the signages for bars and restaurants, and in the popular Lotería children’s game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.aeonmedia.co/user_image_upload/3945/insert-detail-diego-river-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Painting of a crowd with a skeleton in a fancy hat, people in period attire, rich colours, and detailed expressions.&quot; class=&quot;ld-image-block&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; width=&quot;803&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;ld-image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detail from the mural &lt;em&gt;Dream of a Sunday Afternoon in Alameda Park&lt;/em&gt; (1947) by Diego Rivera&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Courtesy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/adam_jones/20013189894&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Adam Jones/Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Mexican holiday of &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/videos/this-stylish-1957-film-explores-mortality-and-memory-on-mexico-s-day-of-the-dead&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Día de Muertos&lt;/a&gt; (Day of the Dead) – understood as a special time when the souls of dead loved ones spend time with the living – families gather at the cemetery to clean and decorate the grave sites of their ancestors. In the home, many families also create &lt;em&gt;ofrendas&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;these are&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;altars covered with photographs of deceased family members, along with candles, copal incense, marigolds, sugar skulls and offerings of a loved one’s favourite food, drink and indulgences. Such festivals of the dead are far from rare. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/japanese-ghost-stories-dwell-in-the-spirit-of-their-times&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, Obon, or Bon, is the festival that welcomes home the returning souls of dead loved ones, and families clean familial graves and light lamps to guide the spirits of departed ancestors back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these examples in mind, choose a culture – perhaps one that is part of your own familial heritage, or simply one that piques your curiosity – and do some research about its death traditions and beliefs. Ask questions like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did they conceive of death (as an angel, a god or a goddess)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did they believe happened after the death of the body (afterlife, reincarnation)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did they have any methods for staying in communication with deceased ancestors?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might then ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What appeals to me (or does &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;appeal to me) about these traditions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What advantages or disadvantages can I see?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there something I can learn (or bring into my life) from these traditions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How might I feel if I had been brought up in this culture instead of my own? How might I live my life differently? How might I think about death differently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a way I can see past traditions living on in my family even today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write your own obituary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, an oblique entry point allows you to uncover information about yourself that might otherwise be unavailable. In this exercise, I ask you to view your life from the perspective of it having just ended. If you had lived &lt;em&gt;the life of your dreams&lt;/em&gt;, how might your obituary read? Your obituary could be as brief as a paragraph, or several pages long. Write quickly, without overthinking, and allow yourself to be fanciful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are done, reflect on what you wrote. Did this activity reveal any dreams or aspirations that were surprising to you? If so, what are they, and could you take a first step towards putting one of them into action? For example, if your obituary states that you were the author of six novels, but you have not taken your writing seriously since college, could you commit to taking a half hour each morning to write?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultivate gratitude for a finite life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first important books in my early life was &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;E B White’s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Charlotte’s Web&lt;/em&gt; (1952). Of all the characters in the book, the spider Charlotte has by far the shortest lifespan; she is also the one with the most gratitude for life. In the classic 1973 Hanna-Barbera film based on the book, Charlotte sings a poignant song as she nears her death. In it, she expresses a joyous and profound gratitude for the privilege of having been, if for just a brief while, ‘part of life’s eternal rhyme’. Charlotte uses her final moments to reaffirm her love of – and gratitude for – life, and to assert that, &lt;em&gt;no matter how brief&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;it is a precious gift. In fact, the brevity of her time on earth seems to intensify her appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Charlotte, I have found that taking the time to feel gratitude for the good things in my life – as it is, right here and now – helps me appreciate the gift of life, even in its finitude, and minimises my frustrations about the aspects of life that fall short of my dreams and desires. For years now, every night, I have been practising a sort of daily gratitude ritual. Once I am in bed, eyes closed and moving towards sleep, I take a few deep breaths. Then, for one slow, full breath (in-breath and exhalation), I give thanks for something I appreciated that happened that day. I do this five times each night, paired with five breaths. The things I appreciate are sometimes quite simple, such as wonderful weather, but can also include more noteworthy milestones, such as turning in a manuscript. This gratitude exercise can also be done daily as a written exercise in &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/ideas/learn-the-art-of-journaling-and-archive-your-life&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;your journal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider how facing imminent death might change your life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be challenging to separate the wheat from the chaff when trying to figure out what you really value. How can we learn to distinguish the things that&lt;em&gt; really&lt;/em&gt; matter from the more prosaic longings we encounter every day? One way is through the evocation of regret, which we might see as the flip side of gratitude. In her book &lt;em&gt;The Top Five Regrets of the Dying: A Life Transformed by the Dearly&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Departing &lt;/em&gt;(2011), the Australian nurse Bronnie Ware writes about what she learned over years of working with palliative care patients. Their most common regrets included focusing too much on work, not having retained contact with their friends, and not having had the courage to live a life true to their own values. Kristina Golden, a Morbid Anatomy community member who is also a death doula – or person who helps individuals navigate the dying process – reports that the regret she hears the most is: ‘I should have said “I love you” more.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, ask yourself some questions about your current life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you died today, what would you regret having done or not done in your life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would you change your life right now if you found out that you had five years to live? One year? &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;One&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write down the answers that come up for you. Then, use them to make a change. If, for example, you found that you regret not having cultivated your adolescent talent for drawing, can you find or buy a sketchpad and spend a few moments each morning making art? If you find you regret having drifted from an old friend, can you send them an email, or reach out to make a coffee date?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a better relationship with death is a lifelong process, and I encourage you to continue with the good work you begin here. You can do this by returning to these prompts over a series of months or even years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the most out of this sort of work, I also recommend that you give yourself time and space to process the powerful and emotional material that comes up in a non-direct, non-rational way. This might take the form of yoga, meditation, walks, journal writing, drawing or something else entirely. Pay attention to any images or ideas that bubble up from the unconscious in your dreams or daydreams, and consider giving them form in some way, such as by making a painting or writing a poem. If you find that this sort of reflecting on death is feeling unhealthy or even dangerous for you, set it aside for the time being, or consider talking about it with a friend or a therapist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confronting the reality and unknowns of death can not only make us less afraid of death; it can help us learn to tolerate all of that which we cannot control, to sit with the mystery at the heart of life and still appreciate, and with great joy, the life we have been given. I urge you, then, to allow yourself to be &lt;em&gt;curious&lt;/em&gt; about mortality, to approach it with humility, treating it as the mystery that it has always been and continues to be, despite our impressive scientific advances. It is my hope that, in this way, you might find beauty and value in something that many of us have been told has no value whatsoever. I also hope it will empower you to uncover your own truths and values, and inspire you to live them out in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/reflections-on-mortality-can-help-you-live-well-now-heres-how</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/reflections-on-mortality-can-help-you-live-well-now-heres-how</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Joanna Ebenstein</author></item><item><title>The shame felt in addiction often isn’t toxic – it’s healing</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Eighteen years ago, I was deep in the throes of addiction to booze and benzos. At the end, every morning was the same. I’d wake up only to be greeted by the excruciating recognition that I had failed yet again in my resolution to stop using. The feeling was much more existentially profound and penetrative than the guilt I also felt for drinking oceans of vodka in the previous decade. My problem was qualitative. It was about who I was as a person, about the quality of my character. I was ashamed of myself, ashamed of being me. There was a remedy that I enacted like an automaton. I’d drive to the nearby BP station and buy several morning beers that would ease my physical distress and dull the psychic shame until the next day when the exact same script would repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was an addict in a self-sustaining double bind: I used, eventually and in part, in order to mitigate the shame of addiction. It worked. But using each day in order to dull or defeat the shame of addiction seeded further shame the next day, and thus provided a powerful reason to drink and pop pills on each new bleak morning. &lt;em&gt;Huis clos&lt;/em&gt;, no exit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many compassionate people, including many clinicians, think shame can serve no useful role in recovery from addiction. There are two arguments. First, that shame is uniquely toxic because, like the shame I just described, it is often global, a negative emotional evaluation of who one is: I am a failure as a person. It makes little sense to think that such an evaluation could seed or motivate a healthy confidence that one can overcome the addiction. It makes much more sense to think that experiencing the shame of addiction provides a new reason to use. Second, the current enlightened view is that addiction is a disease, and diseases are not the kind of thing one has control over or responsibility for getting, or not getting, or &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;un-getting.&lt;/span&gt; Since addicts are not responsible for having the disease of addiction, the thinking goes, they should not feel shame, nor should others make them feel ashamed or blame them. We don’t blame people for getting &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;COVID-19,&lt;/span&gt; the flu or brain cancer, and feeling shame for getting these diseases seems irrational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both arguments need nuance. The shame of addiction often does make sense – and it can be therapeutically useful. Furthermore, addiction, if it is a disease, is not the kind of disease for which experiencing shame makes no sense. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to anthropologists &lt;/strong&gt;and cultural psychologists, every culture ever &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1463499605059233&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;studied&lt;/a&gt; uses highly arousing negative emotions – anger, guilt, shame, fear, sadness – to teach its values, norms and practices. These emotions are negative in the simple sense that they have negative valence. They feel bad. This doesn’t mean they are bad. Shame (along with guilt) protects a culture’s values, and a culture builds a self-regulating conscience or a sense of appropriate shame among its members. The self-regulation is key: if one accepts certain norms but is tempted to violate them, one experiences anticipatory shame that, at its best, catches people up short of doing what they think they ought not &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;to do.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most kinds of shame do not involve a negative global evaluation of the self. If a parent says to a child: ‘You ought to be ashamed of yourself for not sharing the blocks with your sister,’ they aren’t inviting the child to experience global shame, to think that he is a bad person. The invitation is to abide by a norm of sharing because it makes games more fun and because that’s what good people do. There are, of course, extreme forms of shame that are weaponised to make people loathe themselves because of unchangeable characteristics – they are perceived as being the wrong colour or shape, or from the wrong place – which is cruel and never justified or helpful. These extreme kinds of global shame are fertile soil for addiction. However, ordinary, everyday shame is not so lethal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinary shame can be informationally rich, in terms of where and how one is failing and might need to step up or change one’s game. It is common to feel shame if one detects that one is falling short of shared values and norms and is consequently perceived as lazy, unreliable, sloppy, socially awkward or dishonest. Socialisation is supposed to work &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;this way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a very common norm that is protected by shame: do not develop a habit that undermines your ability to live a good life or achieve your goals, or that ruins your most treasured relationships. The norm is general – it could apply to habits such as shirking responsibility at work, stealing, or antagonising people – but it applies especially well to addiction, because addiction is a condition that causes personal distress. There comes a time when the costs for the addict dramatically outweigh the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The shame of addiction, properly focused,&lt;/strong&gt; invites the addict to recognise that they were a person before they were an addict – and that they can be that person again, or some new and improved version of that person, if they can find a way to undo their addiction. Three types of failure reliably produce this kind of shame:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Self-control failure:&lt;/em&gt; a loss of control over the substance. The addict tries to moderate or stop using, but can’t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Conventional decency failure: &lt;/em&gt;the addict displays some degree of difficulty in abiding by the conventional sociomoral order because of their addiction. The addict has a picture of a conventionally decent person, and they want to be one, but they aren’t measuring up. They become unreliable, dissemble and make commitments to themselves and others that they don’t keep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Telos failure: &lt;/em&gt;the addict has various plans and goals that they want to achieve: finishing high school, becoming a professional basketball player, comedian, firefighter, partner, parent. Besides all the normal obstacles humans face in achieving their ends, addicts often self-undermine due to their addiction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shame as a response to these three failures is not global. It is not a negative evaluation of every aspect of one’s being. Rather, it is a perfectly sensible emotional response to failing to abide by norms for a good life that the addict accepts. It warrants shame rather than guilt because addiction involves a habit, a set of dispositions, not only a set of proscribed acts (such as drinking too much).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many addicts who experience shame for these three failures are motivated to seek help. In my own case, friends, family and various professionals helped me understand that, despite the way my shame felt at first – like a global indictment of who I was – it made sense for me to feel ashamed only for having perfected a very unhealthy, self-undermining habit. I was a person before my addiction, and the task now was to eliminate the habit without giving up on myself, the person with the addiction. The wisdom in AA and NA meetings often comes around to addicts helping each other experience their shame in this way, in order to keep their eyes on the prize of &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-drink-in-a-healthier-way-by-moderating-your-intake&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;undoing their habit&lt;/a&gt;, without needing to entirely redo themselves as people. We do not tell each other that our shame has no basis, although we often tell each other that global shame and self-loathing are unwarranted and counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process is not always easy. Some addicts started young – early starting age is, sadly, a strong &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1878929316301931&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;predictor&lt;/a&gt; of eventual addiction. They started before they were a fully developed person. These individuals cannot simply be invited to become again who they once were. Other addicts are charmed by their addiction, and experience it as identity-constitutive. They were a person before they were a person with an addiction, but they have trouble seeing how to be that person again and understanding why they should want to. Cases such as these require delicacy, compassion (including self-compassion), sensitivity and wise guidance. In combination with these qualities, addicts and clinicians can still work profitably with shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its best, the shame of addiction is a healing shame. It is focused, not immobilising, and does not embed a desire to punish oneself.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It calls the addict to account, but does not involve a negative evaluation of the whole self. The shame of addiction is not normally like the theatrical shame of Greek tragedy. Oedipus can never escape his shame. He did, after all, kill his father, and marry and sleep with his mother. The shame of addiction is different. The addict can normally undo the cause of their shame – the addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethically speaking, one should &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-cope-with-shame-by-understanding-where-it-comes-from&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;feel shame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; only for what one can control. This brings us to the second argument against shame in addiction, which relates not to the toxicity and globality of shame but to the fact that diseases are not the kind of thing one ought to feel ashamed about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the rub. Every effective treatment of addiction requires the addict to judge their addiction as harmful and to take responsibility for their addiction. Cognitive behavioural therapy assists addicts in &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-know-if-youre-addicted-to-alcohol-or-drugs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;identifying patterns&lt;/a&gt; in their situations, feelings, thoughts and behaviour that sustain the addiction, and working to undo them. In contingency management, small rewards are earned for abstinence or moderation. Motivational interviewing helps the addict gain insight into their most important aims and how the addiction undermines them. Other approaches include therapeutic communities – often cohousing communities with practices designed to heal the addiction – and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/why-didnt-group-therapy-become-a-psychoanalysis-for-the-people&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;group therapy&lt;/a&gt;, such as AA and NA. Addicts can also take medications to treat co-occurring mental health conditions, to diminish their cravings or to substitute a safer substance for the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;addictive one.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When addicts speak of the disease or disorder of addiction, the analogy is almost always to diseases such as &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;type-2&lt;/span&gt; diabetes, where the individual participates to a certain extent (sometimes unwittingly) in the development of the disease. The individual bears some responsibility for developing the condition, and every way out – to remission or recovery – requires a reassertion of responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telling addicts they ought not to feel shame for their addiction is a form of gaslighting. The shame is inevitable, given the constant social messages they receive that addiction is not a sensible or worthy lifestyle choice. Again, shame is what you are supposed to feel if you have a trait or habit that is socially disapproved and that undermines your aims for a good life. In my experience, most people who experience shame for their addictions judge it to be a warranted, authentic response to their predicament, and find that that recognition motivates healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot is this. Beware of glib statements to the effect that, because addiction is a disease, feelings of shame should have no place in how an addict or anyone else conceives the addict’s plight or way to recovery. Addicts have a host of emotional responses to their plight, and people do them no service by telling them that their shame is baseless. Successful treatments use the addict’s own emotional responses to what ails them to provide reasons and motive for recovery. Insofar as addiction is a disease, it is the kind that one must take responsibility in undoing.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/the-shame-felt-in-addiction-often-isnt-toxic-its-healing</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/the-shame-felt-in-addiction-often-isnt-toxic-its-healing</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Owen Flanagan</author></item><item><title>For a happier life, we must balance two old psychological needs</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Most of us know people who struggle to be happy despite having it all. I remember visiting my friend Steve after he struck it rich, and being blown away by his cushy existence. As I wandered through his extraordinary home, I told him that his life was over the top. Steve admitted that it &lt;em&gt;seemed&lt;/em&gt; that way but then explained to me – with a straight face – that it really wasn’t. While I nibbled on his caviar and brie, I learned that the cook didn’t get along with the maid, he and his wife couldn’t agree on where to go on their next vacation, his daughter was waitlisted at the fancy kindergarten, and the list went on. By the time he finished, I felt so sorry for him that I offered to trade places, if only to sort out this vexing cook/maid problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time, I marvelled at Steve’s inability to see his own good fortune but, later, as I was reading Frank Marlowe’s wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucpress.edu/books/the-hadza/paper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Hadza: Hunter-Gatherers of Tanzania&lt;/em&gt; (2010), it occurred to me that I’m just like Steve. And so are you. Anthropological &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/psychology/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.01173/full&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ajpa.1330780409?casa_token=aid1DCQkZKsAAAAA%3A15hTUPCPxJD-RE0d6dIw5SEKYfcUP3KM1vkUCAb-VVFSXPUj_6lRsCEaOJBmBWRczhTrTNELByf6Ias&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;suggest&lt;/a&gt; that we’re no happier (and possibly a lot less happy) than the remaining hunter-gatherers, who eke out a living much like our distant ancestors did. The comforts, safety and ease of modern existence make most of us the equivalent of multimillionaires by comparison with them, but our hunter-gatherer ancestors were probably happier than we are. How could &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;that be?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s more than one answer to this question, but an important part of the story lies deep in our history. Based on evolutionary theory and psychological research, I have come to believe that human evolution has led to a pair of competing psychological needs that must be balanced in order for individuals to experience lasting happiness. These needs reflect two key goals our distant ancestors had to achieve: to &lt;em&gt;bond with others&lt;/em&gt; for their mutual protection, and to &lt;em&gt;develop personal skills&lt;/em&gt; to make them valuable to their group and potential mates. In service of these goals, our ancestors evolved two corresponding needs that still drive us today: from childhood through to old age, humans have a &lt;em&gt;need for connection&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;need for autonomy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In developments that I recount in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harperacademic.com/book/9780062740397/the-social-leap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Social Leap&lt;/em&gt; (2018), after local climate events forced our ancestors out of the trees &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;6 million&lt;/span&gt; years ago, they eventually banded together on the savannah for safety. Their increased cooperation and sociality placed us on a new evolutionary trajectory, which ensured that our most fundamental psychological need was for connection. By &lt;em&gt;connection&lt;/em&gt;, I mean cooperating, forming social bonds, establishing long-term romantic relationships, and attaching oneself to a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The need for connection played a central role in human evolution, as it enabled us to cooperate to solve problems that we were too small, weak or ignorant to solve on our own. Hunter-gatherers who couldn’t see the need for connection soon became lion chow. As a result, their tendency to go it alone was largely removed from the gene pool, and their remains served as a vivid reminder to the folks back home that survival requires connection. Genes pushed our ancestors to connect, their cultural rules demanded connection, parental socialisation reinforced the message, and daily life reminded them that they couldn’t live &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;without it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connection was a matter of life or death then, and it remains critical now. Some forms of connection are new (social media), others are as old as the species itself (having a meal with friends), but whether you’re an introvert or extravert, connection is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vivekmurthy.com/together-book&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;fundamental&lt;/a&gt; to life satisfaction. When we work together, offer or seek advice, attend a party, sit side by side with a friend while studying or watching a movie, or even smile when we meet the eye of a stranger, we feel the imperative of connection. When we bask in the comfort and camaraderie of old friends, we’re feeling the product of &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;6 million&lt;/span&gt; years of evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the same time, the need for connection&lt;/strong&gt; was supplemented by a need for autonomy. By &lt;em&gt;autonomy&lt;/em&gt; I mean self-governance, choosing a path based on your own needs, preferences or skills, and making independent decisions. Connection makes humans effective in their struggles against predators and a harsh environment, but autonomy allows a person to increase their usefulness to others. How does autonomy serve this role? By motivating us to pursue domains in which we have the best prospects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are unique in the extent of our capacity to envision the future. One of the most important tasks our large brain allows us to do is to imagine what might happen later today, tomorrow or next year, and then prepare for it. Perhaps the most remarkable aspect of our preparations is when we change ourselves – when one decides what sort of person one needs to be in the imagined future and then sets about becoming that person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capacity to transform one’s actual self into an aspirational self is a large part of the reason we evolved a need for autonomy. From early childhood, a person’s sense of self becomes focused on personal attributes that seem to have the best chance of leading to success. Domains in which one stands out in a positive way often become central aspects of one’s self-definition. When these abilities become central to someone’s self-concept, they start to occupy the person’s mind, they become more fun and interesting, and one is likely to exercise them whenever possible. It is this dedication to one’s craft, born of autonomy and the desire to shape one’s own destiny, that motivates people to put in the hard work necessary to develop their talents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While forming social bonds with others satisfies the need for connection, it can also constrain a person’s choices by requiring them to consider the consequences of their actions for others. If those constraints are strict, they threaten autonomy. In contrast, prioritising one’s own goals and preferences without any regard for the needs and desires of others would maximise autonomy, but make one unpalatable as a relationship partner or group member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while connection and autonomy both &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11205-020-02565-8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;make&lt;/a&gt; us happy, they must be balanced against each other. Many of us today have shifted to lifestyles that emphasise autonomy and downplay social obligations and, in doing so, we have unwittingly sacrificed the connections that keep our life in balance. Examples of this can be seen in the growing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2022/03/1950-census-records-window-to-history.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;tendency&lt;/a&gt; of Americans to live alone, and in reports of people having fewer close friends. Autonomy without sufficient connection – the dynamic that characterises modern society – creates what I call &lt;em&gt;sad success stories&lt;/em&gt;: people whose achievements feel hollow and unsatisfying because they don’t have a tight network of friends to share them with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why this modern emphasis on autonomy? Connection used to be more of a necessity, and autonomy more of a luxury. In principle, individuals had an opportunity for autonomy every time the group made a decision they didn’t like but, in reality, people couldn’t just do their own thing. When it came time to break camp, if everyone else wanted to go north and you wanted to go south, you would have almost always gone north because it was too dangerous to strike out on your own. Life for our hunter-gatherer ancestors was necessarily filled with compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our modern world, opportunities for autonomy are like fat, salt and sugar – we evolved to crave them when they were rare but now they’re ubiquitous. Increasing wealth, urbanisation and education, along with dramatic increases in the types of occupations and entertainment a person can choose from, mean that people today not only have choices that our ancestors couldn’t dream of, we also no longer depend on close connections for survival the way we once did. As a result, I argue, the evolved tendency to seek autonomy when one has the chance has become a form of miswanting that has seriously disrupted the balance between these two needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where once people were physically fit and highly connected because they spent their lives hungry and threatened, now many of us are out of shape and highly autonomous because we live in comfort and safety. Just because the modern world allows us to live a certain way doesn’t mean it makes us happy. We may get what we want when we prioritise autonomy, but not what we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do we rebalance? The key&lt;/strong&gt; is to incorporate connection into our lives in ways that induce the least friction. I started doing this myself with the onset of the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/span&gt; pandemic. It’s been easy to maintain, because my new protocol is no harder than my old one and a lot more fun. I simply looked at all my activities and, for each one that was conducted alone, I asked myself how I might make it more social. By way of example, my sister and I both like to do the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; crossword puzzles, so we started doing them together even though she lives halfway around the globe. She calls once she’s made her morning coffee, Thursday through Sunday, I put in my earbuds, and we chitchat as we do the puzzle together. I love my sister dearly, but we used to talk only a few times a month because she lives so far away and we’re both so busy. The beauty of our joint-puzzle party is that it doesn’t require any additional time; we do something together that we used to do alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A change like this might be easy to make, but that doesn’t mean it will endure. So you have to make your new routine habitual. If you need to plan every time you want to socialise, you’ll find that you only occasionally spend your free time with others. But if you make connecting a habit, it takes no more effort than brushing your teeth. The best way to establish new habits is to form implementation intentions. By this I mean creating plans that are contingent on something else happening, such as: ‘When my morning coffee is ready, I’ll call my brother to do the crossword.’ Or: ‘When I’m finished eating dinner, I’ll call my old high-school friend so we can chat on the phone as we both clean up the dishes.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many ways to solve the aloneness problem. For example, most of us have lifestyle goals we’re struggling to achieve. They might be exercise goals like going for a twice-weekly run, they might be tidiness goals like picking up the toddler’s toys every afternoon, or they might be self-improvement goals like taking an online course or learning to play an instrument. These are ideal activities to do with others, in person or while chatting on the phone, because friends with the same interests help encourage you to stick with it when you might otherwise give up. By blending your connection goals with your lifestyle goals, you can increase the chance that you’ll achieve both – fulfilling autonomy and connection needs at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fixes might not seem like much, but that’s the whole point. They’re small changes in your daily existence that ramp up connections with virtually no added effort or burden. Those are the changes that stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Idea is adapted from the book &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harpercollins.com/products/the-social-paradox-william-von-hippel?variant=42821898764322&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Social Paradox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; (2025) by William von Hippel. Reprinted courtesy of Harper Books, an imprint of HarperCollins Publishers. © 2025 William von Hippel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/for-a-happier-life-we-must-balance-two-old-psychological-needs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/for-a-happier-life-we-must-balance-two-old-psychological-needs</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>William von Hippel</author></item><item><title>What if your worry problem is really a planning problem?</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Worry is one of the most common ways that anxiety shows up in life. It fills our minds with nerve-wracking thoughts about the future. &lt;em&gt;What if I forget what to say during my speech? How will I make friends in the new city I moved to? What will happen to my family if I receive harrowing news from my next doctor’s visit?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, these kind of worrisome thoughts are uncomfortable, but they’re mostly fleeting and little more than a nuisance. For others, they can become all-consuming and debilitatingly painful. Chronic, intense worry of this kind is one of the key symptoms of generalised anxiety disorder (GAD) – among the most frequently diagnosed mental health problems. Although there are established treatments – such as mindfulness meditation and cognitive behavioural therapy – for GAD and other conditions involving out-of-control worry, they are far from perfect. They don’t work for everyone and sometimes their benefits fade over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some researchers seek to better understand worry by studying neurochemistry, and others look to answers in people’s upbringing or past traumas, I believe it’s vital to study the inner workings of the mind – specifically those basic mental processes that cause worries to arise too easily and persist for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this comes down to how we &lt;em&gt;plan&lt;/em&gt; for the future. When you think of planning, such as planning a meal or planning a holiday, it might seem like a benign mental activity that has little to do with pathological worry. However, planning can go wrong in various ways and scientists and clinicians have long suggested that worrying and planning are intimately linked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, more than 30 years ago, the British clinical scientist Andrew Mathews &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0005796790901323&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; that worry had evolved to help us cope with future danger – to plan and problem-solve how to avert imagined threats from materialising. He documented how these processes had gone awry in his patients with generalised anxiety – they engaged in planning that was clearly unproductive. For example, some of them got stuck repeatedly imagining succumbing to an impending threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My work, which I outlined more formally in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/trends/cognitive-sciences/fulltext/S1364-6613(24)00292-4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Trends in Cognitive Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, builds on these earlier ideas and suggests that people suffering from chronic worry engage in &lt;em&gt;biased&lt;/em&gt; and/or &lt;em&gt;excessive&lt;/em&gt; planning. Biased planning involves inaccuracies in the planning process, which can lead us to imagine events in unrealistic ways that are incongruent with how they actually tend to transpire. Excessive planning involves planning at unhelpful times (such as when a threat is far in the future) or beyond the point when it’s useful. If you’ve ever found yourself catastrophising about the future, or tossing and turning in bed about a challenge that’s months way, then you will be able to relate to these descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The promise of thinking about worry in this way is that understanding someone’s particular planning biases and excesses will point to ways to correct them, which will help them worry less and experience reduced anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although Mathews and others continued to&lt;/strong&gt; put forward their hypothesis that anxiety is essentially&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a dysfunctional form of planning for dangerous outcomes (known as the ‘planning-anxiety hypothesis’), until recently the scientific tools simply weren’t available to test it. Planning is difficult to study scientifically because planning is a private mental process and may, in many instances, even elude our own consciousness. For example, when people plan how to take a series of actions in abstract planning tasks (such as in a game of chess), brain imaging research &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(19)30640-3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;shows&lt;/a&gt; that their hippocampus ‘pre-plays’ sequences of actions at speeds they couldn’t possibly be conscious of (such as four actions in &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;150 milliseconds).&lt;/span&gt; So, although it’s clear we have some access to actions we evaluate during planning, the richer process of simulating possible action sequences, and deciding between them, seems to hide in the subconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has implications for modern psychotherapy too. Although therapy can be beneficial, therapists are limited in their capacity to gauge how planning goes awry. The therapy process relies either on thoughts we’re aware of, or thoughts not in our awareness but that are detectable in our behaviour (for example, I might not be aware I’m angry, but my short and sarcastic remarks betray my true feelings). Although I have no doubt an expert therapist could infer that their client is affected by certain planning biases (for example, they might detect a patient’s exaggerated desire for control), it would be unrealistic to expect them to be able to detect certain planning biases underlying worry – especially those operating at a non-conscious and computational level. For this level of understanding, we need cutting-edge research methods that reveal the dynamics of how the brain simulates action sequences (that is, how it simulates planned future actions, such as how you will respond to questions in an upcoming job interview).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contemporary &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06948&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; is using two approaches to find out more about the way people simulate the future during mental planning. First is to create planning tasks in a laboratory setting, such as maze tasks or chess problems, for which we know all the ‘rules of the game’ – all possible events, actions, transitions between events, and what situations are most valuable. In such laboratory tasks, the constraints allow scientists to use computational analyses to infer the way people have simulated future actions based on their decision-making patterns. The second &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.11.01.621475v1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;approach&lt;/a&gt; is to go more directly to the source of planning by analysing brain activity. What’s really exciting is that new neuroimaging methods can now be used to decode the sequences of actions someone is planning. So, for example, if someone is planning how to exit a maze, we can use neural decoding to predict in advance the exact sequence of action the maze navigator will take &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;they act.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does all this new science about planning &lt;/strong&gt;ultimately help us to explain anxiety? The framework I’ve developed links the latest science of planning to the effort to uncover precise planning biases in anxious thought. My framework breaks down planning into two component parts: &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;(1) when&lt;/span&gt; to start and stop planning; and &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;(2) how&lt;/span&gt; to form a model of future scenarios we’re unsure about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with when we start and stop planning, which can be used to explain why some people worry too often. To decide when to begin planning, your brain carries out a cost-benefit analysis, called ‘meta-control’, based on the most efficient use of its limited computational resources. Planning is exhausting, so the benefits of engaging planning must outweigh its inherent cost to effortfully simulate many action sequences. Seen within this cost-benefit analysis, you can think of chronic worriers as potentially having a bias that overvalues the benefits of planning, and undervalues its costs. To return to the example of a job interview, a chronic worrier might plan for a job interview while lying in bed months ahead of when the interview is scheduled, even though it would be far more advantageous to delay planning altogether to get to sleep. One of my research goals is to use computational models to measure planning biases like these that corrupt meta-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After planning begins, it must stop at some point (or we’ve entered some horrifying Stephen King novel). This is another situation in which your brain must perform a cost-benefit analysis, in this case to evaluate whether your current plan is good enough or whether the chance of creating a better plan is high enough that it justifies the cost of engaging in further planning. For people with chronic worry, they might fail to reach this ‘good enough’ threshold to stop planning. This could be because their simulation of future outcomes is &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-stop-thinking-the-worst-and-learn-not-to-catastrophise&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;overly catastrophic&lt;/a&gt;, so they get stuck searching for actions that can effectively avert the intense threats. Alternatively, they might have a very high threshold for what it means to find a ‘good enough plan’. For instance, a chronic worrier facing a job interview might implicitly believe they need to form a plan that has a &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;95 per&lt;/span&gt; cent chance of success (in this case, getting hired). Such a high threshold for success might be near-impossible to internally simulate. As a consequence, they get stuck in a protracted worry episode. Another goal of my research is to develop new methods to measure these unrealistic thresholds reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capacity to control when we initiate or terminate planning critically depends on what scientists call a ‘model of the world’, which forms the second main part of my framework. Essentially, this is the imagined set of actions and events relevant to your plan – and it’s another aspect of planning that can go wrong in pathological worry. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-stop-overthinking-with-help-from-metacognitive-strategies&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;chronic worriers&lt;/a&gt; form a model of the world for a particular scenario, such as a job interview, they may be biased in which actions and events they focus on, and which they ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, assuming you don’t have a worry problem, you might plan ahead for which interview questions you might be asked and how to answer them, but you wouldn’t go so far as to simulate how you will open and close the door to the interview room. You realise implicitly that ignoring those details in your model of the job interview won’t harm your ability to form a good plan. In contrast, a chronic worrier might use their limited resources to focus on simulating minute and unhelpful details of the interview. For instance, they might think about how exactly they will move and breathe in the interview to avoid sounding awkward, even though this won’t help them succeed. By spending all their mental resources on these fine details, they forego thinking through other actions more fundamental to their goal of getting hired, such as how to answer difficult questions well. This is another target of my research – to uncover the mental processes that lead to unhelpful mental models of future events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the science of planning becomes more precise, I’m anticipating that we’ll be able to identify a person’s specific planning biases, and that will present an opportunity to think of ways to causally alter those biases. One approach could be to adapt the kind of planning tasks that we’re currently using in the laboratory. For example, imagine we discovered that someone initiated planning too often because they undervalued the cost of planning and that this was provoking excessive worry. One possibility is that we could use incentives in a laboratory planning task to train the person to perform a more accurate cost-benefit analysis of when to initiate and when to delay planning. Another approach could be focused on helping improve the mental models people use for simulating future challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a couple of examples of the many possible applications of this line of research. Anxiety and worry are the bane of so many people’s lives. I hope that over the next decade we’ll witness real progress, and the planning-anxiety framework will inspire new and effective treatments for chronic worriers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/what-if-your-worry-problem-is-really-a-planning-problem</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/what-if-your-worry-problem-is-really-a-planning-problem</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Paul B Sharp</author></item><item><title>In therapy or meditation, is it normal to feel worse at first?</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Among those who undergo psychotherapy, some &lt;a href=&quot;https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1745-6215-14-S1-P94&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;believe&lt;/a&gt; that their condition might initially worsen before it improves. This is a notion sometimes expressed by clinicians, too: ‘Often you get a little bit worse before you get better,’ the psychologist Laurie Higbed, a provider of psychedelic-assisted psychotherapy, told &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; in 2021. In meditation, there is a similar sentiment; the title of the book &lt;em&gt;No Mud, No Lotus&lt;/em&gt; (2014), by the Zen Master Thich Nhat Hanh, captures the idea that there is no bliss without some suffering. The presumption inherent in such statements is that you must sometimes experience discomfort or pain to achieve a benefit. These sentiments may be true, but they also raise questions about the extent to which one must endure these difficulties, &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;and why.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychotherapy and meditation differ in numerous ways, but their points of intersection are useful here. Both practices are challenging, and the commitment to persisting in them, despite the associated difficulties, is commonly believed to be worth the price. For example, many find it extremely challenging to sit still and ‘do nothing’ during meditation, wading through the stream of thoughts, memories, sensations and distractions that arise when the mind is freed of its normal daily constraints. In therapy, many find it hard to explore their interior world deeply and openly (sometimes for the first time) in the presence of someone they barely know. Both approaches commonly embrace the idea that such efforts can be uncomfortable and sometimes upsetting. Meditation teachers talk about the need to understand ‘suffering’ in order to potentially free ourselves of it. Likewise, practitioners of cognitive behavioural therapy recognise that &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/ideas/psychotherapy-is-not-harmless-on-the-side-effects-of-cbt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;temporary discomfort&lt;/a&gt; in sessions may be key to positive outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the amount of discomfort and whether people agree to the possibility in the first place are essential to ethical practice. I contend that sayings like ‘It has to get worse before it gets better’ often gloss over the reality that some meditations and therapies simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/can-meditation-really-make-the-world-a-better-place&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;don’t work&lt;/a&gt; for everyone, while others are &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/my-dismal-years-in-psychoanalysis-with-melanie-kleins-disciple&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;actively harmful&lt;/a&gt;. So, when is getting worse a sign that ‘the process’ is working, and when is it an indicator that the approach is unhelpful or even harmful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/21677026241298269&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; of nearly 900 meditators, my colleagues and I found that &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;58 per&lt;/span&gt; cent had experienced an unexpected, negative event that they attributed to the practice. Among the most common of these adverse effects were the recurrence of distressing thoughts or images, anxiety, bodily tension or pressure, exhaustion or fatigue, and feeling socially disconnected. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39074446/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Estimates&lt;/a&gt; of adverse effects in psychotherapy are similar in type and occurrence. The recurrence of unpleasant memories is the most common. Sleep problems and feeling more stressed, worried or generally unpleasant are also relatively frequent. Together, these findings underscore that many people experience at least temporary negative effects from undertakings that are fundamentally intended to provide help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem to suggest that some discomfort is to be expected. But it’s important that we differentiate between &lt;em&gt;discomfort &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;distress&lt;/em&gt;. We also need to define the concept of &lt;em&gt;harm. &lt;/em&gt;These clarifications can help us answer the question of whether things need to get worse before they can get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manageable, temporary discomfort &lt;/strong&gt;and prolonged, intolerable distress are very different experiences. And yet, similar terms are increasingly used to describe both (eg, ‘stress’, ‘trauma’, ‘depressed’). The psychologist Nick Haslam has &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2016-08154-001&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt; that the use of such terms has broadened in recent years to encompass an ever-wider range of ideas. While these terms historically reflected medical concepts, often requiring clinical treatment, they are increasingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2024-18110-002&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;used&lt;/a&gt; to refer to everyday experiences. The broadening of concepts to capture a wider range of less extreme experiences might make it harder to know whether unpleasant challenges are a sign of things gone wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temporary discomfort is often a &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/09567976211044685&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;condition&lt;/a&gt; of personal growth. Although it can be unpleasant to confront something you fear, to consider an alternative to a strongly held belief, or attempt to tolerate uncertainty, the possibility for change manifests in these pursuits. This kind of temporary discomfort is normative and &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1959-00842-001&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;perhaps&lt;/a&gt; even necessary to certain treatments or practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an example from therapy: if you are receiving treatment for a phobia, the temporary experience and toleration of anxiety is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0272735807000074&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;process&lt;/a&gt; by which the trigger and the reaction become disentangled. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/videos/can-you-cure-a-phobia-by-medically-rewriting-the-original-fear-memory&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;skilled psychologist&lt;/a&gt; is trained in how to manage the response such that it does not become overwhelming, else the therapy will fail to work. Heightened general anxiety (ie, anxiety unrelated to the feared situation or object) or an inability to sleep would be unintended negative outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In meditation, an increased awareness of a restless mind or harsh inner critic could initially be frustrating or upsetting. You might feel anxious about how much work lies ahead or even feel disheartened about how you (like many of us) have developed a repertoire of unhelpful behaviours. Such insights allow for the possibility of practising different behaviours that are more aligned with what you intend. But, sometimes, the frustration, anxiety or sadness is more than one is equipped to handle in the moment. Recognising the need to change one’s behaviour (whether in the moment, in the practice, or in life), alongside the awareness of one’s current capacity to do so, could be a sign of progress – but only if it isn’t overwhelming and unending. Again, we need to be able to endure short-term discomfort, but we shouldn’t be expected to manage lasting distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no clear-cut threshold for how bad an experience has to be to cause harm, which is why I and other researchers want to uncover more about the full range of potential side-effects. The World Health Organization &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-IER-PSP-2010.2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;defines&lt;/a&gt; harm as physical, psychological or social suffering and/or functional impairment. As suffering is notoriously challenging to define (just ask meditation teachers), let’s focus on functional impairment – a disruption in one’s day-to-day activities. While rates of people having any adverse effects in meditation and psychotherapy are around 50 to &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;60 per cent,&lt;/span&gt; around &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;9 per&lt;/span&gt; cent of meditators in our study reported functional impairment. These effects are not always short-lived, either: approximately &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34074221/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;1.2 per&lt;/span&gt; cent&lt;/a&gt; of meditators have experienced an adverse effect with functional impairment lasting at least a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the most common types of serious harms in &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/acps.13225&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;meditation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8503914/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;psychotherapy&lt;/a&gt; are a worsening of the very mental health symptoms people use the practices to address, such as anxiety, depression or traumatic memories. In some cases, new symptoms emerge. Occasionally, with meditation, the effects can be as severe as psychotic episodes, hallucinations or suicidality. Fortunately, ‘extreme’ symptoms do seem to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s12671-024-02384-9&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;rare&lt;/a&gt;, but even small percentages can have big impacts when one in five people use meditation and psychotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In his seminal work&lt;/strong&gt; on psychological treatments that cause harm, the clinical psychologist Scott Lilienfeld &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26151919/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;cautioned&lt;/a&gt; that, in general, we should be sceptical of the notion that it has to get worse before it gets better, but especially in cases where ‘getting worse’ doesn’t quickly shift to ‘getting better’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scepticism was based on what researchers know about indicators of positive outcomes in psychotherapy. Simply put, there is no empirical evidence that a worsening of symptoms precedes getting better. In fact, there is good evidence to the contrary. So-called ‘sudden gains’ – rapid, stable and large decreases in symptoms – are robustly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0272735820300155#bb0270&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;associated&lt;/a&gt; with better, more lasting treatment outcomes. A large &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26235730/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; analysing psychological function in psychotherapy found that sudden, early gains were the most common pattern &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;(75.3 per&lt;/span&gt; cent), slow and steady gains were in the middle &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;(19.3 per&lt;/span&gt; cent), and early deterioration was the least common &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;(5.4 per&lt;/span&gt; cent). Notably, those who initially got worse were no better off than the first group after 11 sessions. Perhaps getting worse before getting better is not only uncommon but unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we must remember our distinction between discomfort, distress and harm. Discomfort is almost certainly occurring at some level for most who aim to change their behaviour or manage mental ill-health. Therapy and meditation are often challenging. If any distress occurs, evidence would suggest it ought to be mild and short-lived. And if an intervention or practice makes it harder to function in day-to-day life, then that needs to be taken seriously, and whatever has gone wrong must be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are considering starting or resuming meditation or psychotherapy, I would suggest finding out a few things to reduce the risk of needless discomfort or distress. A therapist, teacher or instructor should be able to provide you with all this information. The likely benefits ought to outweigh the likely risks. No programme will work for everyone, but the odds should at least be in your favour. There ought to be evidence that a particular practice or approach can result in the achievement of your desired goals. It’s also worthwhile knowing about the provider’s training and experience. You want to be guided by someone who understands the difference between discomfort, distress and harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing these things might not fully prevent harms and most certainly will not eliminate discomfort. But it will help to minimise harms and maximise the benefits. And if your experience with an intervention or practice starts getting worse and doesn’t quickly take a turn to getting better, my recommendation would be to stop, speak to the provider, and perhaps seek out another practice (and, possibly, another provider). While worthwhile endeavours are often challenging – and we can all benefit from being more comfortable with being uncomfortable – pursuing our goals shouldn’t be unbearable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/in-therapy-or-meditation-is-it-normal-to-feel-worse-at-first</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/in-therapy-or-meditation-is-it-normal-to-feel-worse-at-first</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Nicholas Van Dam</author></item><item><title>Instead of wrestling with self-defeating thoughts, try this</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;   &lt;p&gt;You know the kind of day. You wake up late, spill coffee on your new shirt, forget to pack your child’s lunch, or otherwise get off to a rough start, and by the time you sit down for a busy day of work, your mind is already in overdrive. ‘You can’t handle this,’ it might whisper. Or even: ‘You’re useless.’ Thoughts like these creep in, uninvited, and suddenly they’re not just thoughts – they feel like facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you try to push the difficult thoughts away, telling yourself to ‘snap out of it’ or ‘stay positive’, but the harder you fight, the louder they seem to become. Maybe you get fully caught up in them, replaying the times you’ve messed up in the past, spiralling deeper into self-criticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever found yourself caught in a loop like this, you’re not alone. Our minds are brilliant, busy machines, but they have a tendency to get tangled up in self-defeating thoughts. Many of us have these kinds of thoughts daily as we face our responsibilities and challenges, worry about whether we’re up to them, and experience inevitable setbacks and mistakes. These include thoughts &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;such as&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘I’m not good enough’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘I’m bound to fail’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘I probably look like an idiot’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘There’s no point in trying’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a fast-paced and often overwhelming world, it’s common to have thoughts like these, which can promote anxiety and stress. But you don’t have to allow these thoughts to consume you; there are more skilful ways to respond. Ways that don’t involve constantly fighting with them or pushing them away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why these thoughts are so ‘sticky’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into better ways of responding, there are some key things to know about how the mind tends to operate, and they help explain why certain thoughts have such a powerful hold &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;on us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mind is naturally drawn to &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1037/1089-2680.5.4.323&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;negative information&lt;/a&gt;, especially when it’s about you. This tendency likely evolved as a survival mechanism. Human ancestors who were anxious about potential threats were more likely to avoid danger – and to survive long enough to pass on their genes. As a result, the modern brain is wired to focus on perceived threats, problems and mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mind is also a storyteller. It excels at making sense of complex information quickly, even if it means &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/ideas/your-life-is-not-a-story-why-narrative-thinking-holds-you-back&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;oversimplifying&lt;/a&gt; or jumping to conclusions. This ability helps people make decisions, but it also leaves one vulnerable to cognitive distortions. For instance, if someone looks at their life so far and comes to believe that they are ‘a failure’, they might hold tightly to this story about themselves, even in the face of strong evidence to the contrary. Why would someone do this, especially when it causes them pain? Because coherence, the feeling that the story ‘fits’, often matters more to the mind than accuracy. The mind prioritises keeping a story intact over questioning whether it’s actually true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A related difficulty has to do with our ability to learn by association. To give an example, see if you can answer the following question: how are a &lt;em&gt;whale &lt;/em&gt;and an &lt;em&gt;eggplant &lt;/em&gt;similar? You probably haven’t been asked this before, but your mind can likely come up with some creative answers – perhaps their shape, or the fact that both are edible (in theory). This ability to relate even seemingly unrelated things is central to language and thought. However, this same ability can cause trouble when it comes to negative thoughts about yourself. If someone once told you that you were ‘not good enough’, for example, your mind might have started linking this evaluation to other experiences of failure or rejection. Over time, these connections can form a tangled web of associations that reinforces a belief like ‘I’m a failure’. Even small challenges might trigger this belief, not because it’s objectively true, but because your mind has derived this connection repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, thoughts such as these stick because they’re part of a vast relational network built on past learning. They feel familiar and logical, but that doesn’t mean they &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;serve you&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why grappling with thoughts doesn’t always help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a self-defeating thought, one possible response is to try to argue with it. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thought: ‘I’m not good enough.’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Response: ‘That’s not true – I’ve achieved things.’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thought: ‘Maybe, but what if I fail this time?’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Response: ‘No, I’ll be fine. I’ve got this…’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this sometimes helps in the short term, it often leads to a mental tug-of-war. The more you argue with a thought, the more attention and power you &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;give it&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relational frame theory (RFT) explains this well. When you engage with a thought by arguing or rationalising, you strengthen its relational connections. It’s like adding more threads to an already tangled web. Each argument can also spawn new worries: ‘If I fail, maybe they’ll judge me,’ or ‘Even if I succeed, what if I can’t &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;maintain it?&lt;/span&gt;’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘solution’ to tricky thoughts isn’t just more thinking. Instead, it involves changing how you relate to the thoughts. Let’s explore how to do &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;this now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognise when a thought is unworkable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason negative thoughts can feel so powerful is that they often contain a grain of truth. For example, the thought ‘I might fail’ is true – failure is always a possibility. The thought ‘I’m not good enough’ might have a bit of truth to it, in the sense that you (like everyone else) probably have room for growth and improvement. But just because a thought is true, or partly true, doesn’t mean it’s helpful &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;to you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acceptance and commitment therapy (ACT) encourages people to evaluate thoughts not based on their truth, but on their &lt;em&gt;workability&lt;/em&gt;. This means asking yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does holding on to this thought help me live the life I want?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it move me toward what is important &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;to me?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the answer to these questions is ‘no’, it might be worth letting the thought go, even if it feels true. For example, the thought ‘I’m not good enough’ might feel true, especially if it echoes how you perceive your past experiences. But if this thought leads to self-doubt and avoidance (not engaging with a new hobby, skill, friendship, etc), it’s not workable. That is, it is not helping you live the life you want, nor is it moving you toward what is important to you. Instead of debating how true or untrue the thought is, you can recognise that it is not serving you – and decide to respond to it in a different, more &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;skilful way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach involves grounding yourself in the present, distancing yourself from the thought, and then choosing actions that line up with your values. The next steps will help you put these ideas into practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect to the present moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-defeating thoughts often take you out of the present: your mind drags you into the past with rumination (‘I can’t believe I messed that up’), or into the future with worry (‘I won’t be able to manage’). Cultivating present-moment awareness can help you regain a sense of clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notice what’s happening:&lt;/strong&gt; acknowledge when your mind is spinning into worry or self-criticism. Pause and tell yourself that you are having a difficult thought, but you don’t need to fight it or &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;fix it.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Focus on your surroundings and your &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-breathe-your-way-to-better-health-and-transcendence&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;breath&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; bring your attention to your immediate environment. What can you see, hear or feel right now? You can also ground yourself by paying attention to the sensation of your breath as you inhale and exhale. This can be brief, just for a few seconds, or longer if you have the time and space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Repeat:&lt;/strong&gt; each time your mind pulls you back into a spiral, return to this process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;By refocusing your attention on the present – allowing yourself even just a moment of peace – you’ll be better positioned to choose how you respond to distressing thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create distance from your thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re caught up in tricky thoughts, they can become all-consuming and start to feel like facts. But thoughts are just that: thoughts. They are fleeting mental events, not necessarily accurate reflections of reality. By building some distance from your thoughts, you can see them for what they really are. This distance can take the sting out of the tail of the thoughts and give you the space to consider your actions more fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practical techniques for building this distance include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Notice the thought without judging it. &lt;/strong&gt;Observe the thought as if you were an outsider. For example: ‘Ah, there’s the thought that “I’m not good enough.”’ Here, you are moving away from judgments about the thought as either good or bad, and merely acknowledging that you are having the thought. If judgment creeps in, acknowledge that too, with kindness: ‘There’s the thought that I’m judging myself for having this thought.’ The goal isn’t to stop the thought but to create some distance, allowing you to respond rather than react.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Use distancing language to step back from the thought.&lt;/strong&gt; You can add an additional mental buffer by thinking to yourself: ‘&lt;em&gt;I’m noticing I’m having the thought &lt;/em&gt;that I’m not good enough.’ In doing so, you create a metaphorical&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;distance between the thought and yourself, such that it seems less a part of you and merely something that your brain is throwing &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;at you.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try for a moment, starting with a thought such as ‘I’m not good enough’ – notice how it feels to have the thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now try: ‘I notice the thought “I’m not good enough”’ – how does that feel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now try: ‘I notice I’m having the thought that “I’m not good enough”’ – how does that feel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledge the thought with humour.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, you might say: ‘Thanks, mind, for trying to protect me!’ Our minds are not always good at differentiating between genuine threats (such as being in danger right now) and hypothetical threats related to your thoughts (such as the possibility that you will fail). Therefore, by thanking your mind in this example, you try to acknowledge that the mind has a function here, but not one that is currently helpful or practicable. Thanking your mind can interject some humour into this misapplied process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make a choice that aligns with your values&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve grounded yourself and created some distance from your thought, the next step is to choose how you will act. By reminding yourself of what is important to you in life, you can focus your actions on moving toward these things, rather than just moving away from what you would like to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would I like to act in this moment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s important to me &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;right now&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I could choose to be the kind of person I want to be, what steps would I take?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of letting the difficult thought you’ve had dictate your behaviour, reconnect with what you value. Consider again the thought ‘I’m not good enough’, which may come with an urge to avoid something – for example, to quit a hobby or give up on learning a new skill. You can ask yourself: what is it about engaging in that hobby or learning that skill that’s important to you? What values or qualities underlie it, for you? Creativity? Self-expression? Exploration? Self-development? Reflecting on what’s important to you can help you see past a self-defeating thought and act in a way that aligns with your values – which, in this case, might look like persisting in your endeavour and seeking some tutoring or support, rather than quitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other key values that might inform your behaviour could include empathy, fairness, loyalty and many more. By unpicking your &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/ideas/a-philosophical-approach-can-help-you-identify-what-truly-matters&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;underlying values&lt;/a&gt;, you can use them to focus your actions, instead of being steered by negative thoughts or fear of those thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tune into the emotion behind the thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after you’ve gone through the preceding steps, you might find that some unpleasant or distressing feelings require attention. Self-defeating thoughts are deeply intertwined with emotions, and true freedom requires attending to your emotional world. This means noticing the emotions related to your thoughts, allowing yourself to feel them, and responding with compassion, rather than avoidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’ve been having the thought ‘I’m not good enough,’ you might pause and ask: ‘What am I feeling right now?’ The emotions might be uncomfortable, but by turning toward them with openness, you can begin to process them, rather than getting stuck once more in a loop of unhelpful thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve identified the emotions, you can respond in ways that help you cope. For instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you notice &lt;strong&gt;fear&lt;/strong&gt;, you might take a moment to ground yourself by focusing on your breath or reminding yourself of your values and why you’re doing what you’re doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you uncover &lt;strong&gt;shame&lt;/strong&gt;, you could &lt;a href=&quot;https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-be-kinder-to-yourself-by-practising-self-compassion&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;practise self-compassion&lt;/a&gt; by acknowledging that everyone struggles and that it’s OK to not be perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you feel &lt;strong&gt;sadness&lt;/strong&gt;, you might allow yourself to simply sit with the feeling for a while, offering yourself kindness and recognising that it’s part of being human.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending to the emotions connected to negative thoughts is another way to shift from battling with your thoughts to taking care of yourself in a meaningful way. This helps loosen the grip of a thought and allows you to act based on what truly matters &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;to you&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;subheading&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having negative, challenging thoughts is a natural part of life. Our minds are wired to focus on negativity, create stories and form associations, which can sometimes leave us feeling stuck or overwhelmed. But with a better understanding of how the mind works, you can begin to approach your thoughts with greater curiosity and compassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steps we’ve described are simple but powerful tools for responding to difficult thoughts in a way that promotes clarity, resilience and purpose. While you can’t always control the thoughts that your mind produces, you can choose how to respond to them. The next time your mind whispers that you’re not good enough, that you’re bound to fail, or some other thought that you find unworkable, take a breath, notice the thought with some appropriate distance, and then ask yourself: ‘What really matters to me &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;right now?’&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/instead-of-wrestling-with-self-defeating-thoughts-try-this</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/instead-of-wrestling-with-self-defeating-thoughts-try-this</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Joe Oliver, Kristy Potter</author></item><item><title>Too many men lack close friendships. What’s holding them back?</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;‘I get sad at weddings, but not for the reason you might think. When I see the groom with his best man, I can’t think of any man who knows me well enough to fill that role.’ &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Lawrence, 32, &lt;/span&gt;is one of more than 500 class- and race-diverse men in English-speaking countries whom I’ve canvassed on the subject of intimacy and friendship over the past two years. A software engineer in Hawaii, Lawrence wishes he had more close friendships with men, but even initiating a coffee feels like a risk: ‘With a woman, you can be like: “Hey, let’s go to the park, let’s get a coffee.” With a man, it’s like, will he think I’m gay or something?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interviewee, Kieran, 40, a white primary school teacher from Ireland, said he regrets fumbling his chance to offer support to a friend, Sam. Over drinks at the pub, Sam confided to Kieran that he struggles with an anxiety problem. Kieran’s immediate reaction was: ‘Don’t embarrass yourself.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kieran hadn’t ever heard male friends his age talk about their mental health conditions. Ill-equipped to meet the moment, he stumbled through until the conversation switched back to one of their ‘on table’ topics: sports, politics and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On his way home from the pub, Kieran realised that Sam’s experience mirrored something he had felt himself, though he had never been able to name it ‘anxiety’ until he heard another man say it out loud. But the moment to ease Sam’s shame, and disclose his own struggles, had already passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranging in age from 23 to 95, the men I surveyed answered questions about the nature of their intimate connections. Were they satisfied with their social support network? Who does their support come from? Is there anything – or anyone – missing? Such questions are timely. Recent research indicates that one in five men in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.americansurveycenter.org/why-mens-social-circles-are-shrinking/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;the US&lt;/a&gt; and one in three men in the UK lack close friendships entirely. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.equimundo.org/resources/state-of-american-men/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;Two-thirds&lt;/a&gt; of young American men say: ‘No one really knows me.’ Nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.movember.com/story/view/id/11740/men-s-health-survey?tag=where-the-money-goes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;half of men&lt;/a&gt; in the UK feel they cannot confide in a friend about their problems. American men are &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;50 per&lt;/span&gt; cent less likely to report receiving social support – having someone check in on them or offer help when they need it – in a week than women, and also report having fewer friendships than they did &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;30 years&lt;/span&gt; ago. But it is the quality of men’s bonds, measured against the human psychological need for deep social connection, not necessarily the number of their friendships, that paints a gendered picture of social deprivation. What men often lack is not friends, but &lt;em&gt;closeness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-quality, close friendships involve intimacy,&lt;/strong&gt; the fragile closeness born of risking ourselves and being met with acceptance and belonging. This kind of closeness can evade men in environments that operate on norms of indifference or active hostility towards expressing what is happening in their inner worlds. Luis, 31, a Latino primary care doctor in California, touched on this indifference when he told me about the time he shared the painful story of a breakup over a meal with his childhood friend Andrés. ‘That sucks, man,’ Andrés responded, but then had nothing else to say. Bids for support are not always met with the willingness or emotional competence required to provide what many men are &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;looking for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navid, 44, a Persian American business coach, spoke about being mocked as a teenager by his friends for expressing affection toward other boys. For a look that lingered too long or a pat on the back that seemed more a stroke than a thwack, ‘they called me a faggot,’ he said, recalling the all-purpose signifier for any behaviour deemed ‘too feminine’. Later, when someone in his circle made similar attempts at physical or emotional affection, Navid caught himself flinging the same word at them. ‘If I’m calling you that, there’s no way I can be it,’ he explained. It’s a hallmark of how men surveil each other’s behaviour: the punished becomes the punisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the pub, at school, in the office or on the sports field, men in most Western societies (though growing research &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/en/publications/man-enough-measuring-masculine-norms-to-promote-women-s-empowerment_6ffd1936-en.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;suggests&lt;/a&gt; these dynamics are not geographically confined) are asked to perform a masculinity that values self-sufficiency and disdains emotional ‘oversharing’, especially with other men. This process is learned. For every commentator who suggests that boys are simply less community-minded and relationally intelligent than girls, there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.degruyter.com/document/doi/10.18574/nyu/9780814724859.001.0001/html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2014-29891-001&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;shows&lt;/a&gt; how boys are &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/socpro/article-abstract/68/2/490/5816314&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;incentivised&lt;/a&gt;, through subtle and overt cues, to hide their sensitivity until – like any muscle that is not used – it atrophies. The US psychologists Christopher Reigeluth and Michael Addis spotlight such cues in their research on the policing of masculinity. One 17-year-old white boy in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/buy/2015-24706-001&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; put it &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;this way:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I was just, like, depressed all the time. And my friend called me ‘a depressed little bitch’. And it really got to me because I had just lost my grandfather … When he said that to me, I learned to hide how I was feeling.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my own work, Navid demonstrates the protracted consequences of this social learning process. Taught to retract his bids for connection, or risk mockery, he said: ‘I didn’t know how to have intimacy with anyone I’m not sexually attracted to,’ alluding to the one place – or person – many men turn to for softness and intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over and again, men expressed a chronic sense of lack within their male friendships. When I asked &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Eagle, 44,&lt;/span&gt; a mixed-race school administrator from Arizona, if he had close friendships, he replied: ‘Do you mean outside of my wife?’ looking confused. Eagle sought male friends but, like many other men, he found that ‘friendship with men is a lot of activity and discussion about what is happening, and never really exploring your inner world.’ &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Jared, 40,&lt;/span&gt; felt similarly: ‘I wish it was easier to make friends and keep friends as a guy, but I think it’s easier to self-disclose with women.’ Women, he added, ask better questions and remember to follow up. As Kenneth, a white 28-year-old in Canada, put it: ‘Women offer me actual relationships, whereas men just offer me experiences.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many men in my work rely centrally on the women in their lives, even when these women do not centrally rely on them. &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;George, 24,&lt;/span&gt; a mixed race engineer in the UK, said: ‘My only social outlet apart from work is being with my girlfriend, and maybe mixing with her friends as well.’ &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Ed, 82,&lt;/span&gt; said: ‘I wouldn’t know what to do socially if my wife died.’ The idea that only women can provide nurturing companionship creates a fraught context for reciprocal relationships between men and women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few interviewees ever question whether they are, in one man’s words, a ‘leech’ on women’s time. One group was an exception: queer and trans men – who often sit furthest from the top of the masculinity hierarchy. This group was often acutely aware of how women in their lives – not just romantic partners, but friends, family members and colleagues, too – were heavily relied upon for a type of emotional support that my colleague and I &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2025-35803-002.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;call&lt;/a&gt; ‘mankeeping’. &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Paul, 28,&lt;/span&gt; a Latino American gay man, finds himself caring for women friends who are burnt out by supporting their straight male romantic partners. ‘When straight men fail, we have to pick up the pieces,’ he said. He recommends that straight men ‘diversify who [they] communicate to. You can’t just rely on your wife or girlfriend to be your emotional labourer.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alao, 33, a Nigerian gay man, put it more bluntly: ‘Straight men have a lot to learn from us.’ For him, the casual tenderness and care often seen in same-gender male relationships shouldn’t be confined to the queer community. Trans men echoed this perspective, drawing from their unique vantage point of navigating masculinity while remembering their previous girlhoods or womanhoods. ‘As a man with a girlhood, I’m confident in expressing vulnerable needs,’ said Liam, 28, a graduate student in New Jersey. He added that friendships with cisgender men often feel like ‘a step down in intimacy’. These relationships could be richer, he believes, if cisgender men risked sharing their own ‘vulnerable needs’, and also learned how to meet that need in others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For straight, cisgender men courageous enough&lt;/strong&gt; to leave behind the masculine norms that restrict intimacy with other men, much awaits. &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Quincy, 38,&lt;/span&gt; a former US Army combat medic, started a friendship group for Black men in Phoenix, Arizona, when he noticed that there were no opportunities for men to meet in his area outside of sports or professional networking. ‘The first thing we had to do was actually learn how to be good friends,’ he said, noting that, while getting willing men together in a room was easy, learning empathy and active listening meant leaving outdated notions of manhood behind. Similarly, for &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Nem, 40,&lt;/span&gt; a Black actor in London, years of working against masculine defaults meant giving up the urge to be each other’s masculine saviours: ‘We can finally stomach each other’s stuff without having to find a solution.’ The impulse to fix, rather than to feel, often leaves men stuck in patterns that limit connection, meaning the first step to closeness is often unlearning the default practices of interacting with &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;other men.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;João, 30,&lt;/span&gt; a mixed-race man living in London, and his best friend Abilo, in São Paulo, who have learned to simply ‘be’ in each other’s presence without needing an activity or agenda. The two straight men grew closer in their 20s, when Abilo was completing military service in Brazil and João was ending a long and significant romantic relationship. Both wrestled with emotional difficulties and relied on each other daily. João told me: ‘Nothing nears what we have.’ They meet in person only twice a year now, but each phone call ends with: ‘I love you, see you tomorrow.’ When João returns to Brazil, the two of them lie on the couch, Abilo’s legs draped over João’s while they are deep in discussion. They walk arm in arm down the streets of São Paulo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American best friends &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Basil, 30,&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Alex, 29,&lt;/span&gt; start their conversations with unconventional endearments. ‘Hello, you beautiful kumquat,’ Basil sometimes says, to which Alex responds with: ‘Hello, my perfect cinnamon roll.’ Friends for a decade, it took them years to converse openly about ‘how we were really doing,’ Alex told me. ‘When I started to let him in slowly,’ Alex said, ‘it was like he saved me.’ When I asked what he had been saved from, he responded: ‘I felt like I could actually invest in someone who wasn’t my partner. There was another person who actually cares about me.’ Honouring their regular check-in by phone was among the strategies they used to cultivate closeness – even saving it as an event in the calendar so they wouldn’t miss it. They started to welcome long silences during their walks or drives, realising it made them both feel at ease. They became more curious about each other – actually voicing, not just noticing, when the other seemed off. Ten years on, their weekly check-in ritual contains jokes, information, life updates, sadness, pain, playful weirdness. ‘We feel safe enough to share all of it,’ said Basil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like João or Basil, the men I interviewed who had close friendships with other men struggled less with their mental health, and reported happier partnerships with women, than the men who relied solely on a romantic partner. Across medicine and the social sciences, compounding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesocialcreatures.org/thecreaturetimes/social-connection-physical-health&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; shows that having friends with whom we can share our problems serves to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0149763419308292?via%3Dihub&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;modulate&lt;/a&gt; the body’s stress response. ‘The people who turn out to be the happiest and the healthiest are those who have good, warm connections to others,’ Robert Waldinger, the director of the Harvard Study of Adult Development, said in a TED talk &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;in 2022.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have, as a society, always demanded bravery from men. But so many are still lost when it comes to the bravery that close relationships demand. I think about Kieran, about Lawrence, and wonder what would happen if they took a different kind of male ‘risk’ – the kind that Basil and Alex, or João and Abilo, took when they worked to cultivate a friendship of complete range and stunning comfort. What if Kieran had apologised to Sam that night in the pub and shared his own experience of anxiety? What if Lawrence bit the bullet and asked another man out for coffee? This is the kind of bravery men need right now – the courage to be known.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/too-many-men-lack-close-friendships-whats-holding-them-back</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/too-many-men-lack-close-friendships-whats-holding-them-back</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Angelica Puzio Ferrara</author></item><item><title>Why it’s possible to be optimistic in a world of bad news</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;p&gt;What does it mean to be optimistic? We usually think of optimism as an expectation that things will work out for the best. While we might accept that such expectations have motivational value – making it easier to deal with the ups and downs of everyday life, and the struggle and strife we see in the world – we might still feel dubious about it from an intellectual perspective. Optimism is, after all, by its nature delusional; ‘realism’ or outright pessimism might seem more justifiable given the troubles of the present and the uncertainties of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us familiar with Voltaire’s celebrated novel &lt;em&gt;Candide, or Optimism &lt;/em&gt;(1759) might be reminded of his character &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;Dr Pangloss&lt;/span&gt;, and his refrain that all must be for the best ‘in this best of all possible worlds’. As Pangloss and his company are subjected to disaster, war, mutilation, cruelty and disease, his article of faith seems increasingly blind. Pangloss, a professor of ‘metaphysico-theologico-cosmolo-nigology’, is a vicious caricature of the great German polymath Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz, and his catchphrase is Voltaire’s snappy formulation of the German’s attempt to provide a logical argument for optimism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, really, a theological argument. Leibniz didn’t set out to explain why some people are perpetually cheerful about their prospects, but why an all-powerful, all-seeing and all-loving God allows evil to exist in the world. This ‘problem of evil’ has been debated for millennia, but it was Leibniz who first attempted to reason his way to an answer, rather than look to scripture for one. His inspiration came from his realisation, in the early 1680s, that the path taken by light through a system of prisms or mirrors always followed the ‘easiest’, or ‘optimal’, path from source to destination. As the contemporary philosopher Jeffrey McDonough &lt;a href=&quot;https://global.oup.com/academic/product/a-miracle-creed-9780197629079?cc=pl&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;argued&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;A Miracle Creed&lt;/em&gt; (2022), he soon realised that many other phenomena followed a similar ‘principle of optimality’ – including, perhaps, the entirety of God’s creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until that point, it had generally been assumed that the cosmos was precisely the way it had to be. Leibniz, on the other hand, argued that God could have chosen from many laws and ingredients when making the world, but some combinations would not be internally consistent. So God, in His wisdom, chose the particular combination that led to a world that was both ‘simplest in hypotheses and richest in phenomena’. That might not be a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; world, containing no suffering or evil, but it would be the best of all &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; worlds. While there might be many possible ways to make a world, there’s only one &lt;em&gt;optimal&lt;/em&gt; way. And this view of the world came to be known as &lt;em&gt;optimism&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leibniz’s view, put forward in his book &lt;em&gt;Theodicy &lt;/em&gt;(1710), did not win instant acclaim. Critics sniffed at the idea that God’s motives could be deciphered in this way. But it was Voltaire, almost half a century later, who dealt the killing blow. &lt;em&gt;Candide&lt;/em&gt; proved enormously successful. Published in five countries simultaneously, it is estimated to have sold more than &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;20,000 copies&lt;/span&gt; in its first year alone. Voltaire’s acerbic depiction of Leibniz and his ideas stuck – and, since the German was long dead, he was unable to fight his corner. Even today, many people are much more familiar with Voltaire’s satirical take than Leibniz’s &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;rational one.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But was Leibniz on to something? &lt;/strong&gt;Could his worldview help us regain a clearer sense of how to be optimistic in the present day? In his day, the idea that the world could be arranged any differently was novel to the point of outlandishness. Over centuries, that gradually changed as it became clearer that the cosmos contains places that are nothing like Earth, and that our planet itself had been dramatically different in the past. But it shot to prominence in the middle of the &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;20th century&lt;/span&gt;, when both philosophy and physics converged on the idea that ours is only one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/why-identity-morality-and-faith-splinter-in-the-multiverse&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;many possible universes&lt;/a&gt; – or, at least, that this is a useful way to think about certain problems in logic and quantum theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many other problems, too. This intellectual respectability has turned into cultural ubiquity: the idea that there are many possible worlds is intuitively appealing in a time when ever fewer people accept the idea of a divine plan. We are more likely to believe that the future is open, with many alternative paths we could take from today to tomorrow. Whatever its scientific merits, the multiverse has become ubiquitous as a metaphor for the way the courses of our lives, and of our societies, are set by the decisions we make, the actions we take and the accidents that befall us. Once, we might have assumed that our fates lay in the lap of the gods, or that implacable physical laws dictate our every move. Today, we think the responsibility lies &lt;span class=&quot;ld-nowrap&quot;&gt;with us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That makes Leibnizian optimism more appealing than it has been for centuries. Besides the renewed relevance of its central metaphor, Leibnizian optimism reminds us that we cannot see or understand the whole design of the world. And if we attempt to fix one problem at one time and place, there will likely be consequences elsewhere that we can’t anticipate. Climate change is a byproduct of the massive economic uplift engendered by the Industrial Revolution. The collapsing demographics of many societies result in part from huge improvements in infant mortality and life expectancy. The technology that lets you read my ideas here also reshapes societal norms and disrupts our polities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean we should stop trying to improve the world: it means we should expect perfection to remain perpetually out of reach. That’s not such a bitter pill to swallow: a few technological fantasists aside, no one really expects utopia to arrive tomorrow, or the day after that. But we can still strive for the best of all possible worlds. The key to making Leibniz’s version of optimism relevant to a secular, 21st-century worldview is to make ‘the best of all possible worlds’ an aspiration, not a statement of belief. We may or may not live in a multiverse; but we can better shape the Universe we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; live in if we think about its unrealised branches and forks – whether those lie along roads not taken in the past, or the paths we might walk into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might sound abstract or fanciful. But in fact, as I detail in my book &lt;em&gt;The Bright Side &lt;/em&gt;(2025), there are many ways in which multiversal thinking is already applied, many of them down-to-earth and serious. We devise scenarios for the future of the climate, and our reactions to it; we role-play how markets might be plunged into crisis, conflicts might unfold and pandemics be contained. Counterfactual historians ask: ‘What if?’, the better to understand how the world of today emerged from the world of yesterday – and futurists ask the same question to understand how it might give rise to the world of tomorrow. Billions of dollars, millions of lives, the trajectory of industries, societies and nations are determined, more or less explicitly, by possible-worlds thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes, optimism can take the form of blind faith that the future will be brighter than the present. Most of us, in our everyday lives, need some of that faith in order to keep moving forward when times get tough, when obstacles present themselves and the future is full of unknowns. But when it comes to how we think about the world we live in, and the challenges we all face, Leibnizian optimism – the &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; optimism – provides a fertile way to evaluate our options and shake off our feelings of fatalism. The world, and the future, is always full of possibilities – and we can always strive to make it the best of all possible worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adapted from &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://canongate.co.uk/books/4754-the-bright-side-why-optimists-have-the-power-to-change-the-world/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bright Side: Why Optimists Have the Power to Change the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; (2025) by Sumit Paul-Choudhury, published by Canongate Books.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://psyche.co/ideas/why-its-possible-to-be-optimistic-in-a-world-of-bad-news</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://psyche.co/ideas/why-its-possible-to-be-optimistic-in-a-world-of-bad-news</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Sumit Paul-Choudhury</author></item></channel></rss>