<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Atlantic - LATEST</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/latest/</link><atom:link href="http://rss.wudifeixue.com/theatlantic/latest" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>The Atlantic - LATEST - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:30:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Trump Wants Credit for That Too</title><description>&lt;div&gt; The president is boasting about initiatives from before he took office. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/L5eCjhJWk5tTsT7bk4B7-gjOcTY=/0x207:6002x3583/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/GettyImages_2205591763/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Donald Trump stands with his arms outreached on the red carpeted walkway in the Kennedy Center&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Chip Somodevilla / Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   &lt;p data-flatplan-paragraph=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is an edition of &lt;/i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;i&gt; Daily, a newsletter that guides you through the biggest stories of the day, helps you discover new ideas, and recommends the best in culture. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/atlantic-daily/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sign up for it here.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;   “Everyone is calling it the”—Donald Trump paused while &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-speech-political-rally-washington-january-19-2025/#20&quot;&gt;speaking&lt;/a&gt; to a crowd at a rally the day before his inauguration. “I don’t want to say this,” he insisted. “It’s too braggadocious, but we’ll say it anyway—the Trump effect.” He went on to describe how the stock market was booming and bitcoin prices were surging, and then boasted about a domestic-infrastructure investment from Apple, much of which had &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2025/02/24/apple-announces-500-billion-investment-us-over-next-four-years/&quot;&gt;already been&lt;/a&gt; planned before the November election.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In spite of his claims to the contrary, Trump has no qualms about taking credit, including for achievements that were in progress or complete before he took office. The president has taken full responsibility for negotiating &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-trumps-washington/the-trump-effect-on-deal-making-and-credit-claiming-in-trump-20&quot;&gt;a hostage swap and a cease-fire deal&lt;/a&gt; in the Israel-Hamas war (Trump posted on social media in mid-January that “this EPIC ceasefire agreement could have only happened as a result of our Historic Victory in November”), not mentioning that President Joe Biden had announced some of the deal terms last year. The Trump administration said that its policies had quashed migrant border crossings; immigration data are hard to parse, especially for such a short time period, but &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/09/nx-s1-5318679/the-trump-administration-claims-credit-for-a-quiet-border-the-data-shows-otherwise&quot;&gt;tallies show that&lt;/a&gt; border crossings had already been on the decline during the Biden administration. And this week, Trump &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/03/18/trump-musk-spacex-astronauts/&quot;&gt;credited&lt;/a&gt; himself with returning two astronauts who had been stranded for months at the International Space Station; last summer, NASA announced its &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2025/03/18/white-house-starliner-donald-trump-musk/82530248007/&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/a&gt; to bring them home in 2025, but &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/12/nx-s1-5324653/trump-space-musk-astronauts-international-space-station-nasa&quot;&gt;Trump still claimed&lt;/a&gt; without evidence that Biden “was embarrassed by what happened, and he said, ‘Leave them up there.’”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump relied on similar framing during his campaign: Ahead of a debate with Biden last year, he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/112581578465882555&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; that “low INSULIN PRICING was gotten for millions of Americans by me, and the Trump Administration, not by Crooked Joe Biden,” saying of his opponent that “all he does is try to take credit for things done by others, in this case, ME!” Shared credit would have been appropriate here: Trump did sign an &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/08/trump-claims-credit-for-bidens-insulin-price-cap.html&quot;&gt;executive order&lt;/a&gt; in his first term that capped out-of-pocket costs of insulin for some Medicare patients at $35 a month, but &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://kffhealthnews.org/news/article/fact-check-trump-lower-insulin-prices-false/&quot;&gt;Biden expanded this cap&lt;/a&gt; to all Medicare drug programs through the Inflation Reduction Act, affecting significantly more patients. Trump enjoyed taking credit for &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.msnbc.com/rachel-maddow-show/trump-keeps-taking-credit-obama-era-successes-msna1067356&quot;&gt;Barack Obama–era achievements&lt;/a&gt; during his first term too: In 2017, for example, he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/fact-checking-what-trump-has-taken-credit-for/&quot;&gt;claimed credit&lt;/a&gt; for Obama’s immigration plan and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/03/trump-ford/521085/&quot;&gt;bragged&lt;/a&gt; about a Ford-factory investment that had been in progress since a 2015 union contract.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Politicians are storytellers, and Trump is shameless about telling only the version of the story that flatters him. The stock market is thriving under the Biden administration? That’s thanks to &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;http://apnews.com/article/trumps-comments-about-stock-market-dba336a82ffaf000b80e7218d749995a&quot;&gt;projections that Trump will win&lt;/a&gt;, he claimed last year (even though economists &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/business/economy/economy-gdp-report.html&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that such gains were also linked to low unemployment, flagging inflation, and solid growth). The economy is struggling after Trump takes office? &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/18/economy/us-trump-blame-biden-economic-data/index.html&quot;&gt;Blame the “catastrophic” situation&lt;/a&gt; Biden left him with (even though many economists suggest that recent stock-market downturns are due to anxiety about the effects of Trump’s trade war). Talking about the egg-price crisis in January, the White House team pilloried the Biden administration for killing sick chickens, neglecting to note that this was a tack &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.poynter.org/reporting-editing/2025/price-eggs-shortage-biden-fault-trump/&quot;&gt;Trump also took&lt;/a&gt; during his first term.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Biden struggled to communicate victories during his term, particularly those &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2023/10/bidenomics-2024-campaign-term/675533/&quot;&gt;related to the economy&lt;/a&gt;, which left a “void” for Trump to fill, Lori Cox Han, a scholar of the presidency at Chapman University, told me. And Americans’ perception that the economy was struggling under Biden, boosted by their personal experience of inflation, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/11/biden-harris-economy-election-loss/680592/&quot;&gt;affected how they voted&lt;/a&gt;. Whenever the White House changes hands, some projects inevitably bleed from one administration into the next. Embracing continuity between terms can be a sign that a president cares more about good policy outcomes than about bucking his predecessor: If a federal initiative is good for Americans, why not continue? But Trump is doing something different—he’s attempting to erase other presidents’ role in policy achievements entirely.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Past presidents have also tried to claim credit for a victory set in motion by the previous administration—or perhaps even to hold off the victory until they can take office. The &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/expert-analyzes-new-account-of-gop-deal-that-used-iran-hostage-crisis-for-gain&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; of whether Ronald Reagan’s aides tried to delay the release of U.S. hostages in Iran so that they could come home during the early days of his administration—with the accompanying photo opportunities—has been discussed for years. Still, Han said, unspoken rules of decorum generally prevent new presidents from claiming full credit or trashing their predecessors. This, she noted, is another norm that Trump has disregarded.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump has long sought to portray himself as America’s sole savior. Recall his 2016 campaign refrain: “I alone can fix it.” As my colleague Yoni Appelbaum &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2016/07/trump-rnc-speech-alone-fix-it/492557/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; at the time, in beseeching Americans to place trust in him and only him, Trump “broke with two centuries of American political tradition, in which candidates for office—and above all, for the nation’s highest office—acknowledge their fallibility and limitations, asking for the help of their fellow Americans, and of God, to accomplish what they cannot do on their own.” Trump seems set on sending the message that he doesn’t need help—and that, implausibly, he hasn’t received any along the way.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;b&gt;Related:&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2024/11/donald-trump-barnum-21st-century-showman-politician/680607/&quot;&gt;The 21st century’s greatest, ghastliest showman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/06/donald-trumps-sinister-assault-truth/591925/&quot;&gt;Trump’s sinister assault on truth&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Fr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;em&gt;om&lt;/em&gt; 2019&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Here are four new stories from &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/stephen-miller-presidency/682097/&quot;&gt;Stephen Miller has a plan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/columbia-academic-freedom/682088/&quot;&gt;The cost of the government’s attack on Columbia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/dei-columbia-funding-cuts/682091/&quot;&gt;The DEI catch-22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/credit-card-racket/682075/&quot;&gt;There are two kinds of credit cards.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Today’s News&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Donald Trump and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/ukraine-russia-war-ceasefire-talks-drones-65c00a0afd130731e0e0c054ac528b44&quot;&gt;held a call&lt;/a&gt; to discuss cease-fire negotiations between Russia and Ukraine. Trump suggested that America could assume control of Ukrainian power plants to protect that infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The Federal Reserve &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/Business/fed-set-make-interest-rate-decision-outbreak-trade/story?id=119905993&quot;&gt;left interest rates unchanged&lt;/a&gt; and signaled that inflation may be slightly higher than their December forecast predicted.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Turkish police &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/world/middleeast/turkey-istanbul-mayor-arrest.html&quot;&gt;arrested&lt;/a&gt; Istanbul Mayor Ekrem İmamoğlu, a top political rival of Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, on allegations of corruption and terrorism.&lt;/li&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Evening Read&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   What Impossibly Wealthy Women Do for Love and Fulfillment  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;i&gt;By Sophie Gilbert&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;p&gt;As &lt;i&gt;With Love, Meghan&lt;/i&gt; went on, it started to hit a few of the classic pleasure points. A beautiful woman with a wardrobe of stealth-wealth beige separates and floral dresses? Check. A fixation, both nutritional and aesthetic, on how best to feed one’s family, down to fruit platters arranged like rainbows and jars of chia seeds and hemp hearts to sneak into pancakes? Check. A strange aside where she details what it meant for her to take her husband’s name? &lt;i&gt;Ding ding ding&lt;/i&gt;: We’re in tradwife territory now. This is absurd, of course. Meghan isn’t a &lt;i&gt;tradwife&lt;/i&gt;; if anything, she’s a &lt;i&gt;girlboss&lt;/i&gt;, a savvy, mediagenic entrepreneur with a new podcast dedicated to businesswomen and a nascent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/meghan-sussex-as-ever-brand-announcement&quot;&gt;retail brand&lt;/a&gt;. So why does she seem to be trying so hard to rebrand as one, offering up this wistful performance of femininity and old-fashioned domestic arts that feels staged—and pretty familiar?&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/with-love-meghan-tradwife-domesticity-review/682082/&quot;&gt;Read the full article.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;b&gt;More From &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/putin-trump-ceasefire-proposal/682092/&quot;&gt;Trump gets a taste of Putin’s tactics.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/enlightenment-trump-far-right-europe/682086/&quot;&gt;A battle for the soul of the West&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/congress-doge-spending-tom-cole/682089/&quot;&gt;Even Tom Cole is defending DOGE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/trump-populism-britain/682055/&quot;&gt;The global populist right has a MAGA problem.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/trumps-press-freedom-hungary-orban/682060/&quot;&gt;Trump’s attempts to muzzle the press look familiar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;   &lt;b&gt;Culture Break&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;b&gt;Watch (or skip).&lt;/b&gt; &lt;i&gt;The Electric State&lt;/i&gt; (streaming on Netflix) is a lesson on how to make an &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/the-electric-state-netflix-budget-russo-brothers/682090/&quot;&gt;instantly forgettable, very expensive movie&lt;/a&gt;, Shirley Li writes.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;b&gt;Read.&lt;/b&gt; In his &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/12476/9781912559695&quot;&gt;latest book&lt;/a&gt;, the writer Julian Barnes doubts that we can ever really overcome our fixed beliefs. He should &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2025/03/why-its-hard-to-change-your-mind-julian-barnes/682063/&quot;&gt;keep an open mind&lt;/a&gt;, Kieran Setiya writes.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/free-daily-crossword-puzzle/&quot;&gt;Play our daily crossword.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;i&gt;Stephanie Bai contributed to this newsletter.&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;em&gt;&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://link.theatlantic.com/click/29767897.0/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhlYXRsYW50aWMuY29tL25ld3NsZXR0ZXJzLz91dG1fc291cmNlPW5ld3NsZXR0ZXImdXRtX21lZGl1bT1lbWFpbCZ1dG1fY2FtcGFpZ249YXRsYW50aWMtZGFpbHktbmV3c2xldHRlciZ1dG1fY29udGVudD0yMDIyMTEyMQ/61813432e16c7128e42f4628B52865c35&quot;&gt;Explore all of our newsletters here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;em&gt;When you buy a book using a link in this newsletter, we receive a commission. Thank you for supporting &lt;/em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2025/03/trump-biden-ceasefire-astronauts-insulin/682099/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2025/03/trump-biden-ceasefire-astronauts-insulin/682099/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Stephen Miller Has a Plan</title><description>&lt;div&gt; The White House point person on immigration is pursuing a strategy that is bedeviling his opponents and could provoke a constitutional crisis. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/h1t9Icp-yl0AoxN-jjVDDesm_wM=/0x0:2700x1519/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_13_stephen_miller_AZ/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A black and white photo of Stephen Miller, with his hand in the foreground&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mark Peterson / Redux&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   During the first Trump administration, when Stephen Miller’s immigration policy proposals hit obstacles in federal court, rumors would circulate about his plans to dust off arcane presidential powers. Government lawyers were wary of overreach; officials in the West Wing and at the Department of Homeland Security would sometimes snicker.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;em&gt;LOL Stephen&lt;/em&gt;, they’d say, amused by his creative zealotry.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   No one is laughing now. Miller, Donald Trump’s Homeland Security adviser and deputy chief of staff, has returned to the White House stronger and more determined than ever to silence the derision and plow through legal constraints.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Miller tried to deter migration during Trump’s first term with a series of moves implemented by trial and error, mostly one at a time. He tried “zero tolerance” &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2022/09/trump-administration-family-separation-policy-immigration/670604/&quot;&gt;family separations&lt;/a&gt;, asylum &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://immigrantjustice.org/sites/default/files/uploaded-files/no-content-type/2019-08/Asylum_Timeline_August2019.pdf&quot;&gt;bans&lt;/a&gt;, and the “Remain in Mexico” &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/trump-mexico-immigration-deal-has-additional-measures-not-yet-made-public/2019/06/10/967e4e56-8b8e-11e9-b08e-cfd89bd36d4e_story.html&quot;&gt;policy&lt;/a&gt;. When the coronavirus pandemic hit, Miller finally had a plausible justification for using the emergency public-health law he had &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://americanoversight.org/emails-show-stephen-miller-led-efforts-to-expel-migrants-at-the-border-under-title-42/&quot;&gt;long coveted&lt;/a&gt; as a border-control tool, and he rode that policy—Title 42—to the end of Trump’s first term.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2018/05/stephen-miller-trump-adviser/561317/&quot;&gt;McKay Coppins: Trump’s right-hand troll&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Miller’s policy making was generally reactive then, a response to the border pressures the administration was struggling to contain, former officials who worked with him say. As one career DHS official told us on the condition of anonymity, he was “throwing mud at the wall to see what would stick.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Miller’s approach is different this time. He has unleashed an everything-at-once policy storm modeled after the MAGA guru Stephen K. Bannon’s “flood the zone” formula. Drawing on policy ideas worked up in conservative think tanks during the four years between Trump’s terms, Miller’s plan has been to fire off so many different proposals that some inevitably find a friendly court ruling, three administration officials told us.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   This tactic also gives Miller multiple ways to seal the border, shut down the U.S. asylum system, and ramp up deportations. “It’s &lt;em&gt;Do everything all at once everywhere&lt;/em&gt;,” says Mark Krikorian, the executive director of the Center for Immigration Studies, a group aligned with Miller that has incubated some of his policy ideas.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The administration’s court-defying use of the Alien Enemies Act this past weekend to send hundreds of deportees to a prison in El Salvador—including some after a district-court judge explicitly told the government not to—was his most brazen gambit yet. Miller did not respond to a request for comment.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The 1798 act has been used only three times in U.S. history: during the War of 1812, World War I, and World War II, when it provided the legal justification for the internment of Japanese, Italian, and German citizens. The Trump administration claims that the United States has been infiltrated by transnational gangs, including the Venezuelan prison syndicate Tren de Aragua, that it has designated terrorist groups.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   After Trump called for the impeachment of the federal judge who tried to stop the deportations, calling him a “Radical Left Lunatic,” Supreme Court Chief Justice John Roberts issued a rare public rebuke. “For more than two centuries, it has been established that impeachment is not an appropriate response to disagreement concerning a judicial decision,” he wrote.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2025/03/trump-justice-roberts-impeachment-judge/682087/&quot;&gt;David A. Graham: What John Roberts’s rebuke of Trump left out&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Legal scholars say that the Trump administration’s deportation flights have pushed the country closer to a constitutional crisis than any other moves it has made.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   T&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;hree months after&lt;/span&gt; leaving the White House, in April 2021, Miller co-founded a Trump-aligned think tank, the America First Legal Foundation, that he fashioned as a right-wing counter to the American Civil Liberties Union. The group’s lawyers filed scores of lawsuits against the Biden administration and U.S. companies. They also provided legal firepower to Texas Governor Greg Abbott and other Republican officials launching state-level immigration crackdowns.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Miller and Gene Hamilton, his longtime ally and an AFL co-founder, collaborated closely to prepare the immigration policy blitz of Trump’s second term, according to a former U.S. official who has worked for years with both men and requested anonymity to speak candidly.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “Very rarely at this level do you get a second chance at the same issues,” the official told us; Miller “knows what works and doesn’t work.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Miller boasted during a November interview with Fox News of his plans to overwhelm opponents with rapid-fire executive actions from “the moment President Trump puts his hands on that Bible.” In the past two months, the administration has attempted to &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/01/birthright-citizenship-trump/681219/&quot;&gt;end birthright citizenship&lt;/a&gt;, declared an invasion at the southern border, suspended asylum processing, restored the “Remain in Mexico” policy, and deployed the U.S. military &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/01/trump-cbp-one-immigration/681431/&quot;&gt;to guard the border&lt;/a&gt; and send deportees to Guantánamo Bay. Trump has enlisted nearly every federal law-enforcement agency to help with his mass-deportation campaign, a mobilization akin to a wartime effort.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump, Miller, and their allies have spent years attempting to convince the public that illegal immigration is an existential threat. While Democrats and skeptics roll their eyes at “invasion” rhetoric, the administration is systematically asserting wartime authorities predicated on the notion that the United States is facing a foreign invasion that justifies extraordinary powers that go well beyond those that presidents have typically employed. Miller claims that the administration is “liberating” U.S. states and cities from murderers and rapists, a position he uses to depict his critics as treasonous.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The invocation of the Alien Enemies Act was partly meant to bolster the number of deportations. Trump has been frustrated at the &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/trump-immigration-deportation-agenda/682005/&quot;&gt;pace of removals so far in his term&lt;/a&gt;, which is well below the “millions” he promised, one senior White House official told us. But the move also sent a pair of other, secondary messages.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   It was a dare, the official said, for critics to defend people who include immigrants with violent criminal records and alleged ties to a gang the administration has designated a terrorist organization.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “These are the worst of the worst,” the official said. “Do Democrats really want to be out there on a limb defending them?”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Among the deportees sent to El Salvador were a murder suspect, several people accused of assault, and others with misdemeanor charges, the ICE official Robert L. Cerna II &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.278436/gov.uscourts.dcd.278436.26.1_1.pdf&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; the court.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Cerna acknowledged that many of the deportees sent to El Salvador over the weekend did not, in fact, have criminal records, but said that was “because they have only been in the United States for a short period of time.” Cerna said some deportees were arrested because they were caught in the presence of suspected gang members.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The deportations have alarmed civil-rights lawyers and some Democrats, who cite a lack of due process as well as potential cases of mistaken identity for some of those being shipped to a foreign prison. Reporters at Reuters and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; spoke with family members of deportees this week who deny that their loved ones are affiliated with violent gangs and say that the men came to the United States to work.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “Two things are starkly different from Trump’s first term,” Lee Gelernt, the ACLU attorney who led the challenge to the family-separation policy and other Miller initiatives, told us.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “One is the pace at which they are issuing policies,” Gelernt said. “The other is the more strident stance they are taking in court, refusing to relent on even the smallest things.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/trump-immigration-deportation-agenda/682005/&quot;&gt;Nick Miroff: ICE isn’t delivering the mass deportation Trump wants&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Gelernt said he’d been working through the night late last week to prepare briefings for the ACLU’s suit to stop deportees from being sent to the U.S. military prison at Guantánamo. Then he spent the weekend trying to stop the administration from using the Alien Enemies Act to bypass immigration courts. The relentless pace is a direct result of Miller’s plan to grind down opponents and break institutional resistance.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “The first 100 days will be a bolt of lightning,” Miller told Fox News in November. “The deep state, the swamp, and the Communists won’t know what hit them.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   W&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;hile Miller&lt;/span&gt;, White House “border czar” Tom Homan, and Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt have issued defiant statements attacking U.S. District Judge James Boasberg, who ordered the government to halt its removal of the Venezuelans, Justice Department lawyers have insisted in court filings that the administration did not intentionally violate court orders.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Yesterday, Attorney General Pam Bondi and other top DOJ officials told the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia that the immigration officials did not heed Boasberg’s orders Saturday evening because the deportation flights he’d tried to stop had already left U.S. airspace by the time he’d ruled. Trump officials are also challenging the judge’s eligibility to stop the administration more generally, asserting that the president’s efforts to conduct foreign affairs and protect national security is beyond the district court’s jurisdiction. If the administration’s use of the Alien Enemies Act is blocked, the White House and Trump-affiliated media intend to continue attacking individual judges and paint the entire legal system as out to stymie the president’s agenda, two officials said.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   U.S. relations with the government of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro have been broken for years, crimping ICE’s ability to send back deportees amid a historic influx of migrants from the South American nation. El Salvador’s president, Nayib Bukele, saw an opportunity to deepen his ties to the MAGA movement and offered to become Trump’s jailer “for a very low fee” ($6 million a year for the deportees he’s accepted so far).  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   It is unclear if the deportees will have any chance to challenge their detention in El Salvador. Bukele taunted the district-court judge for failing to stop the flights. He &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/nayibbukele/status/1901245427216978290&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; on social media that the detainees he’s received will be sent to his country’s Terrorism Confinement Center, a mega-prison complex, where they will perform forced labor.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The men—their heads shaved, their arms and legs in chains—have since been featured in videos distributed by the government of El Salvador. Family members of the men say they’ve had no way to communicate with their loved ones. So they study the propaganda videos for &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/2025/03/18/trump-migrants-venezuelans-deportation-bukele/&quot;&gt;glimpses&lt;/a&gt; of sons and spouses among the deportees.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/stephen-miller-presidency/682097/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/stephen-miller-presidency/682097/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Make an Instantly Forgettable, Very Expensive Movie</title><description>&lt;div&gt; The Russo brothers’ &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; films took hold of popular culture, but the directors have yet to repeat that kind of success. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/GNpgMPlCtkgIN0grJB7CMIzTtrw=/0x0:2478x1394/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_13_electric_state_AZ/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Electric State&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   Joe and Anthony Russo, better known as &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2019/05/russo-brothers-interview-avengers-marvel-endgame/588832/&quot;&gt;the Russo brothers&lt;/a&gt;, have enjoyed two of the most lucrative careers in Hollywood. The bulk of their success comes from the features they’ve co-directed for Marvel: Three of those projects, in which they helped turn comic-book characters into icons and “cinematic universes” into a standard practice, are among the 50 highest-grossing movies of all time. Two of them—&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2018/04/avengers-infinity-war-marvel-review/558983/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2019/04/avengers-endgame-review-marvel/587821/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—made &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2019/04/avengers-endgame-behind-its-historic-box-office/588280/&quot;&gt;more than $2 billion&lt;/a&gt; at the box office globally. Apart from James Cameron, they’re the only directors to have crossed that milestone at least twice.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Judging by their filmography since &lt;i&gt;Endgame&lt;/i&gt;, though, it’s unlikely that the Russos will do so for a third time—at least, not without the Avengers. The astronomical budgets the pair have commanded over the past half decade have not yielded Hulk-size cultural footprints: Netflix, which began green-lighting expensive movies &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2022/07/netflix-subscribers-stock-prices-big-studio-movies/670517/&quot;&gt;to help build its own franchises&lt;/a&gt;, stated that the Russos’ $200 million spy thriller &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2022/07/the-gray-man-review-handsome-ryan-gosling/670926/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Gray Man&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; topped its most-watched list for two weeks. But neither the film nor Ryan Gosling’s assassin protagonist has lingered in the public memory. &lt;i&gt;Citadel&lt;/i&gt;, the Prime Video series the Russos produced, is one of the priciest shows ever made, at more than $300 million for its first season. Conceived by an Amazon executive, &lt;i&gt;Citadel&lt;/i&gt; was meant to kick-start a “&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://deadline.com/2023/06/citadel-was-a-victory-for-amazon-says-drama-chief-needs-time-to-grow-1235414045/&quot;&gt;global franchise&lt;/a&gt;,” but it barely made an impression with viewers; in its first month of availability, the show &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://variety.com/2023/tv/news/citadel-ratings-nielsen-viewership-low-1235637650/&quot;&gt;never entered&lt;/a&gt; Nielsen’s Top 10 streaming rankings. Without Earth’s Mightiest Heroes, the Russos’ work has become formulaic and ephemeral. Ambitious studios, it seems, can’t simply buy their way into the zeitgeist.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Yet here the Russos are again, with another exorbitant attempt to establish a new blockbuster series. &lt;i&gt;The Electric State&lt;/i&gt;, now on Netflix, is a $320 million adaptation of Simon Stalenhåg’s graphic novel about a girl who, joined by an intelligent robot, searches for her brother across a retro-futuristic, dystopian America. Some of that money has evidently been put to good use: The visual effects are seamless, the robot designs are genuinely cool, and the set dressing is meticulous. The cast, too, is stacked: Holly Hunter, Colman Domingo, and Brian Cox pop up. Their roles, though, are so absurdly small that they suggest heavy reshoots and excised footage.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2019/04/avengers-endgame-behind-its-historic-box-office/588280/&quot;&gt;Read: What &lt;i&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/i&gt;’s historic box office means for the future&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Hollywood studios granting massive funds to directors who have made box-office hits is a common practice—especially for projects that appear likely to return on the investment. But the Russos have become unusually adept at demonstrating the creative limitations of those piles of cash. Companies have made clear their desire to generate fresh cinematic universes, and Stalenhåg’s book is an excellent starting point for an expansive film adaptation: His evocative artwork explores lands that practically beg to be rendered on the big screen, and his heroine’s quest is filled with pathos. Anthony Russo himself &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/the-electric-state-millie-bobby-brown-chris-pratt-1236034707/&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;, during a panel at New York Comic Con last October, that he and his brother were excited “to figure out what kind of story we can tell in this world.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The story they tell, however, replaces the originality of Stalenhåg’s book with algorithm-friendly, inelegant slop. The Russos reduce the graphic novel’s haunting and macabre tale down to a clichéd battle between unethical humans and sentient machines, in which the latter tried to assert their rights and lost; it’s a generic good-versus-evil setup not unlike those found in &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2022/07/the-gray-man-review-handsome-ryan-gosling/670926/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Gray Man&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;Citadel&lt;/i&gt;. Millie Bobby Brown—the closest thing Netflix has to an in-house star—plays Michelle, a teenager sympathetic to the automatons’ plight who rallies a group of misfits to dethrone a heartless tech mogul, Ethan (Stanley Tucci), who believes that humans and robots shouldn’t coexist. Ethan wants to give people the edge by hooking them up to the virtual-reality headsets he invented; Michelle would like everyone to log off and touch some grass.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   What Michelle and Ethan do have in common is that they’re both one-dimensional archetypes with tragic backstories. The film around them is equally bland. &lt;i&gt;The Electric State &lt;/i&gt;is so transparently eager to satisfy as many demographics of viewers as possible that it proves its own message: that a world dependent on business interests and technological optimization dulls artistic potential and human ingenuity. All that’s left is a wasteland of half-baked ideas searching for a home.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2022/07/netflix-subscribers-stock-prices-big-studio-movies/670517/&quot;&gt;Read: ‘Netflix thinks exactly like an old movie studio’&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   There’s a self-conscious streak to &lt;i&gt;The Electric State&lt;/i&gt; that renders it inert from the start. The Russos populate the cast with big names (and Marvel standbys) such as Chris Pratt and Anthony Mackie, actors whose chemistry with each other almost distracts from the weak storytelling. Michelle resembles the protagonists of 2010s &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2011/03/casting-the-hunger-games-in-praise-of-katniss-everdeen/72164/&quot;&gt;young-adult&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2014/03/must-every-ya-action-heroine-be-petite/284568/&quot;&gt;films&lt;/a&gt;, complete with pithy lines (“I have a condition where I can only live in reality,” she scoffs) and a signature hairdo. Each character is meant to be easy to root for or against, which forces them to be simplistic; Michelle’s ally Keats, lazily played by Pratt, is so underwritten that I’m surprised he even has a name. And many of the robots, despite how lifelike they look, have boring personalities. Woody Harrelson voices the Planters mascot, Mr. Peanut—further proof of the budget going toward procuring recognizable imagery—but the generic role stifles the actor’s eccentric charm.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   As I watched &lt;i&gt;The Electric State&lt;/i&gt;, I was reminded of other projects, good and bad: the philosophical musings of &lt;i&gt;Blade Runner&lt;/i&gt;, the flashy incoherence of the &lt;i&gt;Divergent &lt;/i&gt;films, the character design from the terrific horror video game &lt;i&gt;Soma&lt;/i&gt;. The Russos were obviously influenced by Steven Spielberg’s output in particular, but what they’ve achieved is more akin to the much-maligned, reference-ridden &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2018/03/ready-player-one-review/556769/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;than &lt;i&gt;E.T.&lt;/i&gt; The directors had the money and incentive to strip popular works for parts—mimicking previous successes seems like a safe bet for attaining the widest possible appeal and the highest number of viewing minutes, the metric by which many streaming platforms assess how well their projects perform. But such choices leave the movie feeling too familiar, and it’s unable to build an identity of its own. Every intricately devised robot, every “Hey, it’s that guy!” actor, every closely replicated image from Stalenhåg’s graphic novel becomes nothing but window dressing.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Of course, even the most acclaimed filmmakers can fall victim to the constraints of corporate expectations. Barry Jenkins’s best efforts to enliven the &lt;i&gt;Lion King &lt;/i&gt;prequel, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2024/12/mufasa-the-lion-king-review/681116/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mufasa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, couldn’t prevent it from feeling like a capital-&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; Product. Jenkins’s fellow Oscar winner Chloe Zhao similarly struggled to set &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2021/10/chloe-zhao-eternals-marvel-review/620460/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Eternals&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;apart from the rest of Marvel’s green-screen-heavy fare. The Russo brothers, meanwhile, are known for their past accomplishments with transforming movies into merchandising opportunities. But their latest entry into this costly genre is yet another embarrassment in a string of them, and similarly destined to be forgotten. &lt;i&gt;The Electric State&lt;/i&gt;, with its predictable final shot teeing up a sequel,&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;argues for a society that values togetherness and imagination. Yet the movie—under the guidance of its directors and producers—just can’t be bothered to do any of that imagining itself.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/the-electric-state-netflix-budget-russo-brothers/682090/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/the-electric-state-netflix-budget-russo-brothers/682090/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Battle for the Soul of the West</title><description>&lt;div&gt; The assault on Enlightenment values is tearing both Europe and America apart. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/Y3GT4BcEWbLh51opPm-DDaRQ4sA=/0x0:2000x1125/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/25_3_18_Azizi_Soul_of_the_west_final2/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A fraying rope that has split in two is shown on a field of red with scattered blue, yellow, and white stars.&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by The Atlantic. Source: Getty.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   For President Donald Trump, last month’s spat at the White House with Ukraine’s President Volodymyr Zelensky was “great television.” To the rest of us, it was a horrifying realization of our worst fears: a real-time crumbling of the Euro-American alliance, which has been the bedrock of the international order since 1945.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Europeans have recently been discovering a new resolve for standing on their own. Perhaps the most candid response came from the European Union’s foreign-policy chief, Kaja Kallas, who said that “the free world needs a new leader.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   There is plenty of good sense in the EU taking a resolute stand. The need for “strategic autonomy” is not only the preoccupation of French President Emmanuel Macron; it has been part of the bloc’s codified global strategy since 2016 as well. Now Trump is &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.france24.com/en/europe/20250226-trump-says-eu-formed-to-screw-united-states-tariffs&quot;&gt;fulminating&lt;/a&gt; against the EU, claiming that it was “formed in order to screw the United States,” and European autonomy has become an urgent priority.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But to reduce this moment to a Euro-American clash, let alone to resort to clichés about the supposedly essential qualities of Europe and the United States, would be a fundamental mistake. The current rift is part of a broader battle for the soul of the West. On one side are those who believe that Western countries should continue to be characterized by open societies, Enlightenment values, pluralism, and liberal democracy, as they mostly have been for the past few decades. The most notable opposition to this status quo comes from ultranationalists who believe that the West has gone too far in its espousal of progress and liberalism, and that it must revert to a civilizational ethos centered around Christianity—one that is more traditional and less libertine, less feminist, and less internationalist (or “globalist,” as they like to call it). As a shorthand, I call them anti-liberal counterrevolutionaries.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Both sides have long had partisans in both America and Europe. For about a decade, the standard-bearer for the nationalist right has been Viktor Orbán, the self-styled “illiberal” prime minister of Hungary. Orbán’s fellow anti-liberal counterrevolutionaries have grown in political relevance and popularity across the EU, though they are still relatively marginal. For inspiration, they look to the Russia of Vladimir Putin, whose national chauvinism, banning of “gender ideology” and “gay propaganda,” and revisionism against the world order fit well with their agenda.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/tragic-success-global-putinism/681976/&quot;&gt;Michael McFaul: The tragic success of global Putinism&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The European far right traditionally fulminated against Atlanticism, decrying the United States as the fulcrum of a global liberal order from which Europeans must de-link. But the immense influence of anti-liberal counterrevolutionaries over Trump, especially evident in his second administration, has turned the tables. The world’s mightiest country is now an ally for Europe’s far right. Trump’s first term also encouraged these elements, but its direction wasn’t always stable or clear.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   This time around, some of the most influential figures in Trump’s court have commitments to the anti-liberal counterrevolution: Vice President J. D. Vance, Elon Musk, Donald Trump Jr., and Tucker Carlson, to name a few. One common theme among these men is their championing of Orbán’s Hungary. In 2022, Carlson made a documentary about the country, portraying Orbán as leading “the fight for civilization” against the liberal philanthropist George Soros. Don Jr. made a well-publicized trip to Budapest last year and spared no words in praising Orbán’s Hungary as “one of the last beacons of hope in Europe.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2024/07/why-special-republican-relationship-hungary-so-worrying/679035/&quot;&gt;Zack Beauchamp: Make America Hungary again&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   American proponents of Orbán often praise his hard-line policies on migration and refugees, but this is a red herring. Politicians across the political spectrum in Europe have taken anti-migration positions of various kinds. The admiration for Orbán comes from his unapologetic assault on the liberal values that have defined the West for generations. In a now-famous speech in Romania in 2014, Orbán espoused his anti-liberalism in detail and attacked the United States in terms that have become familiar on the American right: “The strength of American soft power is in decline, and liberal values today embody corruption, sex, and violence and, as such, discredit America and American modernization.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Orbán’s critique is not of any one policy but of something fundamental about the soul of the West. And it reflects a view that has found fuller expression in the words of the Russian far-right philosopher Aleksandr Dugin, a treasured &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://tuckercarlson.com/the-tucker-carlson-encounter-aleksandr-dugin?utm_source=google&amp;amp;utm_medium=paid&amp;amp;gad_source=1&amp;amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwytS-BhCKARIsAMGJyzrioVs96VWqe41hDK5j7L6kEMnH7t7iS_sv6yffy-bPCABrvY-OoLgaArFeEALw_wcB&quot;&gt;guest&lt;/a&gt; on Carlson’s show last year. Dugin sees a dichotomy between liberalism and its enemies that goes back to antiquity. For him, Putin’s Russia represents the “eternal Rome,” a land-based empire of conservative virtue, set against the liberal West’s “eternal Carthage,” a maritime empire of circulation and exchange. Dugin rails against the European Enlightenment, the intellectual root of modern rationalism and liberalism, and defines himself in the lineage of Counter-Enlightenment thinkers, such as Friedrich Nietzsche and Martin Heidegger.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The American right has another major critic of the Enlightenment much closer to home. The billionaire Peter Thiel has been &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.michaelmillerman.com/blog/dugin-influences-western-thought-and-politics&quot;&gt;compared&lt;/a&gt; to Dugin by the latter’s biographer. As early as 2007, Thiel offered a sweeping &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.jstor.org/stable/10.14321/j.ctt7zt6qq&quot;&gt;critique&lt;/a&gt; of Western enlightened thought, inveighing against both Karl Marx and Adam Smith for giving primacy to earthly human needs. Instead, he advocated for “an older Western tradition” that wasn’t afraid to “seek glory in the name of God or country.” Thiel argued that the Enlightenment was a “very long intellectual slumber and amnesia,” from which the West should reawaken into something more like the medieval age. He criticized George W. Bush’s administration for fighting the War on Terror in the name of democratic values and suggested instead an explicitly anti-Islamic campaign in the tradition of the Crusades. Thiel evinced an affinity for the German jurist Carl Schmitt—one of the Nazi luminaries, along with Heidegger, of the anti-liberal counterrevolution.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Since 2019, Thiel has been a major supporter of the national conservative movement that has helped give an intellectual identity to Trumpism. Vice President Vance is a prominent figure in that movement. As early as 2021, Vance &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theamericanconservative.com/a-civilizational-crisis/&quot;&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; about a “civilizational crisis” in the West and claimed that “every single major cultural institution” in the U.S. had been “lost.” Earlier this month, when asked about European-American ties, he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/video/6370057044112&quot;&gt;praised&lt;/a&gt; Europe as the “cradle of the Western civilization,” with which the United States has “religious bonds” and “cultural bonds,” before stating that Europe was “at risk of civilizational suicide.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Vance’s answer is notable not just for what it states but for what it omits. The actually existing transatlantic relationship has long been based on a common espousal of liberal democracy, built on the legacy of defeating fascism in World War II. But for Vance, the proper foundation for Euro-Atlantic ties should instead be Christian faith.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The postwar order we have known was the product of a broad alliance that brought together socialists and liberals against fascism. This order dismantled colonial empires; it conceived of new institutions, such as the United Nations, to foster international dialogue in place of aggression, and new covenants, such as the International Bill of Human Rights, to codify both the civil rights advocated by liberals and socioeconomic rights advocated by socialists.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Unsurprisingly, the anti-liberal counterrevolutionaries of today have no sympathy for this legacy. In fact, historical revisionism about World War II is an important feature of their movement. For years, the European far right has engaged in various forms of Holocaust relativization or outright denial. Last year, Carlson &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2024/09/holocaust-denial-podcast-historians/679765/&quot;&gt;hosted&lt;/a&gt; the Holocaust-denying podcaster Darryl Cooper and introduced him as America’s “best” historian. Not only did Cooper make denialist claims about the Holocaust—he criticized the post-1945 order as making it “effectively illegal in the West to be genuinely right-wing.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/09/anti-semitism-american-right-wing/679992/&quot;&gt;Yair Rosenberg: The anti-Semitic revolution on the American right&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   These are not isolated ideas but a political campaign, with proponents on both sides of the Atlantic, against the post-1945 order and the broader Enlightenment tradition. Its proponents reject the full spectrum of European and American liberal thought, from left to right, and hark back to a West defined by their reading of Christianity and traditional values.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The anti-liberals are a growing force in European politics. Last year, Orbán’s Fidesz party helped establish Patriots for Europe (PfE), the third-largest grouping in the European Parliament, with which 86 of 720 MEPs identify. Its most notable member is France’s National Rally, a once-marginal party that is now the main opposition force in the EU’s second-largest economy. The bloc’s other member parties are currently parts of governments in the Netherlands and Italy. The Trump administration has given these far-right entities new momentum. Elon Musk openly supports not just Orbán’s sister parties, such as Spain’s Vox, but even Germany’s AfD (Alternative for Germany), which was deemed too extremist for PfE and instead joined the more extreme Europe of Sovereign Nations, whose member parties are even more explicitly pro-Putin, anti-NATO, and anti-American.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Such extreme parties are still relatively marginal in European politics. Of the 27 member states of the European Union, at least 20 are currently led by mainstream liberals, centrist conservatives, or Socialists. For now, thinkers spanning a wide spectrum—the American center-right political theorist Francis Fukuyama, say, and the Slovenian Marxist Slavoj Žižek—can still share in the view of Europe as a bastion of Enlightenment values worth preserving.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   To uphold the best of this European tradition now will require more from liberals than just a defense of the old continent against the new. Much as their anti-liberal rivals have done, Western liberals will have to forge transatlantic links and demonstrate their willingness to fight for their values. Broad fronts and global alliances made the post-1945 order. To keep it will require nothing less.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/enlightenment-trump-far-right-europe/682086/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/enlightenment-trump-far-right-europe/682086/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Even Tom Cole Is Defending DOGE</title><description>&lt;div&gt; “A Republican House is not going to chain down a Republican president.” &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/HT5jxPeqHGFXpLsbqPc0NYIrGOY=/0x0:6000x3375/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/GettyImages_1244787013_copy/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black-and-white photograph of Tom Cole, dressed in a suit, surrounded by reporters holding their phones up toward him.&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Kent Nishimura / Los Angeles Times / Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   If any House Republican was going to resist President Donald Trump’s effort to unilaterally bulldoze the federal government, Representative Tom Cole would be at the top of the list.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   As the chair of the House Appropriations Committee, Cole is the keeper of Congress’s purse, which the Trump administration has repeatedly &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/01/trump-executive-order-spending-congress/681484/&quot;&gt;seized&lt;/a&gt; for itself. But even Cole, now 75 and in his 12th term representing Oklahoma, is just fine with Trump and Elon Musk slashing the government without approval from Congress. When, during negotiations over federal spending this month, Democrats insisted on restraining Musk’s Department of Government Efficiency, Cole rejected their demand out of hand. I thought I detected a hint of satisfaction when he recalled his refusal: “I’m sorry, that’s not happening.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Rather than trying to curb DOGE’s authority, Cole has worked behind the scenes to adjust its targets—in at least one case pushing back on cuts that would have hurt his constituents. Earlier this month, Cole told me, he and Musk sat down over bourbon and cigars to discuss DOGE’s mission. Cole said he gently encouraged Musk to consult members of Congress before making cuts. “I guarantee I know my district better than anybody in DOGE, or anybody in Treasury, or anybody in these departments,” Cole told me, summarizing his message. “So it’s usually wise to talk to me … If I think it’s a wrong move, I’m going to say no, and I’m not going to be part of it.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Cole said the billionaire acknowledged that DOGE had made mistakes. “When we make them, we’ll fix them,” he recalled Musk saying. “So far,” Cole told me, “I’ve found them to be good to their word.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/doge-musk-catastrophic-risk/682011/&quot;&gt;Brian Klaas: DOGE is courting catastrophic risk&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   When I asked Cole to explain his support for an agency that clearly encroached on Congress’s prerogatives, he offered a cold political calculus. “A Republican Senate, a Republican House is not going to chain down a Republican president,” he told me last week. Democrats “wouldn’t have done that to Barack Obama or Joe Biden. We’re certainly not going to do that to President Trump.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Cole is nothing like a typical Trump supporter in Congress. He’s an institutionalist who has been willing to oppose conservative hard-liners, and he owes his position not to Trump or the MAGA base but to years of developing close ties with powerful Republicans inside the Capitol. But Cole’s defense of DOGE is not exactly a shock to those who know him. He’s a staunch ally to party leaders who, earlier in his career, ran the House GOP’s campaign efforts. And Trump and Cole have been on good terms for years. During his first term, the president would sometimes call Cole to praise his TV appearances.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Cole knows where his voters are and where the party is. Sometimes he lets their opinions dictate his own. On January 6, 2021, hours after hundreds of Trump supporters ransacked the Capitol, Cole voted against certifying Biden’s presidential victory in two states—a decision he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://cole.house.gov/media/press-releases/cole-statement-electoral-college-count&quot;&gt;attributed entirely&lt;/a&gt; to respecting the views of his Oklahoma constituents, whose support for Trump reached a nearly two-to-one ratio.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Still, Democrats have long viewed Cole as a Republican they can make deals with—a rarity in today’s GOP. When Republicans were struggling to find a speaker after the ouster of Kevin McCarthy in 2023, some Democrats mentioned Cole as a possible compromise choice. (He did not want the job, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2023/10/kevin-mccarthy-congress-tom-cole-interview/675566/&quot;&gt;he told me at the time&lt;/a&gt;.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   So Cole’s support for Musk and DOGE has disappointed Democrats. In a hearing last week, Representative Joe Neguse, a Colorado Democrat, sharply criticized Cole for backing DOGE while also asking the Trump administration to &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.oudaily.com/news/tom-cole-national-weather-center-noaa-lease-doge-donald-trump-cuts-layoffs/article_1c1870a0-fba0-11ef-9053-f32e52b55e1b.html&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/a&gt; its plan to close federal offices located in and around his district.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In our interview, Cole offered no apologies. “If I think they’re wrong, I’ll bring it to their attention,” he said of DOGE. “I’ll argue my case, and hopefully I’ll be able to persuade them.” But Cole hasn’t objected to Trump and Musk effectively closing USAID on their own, even though he supports foreign aid. “It might need to be shut down,” Cole said, referring to the agency. &lt;i&gt;Isn’t that Congress’s job?&lt;/i&gt; “Well, yeah,” he replied, “but Congress doesn’t always do its job. When Congress doesn’t do its job, I’m not going to be mad at an executive [branch] that’s trying to save money.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   We were speaking inside the Capitol, a short walk from the House chamber where Cole was leading the debate over a bill that Republicans soon muscled through to fund the government for the next six months. Democrats argued that the measure would further empower Trump to wage his war on the government, which many of them believe has precipitated a constitutional crisis. Cole, who was a historian before he became a politician, thinks that view is a bit much.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The power struggle between Congress and the president, he said, “is as old as the Constitution. We go back and forth all the time.” He and other Republicans argue that Trump’s efforts to expand presidential power to cut spending is no different from Biden’s repeated attempts to forgive student-loan debt over the objections of both Congress and—in their telling—a Supreme Court ruling. The question of whether Trump has overstepped legal bounds, Cole said, “will be settled in the court.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/trump-alien-enemies-act/682068/&quot;&gt;Read: The ultimate Trump story&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I asked Cole if he was worried that Trump would defy judicial orders. “No, I don’t think so,” he replied. And even if Trump did ignore the courts, Cole suggested, it wouldn’t be the end of the world. He noted that past presidents have disregarded rulings without terminating the republic. “I don’t defend that, but it’s not like this is some unprecedented assault on democracy,” Cole said. “I’m not going to worry too much,” he told me, referring to potential constitutional crises. “We’ll deal with them as they come up.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Cole has a tendency to sound like a mere observer, which he is not: Lawmakers in his position have wielded immense power over funding, which they’ve used to curtail House speakers and even the occasional president. But serving as the appropriations chair matters somewhat less in a party that wants to cut spending, especially when that party is content to let the White House get its way. Cole seems okay with that. “If we ultimately disagree, well, we’ll just fight it out. That’s not unusual,” he told me. “Do I have better success with this administration than the last one? Sure. Welcome to politics.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/congress-doge-spending-tom-cole/682089/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/congress-doge-spending-tom-cole/682089/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The DEI Catch-22</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Columbia researchers believe their grants are being cut because of diversity components that were imposed by the federal government. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/MgqM6TMADt4xFISeXZxnyG69_Mc=/0x0:5760x3240/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_18_ColumbiaUnivFunding/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A color photograph of brick buildings and a green lawn on Columbia University campus in Morningside Heights, New York.&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Andrew Cribb / Alamy&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   &lt;p data-flatplan-paragraph=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;i data-stringify-type=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;This article was featured in the One Story to Read Today newsletter. &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; data-gtm-vis-first-on-screen31117857_899=&quot;984608&quot; data-gtm-vis-has-fired31117857_899=&quot;1&quot; data-gtm-vis-total-visible-time31117857_899=&quot;100&quot; data-sk=&quot;tooltip_parent&quot; data-stringify-link=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/one-story-to-read-today/&quot; delay=&quot;150&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/one-story-to-read-today/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sign up for it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;the Trump administration&lt;/span&gt; announced that it was canceling $400 million worth of grants to and contracts with Columbia University, ostensibly to punish the university for its handling of anti-Semitism amid pro-Palestinian campus protests, one important detail went unspecified: what type of funding, exactly, would be getting cut. In the weeks since, researchers at the university have found themselves moonlighting as detectives, trying to understand why some of them saw their life’s work upended while others were spared.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   They believe they have found a pattern. As far as they can tell, nearly all of the canceled grants seem to have made some mention of diversity, equity, inclusion, or other disfavored topics, several med-school researchers told me.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Making the cuts even more maddening is the fact that, at least until a few months ago, the federal government &lt;em&gt;required &lt;/em&gt;researchers to include plans to “enhance diversity” in many grant applications. And under a policy first implemented during the George H. W. Bush administration, the National Institutes of Health long &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.niaid.nih.gov/grants-contracts/research-supplements&quot;&gt;offered&lt;/a&gt; supplemental funding for grants that employed someone from an underrepresented minority group. Now the same factors that helped researchers get their grants approved may have become liabilities. “You can imagine how it feels to be terminated for following the government guidelines,” Domenico Accili, an endocrinology professor, told me.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/dei-letter-universities-trump/681986/&quot;&gt;Rose Horowitch: Colleges have no idea how to comply with Trump’s orders&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Beyond the capriciousness of punishing researchers for following the prior administration’s rules, the grant cancellations demonstrate the impossible position that Columbia’s researchers are in. If they didn’t pursue DEI objectives before, they could have lost out on grants or even violated congressional mandates. If they did, they’re at risk of ending up as collateral damage in the culture war. They’d prefer to just get back to the science.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;The cuts have already&lt;/span&gt; had significant effects. Because medical-research funding is such a large share of federal support for higher education, Columbia’s med school has borne the brunt of the funding cuts. This makes the punishment seem even more arbitrary—the medical school is several miles away from the campus where the bulk of the pro-Palestinian protests occurred. Columbia’s cancer center has stopped work on several clinical trials for disease treatment and symptom management, Dawn Hershman, an oncologist, told me. Hershman said that, unlike many of her colleagues, she isn’t convinced that there is any DEI-specific pattern to the cuts thus far; even so, her lab has been modifying clinical research to comply with Trump’s anti-DEI directives. “This type of disruption costs money and time—time that people with cancer don’t have,” she said. Accili, who leads the Diabetes and Endocrinology Research Center, had to stop work on a clinical trial that had tracked patients since the 1990s. Because he can’t finish the study, all the data are unusable, he told me.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   If the Trump administration is in fact targeting these grants because of ideological factors, it’s caught a lot of apolitical research in the crosshairs. According to an email from the director of the Columbia Stem Cell Initiative to colleagues, grants to train aspiring researchers were canceled because of their diversity component. Grants that mentioned climate, race, HIV, or COVID also appear to have been cut, as were grants that support centers to study cancer, diabetes, and Alzheimer’s.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2025/02/nih-grant-freeze-biomedical-research/681853/&quot;&gt;Read: Inside the collapse at the NIH&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Megan Sykes, the director of the Columbia Center for Translational Immunology, received supplemental funding to employ a Black graduate student on her research grant. But the grant itself studied better ways to transplant animal organs into humans. One of the grants canceled at Accili’s lab included an effort to recruit transgender patients. But the study itself looked at the progression of bone disease in humans. (Accili told me that, when it came to grants to support early-career scientists, filling out the paperwork related to the NIH’s diversity requirement was sometimes a burden. Some specialties already struggle to recruit enough young physicians; adding new demands, he said, only makes that more difficult.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   One engineering-school professor whose graduate student lost the grant that paid his stipend said that the student didn’t participate in the protests on either side. “It’s so disconnected from anything he does,” the professor, who requested anonymity for fear of more grant cuts, told me. “He’s ending up suffering consequences nominally for how Columbia’s leadership handled the protest.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Some of the researchers feeling the biggest effects of the punishments are themselves Jewish. Columbia has an unusually high proportion of Jewish students and professors. (The Jewish campus organization Hillel estimates that Columbia’s grad-student population is 16 percent Jewish.) Many are seeing their livelihood thrown into question in the name of fighting anti-Semitism. They’re aware of the irony. Sykes, who’s Jewish, told me that she’s frightened by the rise of anti-Semitism. “But I just don’t understand the connection between that and NIH-funded biomedical research,” she said.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Last week, Trump’s anti-Semitism task force told Columbia that it would consider restoring the $400 million if the university takes a number of specific steps to crack down on pro-Palestinian protesters and address anti-Semitism, including changing its discipline policies and banning masks that protesters use to conceal their identities. But even if the money comes back, things won’t return to the way they were before. Now that Trump has set the precedent of pulling scientific funding as a punishment for unrelated offenses, scientific research will always be at risk of being caught in the middle. Prior administrations, including Joe Biden’s, have used university funding as a way to further certain priorities. But Trump’s is the first to wield the threat of lost federal funding as a political cudgel. If obeying the dictates of one administration places scientists at risk of being persecuted by the next, what are they to do?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Accili has warned faculty members not to use any terms related to diversity, equity, and inclusion in future grant proposals. He has even advised them to avoid technical phrases, such as “gain of function,” that have become associated with pandemic-related controversies. “We’re in a phase in which we have to watch what we write or what we say for fear of offending the ongoing political sensitivities,” he told me. That has never been an ideal condition for scientific progress.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/dei-columbia-funding-cuts/682091/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/dei-columbia-funding-cuts/682091/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What Impossibly Wealthy Women Do for Love and Fulfillment</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Meghan, Duchess of Sussex, embraces old-fashioned domesticity on her new lifestyle series. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/z32oBwkvG-6rgM9pNh_ehxagrAE=/0x0:2880x1620/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_17_tradwife/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Collage of Meghan, Duchess of Sussex, on her new Netflix show, &amp;quot;With Love, Meghan&amp;quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by The Atlantic. Source: Jake Rosenberg / Netflix.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   To start with an unpopular opinion: I loved &lt;em&gt;With Love, Meghan&lt;/em&gt;, Netflix’s goofy new lifestyle series, in which Meghan, Duchess of Sussex, smiles winningly in a Montecito kitchen that is not her own, making the hokey jokes you typically find stitched on Etsy home goods (“&lt;em&gt;bready&lt;/em&gt; or not, here I &lt;em&gt;crumb&lt;/em&gt;”), underbaking cakes, and strewing edible flowers on everything that crosses her path. I loved how Meghan’s core kitchen skills appear to be arranging vegetables on a $326 cutting board and emphasizing every single consonant in the word &lt;em&gt;preserves&lt;/em&gt;. I loved when she praised carnations as a humble, budget-friendly flower, then “elevated” them by sticking one (1) into the middle of maybe a thousand dollars worth of peonies. I even loved when she made avocado toast for a quick solo breakfast—who among us?—though I screamed out loud when she promptly sprinkled edible flowers on top.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   By now, you may have seen the memes—TikTok jokers radiating cheer and offering tutorials on how to “prepare” glasses of water. They skewer one of the show’s key contradictions, which is that Meghan, though lovable, is &lt;em&gt;maybe in truth not very good at domestic goddessery&lt;/em&gt;. In the first episode, tending to “her” bees, she relies on a beekeeper, a man who could easily be Fred Armisen doing a &lt;em&gt;Portlandia&lt;/em&gt; bit. “We’ve been doing this for over a year now, but I still need you,” she tells him, smiling. Later, she confesses, “I’ve never liked honey.” When Meghan and Mindy Kaling prepare food for a children’s tea party to which no children actually show up, the finger sandwiches look less like high-tea offerings and more like the scraps in the duchess’s chicken coop. Making tacos with a chef, she has to be told to use two forks to shred chicken breasts or she’ll burn her fingers. She is, however, extremely skilled at opening champagne—no one has popped this many bottles in the lifestyle realm since Martha got out of prison or Ina &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2020/04/ina-gartens-quarantine-playbook-instagram/609238/&quot;&gt;went through pandemic lockdown&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2024/11/martha-stewart-netflix-documentary-review/680823/&quot;&gt;Read: The many contradictions of Martha Stewart&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Watching the show, I found myself stuck on one question: Who is this &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt;? Is there an underserved niche of Santa Barbara moms with their own pristine vegetable gardens who’ve previously been too intimidated to attempt baking focaccia? And yet, as &lt;em&gt;With Love, Meghan&lt;/em&gt; went on, it started to hit a few of the classic pleasure points. A beautiful woman with a wardrobe of stealth-wealth beige separates and floral dresses? Check. A fixation, both nutritional and aesthetic, on how best to feed one’s family, down to fruit platters arranged like rainbows and jars of chia seeds and hemp hearts to sneak into pancakes? Check. A strange aside where she details what it meant for her to take her husband’s name? &lt;em&gt;Ding ding ding&lt;/em&gt;: We’re in tradwife territory now. This is absurd, of course. Meghan isn’t a &lt;em&gt;tradwife&lt;/em&gt;; if anything, she’s a &lt;em&gt;girlboss&lt;/em&gt;, a savvy, mediagenic entrepreneur with a new podcast dedicated to businesswomen and a nascent &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/meghan-sussex-as-ever-brand-announcement&quot;&gt;retail &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/meghan-sussex-as-ever-brand-announcement&quot;&gt;brand&lt;/a&gt;. So why does she seem to be trying so hard to rebrand as one, offering up this wistful performance of femininity and old-fashioned domestic arts that feels staged—and pretty familiar?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In a world in which 99.999 percent of women’s labor at home goes unseen and unappreciated, tradwives demand visibility—cut loose from the demands of a 9-to-5 job, they promise, we women can free ourselves to make the things we already do more beautiful, and to find meaning in everyday routines by turning &lt;em&gt;chores&lt;/em&gt; into &lt;em&gt;homemaking&lt;/em&gt;. The most notorious tradwives on social media turn domestic labor into intoxicating content; think Hannah Neeleman churning butter (with a KitchenAid) or Nara Smith whispering over &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reel/DAv4jGeuux1/?hl=en&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; of herself carving up pork butt while wearing a scarlet couture gown. &lt;em&gt;With Love, Meghan&lt;/em&gt; does exactly the same thing, affirming the home as Meghan’s sanctuary after a bruising, very public introduction to married life, and the acts she performs for friends and family as labors of real love.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But there’s also a playacting component to the show that it can’t quite shake off. Most of us, I’d safely bet, have made pasta, possibly even while another person watches. But we don’t imbue the process with so much &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;. Meghan doesn’t just entertain, she explains on the show; she makes elaborate rituals out of the act of hosting, baking dog biscuits from scratch for one dear friend (who arrives regrettably sans dog) and creating a welcome basket for a beloved former makeup artist, right down to handmixed bath salts and snacks in beribboned bags. Partly, this seems practical—Meghan might not be a trained chef entirely set up for her own cooking show, but her calligraphy skills and decorative abilities are second to none. The word &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt; is peppered throughout every scene, emphasizing Meghan’s key aspiration of prettifying domestic life. Her friends appreciate these efforts—of course they do! But they’re also stiff and slightly awkward on camera, which is perhaps what all the wine is for.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2024/10/momtok-secret-lives-of-mormon-wives-review-feminism-beauty-domesticity/680410/&quot;&gt;Read: MomTok is the apotheosis of 21st-century womanhood&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The overall vibe is one of delightful leisure. “We might have a busy floral day today,” Meghan says, visiting a flower market and walking out with armfuls of bouquets, like she’s in a horticultural episode of &lt;em&gt;Supermarket Sweep&lt;/em&gt;. By contrast, I’ve spent the past few months watching Neeleman, the superstar influencer also known as Ballerina Farm, attend cooking school in Ireland, a 12-week sojourn—her husband and eight children have accompanied her—in which, for once, she seems unafraid to show how hard she’s working. She posts about the duck entrées that go wrong, the prep work for kitchen shifts, the late nights. And I’ve appreciated the transparency of someone really showing the arduousness of her efforts, not just cosplaying scenes of kitchen congress for Instagram. Most of the content creators whom we’ve come to identify as tradwives are more apt to hide both their home labor and the fact that they do indeed have jobs (as influencers).  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   If the goal is inducing aspiration, &lt;em&gt;With Love, Meghan&lt;/em&gt; is indeed “beautiful.” Walking into the room while I was watching, my husband asked if this was “one of those movies with the kitchens,” by which he meant the oeuvre of Nancy Meyers—possibly the biggest compliment any Southern California lifestyle influencer could hope for. If Meghan’s fake garden is this colorful and bounteous, her fake pantry this blissfully stocked, can you imagine the real thing? I don’t begrudge her any of her hard-won happiness making crepes to mop up all her preserves, or getting Roy Choi to help her make fried chicken. (If you watch any one episode, make it that one, because Choi really can &lt;em&gt;cook&lt;/em&gt;, and his chemistry with Meghan is the kind people watch morning television for.) But her series, ultimately, is best appreciated as anthropological study—what impossibly wealthy women do for love and fulfillment—rather than a model for how the rest of us should enact our labors: half as care and half as performance.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/with-love-meghan-tradwife-domesticity-review/682082/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/with-love-meghan-tradwife-domesticity-review/682082/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>There Are Two Kinds of Credit Cards</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Yet another way the poor are subsidizing the rich &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/pFbMS6ueqS4CUAyAUTebAyZWNF0=/0x0:2160x2700/648x810/media/img/2025/03/17/2025_03_17_Credit_Cards/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A pyramid of stacked credit cards, with gold ones at the top&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by The Atlantic. Source: Getty.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   The American consumer is tapped out. Grocery prices &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/02/egg-prices-rising/681844/&quot;&gt;are bananas&lt;/a&gt;, housing prices &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/02/great-affordability-crisis-breaking-america/606046/&quot;&gt;are obscene&lt;/a&gt;, out-of-pocket medical expenses &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/06/america-still-has-huge-price-problem/678678/&quot;&gt;are absurd&lt;/a&gt;, and child care is impossible to afford, if you can find it. To keep up with the basics, let alone the Joneses, American consumers have been charging more and more to their cards. Credit-card balances stand at an all-time high of $1.2 trillion, up more than 7 percent &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorkfed.org/medialibrary/interactives/householdcredit/data/pdf/HHDC_2024Q4&quot;&gt;year-on-year&lt;/a&gt;, and the share of borrowers who are &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/DRCCLACBS&quot;&gt;late on their payments&lt;/a&gt; has reached its highest point since the aftermath of the Great Recession. Serious delinquency rates are climbing, particularly among &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorkfed.org/medialibrary/interactives/householdcredit/data/pdf/HHDC_2024Q4&quot;&gt;consumers under the age of 40&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   High costs are weighing down working-class families, while driving big rewards to rich ones. Over the past few decades, the credit-card market has quietly transformed into two credit-card markets: one offering generous benefits to wealthy Americans, the other offering expensive debt to the poor, with the latter subsidizing the former. While balances are compounding at the highest average APR in decades, a brutal &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lendingtree.com/credit-cards/study/average-credit-card-interest-rate-in-america/&quot;&gt;21.5 percent&lt;/a&gt;, the haves are not just pulling away from the have-nots. The people swiping their cards to pay for food and gas are also paying for wealthy cardholders’ upgrades to business class.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In the credit-card industry, the well-to-do are known as &lt;em&gt;transactors&lt;/em&gt;. They pay off their balance in full every month, avoiding late fees and interest charges. They use credit cards as a convenient payment method, and as a way to earn travel points, cash back, airport-lounge vouchers, seat upgrades, and other goodies. Given how valuable these rewards are, transactors make money by spending money. “If you’re spending $100,000 a year, you’re getting maybe $1,500 back in terms of points or cash,” Aaron Klein of the Brookings Institution told me. “You’re not paying taxes on that. It’s worth closer to $2,500 or $3,000 a year in taxable income.” (That’s double the average worker’s &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CES0500000011&quot;&gt;weekly earnings&lt;/a&gt;.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2015/04/against-credit-cards/390846/&quot;&gt;Joe Pinsker: Against credit cards&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Credit-card companies compete intensely for transactors’ business, Klein explained. These customers rarely default. They rack up huge monthly charges, with firms such as Chase, Citi, American Express, and Capital One skimming a share of their spending. They travel often, allowing credit-card companies to make lucrative deals with airlines and hotel chains.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In contrast, the have-nots are known as &lt;em&gt;revolvers&lt;/em&gt;. Revolvers are subprime borrowers who use credit cards as a payment tool and as a short-term loan, to cover surprise expenses and groceries the week before payday. Such customers tend to take out no-frills cards, without lavish cash-back rewards and travel points. They also tend to carry a balance from &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bankrate.com/credit-cards/news/credit-card-debt-survey/&quot;&gt;month to month&lt;/a&gt;, and sometimes from month to month to month to month.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “When you talk to rich people who pay off their balance, they think that credit-card companies are losing money on them, and they’re the ones subsidizing the people who carry a balance,” Klein explained. “It’s the exact opposite.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Rich families make out in two ways. First, the “swipe” or “interchange” fees that card networks and banks assess on retail businesses serve as a tax on poor families, who disproportionately pay with debit cards and cash. Most grocery stores and online shops charge their customers the same amount for an item, whether the customer pays with a debit card, cash, a credit card, a check, or a Venmo transfer. Accepting cash costs the retailer nothing. Accepting a debit card issued by a large bank costs it &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.federalreserve.gov/paymentsystems/regii-average-interchange-fee.htm#:~:text=The%20Board%27s%20Regulation%20II%20provides,Transaction%20Status%20and%20Network%20Type&quot;&gt;0.05 percent&lt;/a&gt;, plus some change. Accepting a basic credit card costs perhaps 1.5 percent, and a fancy rewards card as much as 4 percent. In 2023, these swipe fees amounted to more than &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://merchantspaymentscoalition.com/credit-and-debit-card-swipe-fees-totaled-224-billion-2023-nearly-one-third-more-previously-believed&quot;&gt;$224 billion, driving up &lt;/a&gt;retail prices by $1,700 a year for the average family. Everybody pays more for their goods; only fancy cardholders get juicy perks and cash returned to them.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Second, transactors benefit from the late fees and interest charges accumulated by revolvers, which credit-card companies use to help finance their rewards programs. This has proved particularly true in the past few years, as high prices and high interest rates have increased revolvers’ debt burdens.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   A strong economy with a brutal cost-of-living crisis is a great economy for the credit-card industry, it turns out. The average balance carried over month-to-month &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.experian.com/blogs/ask-experian/state-of-credit-cards/&quot;&gt;has risen&lt;/a&gt;; interest rates have risen; and card issuers have pushed their APRs far beyond &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/blog/credit-card-interest-rate-margins-at-all-time-high/?utm_source=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=general_updates&amp;amp;utm_term=2.23.24&quot;&gt;prime rates&lt;/a&gt;. As a result, the revenue credit-card firms make from interest payments has ballooned from $76 billion in 2020 to $170 billion in 2024, and rewards cards have gotten more rewarding. The industry argues that swipe fees, not interest and penalties on poorer customers, finance its cash-back and travel programs, Ted Rossman of Bankrate, the financial data and news site, told me. But he does not “totally buy that.” It’s all “part of the calculation.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Now the economy seems to be slowing down: President Donald Trump’s trade war is increasing retail costs, uncertainty is leading businesses to pull back on investment, and firms are hiring fewer workers. Families are spending as much as they can afford, and struggling with mounting, expensive debt. “People take on credit-card debt for practical reasons,” Rossman told me. “That’s a tough cycle to break when the average interest rate is 20 percent.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2016/01/credit-cards-subprime-cfpb/424458/&quot;&gt;Gillian B. White: The unfair opacity of credit cards peddled to the poor&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Rossman noted that high-income families were beginning to look more like working-class families in the credit-card data, with some transactors becoming revolvers. Three in five households credit-card debtors making more than $80,000 annually have been carrying a balance for &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bankrate.com/credit-cards/news/credit-card-debt-survey/#key-insights&quot;&gt;more than a year&lt;/a&gt;, he said. Seriously delinquent balances are increasing, as is the share of loans that some card companies consider unrecoverable. Investors have noticed: The price of shares in American Express, Discover, Capital One, and other lending companies have dropped more than the broader market. Politicians have noticed too: A bipartisan House bill would cap &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://ocasio-cortez.house.gov/media/press-releases/ocasio-cortez-luna-introduce-bill-cap-credit-card-interest-rates-10&quot;&gt;credit-card interest&lt;/a&gt; rates at 10 percent, and a Senate proposal would lower &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/credit-cards/what-to-expect-if-the-credit-card-competition-act-passes&quot;&gt;swipe fees&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The legislation could help reduce borrowing costs and retail prices for millions of families, though Rossman noted that he expected credit-card issuers to raise fees to make up for the lost revenue. In the meantime, with markets swooning, card companies are offering fewer cards to subprime borrowers. This isn’t great news. Relying on expensive debt, and paying fees that subsidize richer card users, is bad enough for poor Americans. Not having a credit card to fall back on might be worse.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/credit-card-racket/682075/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/credit-card-racket/682075/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Cost of the Government’s Attack on Columbia</title><description>&lt;div&gt; American universities have given the country prosperity and security. The Trump administration’s attack on academic freedom endangers all of that. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/xe-n9LNE8H625UszUOgLFMarK1k=/0x0:7867x4425/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_18_ColumbiaUniv2/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of people sitting at tables in a leafy courtyard in front of a building on Columbia University&#39;s campus&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Dave Sanders / The New York Times / Redux&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   The United States is home to the best collection of research universities in the world. Those universities have contributed tremendously to America’s prosperity, health, and security. They are magnets for outstanding talent from throughout the country and around the world.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The Trump administration’s recent attack on Columbia University puts all of that at risk, presenting the greatest threat to American universities since the Red Scare of the 1950s. Every American should be concerned.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The rise of the American research university in the 20th century depended on many factors, including two crucial turning points. The first, at the start of the century, was the development of strong principles of academic freedom that allowed people and ideas to be judged by scholarly standards, not according to the whims or interests of powerful trustees, donors, or political officials. Stanford’s dismissal in 1900 of Edward Ross—an economics professor who had incited controversy with his remarks about, among other topics, Asian immigrants and the labor practices of a railroad run by the university’s founders—&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://ed.stanford.edu/news/academic-freedom-s-origin-story#:~:text=Things%20took%20a%20turn%20in,had%20enough%20of%20Ross&#39;%20outspokenness.&quot;&gt;catalyzed&lt;/a&gt; a movement to protect the rights of faculty members to pursue, publish, and teach controversial ideas. Significant governance reforms took place in the same period, shifting control of professorial appointments from boards of trustees to presidents and faculties.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/teachers-schools-dei-communism/681906/&quot;&gt;Clay Risen: When America persecutes its teachers&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The second turning point came during World War II, when Vannevar Bush, the director of the Office of Scientific Research and Development, created the modern partnership between the federal government and the country’s research universities. Bush recognized that by sponsoring research at universities, the United States could lead the world in discoveries and innovations. Over time, American universities became responsible for a large portion of the government’s scientific programs, accepting tens of billions of dollars a year to perform research that would make the country stronger and improve the lives of its citizens.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   These two developments had an important connection. The government’s successful collaboration with American universities depended on its respect for academic freedom, which, for decades, presidents and legislators from both political parties largely observed. That freedom attracted the world’s finest scholars and facilitated the unfettered pursuit of knowledge.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Robust federal funding helped make American universities the world’s best, but it also created a huge risk. Universities had acquired a public patron more powerful than any private donor; their budgets became heavily dependent on that single source. If the United States government ever repudiated the principle of academic freedom, it could bully universities by threatening to withdraw funding unless they changed their curricula, research programs, and personnel decisions.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   That’s what the Trump administration did this month when it &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/newyork/news/trump-administration-cancels-400-million-columbia-university/&quot;&gt;canceled $400 million&lt;/a&gt; in funding to Columbia without the &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://ny1.com/nyc/all-boroughs/politics/2025/03/10/details-of--400-million-columbia-funding-cut-remain-unclear&quot;&gt;legally required&lt;/a&gt; due process. The government &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/03/14/nyregion/columbia-letter.html&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; Columbia that the money would be restored only if the university met various conditions, which included placing its Middle East, South Asian, and African Studies department “under academic receivership” and making unspecified but “comprehensive” reforms to its student admissions and international-recruiting practices.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Recent events have raised legitimate concerns about anti-Semitism at Columbia. The government can respond to those concerns without infringing on academic freedom. The principles of that freedom do not give faculty or students the right to disrupt university operations or violate campus rules. Nor does this freedom allow faculty to violate the scholarly standards of their discipline or compel students into political activity. To the extent that the government has grounds to investigate, it should use the processes required by law to do so, and it should allow Columbia to defend itself. Instead, the government is using grants that apply to Columbia science departments as a cudgel to force changes to a completely unrelated department that the government apparently regards as objectionable.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Nobody should suppose that this will stop at Columbia or with the specific academic programs targeted by the government’s letter. Precisely because great research universities are centers of independent, creative thought, they generate arguments and ideas that challenge political power across fields as varied as international relations, biology, economics, and history. If government officials think that stifling such criticism is politically acceptable and legally permissible, some people in authority will inevitably yield to the temptation to do so.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/columbia-antisemitism-israel-palestine-trump/682054/&quot;&gt;Franklin Foer: Columbia University’s anti-Semitism problem&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Nor should those who might revile the views expressed by some Columbia faculty members, or who dislike the university’s admission policies, take any comfort from this assault on academic freedom. Universities are now under attack from the right; in the future, left-leaning politicians may demand that universities do their bidding. Under such circumstances, the safest appointments may be the blandest ones—and brilliant scholars, those whom the world most needs, are rarely bland.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The attack on Columbia is a radical threat to scholarly excellence and to America’s leadership in research. Universities and their leaders should speak up and litigate forcefully to protect their rights.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The universities cannot, however, prevail alone. Strong, independent academic institutions produce new technologies and insights that catalyze economic growth, save lives, improve well-being, and overcome injustices. Every citizen and officeholder who cares about the strength of our country must also care about free speech, self-governing thought, and the untrammeled quest for knowledge. They, too, should demand a stop to the government’s unwarranted intrusion on academic freedom at Columbia.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/columbia-academic-freedom/682088/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/columbia-academic-freedom/682088/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump Gets a Taste of Putin’s Tactics</title><description>&lt;div&gt; The Russian leader is offering few concessions in negotiations over Ukraine. How hard is Trump willing to push for the peace he promises? &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/dF3-Vgss0cDTO4kuSGbiEWiaoXM=/0x0:2000x1125/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/PutinTrumpCall/original.png&quot; alt=&quot;Patchwork of photos of Putin and Trump, with telephone cords&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Paul Spella / The Atlantic. Sources: Aleksey Babushkin / AFP / Getty; Chip Somodevilla / Getty.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   Vladimir Putin isn’t going to make this easy for Donald Trump.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   For weeks, Trump has bragged about his close relationship with his Russian counterpart and declared that Putin wanted to bring a quick end to the war that he, of course, started more than three years ago. Trump’s national-security team worked with Ukraine to come up with a 30-day cease-fire proposal in hopes of persuading Moscow to accept it. And his press secretary declared yesterday that Ukraine and Russia were on the “10th yard line of peace.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But when the two men spoke today, Putin had his own ideas.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Putin did agree during the more-than-two-hour call to halt strikes on Ukrainian energy infrastructure, and he pledged to continue negotiations. But that limited deal fell far short of what the White House had forecast in recent days, and it now confronts Trump with a dilemma. In order to secure the peace he has promised, he might have to engage in something he has yet to do: get tough with Putin.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump, predictably, dressed up his call with Putin as a win, posting on social media that the conversation was “a very good and productive one.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The peace process “is now in full force and effect, and we will, hopefully, for the sake of Humanity, get the job done!” he wrote.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In truth, Putin offered next to no concessions, and his goal, according to a Kremlin readout of the call, remains maximalist: preventing Ukraine’s rearmament and sovereignty. In order for him to accept Trump’s full cease-fire proposal, Putin said, Ukraine would have to stop rearming its military and sending new soldiers to the front lines, and all foreign governments—including the United States and Kyiv’s European allies—would have to stop sending military assistance or intelligence to Ukraine.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/claude-malheuret-speech/681947/&quot;&gt;Read: Trump is Nero while Washington burns&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Taken together, those demands would severely weaken Ukraine’s ability to defend itself, and Trump did not agree to them in the call. Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, speaking with reporters in Ukraine after the Trump-Putin call, expressed “skepticism” about Putin’s motivations and made clear that no lasting deal could be made without his nation’s involvement. Still, he added, “if there is a partial cease-fire, this is a positive result,” and he signaled that Ukraine would accept the limited agreement, even though it would allow Russia to continue to pummel his nation’s cities and towns.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   If the strikes on energy infrastructure indeed stop, it would be the most significant mutually agreed suspension of attacks in the war. A senior White House aide framed that to me as a major achievement, the first step toward a broader peace (Trump long ago abandoned his campaign promise to end the war in 24 hours). But Trump’s national-security team will now need to debate a course of action, and the aide, who requested anonymity to discuss internal conversations, conceded that difficult decisions lie ahead. Will Trump allow the U.S. to pressure Moscow—by toughening sanctions on Russia or increasing aid to Ukraine—to push Putin to soften his demands? Or will Trump once more defer to Putin and isolate Kyiv?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The partial cease-fire holds benefits for both sides. Ukraine has struggled for years with Russia’s attacks on its energy grid, which at times have plunged cities into darkness and cold. But agreeing to the deal also was in Putin’s interest—Ukraine has recently ratcheted up its attacks on gas and oil facilities deep in Russian territory, weakening Moscow’s most crucial stream of revenue at a time when the nation’s war-weary economy is struggling.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Marc Polymeropoulos, a former U.S. intelligence official who is a Trump critic, told me that Putin’s demand for an end to those strikes—and his willingness to relinquish his own military’s ability to do the same—is proof that the strikes “are having a much more severe effect than even we imagined. Putin wants them to stop. That’s a pretty good measure of effectiveness.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   That’s all that Putin was willing to give up, though, and he telegraphed his intent to keep the war going or, at least, to end it only on terms that he could dictate. According to the Kremlin readout of the call, Putin insisted on the “absolute need to eliminate the root causes of the crisis,” which include, in Moscow’s view, Ukraine seeking security guarantees from the West, such as admission to NATO or the European Union. Putin also suggested cutting Kyiv out of future negotiations, leaving the talks solely between Washington and Moscow. And his demand for a complete end to all foreign military support to Ukraine is simply a nonstarter: Even though Trump and Vice President J. D. Vance have previously threatened to discontinue American support for Kyiv, Ukraine’s European partners have in recent weeks only increased their pledges.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “It’s clear that Russia remains the obstacle to peace in Europe,” Democratic Senator Chris Coons told me in a statement. “I’m glad to see a halt on infrastructure strikes but many of Putin’s ‘requests’—like a ban on arms or intel sharing—make clear what he is after: a neutered Ukraine that can’t defend itself.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Of note: Neither the White House’s nor the Kremlin’s readout of the call described any discussions between the two leaders over the fate of the territory Russia has seized from Ukraine. Russia has claimed about 20 percent of Ukraine’s land, beginning with the illegal annexation of Crimea in 2014. Air-raid sirens continued to go off around Ukraine today. Still, the call yielded some positives for Ukraine, which will at least for now continue to receive U.S. assistance as it tries to work out backup plans with Europe in case Trump eventually cuts off Kyiv.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “Frankly, this is the Russian playbook of using negotiations as an instrument of armed conflict,” Polymeropoulos, the former intelligence officer, told me. “But in the grand scheme of things, it’s probably less bad than everyone imagined. At least the U.S. didn’t sell Ukraine down the river.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/putin-hitler-munich-parallel/681973/&quot;&gt;Read: Trump is offering Putin another Munich&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Few in the national-security community are counting on Trump to suddenly align himself more solidly with Kyiv. For weeks, he and his administration have embraced Moscow’s view of the war in Ukraine. Trump has decreed that Zelensky is “a dictator,” repeated Putin’s lie that Ukraine started the conflict, declared that Ukraine didn’t have any “cards” in the negotiations, and already denied Kyiv’s top wish—that it be allowed to enter NATO, the alliance designed as a bulwark against Russian aggression. The pause in U.S. intelligence-sharing and shipments of military supplies to Ukraine earlier this month allowed Moscow to make gains on the battlefield, most notably in the Russian territory of Kursk, land that had been Ukraine’s strongest bargaining chip in possible upcoming negotiations. And, of course, in Trump’s first term, the United States at times levied tough sanctions against Moscow, only to be undermined by the president’s warm words for Putin, including during their infamous 2018 Helsinki summit.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   So far, Trump hasn’t done anything to suggest that he’s cooling on Putin. When Zelensky didn’t give Trump everything he wanted in their Oval Office meeting last month, the U.S. president berated his Ukrainian counterpart, and Trump’s allies called for new elections in Kyiv. When Putin didn’t give Trump everything he wanted today, the Russian leader still got a friendly Truth Social post from Trump, pledges of further talks, and possibly &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/trump-putin-hockey-series-d720274e74a35882fcb5c1a99fa295d2&quot;&gt;some hockey games&lt;/a&gt; featuring the best players from each country.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But there were signs that Trump wasn’t happy with how Putin played his hand. Trump has rarely missed opportunities to chat with reporters during the first eight weeks of his presidency; just yesterday, he fielded questions multiple times, including when predicting that Putin wanted peace, and he often boastfully engages with the press while signing executive orders.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Another such signing was scheduled for the Oval Office this afternoon. But reporters were not invited to watch, depriving them of the chance to ask questions about the Putin call. Trump remained behind closed doors.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/putin-trump-ceasefire-proposal/682092/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/putin-trump-ceasefire-proposal/682092/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:30:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What John Roberts’s Rebuke of Trump Left Out</title><description>&lt;div&gt; In pushing back against Trump’s attack on a federal judge, the chief justice neglected to mention the substantive dispute of the case. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/Yye4r21uDB4j9HztAXAoLkELCwI=/0x0:4622x2600/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/GettyImages_2194932616/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chief Justice John Roberts frowns slightly while he wears his robes&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Chip Somodevilla / Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   &lt;p data-flatplan-paragraph=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is an edition of &lt;/i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;i&gt; Daily, a newsletter that guides you through the biggest stories of the day, helps you discover new ideas, and recommends the best in culture. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; data-gtm-vis-first-on-screen31117857_899=&quot;89&quot; data-gtm-vis-has-fired31117857_899=&quot;1&quot; data-gtm-vis-recent-on-screen31117857_899=&quot;89&quot; data-gtm-vis-total-visible-time31117857_899=&quot;100&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/atlantic-daily/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sign up for it here.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;   Yesterday, the Trump administration &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2025/03/donald-trump-el-salvador-brown-university-professor-judges/682080/&quot;&gt;battled&lt;/a&gt; against a federal judge using the instruments of the law. After James Boasberg demanded answers on why hundreds of Venezuelans had been rendered to El Salvador, in apparent defiance of an order he gave, Justice Department attorneys tried to get a hearing canceled, then &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.278436/gov.uscourts.dcd.278436.28.0_1.pdf&quot;&gt;refused&lt;/a&gt; to tell the judge much and suggested he be removed from the case.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   This morning, Donald Trump himself entered the fray, using the instruments of politics. “This Radical Left Lunatic of a Judge, a troublemaker and agitator who was sadly appointed by Barack Hussein Obama, was not elected President,” he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114183576937425149&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; on Truth Social. “This judge, like many of the Crooked Judges’ I am forced to appear before, should be IMPEACHED!!!”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   That was enough to provoke a reply from Chief Justice John Roberts, who seldom makes public comments. “For more than two centuries, it has been established that impeachment is not an appropriate response to disagreement concerning a judicial decision. The normal appellate review process exists for that purpose,” he said in a &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/18/politics/john-roberts-donald-trump-impeachment/index.html&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. For Roberts, that qualifies as a sharp response.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The chief justice is right. Trump’s attack on Boasberg is juvenile, civically illiterate, and perilous to the rule of law. (It was also just an echo of his sidekick Elon Musk’s recent &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thedailybeast.com/elon-musk-immediately-calls-for-judges-to-be-impeached-after-rulings-overturn-doge-firings/?via=twitter_page&quot;&gt;rants&lt;/a&gt; about courts.) But the statement is notable for what it leaves out: any acknowledgment of the substantive dispute in the case, which is whether Trump is defying court orders. Roberts seems more concerned about rhetorical attacks on the personal integrity or employment status of judges than he does with systemic attacks on the judiciary as a whole.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In his end-of-year &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/publicinfo/year-end/2024year-endreport.pdf&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; last year, Roberts wrote that “elected officials from across the political spectrum have raised the specter of open disregard for federal court rulings. These dangerous suggestions, however sporadic, must be soundly rejected.” These suggestions are no longer sporadic, and they are largely coming from one party, yet Roberts’s focus now is on the personal.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The odds of a successful impeachment of Boasberg right now are roughly nil, despite the &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/RepBrandonGill/status/1902028278849786279&quot;&gt;filing&lt;/a&gt; of articles of impeachment by a Republican House backbencher. But the administration does appear to have flouted Boasberg’s order—he’s now trying to determine the facts—following weeks of threats to defy judges. Another judge’s order in a deportation case was also &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/17/us/rasha-alawieh-brown-university-doctor-deported-hezbollah.html&quot;&gt;ignored&lt;/a&gt; this weekend, though the government claims that it hadn’t received official notice. Even if Trump hasn’t yet explicitly defied a court, he appears to be laying the groundwork to do so.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   This focus on personal as opposed to systemic attacks is something of a pattern for Roberts. In 2010, President Barack Obama criticized a Supreme Court ruling during his State of the Union, inducing Justice Samuel Alito to shake his head and mouth “Not true.” A few months later, Roberts called the moment “&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/j-roberts-state-of-the-union-troubling/&quot;&gt;very troubling&lt;/a&gt;”—less because of Obama’s criticism itself than because of the venue and the attendance of several justices.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In 2018, Roberts &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/supreme-court/chief-justice-pushes-back-calls-impeach-judges-rule-trump-rcna196922&quot;&gt;rebuked&lt;/a&gt; Trump for calling a different judge who’d ruled against him an “Obama judge.” In a statement just before Thanksgiving, Roberts said, “We do not have Obama judges or Trump judges, Bush judges or Clinton judges. What we have is an extraordinary group of dedicated judges doing their level best to do equal right to those appearing before them. That independent judiciary is something we should all be thankful for.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The corrective drew a chastened response from Tru—nah, just kidding. “Sorry Chief Justice John Roberts, but you do indeed have ‘Obama judges,’ and they have a much different point of view than the people who are charged with the safety of our country,” he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1065346909362143232?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1065346909362143232%7Ctwgr%5E0a40db811c777de3389ab5f85c28183d1823a3e5%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nbcnews.com%2Fpolitics%2Fsupreme-court%2Frare-rebuke-chief-justice-roberts-slams-trump-comment-about-obama-n939016&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter. And if that’s the way Trump responded in his first term, we can guess how he might reply now, given the lack of relative restraint he has shown more broadly.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The personal differences between Roberts, a quiet and intellectual lawyer of serious ideological commitment, and Trump, a noisy and brash politician more interested in personality than policy, are great. On their views of presidential power, the men are less far apart. Last summer, Roberts wrote a decision for the court that conferred great immunity on Trump’s actions as president. My colleague Adam Serwer &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/congressional-address-supreme-court/681926/&quot;&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt; this connection recently, after Trump approached Roberts following the president’s speech to a joint session of Congress and said, “Thank you again. Thank you again. I won’t forget.” (Trump later said he was expressing gratitude for Roberts swearing him in.) He is unlikely to remember today’s admonition as fondly.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Roberts admittedly has no good options. Perhaps he doesn’t want to weigh in on Trump’s apparent willingness to defy courts because he expects these matters to reach the Supreme Court and doesn’t want to appear to be an interested party. Or perhaps Roberts is less bothered because he believes that the president will prevail on these matters at the Supreme Court. Trump is effective at destroying norms because he forces institutions and individuals to either succumb to his partisan logic or else avoid the fight and thus cede the debate to him.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   During his confirmation hearings to be chief justice, Roberts famously likened judges to umpires, calling balls and strikes. But his statement today is akin to responding to the &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://sabr.org/journal/article/the-black-sox-scandal/&quot;&gt;Black Sox scandal&lt;/a&gt; by defending the officiating. The players here aren’t arguing about the strike zone; they’re trying to rig the game.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2025/03/trump-justice-roberts-impeachment-judge/682087/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2025/03/trump-justice-roberts-impeachment-judge/682087/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Forever 21’s Brief, Hideous Life</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Farewell to a beloved purveyor of trash. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/w0gRFCbW3LL-OsBiMjl0kcCUtwU=/0x0:2000x1125/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_18_forever21/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graphic illustration of the Forever 21 logo with red tape placed over the word &amp;quot;Forever.&amp;quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by The Atlantic&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   Forever 21 opened in my hometown when I was in middle school, when the opening of a new store at the mall was still a big deal. When the sign first went up, nobody knew what “Forever 21” was. I remember thinking that it would be a store marketed to retirement-age women who felt young at heart—Forever 21! This was wrong, but not so far off: Do Won Chang, one of its founders, has said he chose the name because 21 is “the most enviable age.” And it is, especially if you are 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, or 20, which are the ages at which I bought most of my clothes there. I can still smell the polyester and hear the White Rabbits on the sound system.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The clothes were, in theory, inexpensive versions of the latest trends. In practice, they were usually inexpensive versions of recently passed trends, and sometimes they were items so odd that they seemed to have been imported from a different reality (&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/mjs538/times-forever-21-failed-so-hard-its-actually-perfect&quot;&gt;crop top with suspenders&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eater.com/2019/6/6/18655256/forever-21-cheetos-clothing-line-bathing-suits-flip-flops&quot;&gt;Cheetos bathing suit&lt;/a&gt;). But for a suburban teenager with a little bit of cash, the store still felt like a place of possibilities. Yes, Forever 21 was always a disaster: Its racks and racks of cheap merchandise were “arranged” according to surrealist organizing principles that were impossible for the amateur to comprehend, and much of what was for sale was hideous. But I did not have taste—what I had was an after-school job in the mall food court that paid $7.25 an hour. I received paychecks every other week of about $150 that I could “save for college,” or that I could spend on statement necklaces and bubble skirts.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2024/04/americans-peak-stuff-shopping-temu-shein/678224/&quot;&gt;Read: Will Americans ever get sick of cheap junk?&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I think of that store fondly, and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.democratandchronicle.com/story/news/2025/03/03/forever-21-store-closing-at-eastview-mall-in-victor-ny/81184742007/&quot;&gt;now it is closing&lt;/a&gt;. All of the Forever 21 stores remaining in the U.S. are expected to close as well. The company filed for bankruptcy this week—not for the first time, although this one is truly the end. “We have been unable to find a sustainable path forward, given competition from foreign fast fashion companies,” Brad Sell, the company’s CFO, said in a &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250316125020/en/F21-OpCo-LLC-Initiates-Voluntary-Chapter-11-Process-With-Support-of-Its-Lenders&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. He also mentioned “rising costs, economic challenges impacting our core customers, and evolving consumer trends.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Forever 21 grew &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/23/business/forever-21-bankruptcy-chang-family.html&quot;&gt;rapidly&lt;/a&gt; in the 2010s, opening hundreds of stores—many of them in enormous spaces—and reporting billions in annual sales. For a solid decade, Forever 21 was a common feature of the American landscape. At that time, finding a Forever 21 seemed as easy as finding a library. The highlighter-yellow shopping bags were an indelible symbol of the accessibly cool Millennial lifestyle. Some Forever 21 locations even became true destinations. For myself and many of my classmates, the four-story Forever 21 in Times Square was the most exciting part of our senior-class trip to New York City—not joking!  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Now the 20- and 30-somethings who learned to shop by wading through their local Forever 21 locations are &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/AshleyDeLarge/status/1901632148567720165&quot;&gt;mourning the brand&lt;/a&gt; and marking the “&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/search?q=forever%2021%20%22end%20of%20an%20era%22&amp;amp;src=typed_query&amp;amp;f=top&quot;&gt;end of an era&lt;/a&gt;.” You can find many “RIP” comment threads right now in regional Reddit forums, where people often discuss their local malls. Most are lighthearted (&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/deadmalls/comments/1j4cxwn/sad_to_hear_that_forever_21s_closing_at_the/&quot;&gt;“I guess they turned 22”&lt;/a&gt;). Nobody is in a state of shock, because there is obviously not a place in the culture anymore for something like Forever 21.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Today’s young people still like in-person shopping, but they like to do it in &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.voguebusiness.com/sustainability/gen-z-will-drive-explosive-growth-in-secondhand-sales-says-thredup&quot;&gt;secondhand and thrift shops&lt;/a&gt; or, at the other end of the spectrum, in &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.retaildive.com/news/gen-z-in-person-shopping-beauty-luxury-adyen/738198/&quot;&gt;gorgeous stores&lt;/a&gt; that make shopping feel like an Instagrammable excursion. They still like fast fashion too, but they like it faster than Forever 21 does it—online-only brands such as Shein, Fashion Nova, and ASOS can turn out hundreds or even thousands of new styles every week and sell them at unbelievably low prices.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2024/09/shein-ceo-chris-xu-fast-fashion/679709/&quot;&gt;Read: The mysterious, meteoric rise of Shein&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In the past several years, cultural awareness has grown about the reality of the &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/2/3/21080364/fast-fashion-h-and-m-zara&quot;&gt;fast-fashion business model&lt;/a&gt;, which relies on paying factory workers shockingly low wages and takes a &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2021/03/ultra-fast-fashion-is-eating-the-world/617794/&quot;&gt;multifaceted approach&lt;/a&gt; to furthering the ruination of the planet. (Barely used clothes pile up in landfills; synthetic fabrics shed microplastics &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/07/03/book-reviews-plastic-waste&quot;&gt;into the water supply&lt;/a&gt;; the manufacturing of polyester drives greenhouse-gas emissions up and up.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Today, young people shop fast fashion &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2021/7/19/22535050/gen-z-relationship-fast-fashion&quot;&gt;in spite of themselves&lt;/a&gt;. They know it’s bad, but they’re accustomed to convenience and limitless choice, so they do it anyway. Maybe the difference is that now they can buy it from their phone, which is less uncomfortable than looking at it all piled up around them in one physical place. When Forever 21 declared bankruptcy for the first time, six years ago, a retail consultant suggested something like this to &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/29/business/forever-21-bankruptcy.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “The emotional and physical aesthetic of it is not something that the current shopper wants as much,” WSL Strategic Retail’s Wendy Liebmann told the paper. You can’t go home again, and it can’t be 2010 again.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   As an adult, I now realize that the items I impulse-bought at Forever 21 on my 15-minute breaks were (1) contributing to human misery and (2) not worth even the paltry sums I paid for them. I almost never got substantial use out of anything, either because the items were poorly made and fell apart or because I quickly realized that they were ugly and unflattering. The only purchase I remember clearly is a dress I picked out to wear as a bridesmaid in a high-school friend’s wedding, for which I paid $12. I thought it was genuinely chic; I couldn’t believe my luck, and I was impressed with myself for pulling a needle from a galaxy-size hayfield.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But I wore it only once, and I suppose it is in a landfill now. There, it will last a long, long time. Not forever, but much longer than Forever 21 did.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2025/03/forever-21-bankruptcy/682084/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2025/03/forever-21-bankruptcy/682084/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 17:51:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Gaza Cease-Fire Was Always Going to End</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Neither Israel nor Hamas is willing to tolerate the other’s existence. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/yYgSLw1jxA4sd0bwcwvq5lgVw1g=/0x0:2700x1519/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_13_The_Ceasefire_Was_Always_Going_to_End_AZ/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A rubble-filled area of Gaza is seen from inside a bombed building, with people walking around inspecting the rubble.&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Ahmad Salem / Bloomberg / Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   When Israel and Hamas finally agreed to a cease-fire in January, many outside observers &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/ggreenwald/status/1879270818741649656&quot;&gt;credited&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/ryangrim/status/1879303862588477902&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/17/trumps-role-in-gaza-ceasefire-fuels-arab-american-anger-with-biden&quot;&gt;agreement&lt;/a&gt; to Donald Trump’s commitment to peace. Unlike Joe Biden, the story went, America’s new president was willing to put the screws to Israel to compel quiet in Gaza and would keep the deal on track.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   These claims completely misread the map. Trump was less interested in ending the war than in being able to say he’d gotten some hostages out by the time he was inaugurated. Hamas was willing to release those hostages in exchange for hundreds of Palestinian prisoners, but it was never going to agree to permanently lay down its arms. Israel, for its part, sought to extract as many of its people from Gaza as possible and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/01/israel-hamas-gaza-ceasefire-biden-trump/681325/&quot;&gt;wanted&lt;/a&gt; to stay on Trump’s good side so that he might grant them sweeping policy wins later on.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Two months in, this confluence of interests has come apart, and so has the cease-fire. The deal had been on life support for weeks, with no hostages coming out of Gaza and no humanitarian aid going in. No longer willing to grant Hamas a reprieve without receiving anything in return, Israel launched extensive air strikes across the Strip last night, reportedly killing hundreds, including civilians and top Hamas officials. The Trump administration supported the move—the National Security Council spokesperson Brian Hughes &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/18/israel-gaza-war-resumes-airstrikes-hamas&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; reporters that “Hamas could have released hostages to extend the cease-fire but instead chose refusal and war.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   More war is not what the people of Gaza or Israel want. But Gazans have no ability to control or restrain Hamas, and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/netanyahu-poll-numbers/682008/&quot;&gt;not responsive&lt;/a&gt; to the preferences of the Israeli public. Polls have &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://en.idi.org.il/articles/58114&quot;&gt;consistently&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/poll-70-of-israelis-support-second-phase-of-hostage-ceasefire-deal/&quot;&gt;shown&lt;/a&gt; that the majority of Israelis support continuing the cease-fire deal, even if it means releasing some of the worst convicted terrorists in Israeli prisons and ending the war without eradicating Hamas. “The military pressure endangers the hostages while an agreement brings them home,” &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/freed-hostages-warn-renewed-gaza-fighting-risks-lives-of-remaining-hamas-captives/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; Yarden Bibas, a freed hostage whose wife and two children were &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/02/hamass-theater-of-the-macabre/681826/&quot;&gt;murdered&lt;/a&gt; by Hamas. His sentiments were &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/former-hostage-wife-of-current-captive-post-broken-heart-emojis-as-ceasefire-collapses/&quot;&gt;echoed&lt;/a&gt; by other former hostages, who vowed to keep fighting to bring all their fellow hostages home.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/01/israel-hamas-gaza-ceasefire-biden-trump/681325/&quot;&gt;Read: Trump made the Gaza cease-fire happen&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But Netanyahu is not listening to these voices. His coalition relies on the Israeli minority that &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/hostages-families-are-heard-too-much-smotrich-says-during-clash-with-relatives-in-knesset/&quot;&gt;prioritizes&lt;/a&gt; destroying Hamas over returning the hostages, and its far-right members &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/12/israel-right-wing-settler-gaza-netanyahu/676943/&quot;&gt;hope&lt;/a&gt; to seed Gaza with Israeli settlements. Absent any real pressure from Trump, Netanyahu was always going to follow his base. And far from reining Israel in, Trump has &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/02/trump-gaza-takeover/681576/&quot;&gt;floated&lt;/a&gt; relocating Gaza’s population, abolished Biden’s &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2024/03/israel-sanctions-settlers-biden-netanyahu/677647/&quot;&gt;sanctions regime&lt;/a&gt; targeting violent Israeli settlers, and sanctioned the International Criminal Court over its prosecution of Israel. Likewise, Hamas’s patrons in Qatar have been seemingly unwilling or unable to get it to adopt a more conciliatory position.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But setting aside the interests and intentions of Hamas, Netanyahu, and Trump, the Gaza cease-fire was never going to hold for a more fundamental reason: Neither side is willing to tolerate the other’s continued existence. Hamas is sworn to Israel’s destruction. For decades, the terrorist group has &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/10/what-hamas-wants-israel/675648/&quot;&gt;plundered&lt;/a&gt; Gaza and sacrificed its people in pursuit of an unending messianic war to eliminate the Jewish state. Before October 7, Israelis dismissed this aspiration as unrealistic and believed that they were safe behind their high-tech border fence. After October 7, they no longer do.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   For Hamas, the conflict will not end until Israel is gone. For Israel, the conflict cannot end until Hamas is gone. Which means that though a new temporary cease-fire might still be struck in the coming days or weeks, the war will go on.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/gaza-cease-fire-palestine-israel/682083/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2025/03/gaza-cease-fire-palestine-israel/682083/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 17:25:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dear James: I Miss Being on Dating Apps</title><description>&lt;div&gt; I’ve hit the relationship jackpot. But now I have romance FOMO. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/IG7MMD0h4jitxL1kB8Bg3TEh-r0=/0x0:1920x1080/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/final_dear_james_26_miguel_porlan/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A woman and a man, the man&#39;s head replaced by the Tinder logo&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Miguel Porlan&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Is anything ailing, torturing, or nagging at you? Are you beset by existential worries? Every Tuesday, James Parker tackles readers’ questions. Tell him about your lifelong or in-the-moment problems at &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:dearjames@theatlantic.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;dearjames@theatlantic.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;em&gt;Don’t want to miss a single column? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/dear-james/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sign up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to get “Dear James” in your inbox.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Dear James,&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I’m a man in a relationship with a woman I met on Hinge a little over a year ago (we’re both in our early 30s), and things have been absolutely great. I love her, my friends and family all love her, we’re planning to move in together later this year, and ideally this all ends in “happily ever after” with marriage and a kid or two. By all accounts, I’ve won the game of ring toss that is online dating. And yet, part of me misses playing the game.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Throw a rock online and you’ll hit some article about everyone being &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2024/04/dating-apps-are-starting-crack/678022/&quot;&gt;fed up&lt;/a&gt; with and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/family/archive/2024/08/single-quitting-dating-relationships/679460/&quot;&gt;burned-out&lt;/a&gt; by dating apps. But I feel bittersweet about the fact that my days on the apps are, presumably, over. I saw every match and first date I went on as a symbol of hope and possibility. Of course, I experienced disappointments, and yeah, I was ghosted lots of times, but I had plenty of good times too. Through dating apps, I met brilliant, hilarious, beautiful, and incredibly kind women with whom I enjoyed stimulating conversations and intimate moments of multiple varieties, and I’m a little melancholic at the thought that I won’t experience any of that again.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Are these normal things to think at this point in a serious relationship? I’m a bit of an anxious person, and this discomfort definitely seems like something an anxious person would feel in the face of an impending major life event. But is there a point where this nostalgia for the apps stops being something I’ll get over and becomes something I need to address?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Dear Reader,&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Sex, sex, sex. Here’s what I think about that:  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Two important things about sex&lt;br&gt; must be clearly and constantly stated.&lt;br&gt; One: It’s the greatest thing in the world.&lt;br&gt; Two: It’s quite overrated.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Under current conditions, the laws of time and space, etc., choosing a partner means un-choosing all the other partners. It’s not a brilliant system, but it’s what we have. Either you whirl around incontinently, “intimate moments of multiple varieties” a-go-go, or you pledge your genitals to one person and settle down to await … whatever happens next.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Eros, the uncontrollable spirit, the force that through the green fuse drives the flower, is mounting a bit of an assault on your imagination right now. This is completely normal. It’s not going to stop, either. Eros hates domesticity; Eros hates a sensible choice. Eros even hates the right choice—which is twisted, but there we are.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Don’t worry about the “happily ever after” just yet. One thing at a time. (Also, “happily ever after” doesn’t exist.) Move in together; see how that feels. Treat your dreaming libido as an itch rather than an imperative: You don’t have to act on or indulge its every flutter. Unmet needs are like pull-ups for the spirit. Your nostalgia for Hinge is not a problem, in my view, until you go back on Hinge. At that point, it’ll be time for a rethink.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   On your team,  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   James  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Dear James,&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   More than 20 years ago, when I went through a long-distance breakup while abroad, I didn’t care about getting back any of my things. Yet my ex-boyfriend spent a lot of time and money packaging and shipping everything to my relatives’ American address.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   For a long time afterward, I remained too hurt, bitter, and poorer than him to even want to think about it. But now, all these years later, I feel like I should have contributed to the cost and should at least make the offer. I’m not sure why. Maybe the thought has crossed my mind because his children are probably going to start college soon, and the money, I figure, might be helpful to him. Or maybe it’s because the causes we once both believed in seem doomed today—they could possibly use some money, and he might donate what I send him.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I mentioned the thought to my husband, who thinks it would look strange to make an overdue offer so many years later—especially because I didn’t really stay in touch, except for a couple of emails or letters in the years immediately following the breakup.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   What do you think?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;strong&gt;Dear Reader,&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I think this is a good idea. I agree with your husband: It will look strange. But so what? “Better late than never” is one of my go-to proverbs. (And I’m always late, so I go to it a lot.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Perhaps even more important than the money here is the belated acknowledgment of the effort your ex put into taking care of your stuff in the aftermath of your breakup. Whatever else went down—the rights and wrongs, the who-said-what, the foaming water under the bridge—in that respect, he looked after you. With even a certain dogged gallantry. You know all of this, of course, so go ahead and make it right: Rebalance this situation, for yourself as much as for him.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Blowing kisses to my debtors,  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   James  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;hr align=&quot;center&quot; size=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;   &lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;By submitting a letter, you are agreeing to let &lt;/em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;em&gt; use it in part or in full, and we may edit it for length and/or clarity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/dear-james-dating-app-fomo/682071/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2025/03/dear-james-dating-app-fomo/682071/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>They’re Cheering for Trump in Moscow—Again</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Russia, among other autocratic states, is surely thrilled by the president’s decision to close Voice of America, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Radio Martí, and Radio Free Asia. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/7DPVHHEod3ARNlr5JT-6MPd-buc=/0x0:2000x1125/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/RadioFreeEurope/original.png&quot; alt=&quot;A radio mic with an RIP sign attached to it&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by The Atlantic. Source: Getty.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   “This is an awesome decision by Trump.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   What did Donald Trump just do, and who is this happy about it? Is this a Republican politician supporting the president’s plans for a tax cut, or perhaps a MAGA cheerleader applauding deportations? Perhaps it’s some right-wing pundit foot-stomping his approval for an executive order about &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/keeping-men-out-of-womens-sports/&quot;&gt;trans athletes&lt;/a&gt;?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   No. The “awesome decision” was to shut down the U.S. Agency for Global Media (USAGM), the umbrella organization that provides support not only to Voice of America but also to Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Radio Martí, and Radio Free Asia, among other groups. And the clapping is coming not from Washington, but from Moscow. The pleased Trump fan is &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn0lnw1z6yzo&quot;&gt;Margarita Simonyan&lt;/a&gt;, the head of RT and the media group that owns Russian-propaganda outlets such as Sputnik, and one of Russia’s most venomously anti-Western television commentators. (She once &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/kremlin-propagandist-faced-backlash-siberia-nuclear-bomb-comments-2023-10&quot;&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that Russia should detonate a nuclear weapon over its own territory as a warning to the West about supporting Ukraine.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Here’s her &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2vdsAxZ64H0&amp;amp;list=PLLWQyEN3YRo41QwWb7e8J5YjBX80WmGtG&quot;&gt;full comment&lt;/a&gt; (made on Russian television on Sunday night) regarding Trump’s order: “Today is a celebration for my colleagues at RT, Sputnik, and other outlets, because Trump unexpectedly announced that he’s closing down Radio Liberty and Voice of America, and now they’re closed. This is an awesome decision by Trump.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Organizations such as the Voice of America and “the radios,” as they have been called collectively over the years, are among America’s best instruments of soft power. (VOA was created to counter Nazi propaganda during World War II.) During the Cold War, people behind the Iron Curtain relied on these institutions, and especially on RFE/RL, not because they wanted to hear an American point of view—they already knew all about that—but because they wanted &lt;em&gt;news&lt;/em&gt;, real information that they could trust.&amp;nbsp; These are not independent news organizations: They receive support from the U.S. government and other sources. But the journalists at VOA and the radios are not mouthpieces for any government. They are professionals who report and broadcast news and interviews in multiple languages around the world—much to the ire of authoritarian states that wish to control what their citizens read and hear.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Turning off these sources was not some slapdash DOGE move. Trump personally signed an executive order on Friday, shutting down what a White House &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/the-voice-of-radical-america/&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; absurdly called “the Voice of Radical America.” And if the order stands—USAGM is chartered by Congress as an independent agency, and Trump likely does not have the authority to close it down by fiat—he will have succeeded in gutting crucial sources of information relied on by millions of people living under repressive governments. As Max Boot &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://wapo.st/4izIIpf&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; on Sunday, “All of this amounts to a stunning and self-defeating repudiation of America’s legacy as a beacon of freedom around the world.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/elon-musk-trump-usaid/681607/&quot;&gt;Read: Paranoia is winning&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump has long had a grudge against Voice of America in particular; he has &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/news/2025/03/15/trump-media-voice-of-america-00003119&quot;&gt;accused&lt;/a&gt; VOA of skewing its coverage to the left, and of supporting President Joe Biden in the 2024 campaign. He also recently &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/atrupar/status/1899874114841485747&quot;&gt;bristled&lt;/a&gt; at what he thought was an impertinent question from a VOA reporter regarding Gaza. (“Who are you with?” the president asked the reporter. When she answered that she was from VOA, Trump said, “Oh, no wonder.”)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But this is more than just a spat with VOA. By killing off USAGM and the organizations that depend on it, Trump is pulling a thorn from the paws of the world’s worst regimes, the people he seems to believe are his natural political allies and co-religionists. (The news about VOA and Radio Free Asia was happily received in &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/17/china/china-cheers-trump-cut-voice-of-america-intl-hnk/index.html&quot;&gt;Beijing&lt;/a&gt;, for example, where a state-run media outlet cheered the end of America’s “lie factory” and its “demonizing narratives” about China.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   RFE/RL also monitors the press and events in other nations, and provides in-depth analysis of events there that mainstream Western media do not have the time or space to explore. I know this because I wrote some of these reports as a guest analyst for Radio Liberty’s research arm back in the 1980s, during the Cold War. (My first article for RL was a discussion of developments in Soviet civil-military relations.) Throughout my career as a Soviet and Russian expert, I counted on RFE/RL for information from Eurasia. I knew that its reporters overseas faced significant risks from the governments they covered and hostility from autocracies—as well as various terrorist groups—that wanted to silence them. Before the Soviet Union’s downfall, RFE/RL was based in Munich; later, it moved to a campus in the Czech Republic with security rivaling that of a military base.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump, who &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/17/business/trump-calls-the-news-media-the-enemy-of-the-people.html&quot;&gt;regards&lt;/a&gt; any media he cannot control as a political enemy, is anxious to shut down these vessels of news and information. Once closed, they will no longer annoy him, and he will get a pat on the back from people such as Simonyan. But the new director of national intelligence, Tulsi Gabbard, seems eager to see it all burn as well. Indeed, she’s so enthused that yesterday, she &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/stillgray/status/1900989166856659204&quot;&gt;shared an X post&lt;/a&gt; from Ian Miles Cheong, a Malaysia-based right-wing podcaster and journalist manqué. (He has written for RT and is still &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.rt.com/op-ed/authors/ian-miles-cheong/&quot;&gt;listed&lt;/a&gt; on its website.) His post claimed that these organizations “produced and disseminated far-left propaganda” and “perpetuated a pro-war narratives against Russia.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   It’s one thing for the DNI to say that she supports the president’s decision; it’s another to see her reposting material from an online provocateur who came to prominence fighting on Reddit over &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-is-ian-miles-cheong-meet-twitters-favourite-right-wing-commentator/articleshow/111606114.cms&quot;&gt;“Gamergate”&lt;/a&gt; a decade ago. (I contacted the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to ask if Gabbard agrees with Cheong and believes he is a reliable source of information. ODNI has not responded.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   No one should really be surprised that Gabbard is amplifying such nonsense. As I &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2024/11/tulsi-gabbard-nomination-security/680649/&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; last November, her views are so pro-Russian that allowing her to serve as DNI constitutes a national-security threat. But you don’t have to take my word for it: The journalist &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/12476/9783838219097&quot;&gt;Julia Davis&lt;/a&gt;, who monitors Russian media, has kept track of the affection with which Gabbard is regarded in Russia. In December, the Russian state-television host Evgeny Popov surveyed Trump’s prospective Cabinet nominees and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/JuliaDavisNews/status/1885108342927827302&quot;&gt;declared&lt;/a&gt; that none of them were “friends of Russia, except for Tulsi Gabbard.” And Vladimir Solovyov, a talk-show host whose rants are depraved even by the low standards of Russian television, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/JuliaDavisNews/status/1509330152735584262&quot;&gt;referred&lt;/a&gt; to Gabbard as “our girlfriend Tulsi.” (“Is she some sort of a Russian agent?” another guest asked. “Yes,” Solovyov snapped.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Now, some of this gloating in the Russian media is likely just an attempt to pull on American pigtails. The Russians are very good at this game, and they know that referring to the DNI as Russia’s “girlfriend” will throw some Americans into a swivet. But if Gabbard isn’t a Vladimir Putin supporter, she’s doing a good imitation of one: Any sensible American politician would dread a public association with Cheong—today he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/stillgray/status/1901898346391896493&quot;&gt;referred&lt;/a&gt; to Russia’s horrendous 2022 &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/22/video/russia-ukraine-bucha-massacre-takeaways.html&quot;&gt;massacre&lt;/a&gt; of civilians in the town of Bucha as a “hoax”—but Gabbard thought highly enough of his comments to send them out under her official X account.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The courts may yet stop Trump’s assault on USAGM, although if the agency survives, it will be headed by &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2024/12/12/nx-s1-5226920/voice-of-america-kari-lake-voa&quot;&gt;Kari Lake&lt;/a&gt;, who has her own irresponsible plans for VOA. (If there is one &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.azcentral.com/story/opinion/op-ed/laurieroberts/2025/03/17/trump-kari-lake-voice-of-america-fake-news/82494662007/&quot;&gt;bright spot&lt;/a&gt; in all of this, it is that Trump’s executive order may have put Lake out of a job.) But regardless of the eventual legal outcome, the president is proudly showing America and the alliance of democracies it once led that he is on the side of the world’s dictators. The Kremlin and other autocracies have long ached to see Voice of America and Radio Liberty destroyed, but even in their most fevered dreams, they could never have imagined that the Americans would do the dirty work themselves.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/closing-usagm-helps-dictators/682081/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/closing-usagm-helps-dictators/682081/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 15:57:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Life of the Mind Can Only Get You So Far</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Michelle de Kretser’s intellectual coming-of-age explores the fissures between one’s ideals and reality. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/_g76-iqY9LFznHKkldiqpfDFqD4=/0x0:2160x2700/648x810/media/img/2025/03/17/Vanessa_Woods_Final_3_18_25_Sized/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A flower breaking out of a cube featuring a torn image of Virginia Woolf&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Vanessa Woods&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   Every young feminist, at some point, bumps up against the limits of her ideals. For me, it happened in my early 20s. My consciousness freshly raised and my mind spongier than ever, I spent my evenings imbibing the no-nonsense feminism of Vivian Gornick, the big-hearted feminism of &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2021/12/bell-hooks-kentucky-tribute/621124/&quot;&gt;bell hooks&lt;/a&gt;, the caustic feminism of &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2024/09/virginie-despentes-dear-dickhead/679984/&quot;&gt;Virginie Despentes&lt;/a&gt;. On the page, I underlined their wisdom about forging romances rooted in equality and embracing solidarity with other women; yet in life, I chased the approval of apathetic men and harbored resentment for my beautiful, successful peers. I had done all the reading but felt that I was failing the test.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The narrator of Michelle de Kretser’s sharp-witted novel &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/12476/9781646222872&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theory &amp;amp; Practice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Sri Lankan–born grad student at a university in Melbourne, has a similar, self-flagellating feeling early in the book. She has discovered that her boyfriend is cheating on her, and, to her horror, she wants the other woman—“a smart, good-looking, outspoken feminist”—dead. “I’d raged silently, inwardly,” she recalls, “censored by an internal critic who found jealousy a trite, despicable emotion, a morbid symptom that ran counter to feminist practice.” She is immediately ashamed of her reaction. Yet maybe her lapses and mine were not moral failings but case studies in what de Kretser (who, like her narrator, is Australian and was born in Sri Lanka) calls the inevitable “breakdowns between theory and practice.” Feminism is a set of political principles, not social prescriptions. &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2022/08/bad-sex-nona-willis-aronowitz-book-review/671123/&quot;&gt;Ideology rarely maps neatly&lt;/a&gt; onto everyday existence—and it’s in these gaps that we learn the most about who we are, what we believe, and what we really want.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2022/08/bad-sex-nona-willis-aronowitz-book-review/671123/&quot;&gt;Read: How should feminists have sex now?&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The novel begins in 1986, when the narrator has just moved from Sydney to Melbourne to write a thesis about gender roles in the late novels of her hero, Virginia Woolf. Invigorated by the promise of a life of the mind, she buys a dress in a color she describes as “Intellectual Black.” She gets an apartment in a vibrant bohemian enclave bursting with scholars and artists that sits a few steps from the beach. The nearby ocean becomes a model for the kind of knowledge she seeks: something to “carry me beyond the limits of myself,” even at “the risk of drowning.” But in truth, there is no escaping oneself—no city, no dress, no course of study with the power to liberate a person from who they really are.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Not long after breaking up with her boyfriend, the narrator starts sleeping with Kit, a wealthy engineering student with an equally wealthy girlfriend, Olivia. Their trysts are aboveboard, Kit says, because he and Olivia have “a deconstructed relationship.” The narrator convinces herself that she’s fine with this. She’s a “modern woman,” she thinks, “perfectly content with his body’s undeconstructed need of mine.” But that idealized self buckles under erotic strain, and the narrator soon grows obsessed with Olivia: She fantasizes about breaking into her apartment and leaves marks on Kit’s body before she sends him back to her. In a nod to the epistemic value of their dalliance, Kit and the narrator refer to sex as “studying.” Since her thesis involves thinking critically about gender roles, what better way to study than to participate in a three-sided heterosexual power struggle?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   As the narrator discovers, neither our politics nor our principles preclude—or protect us from—unwieldy emotions, embarrassing impulses, or subconscious desires. What’s more, the love triangle forces her to tussle with questions of not only gender but also class. A brown-skinned, first-generation immigrant, she’s opposed to Kit and Olivia’s inborn privilege and the socioeconomic stratification that enforces it; she also wants what they have. “I wanted to join the bourgeoisie,” she says, “and I wanted to destroy it.” The two truths coexist, however uneasily, rather than canceling each other out.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The narrator’s research into Woolf, whose picture she tapes above her desk, reveals another fissure between her ideals—namely, the writer she looks up to—and reality. Woolf looms large in her imagination not only as a pathbreaking feminist writer but also as a fellow survivor of childhood sexual abuse. Reading Woolf’s diary, the narrator is moved by her description of the inner turmoil that lingers after an experience of harm. “What is the word for so dumb and mixed a feeling?” Woolf writes. The narrator recognizes the sentiment: “Dumb, mixed feelings,” she muses, “are knowledge that lives outside language and outside time.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But the narrator faces mixed feelings of a different kind when she reads another diary entry, in which Woolf cruelly describes the Sri Lankan national hero E. W. Perera as a “poor little mahogany coloured wretch.” It feels like a painful, personal blow. How to account for this wrinkle in her image of the beloved author? Again, by holding two truths simultaneously. The “Woolfmother,” as the narrator calls her, is both an intellectual giant and a blatant racist. A friend suggests that instead of abandoning her study of Woolf, the narrator enter into a conversation with her blighted hero. The friend’s prescription: “Write back to Woolf.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The narrator’s white adviser, Paula, dismisses the idea of shifting her thesis to account for Woolf’s racism; she suggests that the narrator focus on Woolf’s public work rather than her private thoughts. But the narrator feels she must “reckon with [the] mahogany-colored wretch” who has “taken up squatting on a corner of my desk.” She notices that both she and Paula have the same poster of Woolf, but Paula’s, notably, is “framed and under glass.” Where Paula wants to keep her idol’s legacy pristine, the narrator wants to wrestle with Woolf—even if it leaves a mark.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Paula, whom de Kretser refers to as the English Department’s “Designated Feminist,” has a rather low tolerance for complexity: At one point, the narrator learns that she once wrote a scathing pan of a woman’s debut novel, tarring the book as “unfeminist” because its female protagonist despairs over the end of her affair with a man. As it turns out, Paula’s boyfriend had left her for this novelist not long before. When it comes to feminism—and to life itself—the narrator prefers to mine the “messy, human truth” that she sees in her adviser’s book review rather than worship a passed-down pantheon of “flawless feminist heroes.” She wants to make sense of&amp;nbsp; the gradations and complications of “female experience”—that is, to go beyond theory and account for practice. Indeed, over the course of the novel, most of her learning happens outside the classroom, through encounters and conversations with other people. As fascinating and edifying as theory can be, it can rarely teach us as much about ourselves as everyday life.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2022/08/the-wall-marlen-haushofer-book/671071/&quot;&gt;Read: Escaping the patriarchy for good&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;em&gt;Theory &amp;amp; Practice&lt;/em&gt; is sly, spiky, and brilliant: an intellectual coming-of-age story that accounts for all that can’t be learned in the academy—or in books. The novel’s meta structure bears this out: The first few pages belong to what appears to be an entirely different book, ostensibly written and abruptly scrapped by the narrator. The writing has “stalled” because, she says, “I was discovering that I no longer wanted to write novels that read like novels,” which she finds deceptive in their tidiness. With this observation, the line between author and narrator blurs: Aspects of the book are clearly lifted from de Kretser’s own life—the novel’s Australian cover even bears a picture of a college-aged de Kretser—yet it warns against drawing any neat conclusions. The story that follows flits confidently between modes: memoir and novel, personal and political, fact and fiction. Essayistic asides commingle with tender memories; heady emotions intrude on serious philosophizing. The aim, the narrator says, is to capture a sense of “formlessness and mess”—in other words, real life.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   De Kretser’s attraction to chaos and contradiction made sense to me; I myself have struggled to make my disparate thoughts and desires cohere. It was only when I began reading about the formless, messy lives of various feminists in biographies and memoirs—rather than, say, their works of polemic or philosophy—that I no longer felt like a failure. Their mistakes, their resentments, and their embarrassing, often unenlightened feelings were so much like my own. I realized that this painful gap between who one is and who one wishes to be is universal—and no amount of knowledge can assuage it. The narrator feels something similar the first time she sees her own “everyday, unglamorous world” reflected back to her in a film about a young feminist who rages against her ex-boyfriend and his new lover. “What made my heart run like a hare,” she says, “was hearing my mind exposed.” And it’s only through this kind of exposure—of our personal lapses, of the unfairness of love, of the faults of our heroes—that we can get anywhere near the truth.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2025/03/theory-practice-michelle-de-kretser-novel-review/682072/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2025/03/theory-practice-michelle-de-kretser-novel-review/682072/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Trump-Tariff Advice: Eat Less</title><description>&lt;div&gt; The policy’s real message is “Tax my voters; enrich my donors.” &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/qBZoGIVj7cQzGEbzubcyz1pTqe0=/0x0:3000x1688/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/Taft_Final/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of Robert Taft next to a photo of an empty plate flanked by fork and knife&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo-illustration by The Atlantic. Source: Getty.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   &lt;p data-flatplan-paragraph=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;i data-stringify-type=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;This article was featured in the One Story to Read Today newsletter. &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; data-gtm-vis-first-on-screen31117857_899=&quot;984608&quot; data-gtm-vis-has-fired31117857_899=&quot;1&quot; data-gtm-vis-total-visible-time31117857_899=&quot;100&quot; data-sk=&quot;tooltip_parent&quot; data-stringify-link=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/one-story-to-read-today/&quot; delay=&quot;150&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/sign-up/one-story-to-read-today/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sign up for it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;   The Republicans swept the elections because of inflation and public disorder.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The year was 1946. The end of wartime price controls had &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2022/02/08/1078035048/price-controls-black-markets-and-skimpflation-the-wwii-battle-against-inflation&quot;&gt;sent prices soaring&lt;/a&gt;. Railways, coal mines, and steel mills were shut by strikes. The Republican message was clear and convincing: “Had enough?”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Yes, said the voters, they had. Democrats lost 55 seats in the House, 12 in the Senate. The Republicans took control of both chambers of Congress, after spending the preceding decade and a half as the minority party in both.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   All seemed set for a huge GOP win in the 1948 presidential election. A leading candidate for the nomination that year was Robert Alphonso Taft, the eldest son of former President William Howard Taft. Robert Taft represented Ohio in the U.S. Senate, where he’d accumulated a staunchly conservative voting record. He opposed foreign aid, distrusted foreign-military alliances, and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/1943/01/30/archives/taft-asks-tariffs-as-prosperity-key-says-we-must-assist-private.html&quot;&gt;championed&lt;/a&gt; a high protective tariff for American industries.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2018/03/trump-william-taft/555656/&quot;&gt;Read: President Taft, the anti-Trump&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In September 1947, Taft toured California. National and local reporters closely followed the probable next president. Some 50 journalists gathered when Taft called a press conference in an auditorium in Santa Cruz. Taft was asked about the cost of living because prices &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.minneapolisfed.org/about-us/monetary-policy/inflation-calculator/consumer-price-index-1913-&quot;&gt;were rising&lt;/a&gt; fast, even faster than in the previous year, when voter discontent had already been burning hot.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Seldom has a single answer to a reporter’s question sunk a political career so rapidly and totally. Here’s how &lt;i&gt;Time&lt;/i&gt; magazine &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://time.com/archive/6600483/national-affairs-the-senator-goes-west/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; what came next:  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;p&gt;Bob Taft was talking matter-of-factly, almost abstractedly, as if he were speaking across a committee table. But for a fraction of a second, every man in the room looked up and stared as if the Senator had just pulled out his penknife, opened it, and absently swallowed it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Taft had been discussing the high price of food and what he thought should be done to allay it. “Voluntary reduction of consumption,” he said, “is the first step. We should eat less … eat less meat and eat less extravagantly.” He went right on talking. The Chicago Daily News’s Ed Lahey broke in, gave him a chance to get off the hook by asking: “Do you think that would cover the whole populace?”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Yes,” the Senator said. “Hoover suggested the same thing some time ago. He suggested that we ought to start … a campaign to save food and eat less.”&lt;/p&gt;   At Taft’s next appearances, hecklers chanted “Eat less, eat less.” Democrats ridiculed him as “Eat Less Taft.” The following year, Republicans rejected Taft as their nominee in favor of the more progressive and internationalist Thomas Dewey, the governor of New York. The GOP had lost its momentum: At the general election, the Democrats held the presidency and regained control of the House and Senate.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I think of “Eat Less Taft” as I hear President Donald Trump’s appointees defend their administration’s consumer-crushing tariffs. On &lt;i&gt;Meet the Press&lt;/i&gt; this past Sunday, the near-billionaire Treasury secretary proclaimed that “the American dream is not ‘Let them eat flat-screens’” and “the American dream is not contingent on cheap baubles from China.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Scott Bessent’s denigration of affordable televisions was not a one-off gaffe. In a speech to the Economic Club of New York on March 6, he &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sb0045&quot;&gt;stuck to the script&lt;/a&gt;: “Access to cheap goods is not the essence of the American dream.” A few days later, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/lutnick-trumps-policies-worth-it-recession/&quot;&gt;was asked&lt;/a&gt; on television whether the Trump tariffs were worth the risk of recession. Lutnick delivered an emphatic yes: “These policies are the most important thing America has ever had. It’s worth it.” President Trump &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/remarks/2025/03/remarks-by-president-trump-in-joint-address-to-congress/&quot;&gt;alluded&lt;/a&gt; to an impending “disturbance” in his March 4 speech to a Joint Session of Congress. Questioned later in the Oval Office about a possible recession, he euphemistically &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/14/nx-s1-5326145/trump-week-shutdown-ukraine-stock-market-doge&quot;&gt;acknowledged&lt;/a&gt; a “period of transition” ahead.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/02/price-america-trump-tariffs/681546/&quot;&gt;David Frum: The price America will pay for Trump’s tariffs&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   So get ready to Eat Less.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   At least Taft’s message offered some kind of hope at the end—and, of course, it wasn’t Taft’s personal fault that food prices had risen. But Trump’s tariffs are Trump’s fault, and it’s clear that if he has his way, they will be permanent.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/irs-trump-tax-revenues-tariffs-eef2ab6930a8672a418af27f61efaed8&quot;&gt;promotes&lt;/a&gt; tariffs as a way to shift the costs of financing the U.S. government from Americans to foreigners. His commerce secretary &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/lauraingraham/videos/new-secretary-howardlutnick-says-its-time-for-a-radical-shiftwere-going-to-make-/1385268479503598/&quot;&gt;suggests&lt;/a&gt; that tariffs might do away with the need for income taxes altogether. Income taxes fall most heavily on the affluent; tariffs fall most heavily on the middle class and poor. Trump has sold his party on tariffs as a way to redistribute the cost of government away from his donors to his voters.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   At the same time, Trump’s tariffs are advertised to do a dozen other magical things. They promise to stop Chinese currency manipulation, as well as to stop fentanyl from coming into the United States. They &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/sb0045&quot;&gt;are supposed&lt;/a&gt; to compel foreign governments to do more of the government regulation that the United States wants (for example, to police intellectual-property theft) and less of the government regulation that the U.S. does not want. Even with this wish list, the tariffs make no sense. If cheap Chinese goods are your issue, why tax Canadian aluminum and Mexican glass? If your goal &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-12/what-are-tariffs-and-how-is-donald-trump-changing-us-trade/104948676&quot;&gt;is to encourage&lt;/a&gt; other countries to increase their defense spending, why start a trade war with Australia after it &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/mar/07/surface-tension-could-the-promised-aukus-nuclear-submarines-simply-never-be-handed-over-to-australia&quot;&gt;already made a down payment&lt;/a&gt; on three U.S.-made nuclear-powered submarines?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Trump is a flimflam man who will promise anything to anybody and count on the suckers forgetting tomorrow what he said yesterday. His Cabinet officers, however, are gradually revealing the true cost of the Eat Less scam. They do not match Taft’s self-harming candor. But their real message of “Less for you, more for us” is reverberating louder and clearer.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/trump-tariff-advice-eat-less/682079/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/trump-tariff-advice-eat-less/682079/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What the Border-Hawk Catholics Get Wrong</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Critics of Pope Francis’s views on immigration are sidestepping a long-standing Catholic tradition—while claiming to uphold it. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/CM8LAHzX4owcBOlNzPxkSY2IUKs=/0x0:2000x1125/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_3_17_What_Border_Hawk_Catholics_Get_Wrong_Sketch_JA/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of Pope Francis superimposed on Catholic art&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by The Atlantic. Sources: Vatican Pool / Getty; Sylvain Sonnet / Getty.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   In a letter to America’s bishops, Pope Francis last month &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vatican.va/content/francesco/en/letters/2025/documents/20250210-lettera-vescovi-usa.html&quot;&gt;decried&lt;/a&gt; a “major crisis” unfolding in the United States: “the initiation of a program of mass deportations.” He called on “all the faithful of the Catholic Church, and all men and women of good will, not to give in to narratives that discriminate against and cause unnecessary suffering to our migrant and refugee brothers and sisters.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Border-hawk Catholics were scandalized.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   R. R. Reno, the editor of the traditionalist religious magazine &lt;em&gt;First Things&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://firstthings.com/pope-franciss-apocalyptic-dream/&quot;&gt;denounced&lt;/a&gt; the pope as “an accelerationist” who believes that a “borderless fraternity is a true utopia.” &lt;em&gt;The Daily Wire&lt;/em&gt;’s Matt Walsh &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/MattWalshBlog/status/1889766655439544589&quot;&gt;characterized&lt;/a&gt; the letter as “pure nonsense,” while the Heritage Foundation’s head, Kevin Roberts, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/KevinRobertsTX/status/1890389572963414403&quot;&gt;called&lt;/a&gt; it a “veiled shot” at Catholic supporters of Donald Trump. Tom Homan, President Trump’s border czar, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/MichaelRWear/status/1889752186126536989&quot;&gt;addressed Francis directly&lt;/a&gt;: “I got harsh words for the pope … He ought to fix the Catholic Church and concentrate on his work, and leave border enforcement to us.” (Each of these critiques came before Francis’s hospitalization last month.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Throughout Francis’s papacy, some American Catholics have accused him of prioritizing a platitudinal liberalism over doctrinal orthodoxy. But on the issue of immigration, Francis’s critics are the ones who appear to be sidestepping Catholic tradition—even while claiming to uphold it.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Start with the incident that prompted the current intra-Catholic dispute over immigration: a back-and-forth between the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops and America’s highest-profile Catholic official. After the Trump administration authorized Immigration and Customs Enforcement to apprehend people in churches and other social-service ministries, the USCCB called the move “&lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.usccb.org/news/2025/human-dignity-not-dependent-persons-citizenship-or-immigration-status&quot;&gt;contrary to the common good&lt;/a&gt;.” Vice President J. D. Vance came to the administration’s defense.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   “There’s this old-school—and I think it’s a very Christian concept, by the way,” Vance told Fox News’s Sean Hannity in late January, “that you love your family, and then you love your neighbor, and then you love your community, and then you love your fellow citizens in your own country, and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; after that you can focus and prioritize the rest of the world.” Vance’s rationale sparked intense debate in Catholic circles, especially online: His supporters &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/michaeljknowles/status/1885721612248305908&quot;&gt;cheered&lt;/a&gt; his use of religious rhetoric, while his detractors &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/JamesMartinSJ/status/1885082087700435303&quot;&gt;accused&lt;/a&gt; him of ignoring key parts of the Gospel.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/02/catholic-charities-trump/681610/&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Bruenig: ‘A very Christian concept’&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Christian theologians through the ages have indeed articulated versions of this principle—called &lt;em&gt;ordo amoris&lt;/em&gt;, or “the order of love”—including Church fathers such as &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newadvent.org/fathers/12021.htm&quot;&gt;Saint Augustine&lt;/a&gt; in the fourth century (“Since you cannot do good to all, you are to pay special regard to those who, by the accidents of time, or place, or circumstance, are brought into closer connection with you”) and &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newadvent.org/summa/3026.htm&quot;&gt;Saint Thomas Aquinas&lt;/a&gt; in the 13th (“We ought to love more specially those who are united to us by ties of blood”). True Christian love, the principle suggests, is guided not by an impulse to maximize utility but by a compassionate preference toward the personal and proximate.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Many of those same Catholic theologians, however, believed that this preference is conditional, not absolute. As Aquinas himself &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newadvent.org/summa/3031.htm&quot;&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Summa Theologiae&lt;/em&gt;: “In certain cases one ought, for instance, to succor a stranger, in extreme necessity, rather than one’s own father, if he is not in such urgent need.” Rightly ordered love prioritizes close kinship—all things being equal. But it’s not ignorant of context or necessity.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Based on the outcry that followed Francis’s letter, you’d be forgiven for thinking it marked a dramatic departure from the views of his predecessors. It didn’t. “To welcome” the undocumented migrant “and to show him solidarity is a duty of hospitality and fidelity to Christian identity itself,” Pope John Paul II &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vatican.va/content/john-paul-ii/en/messages/migration/documents/hf_jp-ii_mes_25071995_undocumented_migrants.html&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; in 1995. His successor, Pope Benedict XVI, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.vatican.va/content/benedict-xvi/en/messages/migration/documents/hf_ben-xvi_mes_20100927_world-migrants-day.html&quot;&gt;remarked&lt;/a&gt; that immigrants and native-born people alike “have the same right to enjoy the goods of the earth whose destination is universal, as the social doctrine of the Church teaches.” In 2010, he selected “one human family” as the theme for the World Day of Migrants and Refugees.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   To be sure, none of the three most recent pontiffs argued that immigration is an unbounded good. Benedict XVI granted that nations are entitled to “regulate migration flows,” while John Paul II thought that “illegal immigration should be prevented.” Francis himself noted in his letter “the right of a nation to defend itself and keep communities safe” from violent criminals, and he stressed the need for “policy that regulates orderly and legal migration.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Still, &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://firstthings.com/pope-franciss-apocalyptic-dream/&quot;&gt;some of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://europeanconservative.com/articles/commentary/the-ngo-pope-commits-ecclesiastical-suicide/&quot;&gt;Francis’s critics&lt;/a&gt; interpreted the letter as a declaration that countries should admit every migrant who doesn’t have a criminal record. They typically cited this line: “The rightly formed conscience” should not equate the “illegal status of some migrants with criminality.” But Francis has previously acknowledged that stricter enforcement can be necessary. In a &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://youtu.be/y0h9fuLTxU0?feature=shared&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; interview&lt;/a&gt; last year, the pope said that a migrant should be received initially but, in certain situations, “maybe you have to send him back.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Some might reasonably find all of this to be another instance of Francis’s &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://thedispatch.com/article/misunderstanding-francis/&quot;&gt;imprecision&lt;/a&gt;—as a Catholic myself, I understand their frustration—or think it imprudent for him to intervene in such a contested and complicated political matter. True enough, his letter wasn’t primarily concerned with balancing competing interests; his goal, it seems, was to emphasize what he regards as the moral error that underlies much of the immigration debate in the United States. If in doing so the pope is guilty of eschewing some nuance, his critics seem altogether uninterested in the deficiency he was pointing out.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   They wouldn’t have to look very far. The first Trump administration enforced a brutal policy that separated thousands of parents from their children, as my colleague Caitlin Dickerson &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2022/09/trump-administration-family-separation-policy-immigration/670604/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt;. (In October, a journalist &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/60Minutes/status/1850689458590384212&quot;&gt;asked&lt;/a&gt; Homan whether there’s a way to carry out mass deportations without separating families; he replied, “Sure there is: Families can be deported together.”) In many cases, restrictionist sentiment has given way to outright xenophobia, perhaps most memorably during Trump’s 2024 campaign, when he scapegoated Haitian migrants in Springfield, Ohio. (Matt Walsh contributed to the panic in a &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u4UflQiYjVs&amp;amp;t=852s&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; titled “Third World Immigrants Are Ruining Our Towns and Eating Our Pets.”) And as the second Trump administration froze funds for initiatives such as the USCCB’s refugee-resettlement program, the &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pillarcatholic.com/p/usccb-lays-off-50-migration-staffers&quot;&gt;bishops’ conference laid off 50 workers last month&lt;/a&gt;. (Responding to pushback from the USCCB over the administration’s loosened ICE guidelines, Vance suggested that the bishops are more &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cbsnews.com/news/jd-vance-interview-face-the-nation-catholic-bishops-ice-order/&quot;&gt;“worried about their bottom line”&lt;/a&gt; than about caring for migrants.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   While the White House posts &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/whitehouse/status/1891922058415603980?s=46&quot;&gt;deportation ASMR videos&lt;/a&gt; and ICE ramps up raids that sometimes &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/01/24/ice-raid-newark-new-jersey-immigration-us-citizens&quot;&gt;mistakenly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/amp/rcna195406&quot;&gt;detain citizens&lt;/a&gt;, it’s hard to read Francis’s letter as gratuitous pining for a borderless utopia. Rather, the pope seems to be making a plea for rhetoric and policies that respect the dignity of every human life—a long-standing Catholic concern that U.S. immigration-policy debates so often ignore.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/francis-immigration-catholics-vance/682078/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/03/francis-immigration-catholics-vance/682078/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Who Wants to Live in the Palisades Now?</title><description>&lt;div&gt; Los Angeles is planning to rebuild with fire in mind, but this landscape is still primed to burn. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/hWwOx92N-FHu1rdDE5W2eAF7D5c=/0x0:2700x1519/960x540/media/img/mt/2025/03/2025_03_13_Palisades_AZ/original.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blocks of gray-scale images of a burnt home, mountains, clouds, and a yellow block of fire&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Tarini Sharma*&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;   T&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;he Palisades Fire&lt;/span&gt; burned its way through Jennifer Champion’s life. It started in the hills where her family liked to hike and moved along the roads she took with her daughters to Elysse’s high school (burned), Annabelle’s middle school (partially burned), and Charlise’s day care (too damaged to use). Nearby, her husband owned three sober-living facilities (one burned; the other two are now uninhabitable, surrounded by rubble). The roof and front wall collapsed at the grocery store where Charlise would get free sprinkle cookies; the one down the street is a pile of warped steel. Champion’s family had lived in the Palisades for about 16 years and, two years ago, leased a house they’d hoped to stay in long-term. That home burned. So did most of the other ones on their street.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Now they are living about 45 minutes away, in Manhattan Beach, where some other Palisades friends relocated too. “Is it convenient for all of us? None of us,” Champion told me, but they wanted to stay together. Elysse transferred to a high school in Santa Monica, about an hour away in traffic, with Palisades friends; Annabelle’s school found a temporary location there too. Champion’s job at Pepperdine University can be nearly two hours away. But she isn’t sure she will be able to keep it anyway, especially now that they don’t have child care for Charlise.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   They are past the first days of the fire—evacuating, securing temporary housing—and the first few weeks—finding a long-term rental, furnishing it with donations from a friend, buying pillows and cutlery. But “none of us know what to do next,” Champion said. Her Palisades friends talk: Do they stay where they are and make Manhattan Beach their home? Rebuilding the Palisades will take years. But right now, they all want to go back if they can.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   I&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;n January,&lt;/span&gt; I drove through Altadena, the other neighborhood destroyed by that month’s fires, with Frank Bigelow, Cal Fire’s deputy director of wildfire preparedness. At lot after lot after lot, the only bit of house still standing was the chimney. The air was acrid and quiet. To Bigelow, the scene recalled an image from a 1961 fire that razed Bel Air, about five miles from the Palisades. (Local legend in Malibu holds that the town’s flock of colorful parrots is descended from pets that escaped Bel Air’s burning homes.)  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The L.A. Fire Department produced a documentary postmortem a year later about all the ways the city had built itself flammable. That old film, he told me, “speaks to every one of the issues we saw” in January—a brush fire that quickly became an urban one; clogged evacuation routes; hydrants running dry; houses built on steep hillsides, where flames travel fastest. Bigelow rewatches it every few years. At the end, over black-and-white footage of a rubble neighborhood, the narrator intones: “Now fireplaces stand as tombstones over row upon row of dead homes on dead streets.” As we drove, Bigelow pointed to the chimneys. “Tombstones,” he said.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   After the 1961 fire, people kept building in Bel Air and into the hills. My father grew up one neighborhood over and, in the 1970s, bought a plot of land in the mountains of Topanga Canyon, overlooking Malibu, where I grew up. And all of the ignition points that humans brought in—power lines, heavy equipment, cars, cigarette butts—started more fires than the land was adapted to handle. Southern California’s chaparral needs fire to regenerate, but historically, it burned only every 30 to 100 years, Alexandra Syphard, a senior research scientist at the Conservation Biology Institute, told me. More frequent fires meant it no longer had enough time to recover between burns, so non-native grasses—far more flammable—filled the gaps. Over time, the landscape has become more and more fit to burn. When a wildfire came through my neighborhood in 1993, it traced a similar path to a fire from 1970, and traveled through burn scars from seven other fires. That 1993 conflagration lapped at the windows of my childhood home; the Palisades Fire finally burned it down.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2025/01/palisades-fire-malibu-deaths/681337/&quot;&gt;Read: The place where I grew up is gone&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   California has tried to build for the inevitable. After the Bel Air fire, Los Angeles updated its building codes, outlawing wood-shingled roofs and mandating that homeowners clear the brush around their house. Since 2008, the state has required that new homes in extremely fire-prone areas—such as my childhood neighborhood and much of the Palisades—have fire-resistant siding, tempered glass, and ember-resistant eves and vents. Many homes in the Palisades were constructed long before 2008 and, when they’re rebuilt, will be brought up to those standards. Fire can consume even the most defensible house, but if everyone designs less flammably, the whole neighborhood is less likely to go, Emily Schlickman, a fire-resiliency researcher at UC Davis, told me. In her ideal world, high-risk communities would have a ring of cleared land around them as a firebreak, robbing the flames of fuel. The local government in Paradise, California, which was destroyed by the 2018 Camp Fire, is trying to buy up land around the community to do precisely that. But many vulnerable places forgo such measures because they could do everything right and burn anyway.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Los Angeles is still trying to decide how to remake its destroyed neighborhoods. A commission of volunteer experts will give the county recommendations on reconstructing (and retrofitting) the area for future disasters. Steve Soboroff, the real-estate developer whom Mayor Karen Bass appointed chief recovery officer, has promised that the Palisades will be rebuilt resiliently (and, also, somehow have their Fourth of July parade this year). And the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/local/ladwp-pacific-palisades-power-lines-underground-customers-pay-cost/3648377/#:~:text=As%20rebuilding%20begins%20in%20the,lines%20underground%2C%20officials%20announced%20Thursday.&quot;&gt;recently pledged&lt;/a&gt; to put all of the Palisades’ power lines underground. In the days after the fire, some Angelenos and experts also advocated for dramatically remaking the Palisades—to be denser, for instance, with firebreaks around the community—but those notions may already be more or less moot. Many residents simply want to get home as quickly as possible, and the city and state have waived certain permitting requirements for those who want to rebuild essentially their same house on the same lot.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Every time these fires wreak this level of damage, people look at the melted cars, curled stucco, and thousands of displaced residents and ask: Should human beings return to these places at all? “When most of us build or buy a home, we carefully appraise the neighborhood. In Malibu the neighborhood is fire. Fire that revisits the coastal mountains several times a decade,” Mike Davis wrote in his famous essay “The Case for Letting Malibu Burn.” (You can tell what he thought of our whole shrubland coastal-living experiment.) Taxpayer dollars helped rebuild these areas, many occupied by rich people, again and again and again. Why not just accept that this coastline is kindling and move on?  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   But abandoning these landscapes altogether just isn’t realistic, researchers told me. Almost a third of all housing in the continental U.S. is already in places where settlements and wilderness intermix. All those people can’t just move. And abandonment isn’t always the best way to manage fires, either. Move everyone out of these half-wild places, and you may have taken away the people who were clearing brush and otherwise reducing the fire risk for the city nearby, Miriam Greenberg, a disaster researcher at UC Santa Cruz who studies the wildland-urban interface, told me. Leaving these areas untouched, Greenberg said, means “the potential for future disasters increases significantly for those adjacent urban areas, which is most of California.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   People have chosen to live here, with fire, for generations. My classmate and her father attended the same middle school; my friends’ parents and grandparents have been in Malibu for decades. A friend recently walked me through his home, which was severely smoke-damaged in the Palisades Fire and which, he told me, was a rebuild: The house had burned down in the 1993 fire. I asked if he’d ever leave, and he laughed: “When I die, I guess.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   M&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt;ost displaced residents&lt;/span&gt; I spoke with want to come home. Ginny Wiley, now in her 80s, grew up in her grandfather’s store, a wooden shack called Wiley’s Bait and Tackle, and took it over decades later. She used to live behind the shop, in what had once been a cottage-style motel for the construction workers who built the Pacific Coast Highway. When the state bought the bungalows to preserve as a historic site, Wiley moved into an apartment in the Pacific Palisades. The fire leveled Wiley’s Bait, the bungalows, and her apartment; she lived in her car for a month and then in a temporary Airbnb. She told me she hopes to rebuild: “I’m going to stay with the store as long as I can.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Insurance helps. But in my community, the difference between “good” and “okay” coverage is already determining people’s futures. Lisa Machenberg and her husband are going to rent nearby while building a home with enough room for future grandchildren; the Amirani family, whose daughter I used to play softball with, hope to live in a trailer on their burned lot, if they can afford to rebuild. Their private insurer dropped them a few years ago—one of the many companies that stopped writing policies in California—and the Amiranis estimate that their coverage will foot only about half the cost of construction.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Renters like Jennifer Champion and her family have no guarantee that they can return to the neighborhood. The Champions asked their landlord if they could purchase his burned lot, but he doesn’t plan to sell. Jennifer’s eldest daughter reminds her that, by the time the Palisades take form again, she will be away at college. Still, the Champions have added themselves to a directory, Protect Pali, that matches people looking to live in the Palisades with residents who want to sell their land.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/02/santa-rosa-fire-rebuild/681603/&quot;&gt;Read: How to rebuild from the ashes&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Because not everyone wants to come back. Jane Warden refuses to rebuild. In 2018, when the Woolsey Fire came through the western half of Malibu (spared by the Palisades Fire this year), it burned down the home where she’d raised her children and spent 10 years growing a garden of eucalyptus, palm trees, and pine trees—highly flammable plants that are everywhere in this part of California. Nick Tinoco, a sociologist at UCLA, followed people in Woolsey’s aftermath and told me that most people he’d spoken with had initially planned to rebuild. But only about 40 percent of the homes lost in that fire have been. The reality, Tinoco found, “was two-plus years of them trying to rebuild and then reaching a point where it was either better for them financially or psychically to let go and move on,” even if only to the next town over. (Trees in the canyons are still black from Woolsey; my prom date’s house is now an overgrown lot of mustard and jimson weed.) People tend to think climate migration is driven by the desire to flee a hazardous place, Tinoco said, but really, it is a by-product of “the long process of trying to stay.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Warden had originally planned to rebuild too, but she got so fed up with permitting that she sold her lot; the buyer quickly built a giant house, and sold it for four times what Warden had paid for the original, she told me. She moved to a neighborhood on the other side of Malibu so her kids could stay in the same school. She started a new garden of less flammable native plants and made a five-foot hardscape perimeter of sand and gravel around her home. The Palisades Fire burned down her house again anyway, and most of her neighborhood.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Her HOA is talking about using factory-built homes when their community rebuilds. “It makes sense, right? Because then you can replace your house easily, if we start thinking of housing as more semipermanent,” she told me. But she personally plans never to live in Malibu again. Losing a house to fire “twice is okay, but three times starts to feel like carelessness,” she said. She will replace her Christmas ornaments for the second time, but she has given up on keeping a personal library and has been leaving books wherever she finishes them. She and her husband are considering moving to the East Coast or to nearby Santa Monica, where the fire risk is generally lower (although portions of it were evacuated in January).  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Fire is a brutal sorting mechanism, deciding who can actually afford to live in a place and who can’t. More money generally enters an area after a fire, because they tend to happen in coveted landscapes, Kathryn McConnell, a disaster sociologist at the University of British Columbia, told me. Five years after Northern California’s Camp Fire, home prices in Paradise have gone up, and so has the number of houses sold that were built on spec, according to a &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2212420925000597&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published last month. Only about &lt;a data-event-element=&quot;inline link&quot; href=&quot;https://calmatters.org/housing/2025/02/mobile-homes-la-fires/&quot;&gt;five&lt;/a&gt; of the area’s 30 mobile-home parks have been rebuilt. The Palisades and Malibu are already extraordinarily expensive places to live; the fires will likely make them more so. The median home price in the Palisades is north of $4 million, and the median income is a little less than $200,000. Some people have been living in the homes their grandparents bought years ago or, like my parents, in mobile-home parks (two of which burned in the Palisades). But after a fire, rebuilding an old house can be financially impossible, especially if it was underinsured, and mobile-home parks might never reopen if the owners decide to sell and move on.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   So far, investors have been the earliest buyers of the burnt lots that people have put on the market. The first one sold in the Palisades belonged to an art teacher, who asked for $999,000 and got about $1.2 million. Richard Schulman, the real-estate agent who brokered the deal, told me that the buyer is a real-estate investor who plans to either build a spec home to sell or just sit on the land for a few years until more people move back and the property values rise.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Schulman is bullish on the Palisades. “This is very valuable land to be on,” he said—secluded yet convenient, with ocean views and a sea breeze. Last month, I stood with him in a leveled townhouse complex along the road where, during the fire, evacuating residents abandoned their vehicles and ran. A mudslide had since closed the lower half of it. “I’m 99 percent sure this is the unit here,” Schulman said, indicating some undulating stucco indistinguishable from the other undulating stucco. He told me that this particular pile was a condo he’d recently listed—a great buy, he said, for a highly speculative investor.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   A small patch of grass on the burnt hillside was still alive. Schulman pointed at the unburnt bit: “If you look at it the right way, it’s like, &lt;em&gt;This is beautiful&lt;/em&gt;. There’s trees; there’s green.” The air smelled of eucalyptus and dead fish, which were lying on the walkway beside us. They had survived the fire, only for the recent rains to wash them out of the community pond. Schulman made a picture frame out of his thumbs and forefingers and held it toward the hill. “If you ignore the burnt hillside back there,” he said, “this is a great place to live.”  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;*Lead image credit: Illustration by Tarini Sharma. Sources: David Rumsey Map Center; Stanford Libraries; Agustin Paullier / AFP / Getty; Robyn Beck / AFP / Getty.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;   &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2025/03/la-fires-palisades-rebuilding/682073/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2025/03/la-fires-palisades-rebuilding/682073/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>