<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0"><channel><title>Gist Featured Articles</title><link>https://grist.org/</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/grist/featured" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Featured Articles on Grist.org - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:23:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>You rely on this agency’s data for weather and climate forecasts. DOGE is decimating its workforce.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Late last month, Rebecca Howard was fired from her dream job. With less than two hours’ notice, the research biologist was told to leave her position with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or NOAA, surveying Alaskan shellfish and pollock populations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Howard is one of the more than 1,000 employees affected by the recent layoffs at NOAA. As a science branch of the Department of Commerce, the agency plays a crucial role in climate research, ecosystem restoration, and oversight of commercial fisheries. The National Weather Service, which provides the data that powers weather apps on phones and informs local meteorologists, is an agency within NOAA.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As part of the Trump administration’s effort to slash the federal budget across various departments, over the last month the agency has fired hundreds of probationary employees — staff that were hired or promoted to a new position in the last year — regardless of their duties.&amp;nbsp; The agency is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/noaa-job-cuts-weather-forecasts-trump-doge-musk-7e35e9d5d757d8fc3f0f50b2bd71c87d&quot;&gt;reportedly preparing to lay off an additional 1,029 employees&lt;/a&gt;, representing a cumulative 20 percent reduction of its workforce. Last week, federal judges in California and Maryland ordered the Trump administration to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-judge-extend-block-trump-administration-ordering-mass-firings-2025-03-13/&quot;&gt;rehire&lt;/a&gt; probationary staffers who were let go.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Howard was one of the probationary employees affected by the first round of layoffs, and said the fisheries management projects she was involved in were being conducted by understaffed teams. As researchers like her leave, she said it’s not clear how the work will continue.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“We need these types of data to know how many fish and crabs we can catch each year, where those populations are going as the oceans change, and to keep track of environmental trends,” Howard said during a press conference organized by Senator Patty Murray, a Democrat representing Washington. Howard pointed out that when a survey of shellfish in the Bering Sea was missed in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic, Alaska’s $200 million snow crab fishery &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/feature-story/snow-crab-collapse-due-ecological-shift-bering-sea#:~:text=NOAA%20Fisheries%20scientists%20attribute%20the,well%20suited%20to%20Arctic%20conditions.&quot;&gt;collapsed&lt;/a&gt; the following year. “Firing people like me will make it incredibly hard for NOAA Fisheries to fulfill its mission,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The Department of Government Efficiency, the budget-cutting entity spearheaded by Elon Musk, has also proposed terminating leases for 19 properties used by NOAA for its operations. Separately, the General Services Administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/statement-regarding-gsas-disposal-of-noncore-assets-03042025&quot;&gt;designated an additional 13 buildings&lt;/a&gt; owned by the agency as “not core to government operations.” The buildings include law enforcement offices for fisheries, a control room that oversees a fleet of 15 weather satellites, and an information center that houses more than a century of climate data archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Climate scientists are also worried about the possible closure of an office that supports the Mauna Loa Observatory, which supplies the longest-running record of atmospheric carbon dioxide measurements. The research station supplies the data behind the Keeling Curve, a graph that shows how much of the planet-warming gas has accumulated in the atmosphere since it was established in 1958.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“Political leadership in this administration doesn’t know the agency’s mission, and they don’t care,” said Richard Spinrad, the former NOAA chief who led the agency during the Biden administration, during the press conference. “These actions are not the strategic moves of a government looking out for its pockets. They are the unnecessary and malicious acts of a shambolic administration.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;NOAA’s $9.8 billion budget represents just &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/7267889/climate-cost-of-trump-staff-cuts-noaa-nasa/&quot;&gt;0.097 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all federal spending, and its employees represent less than 0.5 percent of the entire federal workforce. But because of the agency’s wide-ranging duties and the indiscriminate nature of the cuts, Spinrad says the damage will be felt through virtually “every business sector, every geographic region of the country, and every component of American society.” And as extreme weather services — like flood forecasts, hurricane outlooks, tsunami warnings, and wildfire monitoring — are compromised, American lives will be threatened, he said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The reduction in staff is already hampering operations. The agency has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wxxinews.org/2025-03-12/national-weather-service-suspends-vital-ny-weather-monitoring-after-trumps-staffing-cuts&quot;&gt;suspended the launch of some weather balloons&lt;/a&gt;, which are a key tool in recording atmospheric conditions and real-time storm tracking. NOAA launches these balloons daily to collect crucial data, and without it, weather forecasts could become less accurate over time. The agency has also canceled its long-standing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/13/noaa-cancels-global-warming-briefings-cuts&quot;&gt;monthly briefings&lt;/a&gt; with reporters about seasonal forecasts and global climate conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“The cuts already have been hugely disruptive, and the impacts are growing,” Daniel Swain, a climate scientist at the University of California, told Grist. “Some of [the problems] will manifest during extreme events, and then some of them will probably just take some time to show themselves.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Swain pointed to the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/15/g-s1-54089/tornadoes-wildfires-south-missouri-oklahoma&quot;&gt;deadly outbreak of tornadoes and wildfires&lt;/a&gt; as examples of when “the 24/7 life-saving duties of the National Weather Service are on full display.” A spate of&amp;nbsp; wildfires torched nearly 300 homes in Oklahoma, and at least 40 were left dead after a surge of tornadoes and dust storms tore through the Midwest and South. During these types of extreme weather events, NOAA meteorologists provide real-time updates to first responders, issue public alerts, and help local authorities track storms as they develop. But key hubs for this work, such as The Storm Prediction Center in Norman, Oklahoma, are among the NOAA facilities that DOGE is &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/noaas-storm-prediction-center-facility-planned-doge-cuts/story?id=119882272&quot;&gt;considering&lt;/a&gt; closing. Local news outlets reported that there may not be enough staff left to adequately &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oudaily.com/news/national-weather-center-service-ou-meteorology-students-national-oceanic-and-atmospheric-administration-layoffs-cuts/article_4272b898-f572-11ef-9c52-5bb9d5af94c9.html&quot;&gt;respond to tornado events&lt;/a&gt; due to layoffs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“This is the kind of moment where you might start to see the tangible, real-world, and genuinely life-threatening impacts of these staffing gaps,” Swain said. “These people, despite being in lifesaving roles, were fired without notice or justification.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;On Monday, some NOAA probationary employees who were fired, including Howard, the fisheries research biologist, were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/2025/03/17/climate-energy-agencies-probationary-employees&quot;&gt;rehired&lt;/a&gt; as mandated by federal court orders. Howard said the reinstatement email she received placed her on administrative leave, and that there’s been “no indication” when she will be allowed to return to work. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;“I had been working toward a career in marine science since I was a child,” she said. “Being put back in that stressful situation is not something I would look forward to, but this is what I wanted to do with my career.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/politics/you-rely-on-this-agencys-data-for-weather-and-climate-forecasts-doge-is-decimating-its-workforce/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/politics/you-rely-on-this-agencys-data-for-weather-and-climate-forecasts-doge-is-decimating-its-workforce/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 19:19:25 GMT</pubDate><author>Sachi Kitajima Mulkey</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/GettyImages-2202648720.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Utilities are shutting off power to a growing number of households</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Electric utilities across the United States are shutting off power to a growing number of households, according to a recent report that also found most shutoffs happened during last year’s record-hot summer, a reminder that &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/extreme-heat/how-climate-change-drives-hotter-more-frequent-heat-waves/&quot;&gt;climate change&lt;/a&gt; fuels more intense, frequent, and prolonged heat waves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Shutoffs can be deadly, especially during extreme freezes and blistering heat. And while health issues are the most worrisome risk, there are other threats to daily life such as losing access to phone, internet, medical equipment, and food storage. Basic physical comfort can prove impossible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biologicaldiversity.org/programs/energy-justice/pdfs/Powerless_Report_2025.pdf?_gl=1*hpe2sd*_gcl_aw*R0NMLjE3MzY4NzA5NDguQ2owS0NRaUFzNWk4QmhEbUFSSXNBR0U0eEh3cml0RnBhekQ5M1o3V2hWTHVtQkpUdjFXZEZrUzdGRU1fS01VMEF1SDhOM1FqTkpEZXdNTWFBbm1JRUFMd193Y0I.*_gcl_au*MTc4MTAyMzI3NC4xNzM2ODcwOTQ4&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by the nonprofit Center for Biological Diversity revealed that six investor-owned utilities disconnected customers between January and September 2024 more than 662,000 times, an over 20 percent jump from the same period in 2023. Those companies included Georgia Power, DTE Energy, Duke Energy, Ameren Corporation, Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric, and Arizona Public Service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But all shutoffs, and the harms they cause, are avoidable, said Selah Goodson Bell, lead author of the report. States and local governments have the power to protect customers by enacting policies like comprehensive shutoff bans during extreme heat and reining in utility rate hikes. While most states already ban shutoffs during cold weather, more and more are starting to ban it during heat waves. “It’s going to be up to cities, municipalities, and states to remedy ongoing energy injustices and hold these utility companies accountable,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;It’s hard to know the true extent and nature of shutoffs because only &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;a patchwork of data&lt;/a&gt; exists nationwide. Twenty-two states don’t require utilities to report disconnections at all, and among the ones that do, only 20 states and Washington, D.C., have up-to-date data. Report authors analyzed the six power companies because they provide current disconnection data and collectively serve more than 200 million customers, spanning most regions of the U.S. from California to the Carolinas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;In Georgia, the state’s largest electric utility Georgia Power disconnected customers for nonpayment over 180,000 times from January to September 2024 — a more than 20 percent increase from the same period in 2023. Duke Energy in North and South Carolina also increased shutoffs by nearly 20 percent last year. DTE Energy in Michigan disconnected customers more than 150,000 times, and Ameren in Illinois and Missouri shut off power more than 120,000 times, with both raising shutoff rates in the past few years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric in California and Phoenix-based Arizona Public Service cut off power to fewer customers than the other utilities, the report still found a steady growth in shutoffs since 2022.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Lingering inflation, rate hikes, and climate change have all contributed to the rise in shutoffs, the report found. But the core issue is an “antiquated and broken” utility business model that effectively punishes low-income customers by aggressively raising rates, and then cutting off power when households can’t pay, said Goodson Bell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;As shutoffs increased, the six utilities analyzed in the report also netted $10 billion in profits between January and September 2024, a more than 20 percent increase from the same period in 2023. Less than 2 percent of their shareholder dividends would have prevented all shutoffs last year, the report found. “Customers are losing access to an essential service they need to survive while shareholders line their pockets with lavish returns,” Goodson Bell said.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Besides using more electricity to cope with extreme temperatures, customers are also paying for the mounting costs of repairing and hardening the grid after disasters like wildfires or hurricanes. Yet the report documents efforts by utilities that would worsen climate-driven costs: Almost all the utilities mentioned in the report have worked to expand gas infrastructure and fossil fuel energy supply, and lobbied to weaken rooftop solar and other climate policies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;article class=&quot;in-article-recirc&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;in-article-recirc__label&quot;&gt;Read Next&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__content&quot;&gt;

      
      
                    
            &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__art&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figure&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all&quot; alt=&quot;digital collage of a Black hand turning off a light switch, an electric meter, and the logo for Xcel Energy&quot; class=&quot;js-modal-gallery__hidden&quot; srcset=&quot;https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1600w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=1200%2C675&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1200w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=330%2C186&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 330w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 768w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 1536w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=160%2C90&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 160w, https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/xcel-energy-cutoffs.jpg?resize=150%2C84&amp;amp;quality=75&amp;amp;strip=all 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; height=&quot;900&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__body&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;a class=&quot;in-article-recirc__title-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/energy/a-lack-of-data-hampers-efforts-to-fix-racial-disparities-in-utility-cutoffs/&quot;&gt;A lack of data hampers efforts to fix racial disparities in utility cutoffs&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;in-article-recirc__meta&quot;&gt;
          

  &lt;div class=&quot;tease-meta&quot;&gt;
                            &lt;a class=&quot;byline-link&quot; href=&quot;https://grist.org/author/akielly-hu/&quot;&gt;Akielly Hu&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Representatives from Ameren, Arizona Public Service, DTE Energy, and PG&amp;amp;E told Grist that disconnection is a last resort, and that the utilities offer a range of energy assistance and flexible payment plans. “We recognize that higher costs, including energy bills, can be a challenge for customers,” said PG&amp;amp;E spokesperson Mike Gazda. Duke Energy and Georgia Power did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;For most of the utilities in the report, shutoffs peaked in the summer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;While 42 states already ban shutoffs during cold weather, 23 have now passed heat-based shutoff bans, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.leg.wa.gov/billsummary?BillNumber=1329&amp;amp;Year=2023&amp;amp;Initiative=false&quot;&gt;Washington state in 2023&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lis.virginia.gov/cgi-bin/legp604.exe?241+sum+HB906&quot;&gt;Virginia in 2024&lt;/a&gt;. Last year, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilga.gov/legislation/publicacts/fulltext.asp?Name=103-0019&quot;&gt;Illinois strengthened an existing ban&lt;/a&gt; by lowering the previous threshold of 95 degrees Fahrenheit to 90. That change appears to have already had a measurable impact: According to the Center for Biological Diversity’s report, summertime shutoffs in Illinois were 13 percent lower in 2024 than in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;But in Michigan and California, which both have temperature-based shutoff bans for extreme heat, disconnections by DTE Energy and PG&amp;amp;E still peaked during the summer. Temperature-based shutoff bans in those states fail to adequately protect customers because they don’t require utilities to automatically restore power to households that get disconnected prior to a heat event, said Goodson Bell. That means that even if a household gets their power shut off right before a ban takes effect, if they can’t pay in time, “They will be forced to endure harsh conditions without access to electricity.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Arizona Public Service, on the other hand, has avoided a summertime spike in shutoffs by using a date-based shutoff moratorium from June 1 to October 15. The policy was &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/arizona-heat-death-legacy-3fce53af423293d9fb15d7889dee9e13&quot;&gt;introduced by state regulators&lt;/a&gt; after Arizona Public Service cut off power to a 72-year-old woman who owed $51 on her electricity bill, resulting in her death in 2018. But even date-based protections may not be enough because extreme heat is increasingly happening on days outside summer months, Goodson Bell pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;States should instead use both temperature and date-based restrictions to widen the period of time customers are protected, and ban shutoffs completely for certain customers such as those with medical conditions, he said. Such measures are small steps to address widespread harms, said Sanya Carley, a professor at the University of Pennsylvania who studies utility disconnections. “When it comes to disconnections, I think states need to adopt as many protections as they possibly can.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/climate-energy/utilities-are-shutting-off-power-to-a-growing-number-of-households/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 08:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Akielly Hu</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/shutoffAP23250641911900.jpg?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Climate &amp;amp; Energy</category><category>Economics</category><category>Extreme Heat</category></item><item><title>Where did billions in climate and infrastructure funding go? Search our map by ZIP code.</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-drop-cap has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;By the time President Donald Trump retook office, lawmakers had announced nearly $700 billion in funding for infrastructure- and climate-related projects under two bills passed during Joe Biden’s administration — the Inflation Reduction Act and the bipartisan infrastructure law. That money was promised to all sorts of community and local projects, from clean energy initiatives to water system upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Some of these projects have received their funding. Indeed, some have been completed. But in light of the Trump administration’s freeze on many forms of federal funding, &lt;a href=&quot;https://grist.org/politics/trump-climate-funding-freeze-ira-bil-biden/&quot;&gt;the future of as-yet-undistributed money is unclear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;What kinds of climate and infrastructure projects have been announced in your community and across the country? Which ones may now be at risk? Now you can use your ZIP code to find out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;To understand the stakes of these signature pieces of legislation, Grist developed a tool that combines information across multiple datasets to reveal where more than $300 billion of the funds promised under the two pieces of legislation have been awarded across the United States. Enter a ZIP code, city name, or other location in the search box below to discover projects within any radius of your chosen area.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://grist.org/project/updates/interactive-ira-bil-project-map/&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: calc(50% - 50vw); width: 100vw; height: calc(100vh - 66px); border: 0; margin-bottom: 10px;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;Each point on the map can be clicked to reveal detailed information about the funding amount, project description, and implementing agency. Expand the data table to learn more or download your search results. Where possible, projects are linked to federal spending databases indicating whether or not funds have been disbursed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-default-font-family&quot;&gt;The data powering the tool combines information from archived federal websites, current government data portals, and independent data archivers. Grist’s data team cleaned, standardized, and merged these disparate datasets to create a comprehensive view of federal infrastructure spending under the Inflation Reduction Act and infrastructure law. For more information about our methods, access to the underlying code, and detailed documentation about our data processing and mapping pipelines, visit our open-source &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Grist-Data-Desk/ira-tracker&quot;&gt;repository on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://grist.org/accountability/climate-infrastructure-ira-bil-map-tool/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://grist.org/accountability/climate-infrastructure-ira-bil-map-tool/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Clayton Aldern</author><itunes:image href="https://grist.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/Screenshot-2025-02-12-at-12.43.27.png?quality=75&amp;strip=all"></itunes:image><category>Accountability</category></item></channel></rss>