<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Followin</title><link>https://followin.io</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/followin" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Followin - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://followin.io/favicon.ico</url><title>Followin</title><link>https://followin.io</link></image><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:31:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Trump once again expressed his hope that the Federal Reserve would lower interest rates</title><description>&lt;p&gt;PANews reported on March 25 that on the local time of the 24th, US President Trump stated that he hopes the Federal Reserve will lower interest rates. On the 19th of this month, the Federal Reserve concluded its two-day monetary policy meeting and announced that it would maintain the federal funds rate target range between 4.25% and 4.50%. This decision has drawn criticism from US President Trump, who posted on social media that the Federal Reserve had better lower interest rates because the impact of US tariffs is gradually seeping into the economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17021636</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17021636</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate><author>PANews</author></item><item><title>Particle Network (PARTI) Airdrop and Binance Listing: Everything You Need to Know</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Binance announced that the Particle Networks PARTI token will be in its HODLer Airdrops program. The PARTI token generation event (TGE) will take place tomorrow, March 25, followed by airdrops and listing on several centralized exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OKX is also going to list PARTI. The launch price is still unclear, but Particle Network has strong community support on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Binance to List Particle Network’s PARTI Token &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Binance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-review/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the world’s largest crypto exchange&lt;/a&gt;, has been substantially boosting token projects with its &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/binance-unveils-third-airdrop-type-for-bnb-holders/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;HODLer Airdrops program&lt;/a&gt;. Last week, it caused &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/binance-lists-bubblemaps-bmt-airdrop/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bubblemaps’ BMT token to spike 100%&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s now adding another asset to the program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to its announcement, Binance is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/detail/3ec6cdfea3394ffa9ce6bfeabe8191e5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;hosting&lt;/a&gt; an airdrop for Particle Network’s new token tomorrow at 13:00 (UTC), followed by an official listing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Particle Network is &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/blockchain-infrastructure/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;a blockchain infrastructure project&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to simplifying the Web3 experience. Last July, it also &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/depin-news-minima-logs-mclaren-data-particle-joins-peaq/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;joined the Peaq DePIN ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2022, the network has helped create over 17 million wallets and processed more than 10 million user operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Bubblemaps, Particle Network’s token hasn’t seen a price spike from Binance’s airdrop announcement. This is because PARTI has not had &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/learn/tge-token/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;a token generation event (TGE)&lt;/a&gt; yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to data from CoinMarketCap, PART will be hosted on the BNB Chain, and several exchanges, including OKX, KuCoin, and Binance, will list the token at launch time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, tokenomics &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/detail/3ec6cdfea3394ffa9ce6bfeabe8191e5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;reveals&lt;/a&gt; that PARTI will have a maximum supply of 1 billion tokens. 3% of this will go to HODLer Airdrop participants, and 23.3% will be listed for trading on Binance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another 3% will be allocated to the other marketing campaigns six months after spot listing, but there aren’t any specific details yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s difficult to predict how well PARTI will perform after its TGE. Particle Network’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/ParticleNtwrk/status/1904208710785765874#m&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about the airdrop had over 100,000 views, and Binance token listings &lt;a href=&quot;https://beincrypto.com/myshell-surge-binance-listing/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;typically do quite well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this trend will continue with a fruitful launch that encourages further Web3 innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17021665</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17021665</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:09:00 GMT</pubDate><author>BeInCrypto</author></item><item><title>New Reve Image Generator Beats AI Art Heavyweights MidJourney and Flux at a Penny Per Image</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A little-known AI image generator called &lt;a href=&quot;https://preview.reve.art/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Reve Image 1.0&lt;/a&gt; is trying to make a name in the text-to-image space, potentially outperforming established tools like Midjourney, Flux, and Ideogram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Reve Image 1.0 model, codenamed &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgsys.org/rankings&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Halfmoon&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; operates on a credit-based system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Users receive 100 free credits to test the service after signing up, with additional credits available at $5 for 500 generations—pretty cheap when compared to options like&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.midjourney.com/hc/en-us/articles/27870484040333-Comparing-Midjourney-Plans&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MidJourney&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideogram.ai/pricing?tab=personal&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ideogram,&lt;/a&gt; which start at $8 per month and can reach $120 per month, depending on the usage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reve is great at prompt adherence, visual aesthetics, and typography handling. The model generates high-resolution images across various artistic styles, from photorealistic renderings to abstract art.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s only a little information known about the model, its architecture, its team, and the legal intricacies of its service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But unlike &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/289570/recraft-v3-best-ai-image-generator-you-never-heard-of&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Recraft&lt;/a&gt;—which “owns” users’ outputs if generated using free plans—&lt;a href=&quot;https://preview.reve.art/terms&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Reve grants users ownership rights&lt;/a&gt; over their generated content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team at Reve did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reveimage/reve-image-generator&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;created a GitHub account&lt;/a&gt; but has not uploaded any content. In their Discord server, some users speculate there might be an open-source contribution, but such information has not been confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of giving some love to the open source community may not be so crazy as the company also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reveimage/ComfyUI&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;forked&lt;/a&gt; ComfyUI’s—a well-known UI for running open source AI Image generators—GitHub repository today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Prompt: A high-tech office space with different journalistic elements like a laptop, a telephone, a library, and a vintage typewriter, a cigar, and a mechanical keyboard, with glossy white walls prominently displaying a list of words in multicolor neon lettering. The text elements are arranged vertically from top to bottom, reading &quot;DECRYPT&quot;, &quot;EMERGE&quot;, &quot;DEGEN ALLEY&quot;, &quot;SCENE&quot;, &quot;GG&quot;, &quot;MYRIAD MARKETS&quot;, and &quot;DASTAN&quot;. The minimalist room features clean lines, metallic surfaces, and ambient lighting that casts a soft glow across the workspace, with sleek furniture and modern technological equipment visible in the periphery. Wide-angle interior photography with dramatic lighting that emphasizes neon elements against minimalist surfaces.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our comparative testing, Reve consistently produced impressive results across various prompt types. We tested three key aspects giving equal weighting: prompt adherence, realism, and text generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reve generated images with well-balanced lighting, accurate representation of requested elements, and vibrant multi-colored signage precisely as specified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The white walls appeared appropriately rendered, and journalistic elements on the desk were arranged naturally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When compared directly with &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.decrypt.co/309153/freepik-transformed-generative-ai-powerhouse/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Freepik&lt;/a&gt; Mystic (the best &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.decrypt.co/284932/meet-flux-1-1-pro-best-ai-image-generator/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Flux&lt;/a&gt; workflow in the market) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.decrypt.co/245823/ideogram-2-release-realism-flux-midjourney/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Ideogram&lt;/a&gt; (the best-closed source model with text capabilities)—on the same prompt, Reve achieved superior overall implementation of requirements, providing the best image when all the aspects were considered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Freepik excelled in color grading and light interaction but struggled with texture realism and letter placement, whereas Ideogram accurately captured glossy surfaces but mishandled text elements and was the least realistic of all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner: Reve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Prompt: A detailed hand-drawn illustration depicts a massive black spider with bristling legs and glowing eyes pursuing a screaming woman through a dark jungle setting. The woman, wearing a torn white dress, runs between thick tree trunks covered in vines, escaping from the spider. Dense foliage surrounds the scene, with twisted branches and large leaves blocking most of the dim moonlight filtering from above. The jungle floor is strewn with fallen leaves and gnarled roots. Black and white pen illustrations with rough sketch lines and dark cross-hatching create deep shadows and texture.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We conducted a horror illustration test comparing Reve against outputs from SD3, SDXL, MidJourney, and Ideogram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All models were tasked with creating a scene featuring a woman fleeing from a giant spider in a forest setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reve&#39;s output featured great hand-drawn quality with detailed linework, strong compositional framing, convincing facial expressions, and natural-looking forest elements with appropriate depth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While each competitor showed distinct strengths – SD3.5&#39;s jungle setting, SDXL&#39;s sense of scale, MidJourney&#39;s atmospheric quality, and Ideogram&#39;s color choices – Reve&#39;s illustration comprehensively fulfilled the prompt requirements with superior detail and artistic execution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a hard one to evaluate, but overall, Reve seems to be on par with SD3.5. Its hand-drawn aesthetic featured sophisticated texturing and hatching techniques, while the horror elements were effectively conveyed through the spider&#39;s threatening posture and the woman&#39;s terrified expression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The forest environment appeared cohesive and natural, with technical execution showing skilled perspective, anatomy, and compositional framing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tie: Reve and SD3.5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During testing, we discovered that Reve is actually uncensored but implements content filtering that affects specific outputs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the model appears to understand concepts related to nudity and violence, such content appears pixelated in the final output after generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a big difference because it opens the door for a future way of providing uncensored outputs, probably in high-tier plans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A censored model is not able to generate a specific image because it’s not trained on such content, a filtered model, on the other hand, has actually been trained and understands a concept but restricts its outputs based on a specific criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For users requiring unrestricted content generation, local installations of models like Flux or SD3.5 would likely be more suitable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike most of the image generators on the market that feature inpaint/outpaint edit tools, Reve relies on an instruction based system that understands natural language—similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/310943/google-gemini-2-flash-edit-photos-words-review&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Google’s approach with Gemini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, here is our result after we instructed the model to change a painting of a daylight scene into a night scene:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of selecting an area and using prompts to get the desired results, users must instead “chat” with the model and write their expected outcomes inside of a text box—and pray for the best.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is great for novice users who want to interact with the model and get something that just works. However, experienced users in need of granularity may see this as a cool addition but not really good enough to give them proper results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s better than Google’s AI because it doesn’t degrade the image after new generations, however, it does change the overall aesthetic which may not be ideal for users in need of a model that respects character consistency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reve Image Generator is a nice entry in the increasingly competitive AI image generation market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s very good at prompt adherence, realistic rendering, and versatility across different visual styles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At $5 for 500 credits (effectively one cent per generation), Reve undercuts many competitors while delivering comparable or superior results, becoming the best close source image generator for people wanting to pay for making good images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The flat-rate pricing model adds transparency that many users will appreciate–every image costs exactly one credit regardless of complexity or resolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, it has some limitations. The lack of an edit feature, which has become standard among competitors, may not be a big deal for novice users but may frustrate experienced enthusiasts looking to refine results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lack of a mobile app limits accessibility for on-the-go use, and the limited information about the team and technology behind Reve may be uncomfortable for those caring about long-term support and data handling practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, for users seeking to generate high-quality images without extensive prompt engineering expertise, Reve offers an accessible, cost-effective alternative to more established services. Its versatility and strong prompt adherence make it particularly valuable for users with specific visual requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Edited by &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/author/sebastian&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sebastian Sinclair&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://decrypt.co/author/joshquittner&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Josh Quittner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17021044</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17021044</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:36:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Decrypt</author><category>Interoperability</category><category>Storage</category><category>Smart Contracts</category></item><item><title>Inaugural crypto roundtable shows ‘clarity’ is a long way off</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a segment from the Forward Guidance newsletter. To read full editions, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/forwardguidance&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SEC’s new &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/news/new-sec-crypto-task-force&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;crypto task force&lt;/a&gt; gathered Friday to hear from 11 crypto attorneys and legal experts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the group’s inaugural roundtable discussion, lasting two hours and followed by 90 minutes of public Q&amp;amp;A. The meeting was dubbed the “Spring Sprint Toward Crypto Clarity” and had a focus on “defining security status.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spoiler: To the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/opinion/2025/03/24/the-sec-crypto-roundtable-was-a-missed-opportunity&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;chagrin&lt;/a&gt; of much of the crypto industry, roundtable attendees were &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; able to reach agreement on the very question that has plagued the securities regulator for 5+ years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, answering the question of how to determine whether a crypto asset is a security wasn’t the primary purpose of the meeting. And, given that the SEC is operating with three commissioners and doesn’t currently have a permanent chair, we’d be shocked if the agency even hinted at passing formal rules around crypto.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All that aside, though — even if Friday’s meeting seemed on the surface to be a nothingburger, we’d argue that the conversation was still telling when it comes to what we could expect from the agency in the next few years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are our top takeaways:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Howey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; is still king&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All roads, for better or for worse, lead back to &lt;em&gt;Howey&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel on Friday spent almost the entire time debating how and if cryptocurrencies fit into the four-pronged &lt;em&gt;Howey&lt;/em&gt; test. Until a formal crypto-specific rule is passed (which we don’t expect until the commission is full and a new chair is in place), don’t expect the &lt;em&gt;Howey&lt;/em&gt; talk to die down.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The guestlist was striking&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can’t prove this, but I have a feeling that Friday’s meeting was the largest gathering of crypto-native lawyers inside the SEC, ever (well, save for the depositions and settlement meetings that undoubtedly have taken place over the years).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attendees included a16z Crypto Head of Policy &amp;amp; General Counsel Miles Jennings and Delphi Ventures General Counsel Sarah Brennan.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commission “interpretation” is just that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of &lt;em&gt;Howey&lt;/em&gt;, let us not forget that the SEC’s cherished securities framework is the result of a landmark Supreme Court ruling.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The industry talks a lot about legal wins, like the district court ruling that secondary XRP sales were &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/news/judge-rules-ripple-xrp-not-security&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;not unregistered securities&lt;/a&gt;). But until a crypto case makes it further up the appellate ladder, we aren’t going to have meaningful legal precedent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, commissioners can pass rules and staff can issue guidance, but I’m still a believer that we’ll need to see more judicial opinions before crypto fits neatly into the current securities landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guidance we’ve seen from the SEC in the post-Gensler era is even less permanent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acting Chair Mark Uyeda himself said Friday that these “staff statements” have no legal backing. In other words: As of now, there’s nothing stopping the next chair from coming in and reversing everything that’s happened since Jan. 20.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, the next SEC Chair is widely expected to be &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/news/sec-chair-nominee-crypto-past&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Paul Atkins&lt;/a&gt;, Trump’s pick, who heads to the Senate on Thursday for his nomination hearing. We don’t currently foresee any major hurdles to his confirmation, and we certainly don’t expect him to walk back any of Uyeda’s pro-crypto statements. Still, we’ll be monitoring the situation closely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the news in your inbox. Explore Blockworks newsletters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/daily&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockworks Daily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The newsletter that helps thousands of investors understand crypto and the markets, by Byron Gilliam.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/empire&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Start your morning with the top news and analysis to inform your day in crypto.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/forwardguidance&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Reporting and analysis on the growing intersection of crypto and macroeconomics, policy and finance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/0xresearch&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0xResearch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Alpha directly in your inbox. Market highlights, data, degen trade ideas, governance updates, token performance and more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/lightspeed&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightspeed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Built for Solana investors, developers and community members. The latest from one of crypto’s hottest networks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockworks.co/newsletter/thedrop&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Drop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For crypto collectors and traders, covering apps, games, memes and more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17018823</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17018823</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:34:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockworks</author><category>Layer 1</category><category>Solana Ecosystem</category><category>SEC Security Token</category></item><item><title></title><description>Halfway through the @SonicLabs &amp;amp; http://Swaps.io Flight, fam!😎&lt;br&gt;Keep the momentum going — complete challenges, compete with your friends, and secure your spot on the leaderboard.&lt;br&gt;The clock is ticking &amp;amp; the prizes are BIG!&lt;br&gt;Check the sprints&#39; details if you haven&#39;t &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/edf9cbeaa1668aa550e9e4b32ad1930d.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Your chance to win extra rewards on @Intract_HQ!⚡&lt;br&gt;Complete tasks &amp;amp; test your luck in the $300 #USDC Lucky Draw!&lt;br&gt;🍀10 lucky winners will share the prize pool&lt;br&gt;⏳Only 1 week to go&lt;br&gt;Don’t miss out: https://quest.intract.io/quest/67d2b49f9580a4ddbb1d0993… &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  Another shot at Lucky Draw on @taskonxyz!⚡&lt;br&gt;Complete swapping quests &amp;amp; become one of 10 lucky winners!&lt;br&gt;🍀Winners will share the #prize pool of $300 USDC&lt;br&gt;⏳1 week left to secure your spot in the Lucky Draw&lt;br&gt;Start now: &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17018074</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17018074</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:35:37 GMT</pubDate><author>Swaps.io</author></item><item><title>Infector: Airdropping Tokens on Base Made Simple</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to Bankless &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bankless.comjavascript:;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;or &lt;u&gt;sign in&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are now &lt;em&gt;multiple &lt;/em&gt;solid options for releasing your own token on Base, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clanker.world/?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Clanker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flaunch.gg/?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Flaunch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/rainbowdotme/status/1903095966913143185?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.bankless.com/stubs/fsuv7zpo-400x400-png1715284527.png?class=tiny&quot; alt=&quot;Rainbow&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Rainbow&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Token Launcher&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/zora/status/1893005253827797267?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Zora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With these deployers, you can simplify your token deployment and get straight to community building. Yet that still leaves you with the question of &lt;em&gt;distribution&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, how can you get your token quickly into the hands of your biggest supporters, like your &lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.bankless.com/stubs/farcaster5457417-icon.png?class=tiny&quot; alt=&quot;Farcaster&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Farcaster&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; friends or your Rodeo collectors?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, cue in &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/taydotfun/status/1904170636768944317?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Infector&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I walked through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bankless.com/read/completor-basepaint-app?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Completor&lt;/a&gt;, an app by the Dot team for streamlined BasePaint collecting. Now, Dot&#39;s back in action with the public launch of their Infector platform. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dot.fun/?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bankless.ghost.io/content/images/2025/03/image---2025-03-24T103002.106.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Infector is a DIY airdropping tool that makes it easy to share tokens on &lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.bankless.com/stubs/base4460250-icon.png?class=tiny&quot; alt=&quot;Base&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Base&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in targeted fashion. Here&#39;s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;🔌&lt;strong&gt; Head to &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://infector.fun/?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;infector.fun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; and connect your wallet&lt;/strong&gt; — Once you&#39;re signed in, the app will automatically scan your current token holdings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;🪙&lt;strong&gt; Choose the token you want to airdrop &lt;/strong&gt;— At the top of the UI, press &quot;Select coin,&quot; and pick from your list of available holdings or paste in your desired contract address. Infector also gives you the option to buy tokens that you don&#39;t currently hold. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;📇&lt;strong&gt; Choose your airdrop recipients&lt;/strong&gt; — Next, Infector will provide recipient categories you can select from, like your Farcaster friends, &lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.bankless.com/stubs/zora9377197-icon.png?class=tiny&quot; alt=&quot;Zora&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Zora&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt; commenters, Rodeo collectors, ENS names, and NFT holders. You can select a max of 100 recipients per batch.  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;🧮&lt;strong&gt; Set amount per person&lt;/strong&gt; — In the UI&#39;s last input bar, you can set how many tokens you want to distribute per recipient. For example, in the screenshot below I&#39;ve teed up an airdrop of 50 $HIGHER for the 26 collectors of &lt;a href=&quot;https://rodeo.club/post/0x2A3D683CBE519793BaE6B3a0E052C28b06258ef0/14?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;one of my Rodeo posts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://infector.fun/?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bankless.ghost.io/content/images/2025/03/image---2025-03-24T104734.334.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finish up by completing the approval transaction and the send transaction. Afterwards, a UI modal will pop up that offers you announcement templates for X or Farcaster and links you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://basescan.org/tx/0x4f658a4fababb2125cc268be880efd7c66f2aa5afedd5645d3d0812d5a011ba4?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the Basescan page&lt;/a&gt; of your airdrop send for confirmation.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://infector.fun/?ref=bankless.ghost.io&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bankless.ghost.io/content/images/2025/03/image---2025-03-24T105427.325.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s nice about Infector is that it took me less than one minute to set that distribution up and get it sent out onchain. If you&#39;re exploring all these new token launcher tools lately, consider Infector if you want to do any airdrops—its cheap, fast, and very easy to use!&lt;/p&gt;                    &lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17017601</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17017601</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 18:04:43 GMT</pubDate><author>Bankless</author><category>Layer 1</category><category>Spartan Group</category><category>Governance</category></item><item><title></title><description>Building a huge short position on the $HYPE, token of Hyperliquid. This is despite them currently winning the DEX market with the strongest community and native BTC spot trading coming.
My liquidation price is $80 per HYPE.
Pleaseeeee, and I mean PLEASE, do not liquidate me.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17019955</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17019955</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:53:34 GMT</pubDate><author>Cited</author><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>Things get short-squeezy at about 92k #BTC , looking at dealer net gamma exposure. @Amberdataio @genesisvol #sendit</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17018887</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17018887</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:44:25 GMT</pubDate><author>Shawn Douglass</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>We are excited to introduce our BlockSim Toolkit, allowing users to test our threat monitoring system&#39;s performance like never before. Here is how our new features will empower you in Web3 Security 👇 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/905b2e3099466181a77230612d37e773.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  If you ever wondered how well your security alerts would have performed in past attack scenarios, the Backtest Back feature is for you. The new feature lets you replay real historical threats, refining detection accuracy before attackers strike. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/e9fbcf6bea4a40044dcc1c4e704edfba.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  🔥 Ready to test your security stack? The BlockSim Toolkit is now available. Contact us to try it out or learn more at http://fuzz.land! &lt;br&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/XxQhy815Ar&quot;&gt;Fuzzland | Smart Contract Automated Analysis Solutions&lt;br&gt;Fuzzland is a smart contract automated analysis solution provider. We help blockchain projects to find vulnerabilities and secure their smart contracts.&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17016885</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17016885</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:23:55 GMT</pubDate><author>fuzzland 🥐</author></item><item><title></title><description>Yup, we can absolutely corroborate it 👀📈
A new ATH has been reached on @flowty_io — this past week surpassed 50,000 sales on @flow_blockchain! 🔥
Just a week after breaking the 40k mark, the momentum hasn’t slowed down at all.
Something big is brewing… and it’s just the</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17016720</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17016720</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:00:08 GMT</pubDate><author>Adrià 🎗️</author></item><item><title>A short note on Post Quantum Verkle explorations</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-a-short-note-on-pq-verkle-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A short note on PQ-Verkle&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want to thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/gballet&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gballet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/ihagopian&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@ihagopian&lt;/a&gt; for helping me understand all Verkle Tree’s tradeoffs and resolving all my doubts. Also &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/arantxazapico&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@arantxazapico&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/wizardofmenlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@WizardOfMenlo&lt;/a&gt; for good discussions and help towards understanding the SoTA of lattice-based vector commitments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While revisiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-6800&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EIP6800 (Unified Verkle Tree as ethereum’s state structure)&lt;/a&gt; I asked myself the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;What problem are we actually addressing?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What properties did we actually like from Verkle?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Would Verkle be the best solution in a non-PQ-existant world?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What do researchers dislike about Verkle?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Can we actually &lt;em&gt;harden&lt;/em&gt; Verkle?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall goal of this post will be to answer these questions and try to share all the knowledge obtained within the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-what-problem-are-we-actually-addressing-2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What problem are we actually addressing?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motivation for Verkle trees is clear. Ethereum’s state is growing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that increases the demand on hardware for anyone that wants to participate within ethereum’s protocol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine being a node that doesn’t hold the whole ethereum state. That would dramatically reduce the requirements and therefore &lt;strong&gt;lower the entry barrier&lt;/strong&gt; to more participants within ethereum network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One could say, well, I’ll just ask full-nodes for the witness related to each block. Such that I don’t need to store it locally and instead I’ll fetch it every time I need it.&lt;br&gt;This presents some problems:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You need a proof that attests the witness received are indeed the right ones.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Taken from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-6800#motivation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Motivation section of EIP-6800 itself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A witness accessing an account in today’s hexary Patricia tree is, in the average case, close to 3 kB, and in the worst case it may be three times larger. Assuming a worst case of 6000 accesses per block (15m gas / 2500 gas per access), this corresponds to a witness size of ~18 MB, which is too large to safely broadcast through a p2p network within a 12-second slot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As seen, witness correctness proofs require a huge cost in terms of space and disk access. Which will only increase overtime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Proofs are depth-dependant. Ie. The more the tree grows in the future, the larger the depth. The bigger the proofs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The endgoal would be that blocks are self-contained. ie. anyone that receives a block, can attest its validity without the need of holding the whole ethereum storage locally. But with current MPT witness-size &amp;amp; proof-size. This is not even imaginable as shown in the second point.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what statelessness promises to fix and what Verkle trees were a solution for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-what-properties-did-we-actually-like-from-verkle-3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What properties did we actually like from Verkle?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s briefly explain several of the reasons why we liked Verkle:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-storage-proof-size-4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Storage-proof size&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how a a Verkle Tree and proof of storage of a value looks like (taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2021/06/18/verkle.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Vitalik’s post&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/9/0/90f9b6f2dc30867469085d3a310440a09d105015.png&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/optimized/3X/9/0/90f9b6f2dc30867469085d3a310440a09d105015_2_690x353.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;862×442 30.7 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;No sibling nodes are needed for storage verification. Which allows for a massive increase in arity and decrease in depth of the tree.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Verkle tree proofs require a VC (Vector Commitment) opening proof per tree-level (depth-wise). This means the bigger the arity, the lesser openings we have per proof (as depth decreases wrt arity).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The more leaves/state you need to prove, the more Verkle shines.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;If you pay close attention, for the previous picture, we can see that proving the inclusion of &lt;code&gt;HORSE&lt;/code&gt; requires 3 VC openings + some extra things.&lt;br&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://dankradfeist.de/ethereum/2021/06/18/pcs-multiproofs.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MultiProofs&lt;/a&gt; the overall size of a proof for &lt;strong&gt;ANY AMMOUNT OF LEAVES&lt;/strong&gt; being proven &lt;strong&gt;Sums up to &lt;code&gt;4*32+576=704 bytes + 32 bytes * commitments_in_paths&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;This means Verkle proofs of storage are smaller compared to MPT and Binary trees &lt;strong&gt;FOR ANY AMOUNT OF LEAVES PROVEN&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Verkle Trees enable the capacity of profiting from differential-updatability(which can be less formally understood as homomorphically additive properties). This means we need a lot less data to be fetched from the tree. So you can have a very large arity and not pay the storage costs for it!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is why I say that Differential Updatability is critical for PQ-Verkle trees to make sense&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;Useful short notes on Differential Updatability vs. Stateless Updatability&lt;/summary&gt;&lt;br&gt;- A statelessly-updatable vector commitment (VC) is one that can be updated to reflect changes in an entry using only local information about that change, without needing the entire original vector or additional secret state.In other words, given an old value and its new value at some index, one can compute a token to update the commitment and the corresponding proof for that index, more efficiently than recomputing from scratch.- A differentially-updatable VC is an even stronger notion: the update can be computed using only the difference between the new and old entry ($\delta$), rather than requiring both values separately.In such schemes the commitment is typically homomorphic or linear in the entries, so applying the difference $\delta$ (e.g. adding $\text{m&#39;}_j - m_j$ in an exponent or polynomial) correctly updates the digest and proofs. Every differentially-updatable scheme is inherently statelessly-updatable (since knowing δ is even less information than knowing the old and new values)&lt;/details&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-io-performance-and-improvements-5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;IO performance and improvements&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verkle trees are the best tree-like structures regarding IO performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;There are less nodes overall in the tree thanks to the sparsity of itself.&lt;br&gt;This, essentially means that Verkle trees yield smaller trees (storage-wise).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Accesses to neighbouring positions (e.g. storage with almost the same address or neighbouring code chunks) becomes much cheaper to access. Thus, resulting in IO read rate improvements facilitating possible decreases for opcodes like &lt;code&gt;SLOAD&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethereum-magicians.org/t/rip-7728-l1sload-precompile/20388&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;L1SLOAD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Each internal node only needs to store the commitment to itself, and no reference to its children. This leads to smaller trees, less IO interactions/fetching, smaller opening witness and overall, better performance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As said by &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/gballet&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gballet&lt;/a&gt;: Binary trees might be massaged enough that you can recover some of the same savings, but the lack of possibility to be differentially-updatable will make it difficult to achieve the same results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;With Differential-Updatability, the amount of nodes fetched in order to verify a storage-proof is significantly lower. Thus, improving overall performance of IO proving ops.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/gballet&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@gballet&lt;/a&gt;: […] the IO gain comes from the verification part (no need to read the disk). And also that each node is smaller since it contains no difference, so the iterator sweep of the db is much faster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why does it matter all this matter? &lt;strong&gt;Because IO is the biggest performance killer within ethereum-block execution&lt;/strong&gt;, and so the less data you write at the lowest rate is always better.&lt;br&gt;Also, the smaller tree requires a smaller DB, and DB random reads are a pain in terms of performance, and the larger the DB is, the more painful random reads become.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-would-verkle-be-the-best-solution-if-quantum-computing-is-not-considered-6&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Would Verkle be the best solution if Quantum Computing is not considered?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Short answer, Yes (with KZG undoubtebly, but that’s another discussion).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-storage-proofs-7&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Storage Proofs&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important remark here is that while Verkle Trees provide the “data layout” for extremely efficient proofs to happen. The reality is that IPA’s(Inner Product Argument) VC and IPA-MultiProof scheme are actually the ones doing the heavylifting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One can identify quickly that the proof size that MultiProofs yields its based on 2 things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;IPA (the core primitive of bulletproofs) yields succint and very short proofs thanks to Elliptic Curves being its core engine (among other things that I won’t dive into here).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commitments are extremely short. (1 Bandersnatch EC point &lt;span&gt;\approx 32 \text{bytes})&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;≈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;bytes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; So even though commitments need to be sent alongside the proof, they are actually the same size as a hash. But actually aggregate &lt;strong&gt;A TON&lt;/strong&gt; of leaves or intermediate nodes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/1/5/157166308adda9e543b59f8107074447c9ca33ad.png&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/optimized/3X/1/5/157166308adda9e543b59f8107074447c9ca33ad_2_690x354.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;862×443 30.4 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notice in this image how we actually reduced the 3 VC opening proofs to a single IPA proof that proves all of them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This, when proving state transitions in Ethereum translates into reducing ~(3000-6000) opening proofs to a single IPA proof.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-io-spaceperformance-8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;IO space/performance&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In terms of space the tree takes in disk and performance on reads and random access, Verkle trees would definitely be the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-what-do-researchers-dislike-about-verkle-9&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What do researchers dislike about Verkle?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, this is feedback I’ve been trying to gather. Specially considering the alternatives proposed so far: (&lt;a href=&quot;https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-7864&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Binary Trees&lt;/a&gt; and ZKEVM-MPT).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-pq-resistance-10&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PQ-resistance:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a reason. And multiple concerns/arguments come into play here:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-7748&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;State-tree conversion&lt;/a&gt; is a delicate and complex procedure which could take weeks or even months to be performed by all nodes. It’s a risky thing to do. And going non-PQ Verkle, we would be forced to do 2 tree migrations at least (MPT → Verkle, Verkle → some_PQ_alt).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;ZKEVMs/ZKVMs are PQ-secure (most of them at least, like plonky3-based ones). &lt;strong&gt;BUT&lt;/strong&gt; in order to aggregate all FRI/WHIR/WHATEVER sub-proofs into a single one, &lt;strong&gt;they need to have a distributive way to split the Fiat-Shamir not making it dependent of each RISCV execution trace chunk&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;This is a decent blocker in proving performance for them. &lt;strong&gt;And one way they’re looking to solve this is using Elliptic Curves again!&lt;/strong&gt;. Which will turn ZKVM performance dependant on PQ-insecurity (though alternative solutions exist, just haven’t been deeply checked).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a much larger thing to explain, the TLDR is that these ZKVMs need to use elliptic-curves to decouple FS and make it independant from RISCV execution-trace chunks/overall trace. This, allows them to parallelize a lot more making memory-checking (&lt;strong&gt;but potentially lookups and permutation arguments&lt;/strong&gt; much faster to process**). See more &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/CPerezz19/status/1899242115311325478&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;in this twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;What this comes to say, is that we assumed most of ZKEVM/ZKVM solutions were PQ-secure. But if they actually need Elliptic-curve-based arguments to scale up and give us &lt;em&gt;the golden &lt;code&gt;real time proving&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, we loose the PQ property making ZKVM/ZKEVM approach even more dubious than it already is (for speed and security considerations).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Binary Trees seem to be the best solution atm(unless PQ-Verkle is a thing and is good).&lt;br&gt;The issue with them is that we know proof-size is not going to be nice.&lt;br&gt;Preliminary numbers give ~32 levels of depth of the tree (considering unifying all storage, so code and everything being in the tree too).&lt;br&gt;That means for a single leaf, we need to provide &lt;span&gt;\pi = 32\text{nodes} * 32\text{bytes} \approx 1\text{kB}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;π&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;nodes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;bytes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;≈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;kB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br&gt;Considering we change ~(3000-6000) leaves on each state change, although not linearly, this doesn’t scale well.&lt;br&gt;One could try to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/1586&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WHIR&lt;/a&gt; or some other PIOP to construct a proof that verifies all these openings effectively “compressing” them (recursively aggregating in reality).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main issues that this falls into (after not so rigorous nor deep discussions with &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/wizardofmenlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@WizardOfMenlo&lt;/a&gt;) are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Since we loose all hopes of Opening-proof aggregation (no additively-homomorphic properties exist), we need to prove all the Opening proofs correctness by going &lt;strong&gt;THROUGH EACH ONE OF THEM&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;Doing some quick numbers:&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we take 6000 node updates, at 256 (current arity) items per level, we get to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sage: &lt;span&gt;numerical_approx&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span&gt;6000&lt;/span&gt;*&lt;span&gt;256&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;))&lt;span&gt;20.5507467853832&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;That means &lt;span&gt;2^{20}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; opening verifications. I can’t estimate how does this translate to constraints. But certainly would expect something over &lt;span&gt;2^{23}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It is difficult to actually imagine any hash-based scheme yielding sub-MB proofs except from WHIR itself. And does it with some tradeoffs:&lt;br&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/e/1/e1293b5b7e2461d223075d9ae2232b6fb05c30ab.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;telegram-cloud-photo-size-4-5985836899450865963-y&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/optimized/3X/e/1/e1293b5b7e2461d223075d9ae2232b6fb05c30ab_2_690x152.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;telegram-cloud-photo-size-4-5985836899450865963-y&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;telegram-cloud-photo-size-4-5985836899450865963-y&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1280×282 53.3 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, this would mean that &lt;strong&gt;we loose the &lt;em&gt;Differential Updatability&lt;/em&gt; property. Which significantly impacts IO-related performance in disk reads/access.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That being said, remains to be seen and further explored how good this solution could actually be. As 100kB-1MB proofs aren’t crazy at all (for what PQ-proofs refers to). This comes to say that this isn’t a bad idea at all. Rather not a really good one apparently.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;A short, non-technical explanation for this is that as Sanso mentioned to me some time ago: Elliptic Curves are an anomaly. They have it all (Short proof sizes, fast provers, additively-homomorphic properties, pairings…).&lt;br&gt;We got used to it and now it seems to us that the alternatives (specially PQ-schemes) aren’t close. But we need to accept that these weren’t the rule, rather the exception.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-zk-unfriendliness-11&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;ZK-(un)friendliness&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arithmetizing problems in SNARKs is (and might always be) a huge deal-breaker in terms of performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most challenging aspects of working within SNARK circuits is the optimal arithmetization of what’s known as “wrong-field arithmetic” or simply “foreign field arithmetic.” This operation performs so poorly that people have historically addressed the issue by embedding elliptic curves. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dusk-network/dusk-zerocaf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;I did it myself here for Curve25519&lt;/a&gt;. When working within SNARK circuits, we represent our witness using a finite field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You are not guaranteed to find a curve that possesses the properties you need, nor is it guaranteed to exist. Additionally, such a curve might lack pairings—due, for example, to the Hasse bound—or simply because it cannot be constructed with certain parameters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In STARKs, however, this is not even an option; we always need to emulate arithmetic over foreign fields. This is what &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; ZKEVMs do nowadays, with &lt;code&gt;Secp256k1&lt;/code&gt; as an example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verkle, in this case, uses Banderwagon/Bandersnatch. You can see more details in this post from Kev: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/2yWlVSf_SA-CKba5ZdQ60g&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Understanding The Wagon - From Bandersnatch to Banderwagon&lt;/a&gt;. To simplify, any proving system (in fact, all ZKEVMs) must simulate arithmetic modulo Banderwagon’s base field. As mentioned earlier, field emulation is slow, difficult to reason about, and a pain to implement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is clearly problematic. We all know that, but it can be done—and at least benchmarked (to my knowledge, no results have been published).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-can-we-actually-_harden_-verkle-12&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Can we actually &lt;em&gt;harden&lt;/em&gt; Verkle?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you made it here, congrats! You’re arriving at the most exciting part!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-zk-unfriendliness-13&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;ZK-(un)friendliness&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PQ-Verkle based most-likely on lattices might not be anything close to how bad the arithmetization of elliptic curves is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not because they are simpler. But because usually within the polynomial rings used there, we end up working with primitives of ~64bytes.&lt;br&gt;In particular, we could try to use a field like Goldilocks over polynomial ring. That could basically make this “native” for ZKEVMS or STARKS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This remains to be seen. And it’s a big unknown. But I’d definitely expect the situation to be better than in the case of Verkle+Bandersnatch one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-pq-resistance-14&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PQ-resistance&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the biggest concern against Verkle trees. In order to solve this we need the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A VC that yields small opening proofs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A VC that yields aggregatable/foldable/accumulative opening proofs resulting in significant size-reduction for state proofs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The resulting aformentioned aggregation results are actually small too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The VC or the method to aggregate the openings require no setup.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Everything is efficiently-computable by &lt;a href=&quot;https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-7870#specification&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;the block-proposer hardware requirements&lt;/a&gt; within a reasonable performance that allows for enough time for block propagation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commitments are small (EC-point size or less, so &lt;span&gt;\approx 32\text{bytes}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;≈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;bytes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-details-to-pay-attention-to-15&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Details to pay attention to&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the literature on PCS targets:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commit to &lt;strong&gt;VERY LARGE POLYNOMIALS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Produce succint opening proofs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s important to notice here that we actually don’t care about the first one. And most likely the second one isn’t crucial.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See, tree-level’s width (arity) within Verkle is &lt;span&gt;256&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;256&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; elements. And could potentially be &lt;span&gt;1024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1024&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; or more as advised by some back then. A VC scheme is designed to commit to vectors of lots of elements. Sets of &lt;span&gt;\approx 2^{30}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;≈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; elements. This means there are potential tradeoffs we can take there to actually trade committed vector-size by proof-size or verification complexity among others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On another note, a lot of PCS and VCS have the goal of providing succint opening proofs.&lt;br&gt;BUT, again here, succint opening proofs might not be needed. Specially considering we want to then aggregate them. &lt;strong&gt;It’s the result of the aggregation what needs to be succint&lt;/strong&gt; (or close to it).&lt;br&gt;We can go even further. &lt;strong&gt;Even a linear verifier or quasi-linear would be good.&lt;br&gt;This is because the vectors we commit to are really small&lt;/strong&gt;. So computations that are &lt;span&gt;\approx \text{O}(k*N + c)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;≈&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;∗&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; where &lt;span&gt;\text{\{k, c\}}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{k, c}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; aren’t some crazy constants would be run within &lt;code&gt;ms&lt;/code&gt; or less.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-sota-in-pq-vector-commitments-specially-lattice-based-ones-16&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;SoTA in PQ-Vector commitments (specially lattice-based ones)&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, there are some recent works which have achieved outstanding results in terms of opening-proof size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-vector-and-functional-commitments-from-lattices-httpseprintiacrorg20211254pdf-17&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Vector and Functional commitments from lattices” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2021/1254.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2021/1254.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generally, pre-2020 lattice VCs either had large proofs or relied on a trapdoor setup, limiting their practicality. An example is this work (PPS21), which yields post-quantum VC with shorter proofs (compared to prev literature like Libert et al. work on SIS-based commitments and ZKPs in 2016) but at the cost of a private-key setup (a trapdoor generated by an authority).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/5/e/5e2b548d4388b7dfdf4dc01ce8b87ca774c934bd.png&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/5/e/5e2b548d4388b7dfdf4dc01ce8b87ca774c934bd.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;464×225 16.6 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So as a summary, with this scheme, we sadly get:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trusted setup requirements.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not so good assymptotics. Much worse than Merkle trees.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-scheme-introduced-in-polynomial-commitments-from-lattices-post-quantum-security-fast-verification-and-transparent-setup-httpseprintiacrorg2024281pdf-18&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Scheme introduced in “Polynomial Commitments from Lattices: Post-Quantum Security, Fast Verification and Transparent Setup” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/281.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/281.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This work bridges some initial discoveries made in Module-SIS problem-based schemes to the first really practical scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In particular it has commitment and proof size too big for our purposes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/5/f/5f2d059ee755c6f4b4a641e493776a0f56df7670.png&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/5/f/5f2d059ee755c6f4b4a641e493776a0f56df7670.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1006×402 18.4 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;So not many tradeoffs that we can apparently take here without overcomplicating or significantly increasing proving time.&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-functional-commitments-for-all-functions-with-transparent-setup-and-from-sis-httpseprintiacrorg20221368pdf-19&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“Functional Commitments for All Functions with Transparent Setup and from SIS” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/1368.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/1368.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A really nice suggestion made by Dr Ngoc Khanh Nguyen (one of the main experts within the field) was this work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scheme introduced here, &lt;strong&gt;aside from being statessly updatable&lt;/strong&gt;, improves over prior SoTA stablished in &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2021/1254.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PPS21&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;One can see why by looking at the table:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/1/e/1e11e82d884c797c904da0eaff563963724c5b21.png&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/optimized/3X/1/e/1e11e82d884c797c904da0eaff563963724c5b21_2_690x410.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;1284×764 135 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;We get rid of the squared terms in complexity for the parameters size. As well as the linear size in the proof.&lt;p&gt;Overall, this scheme looks super promising for our use case and one of the ones I’d be interested on analyzing much more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;O(\text{log}^2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;-sized proofs for sets/vectors of at most 1024 elements yields insanely small opening proofs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Statessly-updatability is an awesome feature for Verkle.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Commitment/Proving time aren’t exponential nor anything similar. So we don’t need to worry.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only one question remains for this scheme, which is if we can acually integrate a MultiProofs-like solution&lt;/strong&gt; which accumulates all the opening proofs resulting on a single final one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-greyhound-httpseprintiacrorg20241293pdf-20&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Greyhound (&lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/1293.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/1293.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/c/1/c135a971d9bbe2ec009e4fd205007c4cd2fdcf75.png&quot; title=&quot;image&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/uploads/default/original/3X/c/1/c135a971d9bbe2ec009e4fd205007c4cd2fdcf75.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;472×159 9.04 KB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that sizes here are in kB&lt;/em&gt;&lt;p&gt;So this is one of the latest achievements in PCS-land. Mainly, it obliterates all previous work while also achieving much faster verifiers in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greyhound itself, can be turned into a VCS by interpolating the values polynomial with another polynomial representing the position indexes where values are stored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Khan suggested that while you can obtain a VCS from it, it’s not obvious if it can actually be statessly-updatable. And which would be the tradeoffs that one needs to to in order to get such benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is certainly possible, is to take all the openings needed in a state proof, batch them and use Greyhound to get a &lt;span&gt;O(\sqrt{N})&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;√&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;N&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;-sized proof which can then be thrown to LaBRADOR if needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested on understanding the SoTA of the field, the section 1.1 of this paper does a quite good job at doing so. At least with all the related work to this paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-aggregatability-21&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Aggregatability&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-labrador-usage-is-available-but-not-desirable-22&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;LaBRADOR usage is available but not desirable.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although we could (as suggested by both Khan and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/u/wizardofmenlo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;@WizardOfMenlo&lt;/a&gt;) use a lattice-based proving scheme like &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/1341&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;LaBRADOR&lt;/a&gt; in order to help getting a sub-linear sized proof. This would significantly increase the complexity of the overall solution (the only implementation in existence atm is quite optimized but also &lt;strong&gt;extremely complex to use&lt;/strong&gt;.).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So unless someone with a lot of courage to take &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lazer-crypto/lazer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;GitHub - lazer-crypto/lazer&lt;/a&gt; and rewrite it exists, I’d much rather prefer trying to exploit additively-homomorphic properties to try to accumulate opening proofs without involving proving schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-using-hash-based-proof-systems-for-accumulation-23&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Using hash-based proof systems for accumulation&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One potential path forward is to use a proving scheme like &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/1586&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WHIR&lt;/a&gt; which can yield decently-sized proofs which can be succintly verified (&lt;span&gt;\lt 100\text{kB}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;kB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHIR would drop the requirement for the Opening Proofs to be aggregatable. Thus, enabling more schemes to be used.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the good things about that is that hash-based proving systems are widely deployed and hashes have been studied for long time. So a lot less “exotic” solutions are much more likely to be secure and therefore, have higher chances  making it to mainnet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doing some quick numbers:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we take 6000 node updates, at 256 (current arity) items per level, we get to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sage: &lt;span&gt;numerical_approx&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span&gt;6000&lt;/span&gt;*&lt;span&gt;256&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;))&lt;span&gt;20.5507467853832&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;2^{20}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; nodes to update in worst-case situations (more in the future ofc as we plan to raise gas_limits once statelessness hits mainnet).&lt;br&gt;What could we expect from WHIR here? As in proving-time and proof-size? This questions should be answered for the VCs that we potentially could use.&lt;br&gt;Such that we can discard or heavily consider some of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-opening-accumulation-via-additive-homomorphism-24&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Opening-accumulation via additive-homomorphism&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As in &lt;code&gt;Multiproofs&lt;/code&gt; solution, one would like to compress opening proofs produced at each tree-level by the vector commitment (VC) scheme, while keeping constant-size (or quasi-constant) for the resulting artifact while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This essentially means that we have extremely short proofs, a similar result to what we see in the Beacon chain when Bls signatures get aggregated into a final one that has the same size as any of the original ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It remains to be seen (at least I’m not aware) if there are any VC schemes that have such properties and are PQ-secure.&lt;br&gt;But there are definitely proving schemes that can help us to get there as IPA is doing in MultiProofs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, the preference would be to not need those, as this adds another component within the overall solution and makes it more complex. Which is never desired.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-differential-updatability-25&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Differential Updatability&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the schemes shared previously, only a few were compliant with this feature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remains to be seen if for awesome schemes like Greyhound, achieving this incurrs into a big cost or tradeoff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, it’s important to remember that &lt;strong&gt;THIS IS A MUST HAVE FEATURE&lt;/strong&gt;. As without it, all our aggregation and node-updatability plan to efficiently remove tree-size gets truncated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethresear.ch/#p-53508-conclusions-26&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;PQ-Verkle would tick all the boxes as the main contender for statelessness and storage structure to be used witin ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it’s at least worth investing a bit of time on analyzing a bit more deeply how much we can actually get from this. And which would be the realistic alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it’s equally important to keep &lt;strong&gt;ALWAYS&lt;/strong&gt; in mind, that a good solution isn’t something that works well now. Rather something that will work well when we 10x block gas limits!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve met various people while working on this idea that are working on similar things. And researchers seem to find it an attractive problem to tackle. Which motivates the believe that we might be into something. We weren’t the only ones looking into it and we’re already syncing with these researchers to understand their approaches and ideas/results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for the most promising path atm?&lt;br&gt;Well, it seems that &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/1368.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/1368.pdf&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best ways to go atm.&lt;br&gt;Specially since a linear-verifier isn’t an issue when we have openings of 1024 elements at max.&lt;br&gt;Not only that, but is also important to remark that is one of the few SIS-based scheme that supports differential-updatability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So one of the next steps that we should likely take is to actually evaluate what’s the best approach for opening proof aggregation. Followed up by an identification of the weakest points of the solution (if any) and a comparison against other proposals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s also important to acknowledge that this is yet another complex solution for ethereum.&lt;br&gt;I think the overall protocol complexity discussion should take place elsewhere. But definitely is a conversation that will need to happen. And not for this proposal only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17016255</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17016255</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:46:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Ethereum Research</author><category>Extraterrestrial Token</category><category>Smart Contracts</category><category>Layer 1</category><category>DeFi</category><category>Items</category></item><item><title></title><description>It’s your LAST CHANCE to claim your points and be eligible for a $BLIFFY allocation!&lt;br&gt;🚨 Snapshot for BLIFE Communities happens in less than 24h.&lt;br&gt;Don’t fade this.&lt;br&gt;Here’s what you need to do 👇 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/abdf8d59747a9dea63858ac4975471a9.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Reward distribution explained&lt;br&gt;We’ve designed a custom reward system that’s both fair and motivating for everyone in the top 10,000.&lt;br&gt;🏆 The highest ranks get significantly more: recognizing their exceptional effort.&lt;br&gt;🤝 But everyone who makes it into the top 10,000 gets a &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  🧠 Reminder: $BLIFFY snapshot includes holders of:&lt;br&gt;• BLIFE ID leaderboard (min 2,000 pts)&lt;br&gt;• Sparks&lt;br&gt;• Trumpstones&lt;br&gt;• BLIFStones&lt;br&gt;• BOTS winners&lt;br&gt;• Founders Watch&lt;br&gt;Bliffy is watching the blockchain... Are you in? 👀 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17015331</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17015331</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 16:02:58 GMT</pubDate><author>BLIFE Protocol</author></item><item><title></title><description>$2.5M Raised to Turn American Homes into Onchain Assets&lt;br&gt;Manifest secured a pre-seed round from @vaneck_us, @lattice_fund, @CompoundVC, @SALTConference, and is accelerated by @alliancedao and @CV_Labs.&lt;br&gt;The funding supports the launch of $USH, a tokenized real estate asset, and &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/f44b39c69b2c42ed176dc3fb4f5eec91.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  The Real Estate Problem and Why Tokenization Hasn’t Worked&lt;br&gt;Tokenized real estate has struggled because fractionalized ownership doesn’t scale. Investors still face illiquidity, high fees, and management headaches.&lt;br&gt;Manifest fixes this by turning U.S. real estate into a scalable, &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  Introducing $USH, Real Estate at the Speed of Blockchain&lt;br&gt;$USH is a tokenized real estate asset backed by Home Equity Investments (HEIs), designed for seamless access and integration with DeFi.&lt;br&gt;It provides institutional-grade exposure, off-market discounts, DeFi composability, &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17012545</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17012545</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 13:39:49 GMT</pubDate><author>Manifest Finance</author><category>DeFi</category></item><item><title></title><description>$BTC closed the week above the prior candle, leaving behind a likely Swing Low.  Stocks should have bottomed, for now, too.
No real excuses left now for the bulls, the Cycle count is on their side.  (Week 3).</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17010441</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17010441</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 10:43:11 GMT</pubDate><author>Bob Loukas 🗽</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title></title><description>my plan worked perfectly we had important increases on my level even of 100/200% on some altcoins now we are approaching the key resistance again ... if we have a breakout of this level you will observe other big increases
$TOTAL 2</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17008056</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17008056</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 08:20:09 GMT</pubDate><author>EliZ</author></item><item><title>When SEC officials were sent bullets: Who is manipulating $744 million in funds to long on Bitcoin?</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 21, 2025, the first crypto roundtable of the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) was full of gunpowder. When former SEC enforcement official John Reed Stark said that &quot;crypto investors have received death threats&quot;, this debate on &quot;securities attributes&quot; was not only a dispute over the legal framework, but also the ultimate game for the survival of the crypto industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At the same time, the Bitcoin ETF ended its five-week bleeding cycle with a single-week capital inflow of US$744 million, while Ethereum chain activities fell to a historical low - this dual change in regulation and the market is reshaping the power map of the crypto world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; SEC’s “Definition War”: Regulatory rifts behind death threats &lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.blockbeats.cn/file_v6/20250324/17083805-6e0b-446f-996c-582478c7e9b0.png?x-oss-process=image/quality,q_50/format,webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On March 21, 2025, at the first crypto roundtable of the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), former law enforcement official John Reed Stark’s speech was like a depth bomb, detonating the decade-long regulatory war in the crypto world - &quot;Whenever I advocate for tighter regulation in public, I receive death threats from crypto investors.&quot; This naked accusation not only reveals the bloody confrontation between regulators and the crypto community, but also pushes the ultimate game about the &quot;attributes of securities&quot; to a critical point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The fuse of this war has been laid long ago. Since the SEC launched a series of lawsuits against Coinbase and Binance in 2022, the confrontation between regulators and crypto companies has spread from the courts to the streets. SEC Chairman Gary Gensler&#39;s office records show that he personally received more than 200 death threat emails from around the world between 2023 and 2024. One anonymous letter from Australia even attached a photo of a bullet and wrote, &quot;Crypto freedom cannot be tarnished.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Behind these extreme behaviors is the desperate resistance of crypto fundamentalists to the SEC’s “full securitization” strategy - if 90% of tokens are included in the securities regulatory framework, the living space of decentralized finance (DeFi) will be completely strangled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But the SEC&#39;s iron-fisted supervision is not an isolated action. The new Republican-led SEC committee is trying to reconstruct the power map of the crypto world: the resignation of former chairman Gary Gensler and the establishment of the Crypto Task Force indicate that the Trump administration is dismantling the policy legacy of the Democratic era through &quot;redistribution of regulatory power.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The new acting chairman Mark Uyeda revealed in a closed-door meeting that the SEC may open an exemption channel for NFTs and utility tokens through a &quot;non-securitization statement.&quot; This policy shift may subvert the compliance cost structure of trading platforms such as Coinbase and Kraken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The essence of this battle for definitional rights is a head-on collision between the Howey Test of the 1930s and the Fourth Industrial Revolution. Teresa Goody Guillen, partner of BakerHostetler, pointed out sharply at the roundtable: &quot;When distributed ledger technology (DLT) reconstructs the global business model, the SEC is trying to use the rusty key of &quot;investment contracts&quot; to open the regulatory chain of the digital age.&quot; This contradiction is particularly prominent in the field of NFTs - on the one hand, the SEC acquiesces to the non-securities attributes of leading projects such as BAYC and CryptoPunks, but on the other hand, it has launched a series of lawsuits against social tokens and fan economy NFTs, exposing the fragmentation and opportunism of regulatory logic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Bitcoin ETF&#39;s &quot;Ice and Fire Reversal&quot;: $744 million in weekly inflows hides a mystery&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt; While regulators are mired in the quagmire of definitional power, capital is rewriting the market narrative with real money. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.blockbeats.cn/file_v6/20250324/7a102173-c4ad-423d-8161-7b926fd5adb6.png?x-oss-process=image/quality,q_50/format,webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; From March 17 to 21, the US Bitcoin ETF ended its five-week losing streak with a weekly net inflow of US$744 million. BlackRock IBIT attracted US$105 million in a single day, and the cumulative total net inflow exceeded US$36 billion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But behind this round of &quot;institutional buy the dips&quot;, a secret arbitrage game is being played: the premium rate of Bitcoin futures on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME) continues to narrow to below 2%, causing the arbitrage space between spot ETFs and futures contracts to disappear, and nearly 40% of the capital inflows have been confirmed to have nothing to do with &quot;real demand.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; What is more worthy of attention is the divergence of market consensus. Although the price of Bitcoin has been trading sideways in the range of $83,000-85,500, the on-chain data shows a completely different story: Glassnode has detected that long-term holders (LTH) have increased their holdings of 250,000 BTC in the past 45 days, worth about $21 billion, while the Bitcoin reserves of centralized trading platforms have fallen to the lowest level since 2021. This divergence between &quot;institutional hoarding&quot; and &quot;retail investors leaving the market&quot; suggests that the market is accumulating momentum for a new round of volatility. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.blockbeats.cn/file_v6/20250324/16a2a26f-b82e-488f-a7e9-06aa901e3bbb.png?x-oss-process=image/quality,q_50/format,webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ethereum’s “Darkest Hour”: The Ecosystem Collapse Behind the Layer2 Boom&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt; As Bitcoin ETF regains capital favor, the Ethereum ecosystem is experiencing an unprecedented cold winter. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.blockbeats.cn/file_v6/20250324/0baaae09-f005-4824-b44f-4b428c7c76fc.png?x-oss-process=image/quality,q_50/format,webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Data from The Block shows that on March 22, Ethereum&#39;s daily destruction volume fell to 53.07 ETH (about US$106,000), a 99% decrease from the peak in 2024. The three major indicators of on-chain transaction volume, number of active addresses, and gas fees all fell to historical lows. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.blockbeats.cn/file_v6/20250324/f9436c18-b2ec-4809-8b29-24b219250538.png?x-oss-process=image/quality,q_50/format,webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At the same time, the total locked value (TVL) of Layer2 fell to US$37.8 billion, but leading networks such as Base and Arbitrum accounted for 80% of DEX trading volume. This paradox of &quot;hollowing out of the mainnet&quot; and &quot;Layer2 hegemony&quot; exposes the fundamental flaws of Ethereum&#39;s economic model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Standard Chartered Bank’s forecast has heightened market concerns. The bank halved Ethereum’s 2025 target price from $10,000 to $4,000, pointing directly to the “siphon effect” of Layer2 on the value of the mainnet: “Layer2 such as Base captures 80% of the ecosystem value-added, but only feeds back less than 20% of the fee income to the mainnet.” This unsustainable profit-sharing mechanism has caused the ETH/BTC exchange rate to fall to a historic low of 0.023, even lower than the performance of tokens of competing public chains such as Solana.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The more far-reaching impact comes from regulatory pressure. In the Memecoin Statement, the SEC defined a safe zone for POW assets such as Dogecoin, but remained silent on Ethereum and Layer2 tokens. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.blockbeats.cn/file_v6/20250324/da113960-a4d7-4ab8-968e-cb894416e7ce.png?x-oss-process=image/quality,q_50/format,webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This uncertainty forced funds such as Grayscale ETHE to experience outflows of $102 million in a single week, with cumulative outflows of over $730 million over four weeks, which is shaking the foundation of Ethereum as an &quot;institutional asset.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; The way out: regulatory arbitrage, technological revolution and sovereignty game&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt; In this multi-crisis, three variables will determine the ultimate direction of the crypto market:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 1. The End and Reconstruction of Regulatory Arbitrage&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; The SEC&#39;s crackdown on &quot;securitized tokens&quot; has extended from trading platforms to Layer2 protocols. In March 2025, Coinbase announced the acquisition of the Deribit trading platform and took over the Dubai license, indicating that American companies are evading regulatory risks through offshore structures. However, the &quot;Stablecoin Act&quot; promoted by the Trump administration shows that sovereign states will not allow a regulatory vacuum - the bill requires stablecoin issuers to hold 1:1 cash reserves and prohibits technology companies from getting involved in this field. This &quot;precision sniping&quot; may reshape the $120 billion stablecoin market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 2. Paradox and breakthrough of technological revolution&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; Ethereum developers postponed the Prague upgrade for the 153rd time, exposing the weakness of technology iteration. In contrast, the Bitcoin ecosystem has exploded: the Ordinals protocol has pushed the on-chain NFT transaction volume to over $1 billion, and the Rune protocol has increased BTCFi&#39;s locked position by 300% in a single month. When &quot;Bitcoin programmability&quot; moves from concept to implementation, this self-revolution of the &quot;ancient blockchain&quot; may subvert the survival logic of &quot;Ethereum killers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 3. The rise and game of sovereign digital assets&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; Putin&#39;s declaration that &quot;no one can ban Bitcoin&quot; resonates with Trump&#39;s crypto-friendly policies. Russia plans to build a compliant Bitcoin trading system based on the Moscow Exchange (MOEX), and India&#39;s digital rupee pilot has attracted 15% of crypto offshore funds to return - this &quot;sovereign digital competition&quot; is undermining the hegemony of the US dollar stablecoin and may give birth to a new geo-financial order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt; Conclusion: Finding Certainty in the Reconstruction of Order&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt; The crypto world in 2025 is standing on the fault line where traditional finance and the ideal of decentralization collide. The regulatory game of the SEC, the institutional narrative of Bitcoin ETF, and the ecological dilemma of Ethereum together outline an industry picture full of tension. When death threats and trillions of capital pour into the same battlefield, when the Howey test 89 years ago encounters the fourth industrial revolution, this change has long surpassed the scope of technology and has become an epic experiment for humans to reshape the value exchange system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.marsbit.co/20250324080436301592.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Original link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Welcome to join the BlockBeats official community:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Telegram subscription group: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/theblockbeats&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://t.me/theblockbeats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Telegram group: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.me/BlockBeats_App&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://t.me/BlockBeats_App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Official Twitter account: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BlockBeatsAsia&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/BlockBeatsAsia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17005552</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17005552</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 04:18:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author><category>Layer 1</category><category>Smart Contracts</category><category>ETF</category></item><item><title>The Great Secrecy is Private, Written Before Nillion Coin Launch</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It’s not that privacy technology is not important, but that the combination of privacy technology and tokens is no longer important, at least not at this stage.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt;Written by: Zuo Ye&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Shang Yang knows the strength of horses, and Bigan knows the heart of people. When NIL ascends to the sky, XMR will be delisted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Blockchain originated from privacy technology, especially cryptography. From elliptic curves to zero-knowledge proofs, all of them prove the success of privacy economics in the Web 3.0 era.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But things are not perfect. From XMR being frequently delisted from CEX/DEX to the arrest of the founder of Tornado Cash, you will find that even if Nillion can be listed on Binance, the geek spirit of privacy projects is retreating, and its final product delivery capabilities are far from perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; When it comes to polishing privacy products, blockchain projects of the same type need to learn from their Web2 counterparts and improve their own posture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proton proves that privacy can be a well-functioning product&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; Privacy is a Feature, Not a Product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Simply talking about privacy to strengthen the product form is meaningless. In other words, privacy also requires PMF. The reason why giants such as Google and Meta can violate privacy while making people unable to stop is because of convenience and network effects. They can be used out of the box and everyone uses them. Even individuals have to use them in office scenarios, so they will eventually accept everything from Google.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.techflowpost.com/upload/images/20250324/2025032409345145818575.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Image caption: Giant fined, Image source: Proton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On this point, the regulatory authorities&#39; model of using fines to replace regulation has failed miserably. Even taking the legendary penalty-resistant Google&#39;s $2.974 billion as an example, Google would only need about 16 more days to earn it back, and these fines cannot be converted into revenue for European technology companies, leading to their further powerlessness in the face of Google.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Faced with this problem, Proton&#39;s approach is to build its own full range of products, starting from CERN (European Organization for Nuclear Research). The pure inherent credibility of scientific researchers is higher than that of commercial companies. Cryptography technology, open source code, and product audits are used to build privacy products that are truly meaningful - you can achieve the corresponding functions without using Google&#39;s full range of products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Of course, the current network effects and scale effects are still unable to compete with the giants, but compared with their blockchain peers, the products they provide are sufficient for daily use and are qualified Google Alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.techflowpost.com/upload/images/20250324/2025032409345167874742.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Image description: Pronton products and part comparison, Image source: @zuoyeweb3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Compared with the entire Google Workspace family, the current Proton is basically a counterpart to Proton Mail itself. It is worth mentioning that Proton Mail is also the favorite of Jack Dorsey, the founder of Twitter and Square.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Proton Mail is different from general email products. It can be used without binding a mobile phone number, and supports end-to-end encryption mode to ensure the privacy transmission of emails. Before Telegram is regulated, it can be used in conjunction with TG&#39;s end-to-end mode to basically build a relatively high level of commercial privacy experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Of course, after the fall of Telegram, Proton Mail combined with Signal can also meet the privacy surfing needs of most people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Similar to Telegram, Proton has also begun to enter the Web3 field. Its first product is Proton Wallet. Unlike transaction-oriented products such as Bitget Wallet and Binance Wallet, Proton Wallet is extremely restrained and has relatively simple functions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The significance of Proton is to prove the feasibility of building products based on privacy technology. Different from the advertising profit model of traditional giants, Proton adopts a payment system. Different from the token economics system of Web3 peers, Proton has not reached the stage of issuing coins. We can call it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The non-tokenization practice of crypto technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; From Skiff to Nillion, the Tokenization of Crypto Technology&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; If Pronton is considered to be Don Quixote, then Skiff, Nym, Privasea to Nillion are dwarfs, whose own PMF has not been found yet, but the token (Snow White) has taken the lead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On February 9, 2024, Notion announced the acquisition of Skiff. This is also the first case of a large Web2 product acquiring a Web3 startup. It did not take the coin issuance route to create a new trend in the industry. By the way, this is actually the second time Stripe has acquired Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Skiff is also similar to the Google Suite, with a document suite based on IPFS and an encrypted mailbox service. However, there is a huge problem: the UI is extremely ugly and there is no experience in using it. This is also the biggest problem with current Web3 products. Limited by the slowness and high cost of the underlying blockchain, it is difficult to develop large products based on it to beat Web2 counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Proton is a suitable Google Alternative, but Skiff is not a qualified Proton Alternative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In addition, the development of other Web3 privacy products is also not satisfactory. Nym gradually shifted its focus to the VPN field in the later period. Privasea in the FHE direction emphasized more on adaptation in the AI field, and today&#39;s Nillion is still within the MPC narrative of the previous cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Yes, the narrative is divided into periods. The concepts such as MPC and blind computing (NBC) built by Nillion are derivative narratives of Ethereum and ZK applications in the L2/Rollup field. AA wallet and MPC paradigm belong to this category. With the weakness of Ethereum coin price, privacy technology products are being abandoned by the market. The most obvious is that FHE has not become the next step of ZK. Face-slapping article reference: FHE is the next step of ZK, encryption technology says so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It’s not that privacy technology is not important, but that the combination of privacy technology and tokens is no longer important, at least not at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Without privacy technology, Proton cannot build its own business logic and product matrix, which is a good PMF model. However, for products such as Nillion, the investment of Binance and Hack VC seems to be more important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As for the concept of blind computing, the trusted layer, multi-ecosystem, and privacy AI are not Nillion’s real profit sources. We all know that Nillion’s only product may be its own token. From this point of view, at least Nym really wants to grab the VPN market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.techflowpost.com/upload/images/20250324/2025032409345174036928.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Image description: Nillion&#39;s latest paper, Image source: Nillion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the latest technical paper, Nillion&#39;s research focus is still on the practice of MPC. The traditional secret sharing MPC algorithm will cause a sharp increase in the amount of data during calculation, and Nillion is studying how to reduce the complexity of the algorithm to improve computing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Well, let’s take a look at the opening performance of Nillion tokens. As I said before, this kind of Web3 privacy technology combined with AI cannot find real application scenarios because OpenAI and DeepSeek do not have these factors. If new products with privacy technology can grab market share from them, then it will be a meaningful pioneering move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; If that doesn&#39;t make sense, then check out @Optimism, which really thinks privacy is important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.techflowpost.com/upload/images/20250324/2025032409345183549853.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Privacy is Good and still needs to be demonstrated by Privacy Products. It is meaningless to talk about MPC/ZK/TEE/FHE/AI in vain. Everyone can say empty slogans that do not solve the problem, but they will ultimately damage the social credibility of the technology behind them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The bad consequences have already appeared. Now people are afraid of L2, and they also feel that ZK is a scam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; After Safe caused huge losses to Bybit, not only Vitalik remained silent, but also the front-end brother and the multi-signature mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; Monero (XMR) is a little unfamiliar to people in the BNB Chain Meme speed-passing era, but it should be the last attempt after Bitcoin to truly consider how to combine cryptographic technology with its own application scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On February 7, 2024, two days before Skiff officially announced its &quot;joining&quot; Notion, XMR was delisted by Binance, &quot;exiting&quot; the largest source of liquidity. Perhaps from now on, the so-called privacy technology will be like the F-47, just a part of winning science, but Web3 privacy economics has not yet finally gone bankrupt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17004013</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17004013</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 01:34:51 GMT</pubDate><author>TechFlow</author><category>Nillion</category><category>Privacy</category></item><item><title>Liquidity continues to tighten, is the bull market turning around or has it come to an end?</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;From the MVRV ratio perspective, ETH is currently at a bear market level.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Written by: ChandlerZ, Foresight News&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, after a period of bull market boom, the crypto asset market has begun to show signs of liquidity contraction and changes in investor risk appetite. On-chain data and key derivatives market indicators suggest that the market is transitioning from a high volatility, high speculation state to a more cautious, low liquidity phase. The on-chain activities of Bitcoin and Ethereum show a significant decrease in hot supply and a notable reduction in exchange fund inflows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is the market currently at a turning point? Is it a bull market reversal or the end of a bull run? How should investors seize opportunities amid shrinking liquidity and adjusting risk appetite? This article aims to analyze the current market environment based on on-chain activities of Bitcoin and Ethereum, exchange fund flows, and market dynamics data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Overall Liquidity Tightening and Decreased Market Activity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to glassnode data, Bitcoin on-chain activity has dropped to a level not seen in months, with a significant decrease in transaction numbers, often indicating a consolidation period after high volatility. Bitcoin&#39;s &quot;Hot Supply&quot; is an indicator measuring and quantifying active market capital, representing the volume of Bitcoin held for less than a week. This indicator has dropped from 5.9% to 2.8% over the past three months, showing a decrease of over 50%, further supporting the liquidity contraction phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/7d1b1cf2572c50fa04617bc8c69f92b9.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking solely at on-chain transactions, Bitcoin&#39;s on-chain activity has also decreased to a level not seen in months, indicating a cooling period or short-term interest decline. The reduction in transaction numbers seems to suggest a decrease in speculative activity. If long-term holders are not selling and new fund inflows are limited, the market may enter an accumulation phase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/df922a2e4e764633020ccbd66690b8c3.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Bitcoin miners&#39; share of total on-chain transactions has dropped to 4.23%, the lowest level since November 2022. This data reflects a significant decrease in miners&#39; participation in on-chain trading activities. The lower transaction share may indicate that miners are reducing selling behavior, more often choosing to hold coins to cope with market fluctuations, thereby reducing selling pressure from miner sales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The relative decline in miner transaction volume may also mean that other market participants (such as long-term holders or institutional investors) are more active, with an overall change in on-chain transaction structure. Against the backdrop of market changes and declining mining revenues, miners may be adjusting strategies, reducing frequent on-chain transactions, and focusing resources on optimizing revenue structures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/8b3e2e360afe3de3d4e5c4306072019d.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the futures market, the total open interest has dropped from the ATH of $57B to $37B, a decline of about 35%, indicating a significant reduction in hedging and speculative activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, after the US spot ETF launch in 2024, institutions had previously gained arbitrage profits (Longing ETF + Short futures) in an upward market. However, with weakening market confidence and the unwinding of long-side arbitrage, arbitrage trades have gradually withdrawn, causing ETF fund outflows and further downward pressure on the spot market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/4339e52a797c996ea04ae1a3c9f58c9b.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ethereum Exchange Supply Drops to Near 10-Year Low&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to data from crypto market analysis firm Santiment, due to DeFi protocols and staking products, the available ETH supply on exchanges has dropped to 8.97 million (equivalent to $17.8 billion at current prices, less than 7.5% of Ethereum&#39;s current market cap), the lowest level in nearly 10 years (previous low was November 2015). Compared to just 7 weeks ago, ETH on trading platforms has decreased by 16.4%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drop in Ethereum exchange supply to a near 10-year low indicates a significant tightening of market liquidity. Lower exchange supply means fewer ETH available for sale, reducing potential selling pressure, but also making prices more susceptible to large trades and increasing volatility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/b5131cf4f00ceff9f3b5521aaef5e537.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, in the current state, despite the decline in exchange supply showing an enhanced asset locking effect, the overall market environment and multiple factors still exert downward pressure on prices. The current uncertainty in the macroeconomic environment, changes in market risk appetite, and partial withdrawal of institutional funds are further tightening market liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, volatility in the DeFi sector and the development of competitive public chains are negatively impacting Ethereum&#39;s market expectations. In this context, while lower exchange supply reduces potential selling pressure, unfavorable market sentiment and external environmental factors continue to drive prices downward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using indicators to assess its current state, according to IntoTheBlock data, ETH&#39;s MVRV (Market Value to Realized Value ratio) has dropped to around 0.8. This level is uncommon in Ethereum&#39;s history and typically occurs during bear markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MVRV is usually used to compare the relationship between a token&#39;s market value and realized value, reflecting the supply and demand dynamics of the token in the market, and is used to detect whether the current market price of the token is undervalued or overvalued. It is also used to identify potential market tops or bottoms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/fd3d5dba84513c10e68616cb5f879338.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking back, Bitcoin experienced a stage of consolidation in October 2023 before a wave of appreciation. Whether the market is repeating a similar pattern remains to be observed. Some analysts, like Ki Young Ju, founder and CEO of CryptoQuant, suggest that the bull market cycle may be nearing its end, with prices more likely to show a bearish or sideways trend in the next 6 to 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the Federal Reserve&#39;s recent signals of a loose monetary policy have brought expectations of the end of quantitative tightening and possible restart of quantitative easing, also driving some liquidity introduction. BitMEX co-founder Arthur Hayes tweeted, &quot;Powell has fulfilled his promise, with quantitative tightening (QT) essentially ending on April 1. To truly drive the market into a bull market, either the SLR exemption policy needs to be restored or QE restarted. $77,000 might be Bitcoin&#39;s bottom, but the stock market may need to experience more volatility before Jay fully leans towards Trump&#39;s team. So everyone needs to stay flexible and keep cash on hand.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this environment, the market bottom and subsequent reversal remain uncertain, and investors still need to closely monitor further changes in overall market liquidity, on-chain fund flows, and whale behaviors. For instance, IntoTheBlock has detected that although Bitcoin whale balances have been continuously declining over the past year, March&#39;s data hints at a potential reversal. Currently, whales&#39; holdings have increased by about 62,000 BTC compared to early this month, showing signs of re-accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/4d077c251af0435e69fd6220d2bce26f.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, the market is currently experiencing an adjustment period from a high-risk, high-volatility bull market to a low-liquidity, risk-averse situation. Short-term market sentiment leans pessimistic, with insufficient fund inflows and arbitrage trade unwinding continuing to exert downward pressure on prices. However, the stability of long-term holders and re-accumulation by some whales may provide necessary support for the market in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/17004024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/17004024</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 01:34:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Foresight News</author><category>Ethereum</category><category>Halving Tokens</category><category>Smart Contracts</category><category>Layer 1</category></item><item><title></title><description>What I expect over the next 5 years for AI and Crypto&lt;br&gt;In 1 Year: (March 2026)&lt;br&gt;- BTC 300K or higher&lt;br&gt;- Solana/other fast chains reach 20MM daily users&lt;br&gt;- some humanoid robots in industrial settings&lt;br&gt;- most programing is now &quot;vibe programing&quot;&lt;br&gt;In 2 years: (March 2027)&lt;br&gt;- BTC strategic… https://x.com/i/web/status/1902469257146806552 &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  If we get to these levels, my art budget is going to be insane. &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  sorry i thought you said BTC. I think SOL will outperform in the next 5 years. Possible 50x &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16936509</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16936509</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:16:31 GMT</pubDate><author>Fred Krueger</author><category>Solana</category><category>Halving Tokens</category><category>Solana Ecosystem</category><category>SEC Security Token</category></item><item><title></title><description>Abu Dhabi will invest $2B in the market to start a BIGGEST Bull Run&lt;br&gt;This week, we will see the last fluctuation and $BTC will go to $300k&lt;br&gt;We have little time left to buy low-caps before Alt Season kicks off 👇🧵  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/c80994878624f9a5b946ef3dfe4d0e39.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  I&#39;ll share $10,000 to 25 winners&lt;br&gt;To participate - like, rt &amp;amp; leave your wallet under the FIRST tweet&lt;br&gt;I hope you can multiply this money with low-caps in this thread  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/7690641e0d6b3345733fe29acbb7014d.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Every crypto cycle - is a series of shakes, and fake downstream that scare degens, allowing whales to buy cheap alts&lt;br&gt;The biggest shakes and fluctuations occur just before the uptrend phase&lt;br&gt;In this phase, ppl have the last chance to accumulate before the parabolic rally begins  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/6a19131dbf2b43069e095bfaef4696e9.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  By the end of this month, we will definitely come out of the oscillation phase&lt;br&gt;And see the last shakeout, after which the market will go parabolic, and $BTC will reach a new ATH&lt;br&gt;Look at the 2021 cycle chart, a big shakeout led to a massive bull run right after that  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/478becf117ab4008e284fd7ce53f23b7.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Another catalyst for $BTC to break new ATH - Abu Dhabi&#39;s recent $2B investment in Binance&lt;br&gt;CZ said: investment would flow into alts that Binance supports&lt;br&gt;I tracked Binance wallets to see what tokens they are currently accumulating&lt;br&gt;List of low-cap alts with 1000x perspective 👇  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/7ea0bbc241bc88d438f3cea834938c3a.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  The fastest SOL copy-trading bot with MEV protection&lt;br&gt;http://t.me/toxi_solana_bot?start=ref-jetstart&lt;br&gt;Tested for a month - nothing beats it &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt;  1 ✧ @JupiterExchange | $JUP | MC: $1.43B&lt;br&gt;Jupiter is a DEX aggregator for swapping tokens at optimal prices with low slippage and fees in the Solana ecosystem&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - JUPyiwrYJFskUPiHa7hkeR8VUtAeFoSYbKedZNsDvCN  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/be7f4f1083fb9514562356950123c0df.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  2 ✧ @helium | $HNT | MC: $582.15M&lt;br&gt;Helium is a blockchain network for IoT, enabling data sharing through specialized nodes&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - hntyVP6YFm1Hg25TN9WGLqM12b8TQmcknKrdu1oxWux  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/30efaf3ac154bb2890bcfc85dcb0bba0.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  3 ✧ @bandprotocol | $BAND | MC: $126.84M&lt;br&gt;Band Protocol is a cross-chain data oracle linking real-world data and APIs to smart contracts&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - 0xba11d00c5f74255f56a5e366f4f77f5a186d7f55  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/3ad1abafb48433576c42a823a686402c.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  4 ✧ @Filecoin | $FIL | MC: $1.93B&lt;br&gt;Filecoin is a leading open-source, decentralized data storage system to &quot;store humanity&#39;s crucial information&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - 0x0d8ce2a99bb6e3b7db580ed848240e4a0f9ae153  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/544ea23308cf33a44dca93f77b26eaa8.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  5 ✧ @PancakeSwap | $CAKE | MC: $681.48M&lt;br&gt;Pancakeswap is Binance&#39;s top DEX, known for low fees and fast transactions&lt;br&gt;✧ CA - 0x152649eA73beAb28c5b49B26eb48f7EAD6d4c898  &lt;br&gt;   &lt;img src=&quot;https://static.fwimg.io/img/feed/158d172225e6a05d44d3bdca833a6b83.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;    &lt;br&gt;  Be sure to join my alpha-group for more alpha&lt;br&gt;https://t.me/start_threads &lt;br&gt;   &lt;br&gt; </description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933484</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933484</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:33:51 GMT</pubDate><author>JetStart 👾</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item></channel></rss>