<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>News – The White House</title><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/news/</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/whitehouse/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>News – The White House - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:31:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Statement from Secretary Rubio and NSC Waltz on Call with Zelenskyy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;“Today, President Donald J. Trump and Ukraine’s President Volodymyr Zelenskyy had a fantastic phone conversation.&amp;nbsp; President Zelenskyy thanked President Trump for a productive start for the work of the Ukrainian and American teams in Jeddah on March 11th. The meeting of the senior officials from both nations significantly helped in moving toward ending the war.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;President Zelenskyy thanked President Trump for the support of the United States, especially the Javelin missiles that President Trump was first to provide, and his efforts towards peace. The leaders agreed Ukraine and America will continue working together to bring about a real end to the war, and that lasting peace under President Trump’s leadership can be achieved.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;President Trump fully briefed President Zelenskyy on his conversation with Russian President Vladimir Putin and the key issues discussed. They reviewed the situation in Kursk and agreed to share information closely between their defense staffs as the battlefield situation evolved.&amp;nbsp; President Zelenskyy asked for additional air defense systems to protect his civilians, particularly Patriot missile systems, President Trump agreed to work with him to find what was available particularly in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The two leaders also agreed on a partial ceasefire against energy. Technical teams will meet in Saudi Arabia in the coming days to discuss broadening the ceasefire to the Black Sea on the way to a full ceasefire. They agreed this could be the first step toward the full end of the war and ensuring security. President Zelenskyy was grateful for the President’s leadership in this effort and reiterated his willingness to adopt a full ceasefire.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;President Trump also discussed Ukraine’s electrical supply and nuclear power plants.&amp;nbsp; He said that the United States could be very helpful in running those plants with its electricity and utility expertise.&amp;nbsp; American ownership of those plants would be the best protection for that infrastructure and support for Ukrainian energy infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;President Zelenskyy also thanked President Trump for continuing to push humanitarian concerns, including the exchange of POWs.&amp;nbsp; He noted they had just had a successful exchange and thanked the President for his leadership.&amp;nbsp; President Trump also asked President Zelenskyy about the children who had gone missing from Ukraine during the war, including the ones that had been abducted.&amp;nbsp; President Trump promised to work closely with both parties to help make sure those children were returned home.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They agreed all parties must&amp;nbsp;continue the effort to make a ceasefire work. The Presidents noted the positive work of their advisors and representatives, especially Secretary Rubio, National Security Advisor Waltz, Special Envoy Kellogg, and others.&amp;nbsp; The Presidents instructed their teams to move ahead with the technical issues related to implementing and broadening the partial ceasefire. The Presidents instructed their advisors and representatives to carry out this work as quickly as possible. The Presidents emphasized that in further meetings, the teams can agree on all necessary aspects of advancing toward lasting peace and security.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/03/statement-from-secretary-rubio-and-nsc-waltz-on-call-with-zelenskyy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/03/statement-from-secretary-rubio-and-nsc-waltz-on-call-with-zelenskyy/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:42:26 GMT</pubDate><category>Briefings &amp; Statements</category></item><item><title>Removing Discrimination and Discriminatory Equity Ideology From the Foreign Service</title><description>&lt;p&gt;MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE&lt;br&gt;                                                 THE SECRETARY OF AGRICULTURE&lt;br&gt;                                                 THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE&lt;br&gt;                                                 THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE UNITED STATES AGENCY&lt;br&gt;                                                 FOR INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT&lt;br&gt;                                                 THE CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER OF THE&lt;br&gt;                                                 UNITED STATES AGENCY FOR GLOBAL MEDIA&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SUBJECT: Removing Discrimination and Discriminatory Equity&lt;br&gt;Ideology From the Foreign Service&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Policy and Purpose&lt;/span&gt;. Over the last 4 years, divisive and discriminatory policies were systematically embedded into every part of the Federal Government, including hiring processes and employee performance evaluations in the Foreign Service. It is the policy of the Federal Government that hiring in foreign policy positions, like hiring in all other parts of the Government, shall be based solely on merit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Sec&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/span&gt;. For the purposes of this memorandum:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(a) “discriminatory equity ideology” shall have the meaning given that phrase in section 2 of Executive Order 14190 of January 29, 2025 (Ending Radical Indoctrination in K-12 Schooling);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(b) “Department,” “Foreign Service,” and “Secretary” shall have the meanings given those terms in 22 U.S.C. 3902; and&lt;br&gt;(c) “Foreign Service Member” means an individual described by 22 U.S.C. 3903.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Sec&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Equality and Non-Discrimination in the Foreign Service&lt;/span&gt;. (a) The Secretary of State shall, consistent with applicable law, promptly revise the 2022-2025 Decision Criteria for Tenure and Promotion in the Foreign Service, issued under section 2326.2 of title 3 of the Foreign Affairs Manual, to remove any reference to the Core Precept entitled “Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility.” The Secretaries shall promptly direct all employees of their Departments not to give this Core Precept any force or effect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(b) The Secretaries shall direct all officers and employees of their Departments not to:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(i) base Foreign Service recruitment, hiring, promotion, or retention decisions upon an individual’s race, color, religion, sex, or national origin; or&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(ii) while acting in an official capacity, promote, advocate for, or otherwise inculcate support for discriminatory equity ideology.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(c) The Secretaries shall determine if any current Foreign Service Members have knowingly and willfully engaged in unconstitutional or otherwise illegal discrimination based upon race or other protected characteristics, including actions motivated by discriminatory equity ideology. Consistent with Executive Order 14211 of February 12, 2025 (One Voice for America’s Foreign Relations) the Secretaries shall:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(i) with respect to Foreign Service Members appointed by a Secretary whom that Secretary finds to have engaged in such discrimination, take appropriate action; and&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(ii) with respect to Foreign Service Members appointed by the President, determine whether to refer any findings of discrimination for the President’s consideration or take appropriate action under the Secretary’s own authority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Sec&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;General Provisions&lt;/span&gt;. (a) Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.&lt;br&gt;(b) This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(c) This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;                    DONALD J. TRUMP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/removing-discrimination-and-discriminatory-equity-ideology-from-the-foreign-service/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/removing-discrimination-and-discriminatory-equity-ideology-from-the-foreign-service/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:33:34 GMT</pubDate><category>Presidential Actions</category></item><item><title>Another “Most Wanted” Criminal Captured by the Trump Administration</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Under President Donald J. Trump, the message to criminals who bring harm and destruction to our communities is simple: &lt;strong&gt;you will be found, and you will face justice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img fetchpriority=&quot;high&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;878&quot; src=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/fbi-francisco-javier-roman-bardales.jpg?w=1024&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-6492&quot; style=&quot;width:600px&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/fbi-francisco-javier-roman-bardales.jpg 1266w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/fbi-francisco-javier-roman-bardales.jpg?resize=300,208 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/fbi-francisco-javier-roman-bardales.jpg?resize=768,533 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/fbi-francisco-javier-roman-bardales.jpg?resize=1024,710 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1266px) 100vw, 1266px&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) Director Kash Patel &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/FBIDirectorKash/status/1902008572088909884&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the capture of another fugitive from its “Ten Most Wanted” list — initiating the extradition of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbi.gov/wanted/topten/francisco-javier-roman-bardales&quot;&gt;key senior leader&lt;/a&gt; of the brutal MS-13 gang, Francisco Javier Roman-Bardales, from Mexico to face charges in the United States. Roman-Bardales was wanted “for his alleged role in ordering numerous acts of violence against civilians and rival gang members, as well as his role in drug distribution and extortion schemes in the United States and El Salvador.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The cold-blooded criminal is the &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/_WilliamsonBen/status/1902134931515490444&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;third fugitive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on the FBI’s “Ten Most Wanted” list apprehended since President Trump took office.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnoldo Jimenez — a fugitive wanted on first-degree murder charges — was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbi.gov/contact-us/field-offices/chicago/news/fbi-chicago-announces-capture-of-ten-most-wanted-fugitive-arnoldo-jimenez&quot;&gt;arrested&lt;/a&gt; on January 30, 2025.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Donald Eugene Fields II — a fugitive wanted on child sex trafficking and child rape charges — was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fbi.gov/contact-us/field-offices/stlouis/news/captured-fbi-ten-most-wanted-fugitive-from-st-louis-metro-area&quot;&gt;arrested&lt;/a&gt; on January 25, 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Trump Administration will stop at nothing to keep the American people safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/another-most-wanted-criminal-captured-by-the-trump-administration/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/another-most-wanted-criminal-captured-by-the-trump-administration/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 15:17:29 GMT</pubDate><category>Articles</category></item><item><title>Achieving Efficiency Through State and Local Preparedness</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Purpose&lt;/span&gt;. Commonsense approaches and investments by State and local governments across American infrastructure will enhance national security and create a more resilient Nation. Federal policy must rightly recognize that preparedness is most effectively owned and managed at the State, local, and even individual levels, supported by a competent, accessible, and efficient Federal Government. Citizens are the immediate beneficiaries of sound local decisions and investments designed to address risks, including cyber attacks, wildfires, hurricanes, and space weather. When States are empowered to make smart infrastructure choices, taxpayers benefit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;This order empowers State, local, and individual preparedness and injects common sense into infrastructure prioritization and strategic investments through risk-informed decisions that make our infrastructure, communities, and economy resilient to global and dynamic threats and hazards.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Sec&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Policy&lt;/span&gt;. It is the policy of the United States that State and local governments and individuals play a more active and significant role in national resilience and preparedness, thereby saving American lives, securing American livelihoods, reducing taxpayer burdens through efficiency, and unleashing our collective prosperity. In addition, it is the policy of the United States that my Administration streamline its preparedness operations; update relevant Government policies to reduce complexity and better protect and serve Americans; and enable State and local governments to better understand, plan for, and ultimately address the needs of their citizens.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Sec&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Updating Federal Policy to Save Lives and End the Subsidization of Mismanagement&lt;/span&gt;. (a) National Resilience Strategy. Within 90 days of the date of this order, the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA), in coordination with the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and the heads of relevant executive departments and agencies (agencies), shall publish a National Resilience Strategy that articulates the priorities, means, and ways to advance the resilience of the Nation. The National Resilience Strategy shall be reviewed and revised at least every 4 years, or as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(b) National Critical Infrastructure Policy. Within 180 days of the date of this order, the APNSA, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the heads of relevant agencies, shall review all critical infrastructure policies and recommend to the President the revisions, recissions, and replacements necessary to achieve a more resilient posture; shift from an all-hazards approach to a risk-informed approach; move beyond information sharing to action; and implement the National Resilience Strategy described in subsection (a) of this section. For purposes of this order, critical infrastructure policies do not include any policies related to purported “misinformation,” “disinformation,” or “malinformation,” nor so-called “cognitive infrastructure,” which should be reevaluated consistent with the policy set forth in Executive Order 14149 of January 20, 2025 (Restoring Freedom of Speech and Ending Federal Censorship), through a separate process. The policies to be reviewed and recommended for modification, as appropriate, include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(i) National Security Memorandum 16 of November 10, 2022 (Strengthening the Security and Resilience of United States Food and Agriculture);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(ii) National Security Memorandum 22 of April 30, 2024 (Critical Infrastructure Security and Resilience);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(iii) Executive Order 14017 of February 24, 2021 (America’s Supply Chains); and&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(iv) Executive Order 14123 of June 14, 2024 (White House Council on Supply Chain Resilience).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(c) National Continuity Policy. Within 180 days of the date of this order, the APNSA, in coordination with the heads of relevant agencies, shall review all national continuity policies and recommend to the President the revisions, recissions, and replacements necessary to modernize and streamline the approach to national continuity capabilities, reformulate the methodology and architecture necessary to achieve an enduring readiness posture, and implement the National Resilience Strategy described in subsection (a) of this section. The policies to be reviewed and recommended for modification, as appropriate, include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(i) Executive Order 13618 of July 6, 2012 (Assignment of National Security and Emergency Preparedness Communications Functions);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(ii) Executive Order 13961 of December 7, 2020 (Governance and Integration of Federal Mission Resilience);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(iii) National Security Memorandum 32 of January 19, 2025 (National Continuity Policy); and&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(iv) Executive Order 14146 of January 19, 2025 (Partial Revocation of Executive Order 13961).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(d) Preparedness and Response Policies. Within 240 days of the date of this order, the APNSA, in coordination with the heads of relevant agencies and informed by the reports and findings of the Federal Emergency Management Agency Council established pursuant to Executive Order 14180 of January 24, 2025 (Council to Assess the Federal Emergency Management Agency), shall review all national preparedness and response policies and recommend to the President the revisions, recissions, and replacements necessary to reformulate the process and metrics for Federal responsibility, move away from an all-hazards approach, and implement the National Resilience Strategy described in subsection (a) of this section. The policies to be reviewed and recommended for modification, as appropriate, include:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(i) Executive Order 12656 of November 18, 1988 (Assignment of Emergency Preparedness Responsibilities);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(ii) Homeland Security Presidential Directive 5 of February 28, 2003 (Management of Domestic Incidents);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(iii) Presidential Policy Directive 8 of March 30, 2011 (National Preparedness);&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(iv) Presidential Policy Directive 22 of March 28, 2013 (National Special Security Events); and&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(v) Presidential Policy Directive 44 of November 7, 2016 (Enhancing Domestic Incident Response).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(e) National Risk Register. Within 240 days of the date of this order, the APNSA, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the heads of relevant agencies, shall coordinate the development of a National Risk Register that identifies, articulates, and quantifies natural and malign risks to our national infrastructure, related systems, and their users.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(i) The quantification produced by the National Risk Register shall be used to inform the Intelligence Community, private sector investments, State investments, and Federal budget priorities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(ii) The National Risk Register shall be reviewed and revised at least every 4 years, or as appropriate, to evolve with the dynamic risk landscape.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(f) Federal National Functions Constructs. The Federal Government organizes national preparedness and continuity through the bureaucratic and complicated lens of overlapping and overbroad “functions,” which include: the National Essential Functions, Primary Mission Essential Functions, National Critical Functions, Emergency Support Functions, Recovery Support Functions, and Community Lifelines. Within 1 year of the date of this order, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall propose changes to the policies outlining this framework and any implementing documents to ensure State and local governments and individuals have improved communications with Federal officials and a better understanding of the Federal role. This proposal shall be coordinated through the process established by National Security Presidential Memorandum 1 of January 20, 2025 (Organization of the National Security Council and Subcommittees), or any successor processes, before being submitted to the President through the APNSA.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;Sec&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline&quot;&gt;General Provisions&lt;/span&gt;. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;pre class=&quot;wp-block-code&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;                               DONALD J. TRUMP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;THE WHITE HOUSE,&lt;br&gt;March 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/test/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/03/test/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 14:20:57 GMT</pubDate><category>Presidential Actions</category></item><item><title>Fact Sheet: President Donald J. Trump Achieves Efficiency Through State and Local Preparedness</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENHANCING EFFICIENCY THROUGH STATE AND LOCAL PREPAREDNESS:&lt;/strong&gt; Today, President Donald J. Trump signed an Executive Order to empower states, localities, and citizens to more effectively prepare for incidents like cyber attacks and weather events.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Order enables state and local governments to better understand, plan for, and address the needs of their citizens by reducing the complexity of federal preparedness and response policies.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;It also launches a National Resilience Strategy that articulates the priorities, means, and ways to advance the resilience of the nation.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Order calls for a review of all infrastructure, continuity, and preparedness policies to modernize and simplify federal approaches, aligning them with the National Resilience Strategy. This includes:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shifting national critical infrastructure policy from an “all-hazards” approach to a risk-informed approach, prioritizing resilience and action over mere information sharing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Overhauling national continuity policy to modernize its framework, streamline operations, and right-size the federal footprint for sustained readiness.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating national preparedness policies to reformulate the process and metrics for federal responsibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Order creates a National Risk Register to identify, describe, and measure risks to our national infrastructure, related systems, and their users in order to guide smarter spending and planning.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Order streamlines federal functions so states and communities can work with Washington more easily and effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAVING LIVES THROUGH EARLY PREPAREDNESS: &lt;/strong&gt;President Trump knows that Americans need fast, effective help when crises hit—not delays or excuses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Order injects common sense into both infrastructure prioritization and strategic investments through risk-informed decisions. This will make our infrastructure, communities, and economy more resilient to global and dynamic threats and hazards.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Local leaders and citizens know their needs best—not bureaucrats in Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The Order streamlines operations and updates relevant government policies to reduce complexity, increase efficiency, and better protect and serve Americans. It enables state and local governments to better understand, plan for, and address the needs of their citizens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EMPOWERING STATES AND LOCAL COMMUNITIES: &lt;/strong&gt;This Executive Order delivers on President Trump’s commitment to shift power from Washington to the American people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In his first week back in office, President Trump established a task force to assess FEMA’s ability to effectively address disasters occurring within the United States.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;President Trump also signed an Executive Order to ensure California gets adequate resources to fight wildfires and assist California and North Carolina in rebuilding quicker, putting local needs first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/03/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-achieves-efficiency-through-state-and-local-preparedness/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/03/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-achieves-efficiency-through-state-and-local-preparedness/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 02:29:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Fact Sheets</category></item><item><title>National Poison Prevention Week, 2025</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;By the President of the United States of America&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;A Proclamation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During National Poison Prevention Week, my Administration is addressing the threat of overdose deaths in our Nation from accidental poisoning.&amp;nbsp; By increasing community awareness, strengthening safety measures, and taking decisive action, we are building a new era of American strength, safety, security, and wellness.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among the most serious threats facing our Nation is the rise of fentanyl, which is being trafficked illegally across our borders — a crisis of unimaginable proportions that escalated under the previous administration.&amp;nbsp; Fentanyl and other deadly drugs flooded into our towns and cities, falling into the hands of our children, siblings, parents, friends, and neighbors.&amp;nbsp; Fentanyl is the leading cause of death for Americans ages 18 to 45, with overdoses quickly becoming a leading cause of death for American teens — robbing countless innocent victims of their lives, futures, and dreams.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We cannot allow this devastation and vicious assault on the American people to continue.&amp;nbsp; That is why, on my first day back in office, I directed the designation of cartels as foreign terrorist organizations, ensuring they are treated as a national security threat.&amp;nbsp; I have imposed tariffs on China, Mexico, and Canada — sending a clear message that those fueling this crisis will be held accountable.&amp;nbsp; United States Customs and Border Protection, along with United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement, are on the frontlines of this fight, having seized more than 1,600 pounds of fentanyl in my first 30 days in office.&amp;nbsp; I will continue to do everything in my power to protect children and families, end drug addiction, and keep lethal substances out of our communities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every day, American families endure the devastating impact of preventable poisoning, whether from household chemicals, improper medication use, or the perilous danger of opioids like fentanyl.&amp;nbsp; This week, my Administration urges all Americans to stay informed about the dangers of poisoning and take steps to protect their families.&amp;nbsp; The Poison Help Line, 800-222-1222, is available around the clock, providing free, confidential guidance from medical experts.&amp;nbsp; We will never stop fighting to achieve a future that protects its citizens, defends its communities, and ensures that the American people are happy, healthy, and free.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To encourage Americans to learn more about the dangers of unintentional poisonings and to take appropriate preventative measures, on September 26, 1961, the Congress, by joint resolution (75 Stat. 681), authorized and requested the President to issue a proclamation designating the third week of March each year as “National Poison Prevention Week.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NOW, THEREFORE, I, DONALD J. TRUMP, President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim March 16, 2025, through March 22, 2025, to be National Poison Prevention Week.&amp;nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this week by taking actions to safeguard their families from poisonous products, chemicals, medicines, and drugs found in their homes, and to raise awareness about these dangers in order to prevent accidental injuries and deaths.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&amp;nbsp;thousand&amp;nbsp;twenty-five, and of the Independence of the United&amp;nbsp;States of&amp;nbsp;America the two&amp;nbsp;hundred and forty-ninth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;DONALD J. TRUMP&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/03/national-poison-prevention-week-2025/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/03/national-poison-prevention-week-2025/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 22:18:49 GMT</pubDate><category>Briefings &amp; Statements</category></item><item><title>National Agriculture Day, 2025</title><description>&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;By the President of the United States of America&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;A Proclamation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;From the earliest days of our Republic, our farmers and agricultural communities have been the source of American success — enduring the elements and defying hard conditions to cultivate our land and feed the people.&amp;nbsp; Farming is indelibly engrained in our history, customs, and culture, and stands to this day as the bedrock of our economy and way of life.&amp;nbsp; This National Agriculture Day, we pay tribute to every farmer and rancher who makes our country strong — and we commit to empowering our agricultural community to forge a long, successful, and bountiful American future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;Every day, farmers and agriculture workers ensure that families across America and around the world have stable access to high-quality products — including food for our tables, clothes for our backs, and fuel for our cars.&amp;nbsp; Over 95 percent of all farms in the United States are family-owned and are vital to rural and economic stability, comprising 83 percent of total farm production.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;To make good on my promises to fortify the American farmer and make our Nation’s agricultural products affordable again, I&amp;nbsp;have worked to rapidly reduce the spread of bird flu inherited from the previous administration — including by strengthening biosecurity measures and ensuring rapid outbreak containment.&amp;nbsp; As President, I will ensure that American agriculture remains the gold standard of the world, producing the best food, feed, fuel, and fiber on the face of the Earth.&amp;nbsp; My Administration will strengthen our farmers’ competitiveness on the world stage by promoting fair trade practices, streamlining export processes, and expanding market access.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;For centuries, American farmers and ranchers have been the lifeblood of the American economy.&amp;nbsp; Today and every day, we extend our unending gratitude to the dedicated men and women in farming communities who embody the timeless virtues of hard work and self-reliance.&amp;nbsp; As we continue our new chapter of American prosperity, we commit to embolden the heroes of our agricultural community who work tirelessly with their unwavering American pride to nourish our Nation, feed our families, and fuel our way of life.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;NOW, THEREFORE, I, DONALD J. TRUMP, President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 18, 2025, as National Agriculture Day.&amp;nbsp; I&amp;nbsp;encourage all Americans to observe this day by recognizing the preeminent role that agriculture plays in our daily lives, acknowledging agriculture’s continuing importance to rural America and our country’s economy, and expressing our deep appreciation of farmers, growers, ranchers, producers, national forest system stewards, private agricultural stewards, and those who work in the agriculture sector across the Nation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-left&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&amp;nbsp;thousand&amp;nbsp;twenty-five, and of the Independence of the United&amp;nbsp;States of&amp;nbsp;America the two&amp;nbsp;hundred and forty-ninth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-text-align-center&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; DONALD J. TRUMP&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/03/national-agriculture-day-2025/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/03/national-agriculture-day-2025/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 22:16:02 GMT</pubDate><category>Briefings &amp; Statements</category></item><item><title>Fact Sheet: President Donald J. Trump Removes DEI From the Foreign Service</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESTORING THE VALUES OF INDIVIDUAL DIGNITY, HARD WORK, AND EXCELLENCE:&lt;/strong&gt; Today, President Donald J. Trump signed a memorandum removing radical “Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion” (DEI) from the Foreign Service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The memorandum directs the Secretary of State to remove the “Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility” Core Precept from Foreign Service tenure and promotion criteria.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;It further directs that the U.S. government will not base Foreign Service recruitment, hiring, promotion, or retention decisions on an individual’s race, color, religion, sex, or national origin, nor embed discriminatory equity ideology within any element of the Foreign Service.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Relevant agencies shall identify and take appropriate action regarding any Foreign Service Officer who knowingly and willfully engaged in illegal discrimination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PUTTING MERIT FIRST: &lt;/strong&gt;President Trump believes that hiring in all parts of government should be based solely on merit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the previous administration, divisive and discriminatory policies were systematically embedded into every part of the State Department.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Biden’s State Department conditioned eligibility for promotions on an employee’s ability to pass a DEI loyalty test.
&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2023, Biden’s Chief Diversity and Inclusion Officer for the State Department, Gina Abercrombie-Winstanley, said: “We made the change that if you wanted to be considered for promotion at the Department of State, you must be able to document what you are doing to support diversity, equity and inclusion and accessibility. This is how you are judged for promotion.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Biden’s State Department published a “Five-Year Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility (DEIA) Strategic Plan” that included a department-wide “DEIA Climate Survey” and implemented a comprehensive recruitment plan to aggressively target so-called “underrepresented groups.”&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Foreign policy positions should be filled by the most qualified individuals, not by discriminatory quotas or ideological requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVING AMERICA, NOT IDEOLOGICAL AGENDAS: &lt;/strong&gt;President Trump is restoring fairness and accountability in federal hiring, and terminating DEI across the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In his first week in office, President Trump signed an Executive Order restoring merit-based hiring and promotions across the federal government.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;President Trump also signed an Executive Order ending radical and wasteful DEI programs and preferencing.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;President Trump: “We will terminate every diversity, equity, and inclusion program across the entire federal government.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/03/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-removes-dei-from-the-foreign-service/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/03/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-removes-dei-from-the-foreign-service/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 15:34:18 GMT</pubDate><category>Fact Sheets</category></item><item><title>ICYMI: “Trump’s tariffs are saving the American steel industry”</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The American steel industry will be “reinvigorated” by President Donald J. Trump’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/adjusting-imports-of-steel-into-the-united-states/&quot;&gt;tariffs&lt;/a&gt; on steel imports, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.post-gazette.com/opinion/guest-columns/2025/03/18/trump-steel-tariff/stories/202503170010&quot;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt; Steel Manufacturers Association President Philip K. Bell in today’s &lt;em&gt;Pittsburgh Post-Gazette&lt;/em&gt; — describing how President Trump’s action to close loopholes and exemptions will strengthen the critical industry.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The American steel industry, in other words, is going in reverse, primarily because of increasing imports from exempt countries and product exclusions. With global overcapacity soaring, foreign producers everywhere will take advantage of any gaps in America’s tariffs to find an outlet for their excess steel in the U.S. market.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The harmful impact of a ton of imported steel sold at the domestic industry’s expense does not depend on whether it comes from an ‘ally’ or ‘adversary’ country.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A stable supply of domestically produced steel is more important than ever to America’s national, economic and energy security. In the face of the considerable pressure likely to come to exempt certain countries and weaken the tariffs, the president has stayed strong and continued to put America first on steel trade.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.post-gazette.com/opinion/guest-columns/2025/03/18/trump-steel-tariff/stories/202503170010&quot;&gt;Read the full op-ed here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/icymi-trumps-tariffs-are-saving-the-american-steel-industry/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/icymi-trumps-tariffs-are-saving-the-american-steel-industry/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:22:00 GMT</pubDate><category>Articles</category></item><item><title>President Trump Is Delivering Needed Economic Relief</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Americans are continuing to see the benefits as the economic agenda of President Donald J. Trump and his administration comes into focus. After years of soaring prices and economic pain, the Trump Administration’s focus on cutting regulations and unleashing American energy is leading to stability for Americans’ bottom lines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EGGS:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The average wholesale price of eggs&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/RapidResponse47/status/1901646843282419845&quot;&gt;recorded&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;another huge drop today as the Trump Administration fulfills its&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usda.gov/about-usda/news/press-releases/2025/02/26/usda-invests-1-billion-combat-avian-flu-and-reduce-egg-prices&quot;&gt;plan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for long-term affordability by reversing the previous administration’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2025/02/17/exclusive-trumps-usda-secretary-brooke-rollins-on-lowering-egg-prices-were-on-it-going-to-do-everything-we-can-to-address-it/&quot;&gt;flawed approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On January 21, 2025, the wholesale price for eggs was&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://usda.library.cornell.edu/concern/publications/h128nd72w?locale=en&quot;&gt;$6.55/dozen&lt;/a&gt;; today, it’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ams.usda.gov/mnreports/ams_2843.pdf&quot;&gt;$3.45/dozen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;— a $3.10/dozen (–47.3%) decrease.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;The average wholesale price for eggs has&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/RapidResponse47/status/1901622067608367231&quot;&gt;declined&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for three straight weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GAS:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The nationwide average for gas continues falling as the Trump Administration implements its American energy agenda.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nationwide average for gas has&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/GasBuddyGuy/status/1901606216528241145&quot;&gt;declined&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for four straight weeks —&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fuelinsights.gasbuddy.com/charts&quot;&gt;down&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;ten cents from one month ago and 42 cents from one year ago.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;More than two-thirds of gas stations in the U.S. have gas at $2.99/gallon or less,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/GasBuddyGuy/status/1901672189004304786&quot;&gt;according to GasBuddy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Average gas prices are currently at their&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gasbuddy.com/go/average-us-gas-prices-fall-to-lowest-march-level-since-pandemic#:~:text=The%20average%20price%20of%20gasoline%20in%20the%20U.S.%20hasn%E2%80%99t%20been%20this%20low%20in%20March%20since%202021&quot;&gt;lowest level&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for March in four years. At this point in Biden’s presidency, gas prices had already gone up 49 cents.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Average prices are below $3/gallon in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gasprices.aaa.com/&quot;&gt;majority of states&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul class=&quot;wp-block-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alabama:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.74; One year ago: $3.18; Record: $4.63 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alaska:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.39; One year ago: $3.80; Record: $5.61 (6/19/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arizona:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.34; One year ago: $3.71; Record: $5.39 (6/17/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arkansas:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.72; One year ago: $3.08; Record: $4.54 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;California:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $4.66; One year ago: $4.90; Record: $6.44 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colorado:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.93; One year ago: $3.06; Record: $4.92 (6/21/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecticut:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.00; One year ago: $3.36; Record: $4.98 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delaware:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.87; One year ago: $3.29; Record: $4.99 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;District of Columbia:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.20; One year ago: $3.61; Record: $5.26 (6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Florida:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.10; One year ago: $3.47; Record: $4.89 (6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Georgia:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.89; One year ago: $3.36; Record: $4.50 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hawaii:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $4.52; One year ago: $4.69; Record: $5.62 (7/9/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idaho:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.18; One year ago: $3.37; Record: $5.25 (7/1/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illinois:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.24; One year ago: $3.71; Record: $5.56&amp;nbsp;(6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indiana:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.93; One year ago: $3.53; Record: $5.24 (6/9/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iowa:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.88; One year ago: $3.19; Record: $4.76 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kansas:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.79; One year ago: $3.16; Record: $4.67 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kentucky:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.68; One year ago: $3.14; Record: $4.80 (6/11/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Louisiana:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.71; One year ago: $3.13; Record: $4.56 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maine:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.03; One year ago: $3.28; Record: $5.09 (6/16/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maryland:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.02; One year ago: $3.51; Record: $5.02 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massachusetts:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.96; One year ago: $3.25; Record: $5.05 (6/12/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michigan:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.03; One year ago: $3.64; Record: $5.22 (6/11/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minnesota:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.96; One year ago: $3.21; Record: $4.76 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mississippi:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.63; One year ago: $3.03; Record: $4.53 (6/12/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missouri:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.79; One year ago: $3.21; Record: $4.68 (6/16/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Montana:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.11; One year ago: $3.48; Record: $4.98 (6/19/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nebraska:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.93; One year ago: $3.19; Record: $4.79 (6/17/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nevada:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.73; One year ago: $4.18; Record: $5.68 (6/16/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Hampshire:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.92; One year ago: $3.18; Record: $5.00 (6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Jersey:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.91; One year ago: $3.25; Record: $5.06 (6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Mexico:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.83; One year ago: $3.25; Record: $4.83 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.11; One year ago: $3.37; Record: $5.04 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North Carolina:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.75; One year ago: $3.32; Record: $4.67 (6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North Dakota:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.99; One year ago: $3.30; Record: $4.80 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ohio:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.90; One year ago: $3.22; Record: $5.07 (6/9/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oklahoma:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.66; One year ago: $3.08; Record: $4.67 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oregon:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.72; One year ago: $4.06; Record: $5.55 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pennsylvania:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.21; One year ago: $3.58; Record: $5.07 (6/12/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rhode Island:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.92; One year ago: $3.21; Record: $5.02 (6/13/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Carolina:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.72; One year ago: $3.24; Record: $4.61 (6/12/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;South Dakota:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.93; One year ago: $3.23; Record: $4.80 (6/16/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tennessee:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.70; One year ago: $3.09; Record: $4.64 (6/12/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Texas:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.65; One year ago: $3.07; Record: $4.70 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utah:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.03; One year ago: $3.34; Record: $5.26 (7/1/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vermont:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.13; One year ago: $3.30; Record: $5.06 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virginia:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.89; One year ago: $3.37; Record: $4.87 (6/14/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Washington:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $4.08; One year ago: $4.30; Record: $5.56 (6/16/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;West Virginia:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.85; One year ago: $3.26; Record: $4.93 (6/15/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wisconsin:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $2.87; One year ago: $3.32; Record: $4.92 (6/12/22)&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wyoming:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Today: $3.01; One year ago: $3.11; Record: $4.90 (7/1/22)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it hasn’t even been 60 days since President Trump began his second term.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/president-trump-is-delivering-needed-economic-relief/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/03/president-trump-is-delivering-needed-economic-relief/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 19:27:07 GMT</pubDate><category>Articles</category></item></channel></rss>