<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Weekly Focus | Current Affairs | Vision IAS</title><link>https://visionias.in/current-affairs/weekly-focus/archive</link><atom:link href="http://rss.datuan.dev/visionias/weeklyFocus" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Weekly Focus provides weekly comprehensive analysis of current themes with multidimensional and consolidated content. - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://visionias.in/current-affairs/images/weekly-focus-logo.svg</url><title>Weekly Focus | Current Affairs | Vision IAS</title><link>https://visionias.in/current-affairs/weekly-focus/archive</link></image><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:31:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Technology&#39;s Role in Redefining Indian Society</title><description>&lt;h1&gt;Technology&#39;s Role in Redefining Indian Society&lt;/h1&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;India&#39;s rapid technological advancement has profoundly transformed its society, reshaping the fabric of everyday life. The widespread adoption of smartphones and the expansion of internet connectivity have &lt;strong&gt;democratized access to information, education, and economic opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;. As of March 2024, &lt;strong&gt;India has 954.40 million internet subscribers&lt;/strong&gt;, making it the &lt;strong&gt;second-largest online population globally (PIB)&lt;/strong&gt;. This digital revolution has fueled significant economic growth, particularly in sectors like IT, e-Commerce, and FinTech. However, the impact extends beyond the economy: technology has &lt;strong&gt;influenced India’s social structures, altered cultural practices, and reshaped social institutions and value systems.&lt;/strong&gt; While increased access to technology has enhanced social mobility and empowered previously marginalized groups, it has also brought challenges such as a widening digital divide, changing family dynamics, and evolving cultural norms. In this context, technology has become both a catalyst for progress and a force for profound societal change in India.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;1.What are the Features of Traditional Indian Society?&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-religious:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;India is home to a multitude of religions, including Hinduism, Islam, Christianity, Sikhism, Buddhism, and Jainism. According to the 2011 Census of India, 79.8% of the population identifies as Hindu, 14.2% as Muslim, 2.3% as Christian, and 1.7% as Sikh, with other religions collectively accounting for about 2%.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-lingual:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;India is one of the most linguistically diverse countries globally, &lt;strong&gt;with 22 languages listed under Schedule VIII of the Constitution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Besides these scheduled languages, the Indian Census did record 1,576 rationalized languages as well as 1,796 other mother-tongues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caste System:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The caste system remains a significant aspect of social organization in traditional Indian society, despite various legal reforms. The 2011 Census records show that Scheduled Castes (SCs) make up 16.6% of the population, while Scheduled Tribes (STs) comprise 8.6%.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tribal Communities:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;India has a significant tribal population, with 705 officially recognized tribes. According to the 2011 Census, the tribal population is approximately 104 million, constituting around 8.6% of the national population.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family Structure: Indian society traditionally values joint families, but nuclear families are becoming increasingly prevalent.&lt;/strong&gt; While 70% of Indian households were nuclear families in the 2011 Census, joint families remain more common in rural areas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marriage Customs:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Marriage in traditional Indian society is largely governed by religious and cultural norms. Arranged marriages are common, with 90% of marriages still being arranged, according to a 2018 report by the Indian Human Development Survey.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;2.What are the technological developments happened in Indian Society?&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;India’s technological advancements have spanned various sectors, influencing its economic, social, and cultural dimensions. It includes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information and Communication Technology (ICT):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It includes technologies such as Internet, &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Cloud Computing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Big Data, Internet of Things, Augmented Reality&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Virtual Reality, etc., driven by improved access to&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;high-speed internet, digital infrastructure, and mobile penetration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FinTech (Financial Technology):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It includes increased adoption of mobile banking for financial inclusion, &lt;strong&gt;digital payments&lt;/strong&gt;, digital lending platform, use of &lt;strong&gt;Blockchain&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;in banking and record-keeping, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MedTech (Medical Technology):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It includes telemedicine and remote consultations (e.g., eSanjeevani initiative of government for online consultation), Electronic Health Record management, use of AI in diagnostics, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EdTech (Education Technology):&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It includes adoption of Online Learning Platforms (e.g., SWAYAM Platform), digital classrooms and virtual labs, AI-powered personalized learning, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-Governance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;It includes use of Aadhar in provisioning of services to citizens, Citizen Service Portals (e.g., MyGov), land record digitization, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;3.What are the impacts of technology on Indian society?&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;Technology has had multifaceted impact on Indian society, influencing its economic, social, cultural, and political dimensions. While it has driven progress and development, it has also introduced some challenges.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1. Impact on different stakeholders in the society&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;aspect-ratio:2185/841;&quot; src=&quot;https://d2av8kbir6lh9m.cloudfront.net/uploads/rkc0bc9n69NZjMx1QaF1dFWd7QyuJIkKzTIc7nmR.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2185&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;aspect-ratio:2185/910;&quot; src=&quot;https://d2av8kbir6lh9m.cloudfront.net/uploads/0SWUfNOMCo99CXiNh3c10dvZECrfW04ZMfRULZ2V.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2185&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;aspect-ratio:2185/781;&quot; src=&quot;https://d2av8kbir6lh9m.cloudfront.net/uploads/ejMI9b6w1T0oJerNKoEnqMqPV7hHcI2oiF5PzHWq.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2185&quot; height=&quot;781&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;aspect-ratio:2185/860;&quot; src=&quot;https://d2av8kbir6lh9m.cloudfront.net/uploads/yPM9kYod1zivzuhn2XUujRaSvzWX8ZVjrIXRPsZY.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2185&quot; height=&quot;860&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2. Impact on different Social Institutions of the society&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2.1. Family&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;Technology has significantly transformed the dynamics of family structures in India. Here are some key areas of impact:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuclear Families:&lt;/strong&gt; The rise of nuclear families has become more prevalent due to increased urbanization, globalization, and changing career opportunities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delayed Marriages:&lt;/strong&gt; Technology has influenced societal norms and expectations, leading to delayed marriages and increased age at first marriage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing Gender Roles:&lt;/strong&gt; Technology has challenged traditional gender roles, with women increasingly participating in the workforce and taking on non-traditional roles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emerging Family Structures:&lt;/strong&gt; New family structures, such as single-parent families, same-sex couples, and blended families, are becoming more visible and accepted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;aspect-ratio:2185/1135;&quot; src=&quot;https://d2av8kbir6lh9m.cloudfront.net/uploads/r2rV8CuQTPkBScMu1h8gGRjZsLw5V6WhiZ2Kx4rO.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2185&quot; height=&quot;1135&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2.2. Caste System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;Technology is both a bridge and a barrier within India’s caste system. While it provides tools that challenge historical caste divisions, it also sometimes creates new avenues for reinforcing traditional structures.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology weakening the Caste System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakdown of the Jajmani System&lt;/strong&gt;: Technology allows marginalized groups to find work outside traditional caste-based service roles, diminishing the influence of the caste-bound Jajmani (patron-client) system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Online job platforms like Naukri and gig apps like UrbanClap provide service workers direct access to clients, bypassing caste-based intermediaries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Sanskritization&lt;/strong&gt;: Access to online education, skill-building, and economic opportunities has allowed traditionally lower-caste groups to emulate upper-caste lifestyles and values, a modern form of Sanskritization.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inter-Caste Marriages&lt;/strong&gt;: Dating apps and social networks enable interactions beyond caste lines, increasing the rate of inter-caste marriages, especially in urban areas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Apps like Bumble and Tinder provide people the freedom to date and marry outside caste constraints, challenging traditional marriage norms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media Movements&lt;/strong&gt;: Social media allows marginalized groups to highlight and advocate against caste discrimination, leading to increased awareness and solidarity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Movements like #DalitLivesMatter&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erosion of Traditional Social Practices:&lt;/strong&gt; Sociologist M.N. Srinivas, in his concept of Westernization, discussed how exposure to Western ideas through media could lead to the gradual erosion of traditional Indian practices, particularly those related to family structure and social hierarchy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4 style=&quot;margin-left:0cm;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology strengthening the Caste System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Echo-Chamber Effect:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Social media algorithms often show users content that aligns with their existing interests, leading to caste-based echo chambers that reinforce identity and beliefs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: People joining caste-aligned groups on Facebook may repeatedly see posts that reinforce their caste identities, limiting exposure to diverse perspectives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caste-Based Social Media Groups:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Social media platforms facilitate the formation of caste-specific groups, reinforcing caste identities and sometimes promoting exclusion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Facebook and WhatsApp groups organized by caste communities can perpetuate intra-caste solidarity and discourage social mixing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caste-Based Matrimonial Sites:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Matrimonial websites allow users to search based on caste, thus upholding caste endogamy and traditional marriage practices.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Sites like Shaadi.com and Jeevansathi have caste-based search filters, reinforcing the practice of caste-based marriages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Bias and Profiling:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Algorithms on social media and e-commerce platforms may profile users based on caste-related data, perpetuating stereotypes and biases.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Targeted ads on platforms may use location and community data to push caste-specific content, creating a segmented user experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;4.How the technology is impacting process of Urbanisation and Ruralisation?&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;Technology plays a critical role in driving both &lt;strong&gt;urbanization&lt;/strong&gt; (the movement of people and resources toward cities) and &lt;strong&gt;ruralization&lt;/strong&gt; (bringing urban-like development and services to rural areas). Here’s how it fuels both processes:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology fuelling Urbanization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job Opportunities and Economic Growth&lt;/strong&gt;: Technology-driven &lt;strong&gt;industries like IT, e-commerce, and fintech&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;are predominantly based in cities, attracting people from rural areas seeking better employment prospects and salaries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Bengaluru, Hyderabad, and Mumbai have become major tech hubs, drawing rural talent for IT and tech jobs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education and Skill Development&lt;/strong&gt;: Urban areas &lt;strong&gt;offer greater access to high-quality, tech-enabled educational institutions,&lt;/strong&gt; which attracts students from rural areas who seek advanced education and skill-based training.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Institutes like IITs and IIMs in urban centers attract students nationwide, many of whom stay in cities post-graduation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare and Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;: Advanced healthcare facilities with &lt;strong&gt;specialized hospitals in cities&lt;/strong&gt; draw rural populations who seek quality medical services and improved infrastructure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Urban hospitals with telemedicine services offer quality care, making cities an attractive option for rural families needing advanced healthcare.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Connectivity and Lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;: Access to social media and urban digital services exposes rural populations to city lifestyles, fueling aspirations for an urban standard of living.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Social media and OTT platforms showcase urban lifestyles and opportunities, encouraging rural youth to migrate to cities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology fuelling Ruralisation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Services and E-Governance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Technology brings essential services like banking, education, and government schemes to rural areas, reducing the need to migrate to cities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Platforms &lt;strong&gt;like Common Service Centers (CSCs)&lt;/strong&gt; in India provide e-governance and digital financial services in rural areas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telemedicine and Healthcare Access:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Telemedicine platforms bring urban-quality healthcare to rural residents, allowing remote consultations with city-based doctors and reducing rural-urban healthcare disparity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Platforms like Practo and government initiatives in telemedicine provide rural populations with access to specialized healthcare.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agri-Tech and Smart Farming:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Agri-tech solutions offer rural farmers real-time data on weather, crop health, and market prices, increasing productivity and income, making rural life more sustainable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Apps &lt;strong&gt;like Kisan Suvidha&lt;/strong&gt; provide real-time data to help rural farmers make informed decisions, reducing migration due to agricultural challenges.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-Learning and Skill Development:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;E-learning platforms enable rural youth to access urban-quality education and skills without relocating, which supports local employment and opportunities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;aspect-ratio:2185/904;&quot; src=&quot;https://d2av8kbir6lh9m.cloudfront.net/uploads/y1LS7MDoCYaWg7dI9Tco1EOL1XsyZSvPtEaNW57z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;2185&quot; height=&quot;904&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;5.How the Indian Society is balancing the technology with tradition?&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:0cm;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;India, a land steeped in ancient traditions and rich cultural heritage, is also rapidly embracing technological advancements.&amp;nbsp;This unique juxtaposition has led to a fascinating interplay between the old and the new. As technology permeates every aspect of life, Indian society is navigating this complex landscape, seeking to balance tradition with modernity. This delicate balancing act unfolds at individual, societal, and governmental levels, shaping the nation&#39;s evolving identity. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Individual-level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selective adoption:&lt;/strong&gt; Individuals choose to adopt technology that aligns with their values and traditions. For example, a person might use social media to connect with family and friends while avoiding content that conflicts with their beliefs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Detox:&lt;/strong&gt; Many people practice digital detox, setting aside specific times to disconnect from technology and engage in traditional activities like meditation, yoga, or spending time with family.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional skill enhancement:&lt;/strong&gt; Individuals learn and practice traditional skills like crafts, music, or dance, often using technology to document, share, and promote these skills. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethical usage of Technology:&lt;/strong&gt; People strive to use technology ethically, avoiding cyberbullying, spreading misinformation, and engaging in harmful online activities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindful consumption:&lt;/strong&gt; Individuals make conscious choices about the technology they consume, prioritizing content that enriches their lives and avoids excessive screen time. &lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Setting time reminders on Youtube.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Societal-level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Religious Practices:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Indian temples and religious institutions offer online pujas and live-streamed aarti ceremonies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:18.0pt;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; Peter Berger&lt;/strong&gt; argues that technology enabled the creation of &lt;strong&gt;virtual religious communities&lt;/strong&gt; and digital religious content, allowing individuals to &lt;strong&gt;engage with religion without physically attending religious institutions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural Preservation through Digital Archives and Libraries:&lt;/strong&gt; Societal groups and NGOs create online archives of folk songs, dance forms, and regional languages, promoting cultural preservation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: The People’s Linguistic Survey of India documents Indian languages online.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech-Enabled Tradition:&lt;/strong&gt; Technology is used to modernize traditional practices, such as online yoga classes, virtual temple visits, and digital preservation of ancient texts. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Literacy:&lt;/strong&gt; Efforts are made to promote digital literacy, empowering individuals to use technology responsibly and critically. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Engagement:&lt;/strong&gt; Online platforms are used to foster community engagement, connecting people with shared interests and facilitating knowledge sharing. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At Government-level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital India for Cultural Heritage Preservation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Digitization efforts to preserve cultural heritage, such as monuments, manuscripts, and artwork.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:18.0pt;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheme&lt;/strong&gt;: National Mission on Libraries and Digital India program for heritage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill India Initiative for Traditional Craft and Handloom Promotion:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Programs to upskill artisans in traditional crafts and integrate digital skills.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:18.0pt;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheme&lt;/strong&gt;: PM Kaushal Vikas Yojana (PMKVY) with courses for handicrafts and weaving.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-learning Platforms for traditional knowledge: &lt;/strong&gt;Government e-learning platforms like SWAYAM offering courses on Sanskrit, classical arts, and traditional knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AYUSH integration in mainstream healthcare&lt;/strong&gt;: Promotion of traditional health practices like Ayurveda and Yoga alongside modern medicine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:18.0pt;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheme&lt;/strong&gt;: AYUSH Mission and AYUSH Health and Wellness Centres.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support for E-Commerce platforms to boost artisan economy:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Government collaborates with e-commerce platforms to allow artisans to sell their goods digitally.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:18.0pt;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheme&lt;/strong&gt;: GeM (Government e-Marketplace) facilitates online sales for artisans.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity measures for safeguarding digital heritage:&lt;/strong&gt; The government implements cybersecurity protocols to protect digital archives of cultural heritage, preventing data breaches and unauthorized access to culturally sensitive information under various policies and statutes like the &lt;strong&gt;Digital Personal Data Protection Act, 2023&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;6.How Indian Society can better adapt to technological advancements?&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;The impact of technology on Indian society is profound and multifaceted, shaping various aspects such as communication, education, health care, and governance. To maximize the benefits of technological advancements while mitigating potential drawbacks, several specific strategies and best practices can be adopted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:disc;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bridging the digital divide:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Expand broadband connectivity to underserved regions, subsidize or incentivize the production and distribution of affordable digital devices, conduct community-based campaigns and workshops on digital literacy, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promoting Ethical Use of Technology:&lt;/strong&gt; Establish frameworks for responsible use of technology, focusing on data privacy, digital rights, mandating public disclosure of how algorithms influence decision-making, strengthen fact-checking mechanisms to curb misinformation, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type:circle;&quot;&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example: The OECD&lt;/strong&gt; has developed principles for the ethical use of AI, focusing on transparency, accountability, and human-centered design.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigating job displacement and automation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Strengthen state and corporate initiatives for skill development in emerging fields like AI, robotics, and renewable energy, exploring the option to provide universal safety nets for displaced workers, promote human-centric AI development that augment human abilities rather than replace them, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supporting Startups and Innovation Hubs&lt;/strong&gt;: Provide mentorship and funding through government and private sector partnerships to support startups that focus on social impact, such as health tech or agri-tech solutions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensure Mental-health and social well-being:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Digital detox campaigns to promote healthy screen-time habits, regulate addictive features and restrict exploitative design practices, like endless scrolling, leverage technology (e.g., telemedicine and apps) to provide accessible mental health resources, etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing Smart Governance:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilize technology for efficient service delivery, such as e-governance platforms that streamline processes like licensing, permits, and public grievance redressal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;: Adopt a citizen-centric design for digital services, ensuring user-friendly interfaces and multi-language support to cater to diverse populations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0,0%,0%);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainable Technology Practices&lt;/strong&gt;: Incentivize the adoption of energy-efficient devices and renewable energy solutions, promote circular economy through reuse, refurbishing, and recycling practices in technology manufacturing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;      &lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;   &lt;p style=&quot;text-align:justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:hsl(0, 0%, 0%);&quot;&gt;World Bank emphasizes the future of technology and society hinges on a collective commitment to harnessing technology for the greater good. By prioritizing inclusivity, ethical standards, and sustainability, we can create a technological landscape that not only enhances economic growth but also upholds social values and improves the quality of life for all individuals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;    </description><link>https://visionias.in/current-affairs/weekly-focus/2024-12-04/social-issues/introduction-16</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://visionias.in/current-affairs/weekly-focus/2024-12-04/social-issues/introduction-16</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Vision IAS</author><category>Digital Detox</category><category>Indian Society</category><category>Impact of Technology on Families</category><category>Technology fuelling Urbanization</category><category>Technology fuelling Ruralization</category><category>Digital Divide</category><category>Ethical Use of Technology</category></item></channel></rss>