<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约时报中文网 - 中英对照版</title><link>https://cn.nytimes.com</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.isrss.com/nytimes/dual" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>纽约时报中文网 - 中英对照版 - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:41:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>「中英」马斯克“肢解”美国软实力，北京乐于填补真空</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/22dc-prexy-fkvw/22dc-prexy-fkvw-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;特朗普总统周五宣布了建造下一代隐形战斗机的项目。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;特朗普总统周五宣布了建造下一代隐形战斗机的项目。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Haiyun Jiang for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;When President Trump announced on Friday that the United States would move ahead with a long-debated project to build a stealthy next-generation fighter jet, the message to China was clear: The United States plans to spend tens of billions of dollars over the next decade, probably far longer, to contain Beijing’s ability to dominate the skies over the Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普总统上周五宣布，美国将推进争论已久的下一代隐形战斗机项目，这是向中国发出的明确信息：美国计划在未来10年乃至更长时间里花费数百亿美元遏制北京掌控太平洋空域的能力。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But here on earth, the reality has been very different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但在我们脚踏的土地上，现实却截然不同。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Department of Government Efficiency roars through agencies across government, its targets have included some of the organizations that Beijing worried about most, or actively sought to subvert. And, as with much that Elon Musk’s DOGE has dismembered, there has been no published study of the costs and benefits of losing those capabilities — and no discussion of how the roles, arguably as important as a manned fighter, might be replaced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;政府效率部在政府各机构采取轰轰烈烈的行动，其目标包括了一些北京最担心或积极寻求破坏的组织。而且，就像埃隆·马斯克的政府效率部肢解的许多东西一样，目前还没有关于失去这些能力的成本和收益的公开研究报告，也没有人讨论如何取代这些可以说与载人战斗机同样重要的角色。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the list of capabilities on life support is Radio Free Asia, a 29-year-old nonprofit that estimates its news broadcasts reach 60 million people in Asia each week, from China to Myanmar, and across the Pacific islands where the United States has been struggling to counter China’s narratives about the world. It furloughed all but 75 of its Washington staff members on Friday, trying to stay on the air while court cases develop on Trump officials’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/world/asia/china-trump-voice-of-america.html&quot;&gt;moves to defund U.S. government-supported media&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;这些即将不保的能力中包括自由亚洲电台，一家拥有29年历史的非营利性机构。据估计，其新闻广播每周覆盖亚洲从中国到缅甸乃至太平洋诸岛的6000万人口，美国一直在这些地方努力反驳中国关于世界的叙事。周五，该电视台大部分工作人员被强制休假，只有75名华盛顿员工仍然在岗，努力保持节目播出，与此同时，特朗普官员停止向美国政府支持媒体拨发经费的行动所引起的诉讼仍在继续。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the Pentagon, Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth eliminated the Office of Net Assessment, an internal think-tank. With an annual budget that accounted for a few seconds of Pentagon spending each year, the office tried to think ahead about the challenges the United States would face a decade or two in the future — such as the new capabilities of artificial intelligence, autonomous weapons and the hidden vulnerabilities of supply chains for military contractors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在五角大楼，国防部长皮特·海格塞斯裁撤了内部智库“网络评估办公室”。这个办公室的年度预算在五角大楼支出中显得微不足道，但它试图就美国在未来10年或20年将面临的挑战做出前瞻性的思考——比如人工智能和自主武器带来的新能力，以及军事承包商供应链的隐患。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a revered institution, what a Wall Street Journal editorial this past week called &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/opinion/the-office-that-won-the-cold-war-rip-defense-military-office-net-assessment-73fa33a0&quot;&gt;“The Office that Won the Cold War.”&lt;/a&gt; Mr. Hegseth said in a statement that it would be reconstituted in some unspecified way “in alignment with the Department’s strategic priorities,” though its value was that it challenged conventional thinking about those priorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;这是一个受人尊敬的机构，被《华尔街日报》上周的一篇社论称为“&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/opinion/the-office-that-won-the-cold-war-rip-defense-military-office-net-assessment-73fa33a0&quot;&gt;赢得冷战的办公室&lt;/a&gt;”。海格塞斯在一份声明中说，它将以某种“与国防部的战略重点保持一致”的未指明方式进行重组，尽管该机构的价值在于挑战了关于这些重点的传统思维。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over at the Department of Homeland Security, a series of cyberdefenses have been stripped away, at a moment when China’s state-backed hackers have been more successful than at any time in recent memory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在国土安全部，一系列网络防御措施被裁撤，而此时，中国政府支持的黑客正取得空前的成果。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among those dissolved, at least for the time being, is the Cyber Safety Review Board, created on the model of the National Transportation Safety Board, which examines aircraft accidents and tries to extract lessons learned. The cybersecurity board was just beginning to take testimony on how Chinese intelligence bored deep inside America’s largest telecommunications firms, including the system the Justice Department uses to monitor its “lawful intercept” system, which places wiretaps on people suspected of committing crimes or spying — including Chinese spies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;至少目前已被解散的机构还有网络安全审查委员会。该委员会是以负责调查飞机事故并试图从中吸取教训的美国国家运输安全委员会为模版成立的。网络安全委员会刚刚开始听取有关中国情报机构如何深入美国最大电信公司的证词，包括司法部用于监控其“合法拦截”系统的系统，“合法拦截”对涉嫌犯罪或从事间谍活动的人进行窃听，包括中国间谍在内。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the board has been disbanded. No one at the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency seems able to say what has happened to the investigation into one of the most successful penetrations of American networks, or who is now responsible for figuring out why American telecommunications firms were caught unawares, for more than a year, by China’s Ministry of State Security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;现在委员会已经解散。美国网络安全和基础设施安全局似乎没有人能够说得清，对美国网络最成功入侵事件之一的调查进展如何，也没有人能够说得清，现在是谁负责查明，为何美国电信公司在一年多的时间里毫无防备被中国国家安全部入侵。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The list goes on, more evidence that in its first two months the new administration has been devastatingly efficient in tearing things down, but painfully slow to explain how their actions fit into their broader strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这样的例子还有很多，更多证据表明，新政府上任的前两个月里，在拆除现有机构方面表现得极其高效，但在解释他们的行动如何符合更广泛的战略方面却慢得令人痛苦。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All this has the Chinese celebrating. As the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/world/asia/china-trump-voice-of-america.html&quot;&gt;Voice of America was being dismantled&lt;/a&gt; and fell silent, The Global Times, a mouthpiece of the Chinese Communist Party, wrote that “the so-called beacon of freedom, VOA, has now been discarded by its own government like a dirty rag.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;所有这一切都让中国人欢欣鼓舞。在&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20250319/china-trump-voice-of-america/&quot;&gt;美国之音被裁撤并陷入沉寂&lt;/a&gt;之际，中国共产党的喉舌媒体《环球时报》写道，“美国之音这块所谓‘自由灯塔’的招牌，如今已被本国政府嫌弃得像块脏抹布。”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China is still trying to take its measure of the new administration, which is putting new sanctions on Chinese entities that buy Iranian oil, but is also talking about wiping out the CHIPS and Science Act. The law not only provided federal funding to jump-start the production of advanced semiconductors in the United States, but provided billions for advanced work in a range of key technologies, from batteries to quantum computing, that China is subsidizing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国仍在试图对美国的这届新政府做出评估，新政府在对购买伊朗石油的中国实体实施新的制裁，同时又在考虑废除《芯片与科学法案》。该法案不仅为启动美国先进半导体的生产提供联邦资金，还为从电池到量子计算等一系列关键技术的先进研究提供了数十亿美元的资金，而中国正在为这些研究提供补贴。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s a contradiction, as the Chinese say, that we are cutting back on our instruments of national power while saying that we are stepping up our competition with Beijing,” said Michael J. Green, chief executive of the United States Study Center at the University of Sydney in Australia. “When we reveal human rights abuses or Chinese misinformation, it’s another form of competition with China. And getting rid of it only creates a vacuum that Beijing is going to try to fill. And we are already seeing that happening.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“一方面说我们要削减国家力量的工具，另一方面又在说我们要加强与北京的竞争，用中国人的话说，这是矛盾的，”澳大利亚悉尼大学美国研究中心的首席执行官迈克尔·格林说。“揭露侵犯人权的行为或中国的错误信息，是我们与中国竞争的另一种形式。裁掉它只会造成一个真空，北京将试图填补这个真空。我们已经看到这种情况在发生。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The speed of the dismantlement has left many Asia experts a bit stunned, because they know the new aircraft — which Mr. Trump said would be called the F-47, clearly in homage to his own second term — will not contribute to American deterrence for a decade, if it is on time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;美国拆除机构的速度让许多亚洲问题专家感到有些震惊，因为他们知道，这种新飞机——特朗普说它将被命名为F-47，显然是向他的第二任期致敬——即使按时交付，也不会在10年内为美国的威慑力做出贡献。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The charge for the United States is to deter war with China without capitulation and to compete effectively across all the areas of soft power,” Richard Fontaine, the chief executive of the Center for a New American Security and a former Republican aide to John McCain in the Senate, said on Friday. “The United States has an array of tools to do this, including humanitarian aid, development assistance, support for democracy abroad, and strategic communications efforts. Strangely, these are the efforts most under threat by the new cost-cutting teams.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“美国的责任在不退让的前提下通过威慑防止与中国的战争，并在所有软实力领域进行有效竞争，”新美国安全中心首席执行官理查德·方丹周五表示，他曾在参议院担任约翰·麦凯恩的共和党助手。“美国有一系列的手段来做到这一点，包括人道主义援助、发展援助、对海外民主的支持以及战略沟通努力。奇怪的是，这些努力正受到新的成本削减团队的最大威胁。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If it goes too far,” he warned, “it will amount to unilateral disarmament in the world’s most important contest.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“如果做得太过火，”他警告说，“就等于在世界上最重要的较量中单方面裁军。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is hard to find an understandable theme to the cuts; some are based on perceived acts of disloyalty, or old grudges, or a sense that even state-financed media or think tanks are inhabited by anti-Trump liberals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;很难为这些削减找到一个可以理解的主题；有些是基于被认为的不忠行为，也有些是旧怨，还有些是基于一种感觉——即使是国家资助的媒体或智库中也充斥着反特朗普的自由派。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is especially mystifying. The Office of Net Assessment, for example, was mostly staffed by career civilians or uniformed military, who are asked to think outside the box: How would a prolonged economic downturn in China affect its leaders’ thinking about Taiwan? What happens to warfighting when manned aircraft — like the newly announced jet fighter — can be regularly outmaneuvered by autonomous weapons?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;有些地方尤其显得令人费解。例如，网络评估办公室的工作人员大多是职业文职人员或穿制服的军人，他们被要求跳出固有思维定式考虑问题：中国长期的经济低迷将如何影响其领导人对台湾的看法？当有人驾驶飞机——比如新发布的喷气式战斗机——的机动能力被自主武器轻松超越时，战争会怎样发展？&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cuts at Radio Free Asia, which &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.usagm.gov/2018/09/21/radio-free-asia-launches-documentary-on-former-uyghur-detainees/&quot;&gt;broke many of the biggest stories&lt;/a&gt; about the internment camps China has built to “re-educate” Uyghurs in Xinjiang, are among the most mystifying. Its broadcasts have been attacked by Beijing, which has gone to great lengths to censor the reports and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/06/22/technology/xinjiang-uyghurs-china-propaganda.html&quot;&gt;broadcast their own narrative, often on YouTube and X.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;自由亚洲电台曾报道过许多关于中国在新疆为“再教育”维吾尔人建立拘禁营的&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.usagm.gov/2018/09/21/radio-free-asia-launches-documentary-on-former-uyghur-detainees/&quot;&gt;重大新闻&lt;/a&gt;，它的裁员是最令人费解的事件之一。它的广播受到了北京的攻击，后者不遗余力地审查这些报道，并&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/zh-hans/interactive/2021/06/22/technology/xinjiang-uyghurs-china-propaganda-chinese.html&quot;&gt;经常在YouTube和X上宣传自己的叙事&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bay Fang, the president of Radio Free Asia, a nonprofit that gets its $60 million budget from a congressionally approved disbursement, said in an interview that she doubted the organization was specifically targeted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;自由亚洲电台是一家非营利组织，其6000万美元的预算来自国会批准的拨款。&lt;span&gt;台长方贝在采访中说，她不觉得这是在专门针对她的机构。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;DOGE and the White House were gunning for Voice of America, which has hundreds of millions of listeners and readers, and which Mr. Trump has denounced as “the Voice of Radical America.” In one of his executive orders, he said he would “ensure taxpayers are no longer on the hook for radical propaganda.” (Almost all of Voice of America’s staff of 1,300 journalists have been put on paid leave.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;政府效率部和白宫对美国之音发起了攻击，拥有数亿听众和读者的美国之音被特朗普谴责为“激进美国之音”。在他的一项行政命令中，他说他将“确保纳税人不再为激进的宣传埋单。”（美国之音的1300名记者员工几乎都被要求带薪休假。）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/04/10/multimedia/22dc-prexy/int-china-voa-gktl-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;自由亚洲电台办事处称，资助该电台的联邦拨款已终止。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/04/10/multimedia/22dc-prexy/int-china-voa-gktl-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;自由亚洲电台办事处称，资助该电台的联邦拨款已终止。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Reuters&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“You have only to look at the way dictators in the region are celebrating our defunding,” Ms. Fang said in an interview. “We provide a voice that counters their propaganda and shines a light into dark corners they’d rather leave untouched.” The result, she said, is that “we are an essential way that America wins trust among the people living in these authoritarian countries. Shuttering RFA is not only their loss, but America’s.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“你只要看看该地区的独裁者如何庆祝我们的资金被取消就知道了，”方贝在接受采访时说。“我们发出的声音反击他们的宣传，照亮他们不愿触及的黑暗角落。”她说，“我们是美国赢得这些专制国家人民信任的重要途径。关闭亚洲自由电台不仅是这些人民的损失，也是美国的损失。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winning trust, however, is hard to quantify. It takes years, and the results are not as easy to demonstrate as showing off a new fighter jet and, in the case of the new F-47, the semiautonomous attack drones that fly alongside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;然而，信任的赢得是很难被量化的。这需要花费数年的时间，而且结果并不像展示一架新型战斗机那样容易，就新型F-47而言，还包括展示与其协同飞行的半自主攻击无人机。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Radio Free Asia’s budget is so small that Ms. Fang said she was pretty certain the nonprofit was “collateral damage” as the administration moved to defund the U.S. Agency for Global Media, which also supports Voice of America, Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;自由亚洲电台的预算非常少，因此方贝说，她非常确定该非营利组织是美国政府削减美国全球媒体机构资金的“附带损害”，美国全球媒体机构还支持美国之音、自由欧洲电台和自由电台。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The defunding is taking place even before the Senate has confirmed Mr. Trump’s choice to head the global media agency, L. Brent Bozell III, a conservative political activist. He has picked Kari Lake, the pro-MAGA former journalist who lost a Senate race in Arizona, as the new head of Voice of America, but for now she is only a “special adviser” because Mr. Trump fired the board members that could have replaced the current leader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在参议院确认特朗普选择的全球媒体机构负责人、保守派政治活动家布伦特·博泽尔三世的任命之前，裁撤就已经开始。他选择了支持“让美国恢复伟大荣光”的前记者、曾在亚利桑那州的参议员竞选中失利的卡里·莱克担任美国之音的新负责人，但目前她只是一名“特别顾问”，因为特朗普解雇了本可以取代现任领导人的董事会成员。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This administration clearly regards “soft power” as a largely irrelevant concept. But the lack of it leaves a vacuum that Beijing will happily fill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;本届政府显然认为，“软实力”在很大程度上是一个无关紧要的概念。但这种实力的缺失会留下一个北京乐于填补的真空。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It seems self-defeating that while China mounts unrelenting cyberattacks, builds a Navy to defeat the U.S. Pacific fleet, sends ‘wolf-warrior’ diplomats far afield, and created alternatives to the dollar that America pulls inward and closes off avenues of information to the Chinese people,” said Paul Kolbe, a career C.I.A. officer who spent much of his career countering Soviet propaganda and covert operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“中国发动无情的网络攻击，建立一支能击败美国太平洋舰队的海军，派遣‘战狼’式的外交官到遥远的海外，创造美元的替代品，而美国却向内收缩，并关闭了中国人民获得信息的渠道，这似乎是在自取灭亡，”中情局职业官员保罗·科尔比说。他职业生涯的大部分时间都在打击苏联的宣传和秘密行动。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking from Jakarta, Mr. Kolbe answered his own question: “We affirm Chinese beliefs that they are ascendant, and that our decline is accelerating.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在雅加达接受采访的科尔比说：“我们是在巩固中国人的信念——他们正在崛起，而我们正在加速衰落。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;David E. Sanger报道特朗普政府和一系列国家安全问题。他在时报任职超过40年，著有数本关于美国国家安全挑战的书。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/david-e-sanger&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/22/us/politics/elon-musk-doge-china.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250324/elon-musk-doge-china/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250324/elon-musk-doge-china/dual</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 04:26:07 GMT</pubDate><author>DAVID E. SANGER</author></item><item><title>「中英」与李强和何立峰分别会面的美国参议员戴恩斯是谁</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/22int-china-daines-lbjf/22int-china-daines-lbjf-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;周六，参议员史蒂夫·戴恩斯和中国国务院副总理何立峰在北京。戴恩斯希望成为特朗普政府与中国政府之间的中间人。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;周六，参议员史蒂夫·戴恩斯和中国国务院副总理何立峰在北京。戴恩斯希望成为特朗普政府与中国政府之间的中间人。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Pool photo by Ng Han Guan&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since President Trump began his second term in January, no high-level officials from the United States have met with their counterparts in China, even as the world’s two largest economies have taken turns imposing steep tariffs on each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;自特朗普总统在1月开始第二个任期以来，尽管世界上最大的两个经济体轮番对彼此征收高额关税，但美中两国没有举行过任何高级别官员会晤。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the absence of official meetings, Senator Steve Daines of Montana has cast himself as a go-between. Mr. Daines met with Vice Premier He Lifeng, who oversees many economic issues for China, on Saturday and was set to meet Premier Li Qiang, the country’s second-highest official, on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在没有正式会晤的情况下，蒙大拿州参议员史蒂夫·戴恩斯扮演了中间人的角色。上周六，戴恩斯与负责中国许多经济事务的国务院副总理何立峰会面，并于周日与中国第二号官员李强总理会晤。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an interview with The New York Times on Saturday after the meeting with Mr. He, Mr. Daines, a Republican member of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, said he urged China to take effective action to halt the export of chemical precursors for fentanyl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;戴恩斯周六在与何立峰会面后接受《纽约时报》采访时表示，他敦促中国采取有效行动，制止芬太尼化学前体的出口。戴恩斯是参议院外交关系委员会的共和党成员。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I met with President Trump a few days before I came over, and he was pleased that I was coming to communicate his ‘America First’ message and, importantly, to make sure that Chinese leaders knew the seriousness of the fentanyl issue, and the role that China can play in stopping the shipment of precursors to the Mexican cartels,” Mr. Daines said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“在我来这里的几天前，我与特朗普总统见了面，他很高兴我来传达他的‘美国优先’信息，更重要的是，要确保中国领导人知道芬太尼问题的严重性，以及中国在阻止向墨西哥贩毒集团运送前体方面可以发挥的作用，”戴恩斯说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese officials have said that the fentanyl crisis is rooted in an American failure to curb demand for the drug, and that Beijing has taken effective measures to limit shipments of fentanyl and its chemical precursors. China’s cabinet issued a report earlier this month on its fentanyl measures, and Mr. Daines said this was being studied by American officials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国官员表示，芬太尼危机的根源在于美国未能遏制对这种毒品的需求，中国政府已采取有效措施限制芬太尼及其化学前体的运输。中国国务院本月早些时候发布了一份关于芬太尼措施的报告，戴恩斯称美国官员正在研究这份报告。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Daines said he was trying to lay the groundwork for a meeting between President Trump and Xi Jinping, China’s top leader. “This visit is the first step to arrange and set up the next step, which will be a very important meeting between President Xi and President Trump — when that occurs, I don’t know, where it occurs, I don’t know.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;戴恩斯表示，他正在为特朗普总统与中国最高领导人习近平的会晤奠定基础。“此行是为安排和筹备下一步做准备，这将是习近平主席与特朗普总统之间一次非常重要的会晤——何时发生，我不知道，在哪里发生，我也不知道。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The White House has not named Mr. Daines as acting on its behalf. But Mr. Daines is one of Mr. Trump’s top allies in Congress. He was the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-steve-daines-election-2024-853fcaf1a577a93cbf5bd0a6eea34338&quot;&gt;first member of the Republican leadership&lt;/a&gt; in the Senate to endorse Mr. Trump in 2023 for a second term at a time when many Republican senators were leery of seeing Mr. Trump return to the White House.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;白宫并未指派戴恩斯代表其行事。但他是特朗普在国会的主要盟友之一。2023年许多共和党参议员对特朗普重返白宫持谨慎态度时，戴恩斯是第一个为他的竞选背书的参议院共和党领导人物。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Given Senator Daines’s relationship to Donald Trump, China certainly wants to learn from him about Trump’s China policy intentions — whether he still wants to make a deal with China, and if so, what the deal would look like,” said Wu Xinbo, dean of the Institute of International Studies at Fudan University in Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;复旦大学国际问题研究院院长吴心伯表示：“鉴于戴恩斯参议员与特朗普的关系，中国肯定希望从他那里了解特朗普的中国政策意图——他是否仍然希望与中国达成协议，如果是的话，协议会是什么样的。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China also wants Senator Daines to “bring a message to Donald Trump that China wants to sit down to talk with the U.S. side and to avoid further escalation of the tensions,” Mr. Wu said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;吴心伯表示，中方还希望戴恩斯参议员“向唐纳德·特朗普传达一个信息，即中方希望与美方坐下来谈判，避免紧张局势进一步升级”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump has imposed 20 percent tariffs on goods from China and threatened more. China wants to head off further tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普已对来自中国的商品征收20%的关税，并威胁征收更多关税。中国希望避免进一步加征关税。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There’s a window of opportunity before early April for China and the U.S. to engage each other, and Senator Daines’s visit could play a pivotal role,” Mr. Wu said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“在4月初之前，中美之间有一个相互接触的机会窗口，戴恩斯参议员的访问可能会起到关键作用，”吴心伯说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Daines said that he was not focusing on tariffs with China, because the Office of the United States Trade Representative has not yet finished a policy review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;戴恩斯称，他没有把重点放在与中国的关税问题上，因为美国贸易代表办公室尚未完成政策审查。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump has said he plans to meet with Mr. Xi, without specifying details. China has said nothing publicly about a meeting. But the contacts between working-level administration officials that typically precede such a meeting have been absent so far during Mr. Trump’s second term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普曾表示他打算与习近平会晤，但没有具体说明细节。中国方面则未公开提及任何会晤。然而，在特朗普第二个任期内，通常在此类会晤前会进行的工作层级政府官员之间的接触至今尚未发生。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Xi makes all important decisions in China, particularly on foreign policy. That makes summits with American presidents particularly important in setting the trajectory of bilateral relations. The two leaders met in 2017 when Mr. Xi went to Mar-a-Lago, in Florida, and Mr. Trump went to China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国所有的重要决策都由习近平做出，尤其是在外交政策方面。这使得与美国总统的峰会在确定双边关系走向时尤为重要。两位领导人曾于2017年会晤，当时习近平访问了佛罗里达州的马阿拉歌庄园，而特朗普也在当年访问了中国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lack of engagement with Washington until now has led some in Beijing to begin to doubt whether Mr. Trump is sincere in his expressed desire to meet Mr. Xi, said Yun Sun, the director of the China program at the Stimson Center in Washington.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;华盛顿史汀生中心中国项目主任孙韵表示，至今仍缺少与华盛顿的接触，让北京的一些人开始怀疑特朗普是否真心希望与习近平会面。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“They see him changing his position rapidly on a number of issues,” Ms. Sun said. “That translates into an almost fatalism for the Chinese, that they should aim to prepare for the worst case scenario, that’s their conclusion.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“他们看到他在许多问题上的立场说变就变，”孙韵说。“这对中国人来说意味着几乎只能听天由命，他们应该为最坏的情况做好准备，这就是他们的结论。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Daines said he also expressed concern about China’s barriers to imports, beyond just tariffs, during his visit to Beijing. He declined to provide any specifics. But Montana politicians have long argued that China’s intermittent halts on imports of beef from the state are unfair trade barriers, and not the result of any actual concerns about mad cow disease, as Beijing contends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;戴恩斯表示，他还表达了对中国除关税之外的进口壁垒的关切。他拒绝提供具体细节。但蒙大拿州的政界人士长期以来一直认为，中国间歇性地停止从该州进口牛肉是不公平的贸易壁垒，而不是像中国政府所辩称的那样，是出于对疯牛病的实际担忧。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Daines lived for six years in southern China in the 1990s as a project manager for Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, the American consumer products giant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;上世纪90年代，戴恩斯曾作为美国消费品巨头宝洁公司的项目经理在中国南方生活过六年。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This weekend’s trip is Mr. Daines’s sixth to China since his election to the Senate in 2014, making him one of the few members of Congress who have continued traveling to the country even as relations have deteriorated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;本周末的行程是戴恩斯自2014年当选参议员以来的第六次中国之行，这使他成为在美中关系恶化的情况下仍坚持前往中国的少数国会议员之一。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keith Bradsher是《纽约时报》北京分社社长，此前曾任上海分社社长、香港分社社长、底特律分社社长，以及华盛顿记者。他在新冠疫情期间常驻中国进行报道。 &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/keith-bradsher&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meaghan Tobin是时报科技记者，常驻台北，报道亚洲地区的商业和科技新闻，重点关注中国。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/meaghan-tobin&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/22/world/asia/trump-china-xi-daines.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20250324/trump-china-xi-daines/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20250324/trump-china-xi-daines/dual</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 03:01:11 GMT</pubDate><author>KEITH BRADSHER,MEAGHAN TOBIN</author></item><item><title>「中英」赖清德“拒统17条”：为何选在此时对北京展示强硬立场</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/21/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-01-gvbh/00int-taiwan-china-01-gvbh-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;上周五，台湾总统赖清德访问台北松山空军基地。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;上周五，台湾总统赖清德访问台北松山空军基地。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Ann Wang/Reuters&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;After Taiwan’s president, Lai Ching-te, launched a broad drive this month against what he warned was expanding Chinese subversion and spying, the backlash was swift.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;本月，台湾总统赖清德针对他所警告的中国日益扩大的颠覆与间谍活动发起了一场大规模行动，随后迅速引发了强烈反弹。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Across the Taiwan Strait, Beijing hit back, sending a surge of military planes and ships near the island and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.taiwan.cn/xwzx/xwfbh/gtbxwfbh/tuwen/202503/t20250313_12689917.htm&quot;&gt;warning that&lt;/a&gt; he was “playing with fire.” In Taiwan, Mr. Lai’s opponents accused him of dangerously goading China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;台湾海峡对岸的北京发起反击，派出大量军机和军舰靠近台湾，并&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.taiwan.cn/xwzx/xwfbh/gtbxwfbh/tuwen/202503/t20250313_12689917.htm&quot;&gt;警告&lt;/a&gt;赖清德正在“玩火”。在台湾，赖清德的反对者指责他危险地挑衅中国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Mr. Lai is wagering that he can — and, his supporters say, must — take a harder line against Chinese influence now, notwithstanding the threats from Beijing and the possibility that Taiwan’s opposition parties will dig in deeper against his agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;尽管面临来自北京的威胁，且台湾反对党可能会采取更多措施来反对他的议程，但赖清德正在打赌，他现在能够对中国的影响采取更强硬的立场，他的支持者也认为他必须这样做。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lai appears to have concluded that China will limit its actions against Taiwan while Beijing focuses on trying to negotiate with President Trump over the escalating trade war, said &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/expert/david-sacks&quot;&gt;David Sacks,&lt;/a&gt; a fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations who monitors Taiwanese affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;美国外交关系委员会关注台湾事务的研究员&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/expert/david-sacks&quot;&gt;大卫·萨克斯&lt;/a&gt;表示，赖清德似乎已得出结论，在北京一心试图与特朗普总统就不断升级的贸易战进行谈判之际，中国将克制对台湾的行动。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The best guess is that he assessed that, if he was going to do this, he should do it at a time when China doesn’t want something to complicate its discussions with the United States,” Mr. Sacks, in an interview, said of Mr. Lai’s security steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“最有可能的是，他认为：如果他要这么做，就应该在中国不希望出现什么事情使得与美国的谈判复杂化的时候做，”萨克斯在采访中谈到赖清德的安全措施时说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/02/25/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china/25intepreter-6-ghfp-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2023年，台湾举行军事演习。赖清德总统正在采取措施加强针对中国的安全保障。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/02/25/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china/25intepreter-6-ghfp-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;2023年，台湾举行军事演习。赖清德总统正在采取措施加强针对中国的安全保障。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Lam Yik Fei for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan’s political parties have for decades argued over whether to try to work with or distance the island from neighboring China, which claims Taiwan as its territory, to be taken by force if Beijing leaders so decide. The contention has taken on a sharper edge since Mr. Lai declared on March 13 that China was a “foreign hostile force” exploiting Taiwan’s freedoms to “divide, destroy, and subvert us from within.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;几十年来，台湾各党派一直在争论是应该试图与邻近的中国合作，还是与之保持距离。中国声称台湾是其领土，如果北京领导人决意如此，可以使用武力攻占台湾。自赖清德于3月13日宣称中国是“境外敌对势力”，利用台湾的自由“在台湾内部进行分化、破坏、颠覆等活动”以来，这种争论变得更加激烈。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;He &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://english.president.gov.tw/NEWS/6919&quot;&gt;laid out 17 steps to fight back&lt;/a&gt;, including restoring military courts to try Taiwanese military personnel accused of espionage and other security crimes. He wants to more closely monitor Taiwanese people’s contacts with China to stop what he said was Beijing’s political exploitation of religious, educational and cultural exchanges. He demanded greater disclosure about Taiwanese politicians who visit China. Many such politicians belong to the opposition Nationalist Party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;他&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://english.president.gov.tw/NEWS/6919&quot;&gt;提出了17项反击措施&lt;/a&gt;，包括恢复军事法院审判被指控犯有间谍罪和其他安全罪的台湾军人。他希望更密切地监视台湾人与中国的联系，以阻止他所说的北京利用宗教、教育和文化交流进行政治干预。他要求对访问中国的台湾政界人士的信息进行更多披露。这些政客中的很多人属于反对党国民党。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have no choice but to take even more proactive measures,” Mr. Lai said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我们没有选择，必须采取更积极的作为，”赖清德说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beijing despises Mr. Lai and his Democratic Progressive Party, accusing them of being separatists. Chinese officials quickly denounced Mr. Lai’s speech, especially his use of the term “foreign hostile force.” Taiwan’s opposition Nationalist Party, which favors ties and talks with China, accused Mr. Lai needlessly fanning tensions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;北京鄙视赖清德和他所在的民进党，指责他们是分裂分子。中国官员迅速谴责了赖清德的讲话，尤其是他使用的“境外敌对势力”一词。主张与中国建立联系与对话的台湾反对党国民党指责赖清德无端煽动紧张局势。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-zhkt/00int-taiwan-china-zhkt-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;台湾国防部发布的一张照片显示，3月，台湾军方人员在一个未公开的地点对海军快速布雷艇进行准备工作。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-zhkt/00int-taiwan-china-zhkt-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;台湾国防部发布的一张照片显示，3月，台湾军方人员在一个未公开的地点对海军快速布雷艇进行准备工作。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Taiwan Ministry of Defense/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Specifically singling out mainland China and the Chinese Communist Party is to some degree a provocation,” &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ly.gov.tw/EngPages/List.aspx?nodeid=55306&quot;&gt;Hsu Chiao-hsin&lt;/a&gt;, a prominent Nationalist lawmaker, said in an interview. “This will trigger even more tensions across the strait.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“特別去点出中国大陆、去点出中共，其实就是某种程度地去挑衅，”著名国民党立法委员&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ly.gov.tw/EngPages/List.aspx?nodeid=55306&quot;&gt;徐巧芯&lt;/a&gt;在接受采访时表示。“那就会发起（导致）两岸更加紧张。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nationalist politicians said they would resist at least some of Mr. Lai’s proposed steps. They argue that reinstating &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-23698791&quot;&gt;military courts&lt;/a&gt;, which were abolished in 2013 after protests over abuses of soldiers, is backsliding. “Many of these 17 steps restrict people’s civil rights,” Mrs. Hsu said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;国民党政治人物表示，他们将抵制赖清德提出的至少部分措施。他们认为，恢复&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-23698791&quot;&gt;军事审判&lt;/a&gt;是一种倒退。2013年，军事审判在因军人遭虐待而引发的抗议活动后被废除。“这个17条里面，有很多都是在限制人民的公民权利，”徐巧芯说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ly.gov.tw/EngPages/List.aspx?nodeid=55311&quot;&gt;Ko Chih-en&lt;/a&gt;, another Nationalist Party legislator, accused Mr. Lai of unfairly casting his domestic critics as “red” tools of Beijing. “Don’t make it like anyone with any connection to China is given a red hat so that everyone is in fear.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;另一名国民党立法委员&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ly.gov.tw/EngPages/List.aspx?nodeid=55311&quot;&gt;柯志恩&lt;/a&gt;指责赖清德不公平地将国内批评者描绘成北京的“红色”工具。“不用好像处处只要是跟中国有任何的关联，每个人就要被框上一个红帽子，让大家处于这种恐惧。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rising political acrimony could further complicate Mr. Lai’s plans, including perhaps most crucially a proposed increase in military spending meant to mollify Washington. President Trump and his team &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/10/world/asia/taiwan-trump-us-support.html&quot;&gt;have said that Taiwan&lt;/a&gt; should sharply raise its defense budget, to as much as 10 percent of its economy, up from the current budgeted 2.45 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;政治紧张局势加剧可能会使赖清德计划的推进更加复杂，其中最关键的可能是为安抚华盛顿而提出的增加军费开支的计划。特朗普总统及其团队&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20241111/taiwan-trump-us-support/&quot;&gt;表示，台湾&lt;/a&gt;应大幅提高国防预算，从目前占经济产出的2.45%提高到10%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lai &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://english.president.gov.tw/News/6908&quot;&gt;vowed last month&lt;/a&gt; to use an additional “special budget” later this year to push overall defense spending to more than 3 percent of the economy. But the increase must win approval from Taiwan’s legislature, where the Nationalists and a smaller party, the Taiwan People’s Party, hold a majority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;赖清德&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://english.president.gov.tw/News/6908&quot;&gt;上个月承诺&lt;/a&gt;，将在今年晚些时候动用一笔额外的“特别预算”，将国防总开支提高到经济产出的3%以上。但这一增幅必须获得台湾立法院的批准，国民党和规模较小的台湾民众党在立法院中占多数席位。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lai may be thinking that despite their anger at him, Taiwan’s opposition parties will ultimately back the planned increase in military spending, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/expert/david-sacks&quot;&gt;Mr. Sacks&lt;/a&gt; said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/expert/david-sacks&quot;&gt;萨克斯&lt;/a&gt;表示，赖清德也许认为，尽管台湾反对党对他感到愤怒，但最终他们会支持增加军费开支的计划。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I think that part of Lai’s calculus is also that if the opposition played games with his proposed defense spending increase, that would get Washington’s attention in a way they really don’t want,” Mr. Sacks said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我认为赖清德的部分盘算还在于，如果反对党利用他提出的增加国防开支的提议来做动作，那将以他们并不希望的方式引发华盛顿的关注，”萨克斯说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-wzjg/00int-taiwan-china-wzjg-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1月，反对党国民党立委参加2025年中央政府预算辩论。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-wzjg/00int-taiwan-china-wzjg-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1月，反对党国民党立委参加2025年中央政府预算辩论。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Cheng Yu-Chen/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Taiwan’s main annual budget passed this year, the opposition imposed cuts and conditions that Mr. Lai’s government said would hamper government operations. The opposition parties have said the cuts were aimed at wasteful spending, and Taiwan’s military preparedness would not be hurt by their measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;今年台湾的主要年度预算案通过时，反对党强行削减开支并附加条件，赖清德政府称这些措施会妨碍政府的运作。反对党称，削减开支是为了防止浪费，台湾的军事准备不会受到这些措施的影响。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“My sense is that President Lai will eventually be able to get a special budget passed by the legislature, but at some political costs,” said &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://globaltaiwan.org/member/russell-hsiao/&quot;&gt;Russell Hsiao&lt;/a&gt;, the executive director of the Global Taiwan Institute in Washington.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;“The opposition parties will make him and the ruling party pay a political price, even though, eventually, they will go along with it — in part because they know that Washington is paying close attention.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我的感觉是，赖清德总统最终能够让立法院通过特别预算，但要付出一些政治代价，”华盛顿的全球台湾研究所执行长&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://globaltaiwan.org/member/russell-hsiao/&quot;&gt;萧良其&lt;/a&gt;说。“反对党会让他和执政党付出政治代价，尽管他们最终会同意这笔预算，部分原因是他们知道华盛顿正在密切关注。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Negotiations over the special budget could be protracted and tense, even if both sides generally agree on more military spending, said &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pf.org.tw/en/pfen/30.html&quot;&gt;Raymond Cheng-en Sung&lt;/a&gt;, the vice president of the Prospect Foundation, a government-funded institute in Taipei. “The limited window of opportunity that we have for getting this done could still vanish,” Mr. Sung said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;位于台北的政府资助机构远景基金会副执行长&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pf.org.tw/tw/pfch/10.html&quot;&gt;宋承恩&lt;/a&gt;表示，即使双方基本同意增加军费开支，关于特别预算的谈判也可能会很漫长，且气氛紧张。“把这件事解决的机会窗口很有限，而且仍然是可能消失的，”宋正恩说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several Nationalist lawmakers, including Richard Yeong-Kang Chen, a former admiral, said they broadly supported a rise in military spending. But the polarized atmosphere made legislative give-and-take harder, Mr. Chen said. Like most opposition politicians, he blamed Mr. Lai for the impasse. Mr. Lai’s side blames obstruction by the opposition parties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;包括前海军上将陈永康在内的几位国民党立委表示，他们普遍支持增加军费开支。但陈永康表示，政治分化的氛围使得立法会上的讨论变得更加困难。与大多数反对党政治人物一样，他将这样的僵局归咎于赖清德。赖清德一方则将问题归咎于反对党的阻挠。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Putting it harshly, there’s virtually no communication now between the two parties,” Mr. Chen said of the Nationalists and Mr. Lai’s Democratic Progressive Party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“现在我严格讲就是说，两个政党几乎没有沟通，”陈永康在谈及国民党和赖清德领导的民进党时说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lai won &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/13/world/asia/taiwan-election-china-us.html&quot;&gt;40 percent of the vote&lt;/a&gt; in the presidential election last year, but his party lost its majority in the legislature, resulting in frequent standoffs over Mr. Lai’s initiatives. &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/front/archives/2024/05/18/2003818026&quot;&gt;Brawls have broken&lt;/a&gt; out in Taiwan’s legislative chamber, and opponents of the Nationalist Party and Taiwan People’s Party &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/28/world/asia/taiwan-protest-fight.html&quot;&gt;staged protests&lt;/a&gt; outside the legislative building last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;去年，赖清德在总统选举中赢得了&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20240114/taiwan-election-china-us/&quot;&gt;40%的选票&lt;/a&gt;，但他的政党在立法院失去了多数席位，导致赖清德的提议经常陷入僵局。台湾立法院曾&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.taipeitimes.com/News/front/archives/2024/05/18/2003818026&quot;&gt;爆发斗殴事件&lt;/a&gt;，去年，国民党和台湾民众党的反对者在立法院外&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20240529/taiwan-protest-fight/&quot;&gt;举行了抗议活动。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-ltkc/00int-taiwan-china-ltkc-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;去年，赖清德总统的支持者在台北的一个抗议活动上。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/22/multimedia/00int-taiwan-china-ltkc/00int-taiwan-china-ltkc-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;去年，赖清德总统的支持者在台北的一个抗议活动上。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;YASUYOSHI CHIBA/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoping to weaken the opposition parties’ grip on the legislature, Mr. Lai’s Democratic Progressive Party has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://eastasiaforum.org/2025/03/20/taiwans-democratic-uncertainty-in-the-face-of-recall-elections/&quot;&gt;backed a recall&lt;/a&gt; campaign against opposition lawmakers, using a rule that members of the legislature can face fresh elections, outside of the usual cycle, if enough voters sign petitions. The The Nationalist Party has, in turn, backed recall petitions against D.P.P. lawmakers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;为了削弱反对党对立法院的控制，赖清德所在的民进党&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://eastasiaforum.org/2025/03/20/taiwans-democratic-uncertainty-in-the-face-of-recall-elections/&quot;&gt;支持罢免&lt;/a&gt;反对派立委的行动，其依据的规则是，如果有足够多的选民签署请愿书，立法委员席位可以在正常选举周期之外重新选举。而国民党则支持罢免民进党立委的请愿。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lai’s recent speech on China appeared partly intended to sharpen the contrast with the opposition, said &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/people/ryan-hass/&quot;&gt;Ryan Hass&lt;/a&gt;, an expert on China and Taiwan at the Brookings Institution. “I think it was intended to reassert control of the narrative, to put people who are opposing his agenda on the back foot,” Mr. Hass said in an interview while visiting Taipei.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;布鲁金斯学会中国和台湾问题专家何瑞恩&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/people/ryan-hass/&quot;&gt;(Ryan Hass&lt;/a&gt;)表示，赖清德最近关于中国的讲话似乎部分意在加强与反对派的对比。“我认为这是为了重新掌控叙事，让反对他议程的人处于劣势，”何瑞恩在访问台北期间接受采访时表示。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, he and many other experts say Taiwan does face growing efforts by China to illicitly influence public opinion on the island, erode confidence in its government and military forces, and to collect intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;不过，他和许多其他专家都表示，台湾确实面临着中国越来越多的企图，包括对岛内舆论的不正当影响、削弱人们对台湾政府和军队的信心，以及收集情报。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Lai said the growing threat from China was reflected in the data: 64 people faced charges of espionage in Taiwan in 2024, he said, three times the number charged with the offense in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;赖清德表示，有数据表明来自中国的威胁日益严重：他说，2024年台湾有64人面临间谍罪指控，是2021年被控间谍罪人数的三倍。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of those accused of spying, Mr. Lai said, were former or current members of Taiwan’s armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;赖清德称，大多数被指控从事间谍活动的人都是台湾武装部队的前任或现任成员。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;p&gt;储百亮(Chris Buckley)是《纽约时报》首席中国记者，自台北报道中国和台湾问题，重点关注政治、社会变革以及安全和军事问题。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/chris-buckley&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amy Chang Chien是《纽约时报》记者/研究员，常驻台北，报道台湾和中国新闻。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/amy-chang-chien&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/23/world/asia/taiwan-china-trump.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20250324/taiwan-china-trump/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/asia-pacific/20250324/taiwan-china-trump/dual</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 01:48:24 GMT</pubDate><author>储百亮,AMY CHANG CHIEN</author></item><item><title>「中英」美国严查入境旅客，你会被拘留或遣返吗？</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20travel-visa-border1-fwbt/20travel-visa-border1-fwbt-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;743&quot; alt=&quot;美国联邦法律赋予政府特工在边境入境点搜查他人财产的权利，包括手机和笔记本电脑。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;美国联邦法律赋予政府特工在边境入境点搜查他人财产的权利，包括手机和笔记本电脑。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks, a flurry of international visitors attempting to enter the United States from other countries have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/world/europe/us-france-scientist-entry-trump-messages.html&quot;&gt;denied entry&lt;/a&gt; at border checkpoints, leading to either deportations to their home countries or days or weeks of detention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;最近几周，大批试图从其他国家进入美国的国际旅客在边境检查站被&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/world/europe/us-france-scientist-entry-trump-messages.html&quot;&gt;拒绝入境&lt;/a&gt;，他们要么被遣返回本国，要么被拘留数天或数周。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 28-year-old British woman &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/mar/18/british-tourist-rebecca-burke-held-by-us-over-visa-released-from-detention-says-family&quot;&gt;arrived&lt;/a&gt; in Britain earlier this week after she was held at an immigration detention center in Washington State for three weeks. She had attempted to enter the United States from Canada, and questions arose at the land-border crossing whether she had the correct visa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;本周早些时候，一名28岁英国女子在华盛顿州的一个移民拘留中心关押三周后回到了英国。她此前试图从加拿大进入美国，在陆路边境口岸，关于她是否持有正确签证的问题引起了怀疑。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her ordeal came shortly after two German tourists in separate incidents &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/13/world/europe/german-tourists-detained-deported.html&quot;&gt;were deported&lt;/a&gt; after trying to enter the United States from Mexico. Both had spent weeks in a detention center in San Diego, and both said they were unclear as to why they had been detained and deported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在她经历这场磨难不久前，有两名德国游客在试图从墨西哥进入美国后被遣返。两人都在圣地亚哥的一个拘留中心待了数周，他们都表示不清楚自己为何被拘留和遣返。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The incidents have sparked international concern over what travelers can expect at U.S. border crossings. Most citizens of most European countries have for years enjoyed visa-free travel, for up to 90 days, to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这些事件引发了国际社会对旅客在美国边境口岸可能遭遇情况的担忧。多年来，大多数欧洲国家的大多数公民都享有免签前往美国旅行的待遇，最长可达90天。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s what to know about travel visas and rights for international visitors entering the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;以下是进入美国的国际旅客需要了解的旅行签证和权利方面的信息。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The basics of entering and exiting the U.S.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;进出美国的基本要求&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;People seeking to enter the United States who are not U.S. citizens must have a valid passport that is not set to expire within six months. Additionally, most people need either a visa or, for citizens of countries participating in the visa-free travel agreement, an &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://esta.cbp.dhs.gov/&quot;&gt;Electronic System for Travel Authorization&lt;/a&gt;, known as an ESTA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;非美国公民想要进入美国，必须持有在未来六个月内不会过期的有效护照。此外，大多数人需要签证，或者对于参与免签旅行协议国家的公民来说，&lt;span&gt;需要申请&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://esta.cbp.dhs.gov/&quot;&gt;旅行授权电子系统&lt;/a&gt;（简称ESTA）。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;ESTAs are applied for online by submitting a photo (or computer scan) of a valid passport, as well as an email address, home address, phone number and emergency contact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;申请ESTA需要在线提交有效护照的照片（或电脑扫描件），以及一个电子邮件地址、家庭住址、电话号码和紧急联系人信息。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For citizens of countries that are not part of the visa-free program, most vetting for visas occurs at consulates in visitors’ home countries, said Jeff Joseph, an immigration lawyer in Denver. Consulate officials will look for signs that people plan to overstay their tourist visas, or intend to work, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;丹佛的移民律师杰夫·约瑟夫表示，对于不属于免签计划国家的公民，大多数签证审核在旅客本国的领事馆进行。领事馆官员会留意是否有逾期滞留的意图，或者是否有工作的打算等情况。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The visa — or the authorization — is just an entry document to get people to the airport or a land border, Mr. Joseph said. It does not guarantee entry to the United States. Once a traveler arrives, they have to prove that they intend to use the visa as directed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;约瑟夫说，签证或授权仅仅是让人们到达机场或陆路边境的入境文件，并不保证能够进入美国。旅客抵达后必须证明自己打算按照签证的规定来使用签证。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immigration officials will ask &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://govassist.com/blog/customs-and-immigration-how-to-answer-questions-at-the-airport-when-you-arrive-in-the-us#:~:text=Common%20Questions%20Asked%20by%20CBP,your%20business%20in%20the%20US.&quot;&gt;routine questions&lt;/a&gt;, usually regarding the purpose of the visit, the duration of the stay, where travelers plan to stay, and what they plan to do. Visitors can be taken for a second round of questioning, which is longer and more detailed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;移民官员会询问一些&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://govassist.com/blog/customs-and-immigration-how-to-answer-questions-at-the-airport-when-you-arrive-in-the-us#:~:text=Common%20Questions%20Asked%20by%20CBP,your%20business%20in%20the%20US.&quot;&gt;常规问题&lt;/a&gt;，通常涉及访问目的、停留时长、旅客计划的住宿地点以及他们打算做什么。旅客可能&lt;/span&gt;需要接受第二轮询问，询问的时间更长、更详细。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Most common visas for visitors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;游客最常见的签证类型&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visitor.html/visa#:~:text=Visitor%20visas%20are%20nonimmigrant%20visas,%2FB%2D2%20visa).&quot;&gt;three categories of visas for nonimmigrant visitors&lt;/a&gt;: a visitor visa for those who want to enter temporarily for business purposes, known as a B-1; a tourism visa, known as a B-2; and then a combination visa for both purposes — a B-1/B-2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;美国为非移民游客提供&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visitor.html/visa#:~:text=Visitor%20visas%20are%20nonimmigrant%20visas,%2FB%2D2%20visa).&quot;&gt;三类签证&lt;/a&gt;：一种是供那些因商务目的临时&lt;/span&gt;需要入境的人使用的访问签证，称为B-1签证；一种是旅游签证，称为B-2签证；还有一种是兼具两种目的的组合签证——B-1/B-2签证。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the visas themselves are &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.rochester.edu/iso/visas/b-1-b-2/#:~:text=While%20B%2D1%20or%20B,for%20the%20Visa%20Waiver%20Program.&quot;&gt;valid for up to a decade&lt;/a&gt;, visitors are only allowed to stay in the country for six months at most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;虽然这些签证本身的&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.rochester.edu/iso/visas/b-1-b-2/#:~:text=While%20B%2D1%20or%20B,for%20the%20Visa%20Waiver%20Program.&quot;&gt;有效期最长可达十年&lt;/a&gt;，但游客最多只能在美国停留六个月。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Travelers with these tourist visas are not allowed to study, work a permanent job, do any paid performances, arrive as a member of a crew on an aircraft or ship, work in foreign press or take up permanent residence, according to the State Department.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;据美国国务院规定，持有这些旅游签证的旅客不允许学习、从事长期工作、进行任何有偿演出、以飞机或船舶乘组人员身份入境、在外国媒体工作或取得永久居留权。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To obtain these visas, prospective visitors must complete an online application, provide required documents such as a passport and photo, and schedule a visa interview. The interviews cost $185.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;为了获得这些签证，有意入境的人员必须完成在线申请，提供所需文件，如护照和照片，并预约签证面试。面试费用为185美元。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visitor.html/visa#:~:text=Visitor%20visas%20are%20nonimmigrant%20visas,%2FB%2D2%20visa).&quot; title=&quot;Link: https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visitor.html/visa#:~:text=Visitor%20visas%20are%20nonimmigrant%20visas,%2FB%2D2%20visa).&quot;&gt;According to the State Department&lt;/a&gt;, the Department of Homeland Security and U.S. Customs and Border Protection, officials “have authority to permit or deny admission to the United States.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;美国&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visitor.html/visa#:~:text=Visitor%20visas%20are%20nonimmigrant%20visas,%2FB%2D2%20visa).&quot;&gt;国务院&lt;/a&gt;、国土安全部和美国海关与边境保护局规定，官员“有权允许或拒绝（旅客）进入美国”。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Countries with visa-waiver programs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;实行免签计划的国家&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20travel-visa-border2-ljqf/20travel-visa-border2-ljqf-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;当国际旅客抵达边境口岸时，移民官员会询问一些常规问题，通常涉及访问目的、停留时长、旅客计划的住宿地点以及他们打算做什么。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20travel-visa-border2-ljqf/20travel-visa-border2-ljqf-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;当国际旅客抵达边境口岸时，移民官员会询问一些常规问题，通常涉及访问目的、停留时长、旅客计划的住宿地点以及他们打算做什么。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Mike Blake/Reuters&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visa-waiver-program.html&quot;&gt;visa-waiver program&lt;/a&gt;, which allows most citizens to travel to the United States for business or tourism purposes for up to 90 days, applies to 43 countries. In return, U.S. citizens can travel to those countries for a similar length of time without a visa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/tourism-visit/visa-waiver-program.html&quot;&gt;免签计划&lt;/a&gt;允许大多数公民以商务或旅游目的前往美国旅行，最长可达90天，该计划适用于43个国家。作为回报，美国公民也可以在类似时长内免签前往这些国家旅行。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The program began in 1986 and is seen as a “&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dhs.gov/visa-waiver-program#:~:text=In%20return%2C%20those%20countries%20must,many%20of%20America&#39;s%20closest%20allies.&quot;&gt;security partnership&lt;/a&gt;” with U.S. allies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;该计划始于1986年，被视为美国与其盟友之间的一种“&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dhs.gov/visa-waiver-program#:~:text=In%20return%2C%20those%20countries%20must,many%20of%20America&#39;s%20closest%20allies.&quot;&gt;安全伙伴关系&lt;/a&gt;”。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Travelers still need a valid ESTA in order to enter the country. The applications cost $21 and the authorizations are active for two years. The ESTA must be obtained at least 72 hours before boarding a flight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;旅客仍然需要有效的ESTA才能进入美国。申请费用为21美元，授权有效期为两年。必须在登机前至少72小时获得ESTA。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is fine print — for example, you cannot obtain an ESTA if you visited certain countries after certain times, such as Cuba on or after Jan. 12, 2021. If you are not eligible for the ESTA, you must obtain a tourist visa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;其中有一些细则——例如，如果你在特定时间之后访问过某些国家，就无法获得ESTA，比如在2021年1月12日及之后访问过古巴。如果你没有资格获得ESTA，就必须申请旅游签证。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those entering the United States with an ESTA are not allowed to study or work a permanent job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;凭借ESTA进入美国的人不允许学习或从事长期工作。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this process, visitors “waive” a lot of rights, Mr. Joseph said, including waiving the right to contest deportation. Because of that, people using this program can be subject to mandatory detention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;约瑟夫说，在这个过程中，旅行者“放弃”了很多权利，包括放弃对被遣返提出异议的权利。正因为如此，使用该计划的人可能遭到强制拘留。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What rights do visitors have?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;游客有哪些权利？&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. federal law gives government agents the right to search people’s property, including their phones and laptops, at border entry points. They do not need to be suspected of wrongdoing in order to be searched, according to the American Civil Liberties Union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;美国联邦法律赋予政府特工在边境入境点搜查他人财产的权利，包括他们的手机和笔记本电脑。根据美国公民自由联盟的说法，这样的搜查不需要首先存在不当行为的怀疑。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All visitors have the right to remain silent. But the burden of proof rests with visa holders. For example, if an officer asks if someone plans to work on their tourist visa, and that person remains silent, the officer is likely to deny them entry, Mr. Joseph said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;所有游客都有权保持沉默。但签证持有者负有举证责任。例如，约瑟夫说，如果一名官员询问某人是否打算持旅游签证工作，而那个人保持沉默，官员很可能会拒绝其入境。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a person is found inadmissible during questioning, they can withdraw their intent to enter the country and may then be allowed to travel back to their home country. Their visa is canceled and they often get the next flight home. But an officer can deny the withdrawal, at which point the visitor is detained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;如果一个人在接受询问时被认定为不可入境，他们可以撤回入境意图，然后可能被允许返回自己的国家。他们的签证将被取消，通常会搭乘下一班航班回国。但官员可以拒绝他们的撤回，在这种情况下，游客就会被拘留。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because these confrontations occur technically outside the country, the rights outlined in the U.S. Constitution do not apply, Mr. Joseph said, and detainees are not necessarily entitled to a lawyer. The government has about 90 days to deport people. That period can be extended if detainees don’t cooperate by providing the correct travel documents, at which point they can be subject to criminal proceedings. Following an order of removal, people are barred from entering the U.S. for five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;约瑟夫说，因为这些状况严格来说发生在美国境外，美国宪法中规定的权利并不适用，被拘留者不一定有权请律师。政府有90天左右的时间来遣返这些人。如果被拘留者不配合提供正确的旅行文件，这一期限可以延长，届时他们可能会面临刑事诉讼。接到驱逐令的人未来五年不得进入美国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Claire Fahy为《纽约时报》报道纽约市及其周边地区。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/claire-fahy&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：经雷&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/travel/us-border-crossing-international-visa.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250324/us-border-crossing-international-visa/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250324/us-border-crossing-international-visa/dual</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 18:59:33 GMT</pubDate><author>CLAIRE FAHY</author></item><item><title>「中英」中国经济再遇大麻烦：政府税收下降</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-01-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-01-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;位于中国滨州的一家铝基材料厂。北京没有那么多钱来帮助面临关税的中国出口商，或帮助消费者抵御经济放缓和房地产市场崩溃。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;位于中国滨州的一家铝基材料厂。北京没有那么多钱来帮助面临关税的中国出口商，或帮助消费者抵御经济放缓和房地产市场崩溃。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buried in China’s latest government budget were some numbers that add up to an alarming trend. Tax revenue is dropping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在中国最新的政府预算中，隐藏着一些数字，综合起来显示出一种惊人的趋势。税收收入正在下降。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decline means that China’s national government has less money to address the country’s serious economic challenges, including a housing market crash and the near bankruptcy of hundreds of local governments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;下降意味着中国国家政府用于应对国家严重经济挑战的资金减少，这些挑战包括房地产市场崩溃和数百个地方政府濒临破产。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weak tax revenue also puts China’s leaders in a box as they square off with President Trump, who has imposed 20 percent tariffs on goods from China and threatened more to come. Beijing has less spare cash to help the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/14/business/economy/china-exports-trump-tariffs.html&quot;&gt;export industries&lt;/a&gt; that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/business/china-mexico-tariffs-trump.html&quot;&gt;driving economic growth&lt;/a&gt; but could be hurt by tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;税收收入疲软也让中国领导人在与特朗普总统对峙时处于不利地位。特朗普已对来自中国的商品征收了20%的关税，并威胁要征收更多关税。中国政府手上用于帮助&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250214/china-exports-trump-tariffs/&quot;&gt;出口行业&lt;/a&gt;的备用资金减少了，该行业有助于&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250317/china-mexico-tariffs-trump/&quot;&gt;推动经济增长&lt;/a&gt;，但可能受到关税的冲击。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drop in tax collections leaves China’s leaders in an unfamiliar position. Until the last several years, China enjoyed robust revenue, which it used to invest in infrastructure, a rapid military buildup and extensive industrial subsidies. Even as economic growth has slowed gradually over the past 12 years, taking a dent out of consumer spending, tax revenue held fairly steady until recently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;税收的减少使中国领导人处于一个陌生的境地。直到最近几年，中国还享有丰厚的收入，用于投资基础设施、快速军事建设和广泛的工业补贴。尽管在过去的12年里，经济增长逐渐放缓，消费者支出受到影响，但税收收入一直相当稳定，直到前不久。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax revenue fell further last year than ever before. And the only two previous declines in recent decades were under special circumstances: In 2020, China imposed an essentially nationwide pandemic lockdown for a couple of months, and in 2022, Shanghai endured a two-month lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;去年，税收收入降幅比以往任何时候都要大。近几十年来，仅有的两次下降都是在特殊情况下发生的：2020年，中国在全国范围内实施了几个月的疫情封锁，2022年，上海经历了两个月的封锁。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s declining tax revenue now has several causes. A big one is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/10/business/china-central-bank-bonds.html&quot;&gt;deflation&lt;/a&gt; — a broad decline in prices. Companies and now the Chinese government find themselves with less money to make monthly payments on their debts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;目前，中国税收收入下降有几个原因。一个大问题是&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250113/china-central-bank-bonds/&quot;&gt;通货紧缩&lt;/a&gt;——物价普遍下跌。企业和中国政府现在发现，他们每月用来偿还债务的钱越来越少了。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-02-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-02-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;在多年为基础设施建设、军事发展和工业补贴提供资金后，税收收入的下降使中国领导人处于一个不同寻常的境地。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-02-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-02-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;在多年为基础设施建设、军事发展和工业补贴提供资金后，税收收入的下降使中国领导人处于一个不同寻常的境地。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Kevin Frayer/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since September, Chinese officials have promised several times that they were on the cusp of doing what practically every foreign and Chinese economist recommends: spending more money to help the country’s beleaguered consumers with such measures as higher pensions, better medical benefits, more unemployment insurance or restaurant vouchers. But again and again, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/16/business/china-consumption.html&quot;&gt;including on Sunday&lt;/a&gt;, they have laid out ambitious programs without providing more than a smidgen of extra spending.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;自去年9月以来，中国官员多次承诺，他们即将采取几乎所有中外经济学家都建议的措施：花更多的钱来帮助陷入困境的中国消费者，比如提高养老金、改善医疗福利、增加失业保险或提供餐饮代金券。但一次又一次，包括&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250317/china-consumption/&quot;&gt;周日&lt;/a&gt;这一次在内，他们制定了雄心勃勃的计划，却没有提供一点点额外支出。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The usual explanation for the frugality lies in longstanding opposition from Xi Jinping, China’s top leader, who warned in a speech in 2021 that China “must not aim too high or go overboard with social security, and steer clear of the idleness-breeding trap of welfarism.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;对于这种节制，通常的解释是中国最高领导人习近平长期以来反对支出，他在2021年的一次讲话中警告说，中国在社会保障方面“不能提过高的目标，搞过头的保障，坚决防止落入‘福利主义’养懒汉的陷阱”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But China’s 2025 budget, which the Ministry of Finance released on March 5, suggests a different explanation: The national government may not have the money. Despite record borrowing, it would be hard-pressed to find the money needed to stimulate consumption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但中国财政部3月5日公布的2025年预算给出了另一种解释：中央政府可能没有钱。尽管借贷达到了创纪录的水平，但要找到刺激消费所需的资金将非常困难。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall tax revenue fell 3.4 percent last year. That might not look like a lot. But it is a sizable divergence from the overall economy, which according to official statistics &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/16/business/china-economy-2024-gdp.html&quot;&gt;grew 5 percent&lt;/a&gt; before being adjusted for deflation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;去年，税收总额下降了3.4%。这看起来可能不是很多。但这与整体经济存在很大差异，根据官方统计，在扣除通缩因素之前，中国经济&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250117/china-economy-2024-gdp/&quot;&gt;增长了5%&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Falling tax revenue means that China’s budget deficits are widening not because of extra government spending to help the economy, but because there is less money coming into the till. The problem has been worsening for years at local governments, which have plummeting revenues from selling state land, and has spread to the national government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;税收收入的下降意味着中国的预算赤字正在扩大，这并不是因为政府为帮助经济而增加了开支，而是因为进入金库的钱减少了。地方政府出售国有土地的收入急剧下降，导致这一问题几年来日益严重，并已蔓延至国家政府。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-03-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-03-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;企业、家庭和中国政府现在都在努力偿还债务。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-03-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-03-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;企业、家庭和中国政府现在都在努力偿还债务。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Vincent Thian/Associated Press&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fitch Ratings calculates that overall revenue for the national and local governments — including taxes and land sales — totaled 29 percent of the economy’s output as recently as 2018. But this year’s budget indicates that overall revenue will be just 21.1 percent of the economy in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;据惠誉评级计算，截至2018年，国家和地方政府的总收入（包括税收和土地销售）总计占经济产出的29%。但今年的预算显示，到2025年，总收入将仅占经济总量的21.1%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roughly half of the decline comes from plummeting revenue from land sales, a well-documented problem related to the housing-market crash, but the rest comes from weakness in tax revenue, a new problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;大约一半的下降来自土地销售收入的急剧下降，这个已有详尽报道的问题与房地产市场崩溃有关。但其余的下降来自税收收入的疲软，这是一个新问题。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;That adds up to a huge sum of money. If overall revenue had kept up with the economy over the past seven years, the Chinese government would have another $1.5 trillion to spend in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这些问题加起来意味着失去一大笔钱。如果过去七年的整体收入与经济增长保持同步，那么到2025年，中国政府的可支配资金应该比现在多出1.5万亿美元。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China announced this month that it would allow its official target for the budget deficit to increase to 4 percent this year, after trying to keep it near 3 percent ever since the global financial crisis in 2009. But analysts say the true deficit is already much larger, because China is quietly counting a lot of long-term borrowing as though it were tax revenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国本月宣布，今年将允许其官方预算赤字目标增加到4%，自2009年全球金融危机以来，中国一直试图将其保持在接近3%的水平。但分析人士说，真正的赤字已经大得多了，因为中国正在悄悄地把大量长期借款当作税收收入来计算。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comparing spending only with actual revenue, without the borrowing, the Finance Ministry’s budget shows a deficit equal to almost 9 percent of the economy. In 2018, it was only 3.2 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;仅将支出与实际收入（不包括借款）相比较，财政部的预算赤字几乎相当于经济总量的9%。2018年，这一比例仅为3.2%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Deficits are quite high and debt is rising quite quickly, so they are fiscally challenged,” said Jeremy Zook, a director of Asia and Pacific sovereign ratings at Fitch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“赤字相当高，债务增长相当快，因此他们面临财政挑战，”惠誉亚太主权评级主管杰里米·祖克表示。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest taxes in China are value-added taxes, a kind of sales tax that the government collects on practically every transaction, from rent to refrigerators. Last year, revenue from value-added taxes fell short of expectations by 7.9 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国最大的税种是增值税，这是一种销售税，政府对从租金到冰箱的几乎每一笔交易都征收。去年，增值税收入比预期低7.9%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The word “deflation” is prohibited in official Chinese documents, so the ministry came up with a euphemistic explanation: “This decrease was mainly due to the fact that the producer prices were lower than expected.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“通货紧缩”一词在中国官方文件中是禁止使用的，因此，财政部给出了一个委婉的解释：这一下降的原因“主要是工业生产者出厂价格低于预期”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-04-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-04-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;自2020年以来，公寓销售暴跌，许多房地产开发商破产。
&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-04-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-04-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;自2020年以来，公寓销售暴跌，许多房地产开发商破产。 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Hector Retamal/Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Producer prices, essentially wholesale prices calculated as goods leave factories and farms, fell 2.3 percent in China last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;生产者价格即商品离开工厂和农场时计算的批发价格，去年，中国的生产者价格下降了2.3%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Revenue from value-added taxes began weakening in 2018. That was when the government cut these taxes sharply for exporters to help them offset the impact of tariffs imposed by President Trump in his first term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018年，增值税收入开始减少。当时，政府大幅削减了出口商的这部分税收，以帮助他们抵消特朗普总统在第一个任期内征收关税的影响。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cost of that tax break has soared since then as China’s exports have surged, producing a trade surplus of almost &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/14/business/china-trade-surplus-trump.html&quot;&gt;$1 trillion&lt;/a&gt; last year even as the rest of the economy stagnated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;从那以后，随着中国出口激增，这一减税的代价急剧增加，去年中国的贸易顺差达到了&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250115/china-trade-surplus-trump/&quot;&gt;近7万亿元&lt;/a&gt;，而其他经济领域却停滞不前。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another problem lies in falling salaries and rising layoffs, especially during the second half of last year. Income taxes collected from individuals were 7.5 percent below expectations last year, the Finance Ministry said in its budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;另一个问题是工资下降和裁员增加，特别是在去年下半年。财政部在预算中表示，去年征收的个人所得税比预期低7.5%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s own steep tariffs on imports are another large source of revenue. But having lost much of their savings in the housing market crash, China’s consumers have cut back on purchases of imports like handbags and perfume, while prices have fallen for many imported goods. So revenue from customs duties was 9.2 percent below forecasts last year, the Finance Ministry said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国对进口商品征收的高额关税是另一大收入来源。但由于在房地产市场崩盘中损失了大部分积蓄，中国消费者减少了购买手袋和香水等进口商品，而许多进口商品的价格也有所下降。因此，财政部表示，去年的关税收入比预期低9.2%。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year’s financial picture could be even worse than the budget anticipates. The Finance Ministry’s budget repeated many of the same optimistic assumptions about tax revenue and overall economic performance that it made last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;今年的财政状况可能比预算预期的还要糟糕。财政部的预算重复了去年对税收收入和整体经济表现做出的许多乐观假设。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Governments in the West derive considerable revenue from taxes on investment gains, inheritances and real estate. But China has no taxes on investment gains or inheritances and almost none on real estate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;西方国家政府从对投资收益、遗产和房地产征税中获得可观的收入。但中国对投资收益或遗产不征税，对房地产也几乎不征税。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-05-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-05-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;浙江省的一条电动汽车生产线。为帮助中国出口商而进行的税收减免付出了巨大代价。
&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/Biz-China-Econ-05-pltf/Biz-China-Econ-05-pltf-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;浙江省的一条电动汽车生产线。为帮助中国出口商而进行的税收减免付出了巨大代价。 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Florence Lo/Reuters&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The general lack of real estate taxes lies at the root of a separate problem: China’s local governments are also running out of money. Until recently, they derived up to 80 percent of their revenues from selling land to property developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;房地产税的普遍缺失是另一个问题的根源：中国的地方政府也面临缺钱的困境。直到前不久，它们高达80%的收入来自向房地产开发商出售土地。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But those sales have plummeted since the housing crash began in 2021, which has gutted demand for new apartments and bankrupted many developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但自2021年房地产市场开始崩盘以来，这些销售大幅下降，导致对新公寓的需求锐减，许多开发商破产。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Local governments are responsible for most pensions, medical benefits and other social spending in China. The national government has been selling extra bonds to raise money for bailing out the weakest local governments, many of which are behind on their debts. The national government has called for local governments to step up social spending but, short on cash itself, has offered scant new financial assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在中国，地方政府承担了大部分养老金、医疗福利和其他社会支出。中央政府一直在出售额外债券，筹集资金救助最弱的地方政府，其中许多地方政府拖欠债务。中央政府呼吁地方政府加大社会支出，但由于自身资金短缺，提供的新财政援助很少。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And new taxes are not likely forthcoming, according to Jia Kang, a retired research director at the Finance Ministry and still one of China’s most influential voices on tax policy. He said in an interview that public opposition to inheritance taxes is strong, while taxes on investment gains or real estate would hurt stocks or the housing market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;据财政部退休研究主任、中国在税收政策方面最有影响力的人士之一贾康称，新税不太可能出台。他在接受采访时表示，公众强烈反对遗产税，而对投资收益或房地产征税会损害股市或房地产市场。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;One factor not causing China’s tax challenges is fraud or tax evasion, Mr. Jia said. The procedures for checking on payments have become very detailed, he said. “It is difficult to cheat in this system.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;贾康说，欺诈或逃税并非造成中国税收挑战的因素。他说，检查付款的程序已经变得非常详细。“在这个系统里很难作弊。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;css-53u6y8&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Siyi Zhao对本文有研究贡献。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keith Bradsher是《纽约时报》北京分社社长，此前曾任上海分社社长、香港分社社长、底特律分社社长，以及华盛顿记者。他在新冠疫情期间常驻中国进行报道。 &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/keith-bradsher&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/21/business/china-taxes-trump-tariffs.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250321/china-taxes-trump-tariffs/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250321/china-taxes-trump-tariffs/dual</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 04:43:09 GMT</pubDate><author>KEITH BRADSHER</author></item><item><title>「中英」从国会到法院，特朗普如何全方位巩固权力</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/dc-trump-power-zgtk/dc-trump-power-zgtk-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;特朗普总统在司法部走廊停下脚步，看挂在那里的他的官方肖像，摄于上周五。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;特朗普总统在司法部走廊停下脚步，看挂在那里的他的官方肖像，摄于上周五。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Eric Lee/The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Trump called for one federal judge seeking basic information about his deportation efforts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/us/politics/trump-venezuela-deportations-doj-court-order.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;to be impeached&lt;/a&gt; amid mounting concern about a constitutional showdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普总统&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/us/politics/trump-venezuela-deportations-doj-court-order.html&quot;&gt;要求弹劾&lt;/a&gt;一名正在寻求获取关于他驱逐移民行动的基本信息的联邦法官，让一场宪法层面摊牌的担忧日益增加。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another judge found that Mr. Trump’s efforts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/us/politics/elon-musk-usaid-doge-unconstitutional.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shut down a federal agency&lt;/a&gt; probably violated the Constitution and stripped Congress of its authority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;另一名法官认为特朗普&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/us/politics/elon-musk-usaid-doge-unconstitutional.html&quot;&gt;关闭一个联邦机构&lt;/a&gt;的做法可能违反了宪法，而且剥夺了国会的权力。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The president was accused of overstepping his executive authority yet again in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/technology/trump-ftc-fires-democrats.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;firing two Democratic commissioners&lt;/a&gt; from an independent trade commission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;总统解除了一个独立贸易委员会两名民主党委员的职务，该做法导致了对他再次超越行政权力的指控。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that was just Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这些还只是发生在周二的事情。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nearly two months into his second term, Mr. Trump is trying to consolidate control over the courts, Congress and even, in some ways, American society and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普再次担任总统已将近两个月，他正在试图巩固对法院和国会的控制权，甚至在某些方面试图巩固对美国社会和文化的控制权。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;His expansive interpretation of presidential power has become the defining characteristic of his second term, an aggressive effort across multiple fronts to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/05/us/trump-federal-law-power.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;assert executive authority&lt;/a&gt; to reshape the government, drive policy in new directions and root out what he and his supporters see as a deeply embedded liberal bias.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;他对总统权力的宽泛解读已成为第二个任期的决定性特征，他在各个方面行使行政权力，以重塑政府、推动政策转入新方向，并根除他和他的支持者眼中根深蒂固的自由主义偏见。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’ve never seen a president so comprehensively attempt to arrogate and consolidate so much of the other branches’ power, let alone to do so in the first two months of his presidency,” said Stephen Vladeck, a professor at Georgetown University Law Center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我们从来没有看到过一名总统如此全面地试图从这么多其他政府分支机构那里僭取并巩固权力，更不用说在担任总统头两个月的时间里这样做了，”乔治城大学法学院教授斯蒂芬·弗拉德克说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congress, which is controlled by Republicans, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/us/politics/trump-republicans-congress-power.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has ceded some of its&lt;/a&gt; core duties to Mr. Trump, handing off elements of the legislative branch’s spending authority to the White House and standing aside as congressionally chartered agencies are shuttered. The president has threatened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114141533823019998&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“lead the charge”&lt;/a&gt; against the re-election of the rare Republican who dares challenge his agenda, and the party has bent to his will at every turn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;由共和党控制的国会已将一些核心职责&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/us/politics/trump-republicans-congress-power.html&quot;&gt;交给了&lt;/a&gt;特朗普，把立法部门控制支出的部分财权交给了白宫，在国会授权成立的机构被关闭时袖手旁观。特朗普已威胁要“&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/114141533823019998&quot;&gt;带头反对&lt;/a&gt;”敢于挑战其议程的少数共和党人竞选连任，该党每次都屈从于他的意愿。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/18/us/trump-executive-order-sec-ftc-fcc.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dismantled independent measures&lt;/a&gt; of checks and balances, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/24/us/politics/trump-fires-inspectors-general.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fired inspectors general&lt;/a&gt; and installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/17/us/politics/bongino-patel-fbi-trump.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;loyalists&lt;/a&gt; at the Justice Department willing to carry out his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/03/07/us/politics/trump-2024-president.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;campaign of retribution&lt;/a&gt;. He has targeted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/podcasts/the-daily/trump-big-law-firms-perkins-coie.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;private law firms&lt;/a&gt; with connections to those he views as political enemies and cowed previously skeptical or hostile business leaders into pledging public support, even as he has imprinted his “MAGA” stamp on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/23/business/trump-dei-corporate-reaction.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;private sector by trying to dictate hiring practices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普已&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/18/us/trump-executive-order-sec-ftc-fcc.html&quot; title=&quot;Link: https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/18/us/trump-executive-order-sec-ftc-fcc.html&quot;&gt;废除了&lt;/a&gt;独立的制衡措施，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/24/us/politics/trump-fires-inspectors-general.html&quot;&gt;解雇了总监察长&lt;/a&gt;，在司法部安插了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/17/us/politics/bongino-patel-fbi-trump.html&quot;&gt;忠诚分子&lt;/a&gt;，他们愿意为特朗普的报复行动效力。他已把目标对准与他视为政治敌人的人有联系的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/podcasts/the-daily/trump-big-law-firms-perkins-coie.html&quot;&gt;私人律师事务所&lt;/a&gt;，迫使以前对他持怀疑或敌对态度的商界领袖公开承诺支持他，为了把他的“让美国恢复伟大荣光”理念在私营部门留下烙印，他甚至试图&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/23/business/trump-dei-corporate-reaction.html&quot;&gt;对私营企业的招聘做法发号施令&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;His efforts to reshape institutions in his image have not been limited to the government and policy. Mr. Trump has tried to spread his influence through the arts, as well, by making himself &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/arts/music/trump-kennedy-center.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;chairman of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in Washington&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;他按照自己的方式重塑机构的努力不限于政府和政策。特朗普还试图把自己的影响力扩大到艺术领域，任命自己为&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/arts/music/trump-kennedy-center.html&quot;&gt;华盛顿约翰·肯尼迪表演艺术中心的主席&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Mr. Trump’s latest target — the judiciary — has been described by constitutional scholars and historians as perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/us/politics/trump-deportations-constitutional-crisis-impeachment.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the most alarming power play to date&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但特朗普的最新打击目标——司法部门——已被宪法学者和历史学家们形容为可能是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/us/politics/trump-deportations-constitutional-crisis-impeachment.html&quot;&gt;到目前为止最令人担忧的弄权之举&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration brushed off an order by James E. Boasberg of the Federal District Court in Washington, who sought to pause the deportation of a group of migrants, many of whom received little to no due process. Administration officials said that most of the migrants were from Venezuela and that all of them were affiliated with gangs. But officials &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/us/trump-deportations-venezuela-gang.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;did not release the migrants’ names or evidence&lt;/a&gt; of their alleged crimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普政府对华盛顿联邦地区法院詹姆斯·博斯伯格法官的命令置之不理，这名法官曾试图叫停对一批移民的驱逐行动，因为其中许多人几乎或者完全没有经过正当程序。政府官员说，这些移民中的大多数来自委内瑞拉，都与帮派有关。但官员并&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/us/trump-deportations-venezuela-gang.html&quot;&gt;没有公布这些移民的姓名或他们涉嫌犯罪的证据&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump has called for Judge Boasberg to be impeached, arguing on social media that “if a President doesn’t have the right to throw murderers, and other criminals, out of our Country because a Radical Left Lunatic Judge wants to assume the role of President, then our Country is in very big trouble, and destined to fail!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普已要求弹劾博斯伯格，并在社交媒体上辩称，“如果一名总统无权将杀人犯和其他罪犯驱逐出我们的国家，只是因为一个激进左翼疯子法官想取代总统的职责，那么我们的国家已陷入了非常大的麻烦，而且注定要失败！”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The White House did not respond late Wednesday to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;白宫在周三晚些时候没有回复记者的置评请求。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump has never been consistent in his attacks on the judicial system generally and on judges in particular. Last week during a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/us/politics/trump-speech-justice-department.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;speech at the Department of Justice&lt;/a&gt;, he suggested that criticism of Judge Aileen M. Cannon, the Florida jurist who dismissed the classified documents case against him last summer, may not be legal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普在笼统地攻击司法系统和具体地攻击法官时，从来都没有一致性。他上周在&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/us/politics/trump-speech-justice-department.html&quot;&gt;司法部发表讲话&lt;/a&gt;时曾暗示，对佛罗里达州的联邦法官艾琳·坎农的批评可能不合法，坎农去年夏天决定对涉及特朗普的机密文件案不予考虑。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But he has applied the same logic of fairness to court cases that he has to presidential elections: They’re fair if he wins but not if he loses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但他判断法庭案件是否公平的逻辑与他判断总统选举是否公平的逻辑一样：他赢了的时候公平，他输了的时候不公平。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In one way or another, Mr. Trump has been a party to lawsuits going back to the 1970s, as a private developer and later as a candidate and president. When he has lost cases, he has tended to attack the judges in question as partisan activists or worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;自20世纪70年代以来，特朗普一直是各种各样的诉讼案的一方，他那时是一名私人开发商，后来成了候选人和总统。当他输掉官司时，他常常会攻击涉案法官是带有党派偏见的激进分子，甚至说更难听的话。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;When he wins, he praises the judge in question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;当他赢了官司时，他会赞扬涉案法官。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump’s allies say he is using his power to enact an agenda that he promised during the campaign, and that he is executing Article II of the Constitution, which sets out the powers of the president.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普的盟友们说，他正在运用自己的权力来推行他在竞选期间承诺的议程，他是在执行宪法第二条赋予总统的权力。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“President Trump’s doing the unthinkable in Washington — he’s doing what he told Americans he was going to do, and he’s doing it fast,” said Mike Davis, founder of the Article III Project, a conservative advocacy group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“特朗普总统正在做华盛顿难以想象的事情——他正在做他告诉美国人他要做的事情，而且做得很快，”保守派倡导组织Article III Project的创始人迈克·戴维斯说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-trump-power-qpwj/20dc-trump-power-qpwj-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;保守派倡导组织Article III Project的创始人迈克·戴维斯是特朗普的盟友之一，他说，特朗普不过是在行使权力，实施选民在他获胜后要求他实施的议程。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-trump-power-qpwj/20dc-trump-power-qpwj-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;保守派倡导组织Article III Project的创始人迈克·戴维斯是特朗普的盟友之一，他说，特朗普不过是在行使权力，实施选民在他获胜后要求他实施的议程。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Eric Lee/The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, a few traditionally right-leaning voices have expressed concern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;尽管如此，一些传统上偏右的声音已表示了担忧。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal editorial page, for example, said Mr. Trump had campaigned on deporting gang members, “but it’s still troubling to see U.S. officials appear to disdain the law in the name of upholding it.” The New York Post ran a headline on its opinion page that said: “Trump, don’t heed the dangerous urge to attack the rule of law.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;例如，《华尔街日报》社论版称，特朗普在竞选期间表示要把帮派成员驱逐出境，“但看到美国官员们好像是在维护法律的名义下蔑视法律，仍令人不安。”《纽约邮报》在其观点版发表的一篇文章的标题是：“特朗普，不要听从攻击法治的危险冲动。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both papers are part of the media empire of Rupert Murdoch, Mr. Trump’s on-again, off-again ally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这两份报纸都是鲁珀特·默多克媒体帝国的一部分，默多克有时是特朗普的盟友，有时不是。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The judiciary, created to provide checks and balances to both the executive and legislative branches, has only rarely faced such open defiance, experts say. Some of Mr. Trump’s top lieutenants &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/cspan/status/1901723856152285503&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;have suggested he has a right to defy court orders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;美国司法部门的设立，是为了制衡行政部门和立法部门的权力，但司法部门以前几乎没有遇到过如此公开的蔑视。特朗普的一些高级副手们&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/cspan/status/1901723856152285503&quot;&gt;已暗示他有权违抗法院命令&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Judges aren’t allowed to control the executive’s legitimate power,” Vice President JD Vance declared last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;副总统万斯上个月宣称：“不允许法官控制行政部门的合法权力。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I don’t care what the judges think — I don’t care what the left thinks,” Mr. Trump’s border czar, Tom Homan, said this week during an appearance on “Fox &amp;amp; Friends.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我不在乎法官们怎么想——我不在乎左派们怎么想，”特朗普的边境事务主管汤姆·霍曼本周在《福克斯与朋友们》节目上说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/dc-trump-power3-mwhz/dc-trump-power3-mwhz-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/dc-trump-power3-mwhz/dc-trump-power3-mwhz-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Haiyun Jiang for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/dc-trump-power2-bjzk/dc-trump-power2-bjzk-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;副总统万斯和特朗普的边境事务主管汤姆·霍曼都已表示，特朗普有权无视法庭命令。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/dc-trump-power2-bjzk/dc-trump-power2-bjzk-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;副总统万斯和特朗普的边境事务主管汤姆·霍曼都已表示，特朗普有权无视法庭命令。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Kenny Holston/The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump’s allies often point out that he is doing what he said he would do during his campaign, when his policy platform, Agenda 47, laid out an agenda of maximalist presidential power. He and his advisers believe he was stymied in his first term through investigations and a resistant federal bureaucracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普的盟友们经常指出，他正在做他在竞选期间说要做的事情，他当时在自己的政策平台Agenda 47上给出了让总统权力最大化的议程。他和他的顾问们认为，他的第一个总统任期内曾受到各种各样的调查，以及抵制他的联邦官僚机构的阻碍。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of his closest allies, including Russell T. Vought, Mr. Trump’s current and former director of the Office of Management and Budget, spent years preparing for the possibility of a second Trump presidency, searching for pockets of independence in the executive branch that could be seized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普的一些最亲密的盟友，包括曾在他第一次当总统期间以及现在担任管理和预算办公室主任的拉塞尔·T·沃特，花了好几年时间为特朗普再次当总统的可能性做准备，在行政部门中寻找能夺取的独立空间。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Vought and other Trump allies have advocated a doctrine called the unitary executive, a legal theory that all power in the executive branch flows from the president.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;沃特和特朗普的其他盟友们一直提倡一个被称为“集权行政”的学说，这个法律理论认为，行政部门的所有权力来自总统。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The great challenge confronting a conservative president is the existential need for aggressive use of the vast powers of the executive branch to return power — including power currently held by the executive branch — to the American people,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_CHAPTER-02.pdf&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mr. Vought wrote&lt;/a&gt; in the conservative blueprint for a Republican presidential transition, Project 2025. He added that it would take “boldness to bend or break the bureaucracy to the presidential will.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“保守派总统面临的最大挑战是，积极使用行政部门的巨大权力，将权力（包括目前由行政部门掌握的权力）归还给美国人民，这是一种生存的需要，”沃特在为共和党总统接管权力制定的保守派蓝图《2025计划》中写道。他还说，这将需要在“让官僚机构屈服于总统的意志上采取大胆行动”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the dozens of executive orders that Mr. Trump signed since taking office, which called for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/ensuring-accountability-for-all-agencies/&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;taking over “independent regulatory agencies,”&lt;/a&gt; asserted similar goals. “For the federal government to be truly accountable to the American people, officials who wield vast executive power must be supervised and controlled by the people’s elected president,” the executive order states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;特朗普上任以来签署的数十项行政命令之一就是要求&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/ensuring-accountability-for-all-agencies/&quot;&gt;接管“独立的监管机构”&lt;/a&gt;，主张了与上述目标类似的东西。“为了让联邦政府真正对美国人民负责，拥有巨大行政权力的官员必须受到人民选举产生的总统的监督和控制，”该行政命令写道。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kenneth T. Cuccinelli II, a former acting deputy Homeland Security secretary in the first Trump administration and a contributor to Project 2025, said those who criticize Mr. Trump’s use of executive power “are doing so primarily to weaken the presidency and this president in particular under the guise of ‘conventional wisdom’ that has no constitutional foundation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;肯尼斯·库奇内利曾在特朗普的第一个任期担任国土安全部代理副部长，他也是《2025计划》的参与者。他说，那些批评特朗普行使行政权力的人“主要是为了削弱总统，尤其是这名总统的权力，他们打着没有宪法基础的‘传统智慧’幌子”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/trump-power6-jfzh/trump-power6-jfzh-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;被特朗普任命为管理和预算办公室主任的拉塞尔·沃特权力巨大，他是保守派文件《2025计划》的主要设计者，该文件已成为特朗普战略的蓝图。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/trump-power6-jfzh/trump-power6-jfzh-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;被特朗普任命为管理和预算办公室主任的拉塞尔·沃特权力巨大，他是保守派文件《2025计划》的主要设计者，该文件已成为特朗普战略的蓝图。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Haiyun Jiang for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Critics of how Mr. Trump is approaching his executive authority say the unitary executive theory does not mean that everything the executive branch does is legal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;批评特朗普如何行使行政权力的人说，集权行政理论并不意味着行政部门所做的一切都是合法的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruth Ben-Ghiat,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;a historian at New York University who studies fascism and authoritarianism, singled out what she said were some of Mr. Trump’s most troubling behaviors: the expansion of executive power, the politicization of the other branches of government, the dismantling of an oversight and accountability structure, and the targeting of those who seek to hold the president and his allies accountable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在纽约大学研究法西斯主义和威权主义的历史学家露丝·本-吉亚特指出了她认为特朗普最令人不安的一些做法：扩大行政权力、将其他政府部门政治化、瓦解监督和问责构架，以及把那些试图追究总统及其盟友责任的人作为打击目标。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The ultimate beneficiary of the acts that we’re seeing happen, whether it’s with the judiciary or other agencies, is Trump himself, because it’s an expansion of his personal power,” she said. “The scale and the speed of what’s going on is terrifying.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我们看到，无论是对司法部门还是其他机构采取的这些做法，其最终受益者都是特朗普本人，因为这是他个人权力的扩张，”她说。“这些行动的规模和速度使人恐惧。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erica L. Green是《纽约时报》白宫记者，报道特朗普总统及其政府。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/erica-l-green&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zolan Kanno-Youngs是《纽约时报》白宫记者，报道拜登总统及其政府新闻。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/zolan-kanno-youngs&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maggie Haberman是《纽约时报》白宫记者，报道特朗普第二任期。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/maggie-haberman&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：Cindy Hao&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div data-poster=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/us/politics/trump-power-courts-crisis.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250321/trump-power-courts-crisis/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250321/trump-power-courts-crisis/dual</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 01:51:25 GMT</pubDate><author>ERICA L. GREEN,ZOLAN KANNO-YOUNGS,MAGGIE HABERMAN</author></item><item><title>「中英」“谁还会来投资？”当局警告长江和记引发香港商界担忧</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-01-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-01-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;2018年，李嘉诚在香港。这位大亨建立了一个横跨地产、航运、电信等领域的帝国。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;2018年，李嘉诚在香港。这位大亨建立了一个横跨地产、航运、电信等领域的帝国。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Jerome Favre/EPA, via Shutterstock&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The deal had the imprint of a Hong Kong billionaire nicknamed “Superman” for his empire building. One of the tycoon’s companies, which for years has run two ports on the Panama Canal, had been thrust into a broader showdown between China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这笔交易带有一位香港亿万富翁的印记，他因建立了自己庞大的商业帝国而被称为“超人”。这位大亨的一家公司多年来一直经营着巴拿马运河上的两个港口，如今被卷入了中美之间更广泛的对决之中。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the billionaire, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/06/business/panama-canal-ck-hutchison.html?&quot;&gt;Li Ka-shing&lt;/a&gt;, got out of the firing line by notching a $19 billion deal to sell the business to a group of deep-pocketed American investors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;因此，这位亿万富翁&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/06/business/panama-canal-ck-hutchison.html?&quot;&gt;李嘉诚&lt;/a&gt;以190亿美元的价格将自己的业务出售给一群财力雄厚的美国投资者，从而远离了火线。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or so it seemed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;至少看起来是这样。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s leaders are now threatening to stop Mr. Li and the company he controls, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/business/hong-kong-panama-canal-ck-hutchison.html&quot;&gt;CK Hutchison&lt;/a&gt;, from seeing the deal through, accusing the conglomerate of betraying Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国领导人现在威胁要阻止李嘉诚和他控制的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/business/hong-kong-panama-canal-ck-hutchison.html&quot;&gt;长江和记&lt;/a&gt;实业有限公司完成这笔交易，指责这家企业集团背叛了北京。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The face-off tests how far Xi Jinping, China’s top leader, is willing to go to exercise his control over business in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这场对峙考验着中国最高领导人习近平在对香港商业领域行使管控权方面愿意走多远。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A former British colony, Hong Kong was returned to China in 1997 with Beijing’s promise it would mostly leave the city to govern itself, allowing it to remain a bridge to China but keep a system of freewheeling capitalism. Mr. Li, as a Chinese entrepreneur who tapped investors in the West to build an empire that included property, shipping and telecommunications, embodied that distinction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;香港曾是英国殖民地，于1997年回归中国，北京承诺让香港拥有相当程度的自治，使其得以继续作为通往中国的桥梁，但保留自由放任的资本主义制度。作为一名华人企业家，李嘉诚利用西方投资建立了一个包括房地产、航运和电信在内的帝国，正是这种独特模式的体现。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-02-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-02-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;巴拿马运河上的巴尔博亚港。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-02-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-02-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;巴拿马运河上的巴尔博亚港。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Enea Lebrun/Reuters&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beijing’s potential intervention in the port deal between CK Hutchison and a group led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/04/business/blackrock-panama-canal-ports-hutchison.html&quot;&gt;BlackRock&lt;/a&gt; now endangers the separation, prominent financiers and business leaders in Hong Kong said. It could also destroy Mr. Xi’s golden goose at a critical moment for China’s economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;香港知名金融家和商界领袖表示，北京对长江和记实业与&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/04/business/blackrock-panama-canal-ports-hutchison.html&quot;&gt;贝莱德&lt;/a&gt;牵头的集团之间港口交易的潜在干预如今危及到了这种区别。这还可能在中国经济的关键时刻毁掉习近平的摇钱树。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;After recording &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/29/business/hong-kong-stocks-hang-seng.html&quot;&gt;losses&lt;/a&gt; in four of the past five years, Hong Kong’s stock market is on fire — a sign of enthusiasm for China’s economy. Chinese companies are choosing Hong Kong over London or New York to list their shares. It offers Mr. Xi a bragging point: Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/16/business/trump-sp-500-stocks-europe-china.html&quot;&gt;President Trump’s inauguration&lt;/a&gt; on Jan. 20, the S&amp;amp;P 500 has fallen about 5 percent while Hong Kong’s stock market is up more than 20 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;香港股市在过去五年中有四年录得&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/29/business/hong-kong-stocks-hang-seng.html&quot;&gt;亏损&lt;/a&gt;，现在却火爆起来——这是投资者对中国经济热情高涨的迹象。中国公司纷纷选择在香港上市，而不是伦敦或纽约。这为习近平提供了炫耀的资本：自&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/16/business/trump-sp-500-stocks-europe-china.html&quot;&gt;特朗普总统1月20日就职&lt;/a&gt;以来，标准普尔500指数下跌了约5%，香港股市却上涨了20%以上。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lawyers and regulatory experts generally believe that the authorities in Hong Kong or Beijing will be reluctant to stop the deal — and it is not clear that there is much they can do. But the mere possibility has put Hong Kong on edge. Beijing and its proxies in the media have kept up a near-daily drumbeat of criticism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;律师和监管专家普遍认为，香港或北京相关当局在出手阻止这笔交易上有所顾虑，而且目前也不清楚它们能做些什么。但仅仅是阻止交易的可能性就已经让香港坐立不安。北京及其在媒体上的代理人几乎每天都在对这项交易大肆批评。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commentaries last week in Ta Kung Pao, a newspaper owned by the Chinese government, called the agreement between CK Hutchison and BlackRock “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/business/panama-canal-ck-hutchison-blackrock.html&quot;&gt;profit seeking and unrighteous&lt;/a&gt;” and a matter of “national security.” The Beijing government agency that overseas Hong Kong policy reposted the comments on its website. On Tuesday, Hong Kong’s top leader, John Lee, piled on to say the deal required “serious attention.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国官方报纸《大公报》上周发表评论称，长江和记实业与贝莱德之间的协议“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/14/business/panama-canal-ck-hutchison-blackrock.html&quot;&gt;唯利是图，见利忘义&lt;/a&gt;”，涉及“国家利益，民族大义”。负责香港政策的港澳办在官网上转发了这些评论。本周二，香港最高领导人李家超也发表评论，称该协议“值得重视”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hu Xijin, a former editor of the Communist Party tabloid Global Times, said CK Hutchison “first needs to be calm and coordinate with China’s national interests.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;《环球时报》的前主编胡锡进说，希望长江和记“既来之则安之……与强大祖国的利益协调一致”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any attempt by Hong Kong or Beijing to stop the deal would be extraordinary. Chinese companies must often seek permission from regulators to move their money out of mainland China. CK Hutchison operates ports worldwide, including in China, but none of the 43 ports that are part of the BlackRock deal are in China. CK Hutchison’s shares are not listed in mainland China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;香港或北京阻止这笔交易的任何尝试都将是非同寻常的。中国企业往往必须获得监管机构的许可，才能将资金转移出中国大陆。长江和记在世界各地运营港口，包括在中国，但贝莱德交易涉及的43个港口中，没有一个在中国。长江和记的股票并未在中国大陆上市。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CK Hutchison declined to comment. BlackRock did not respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;长江和记拒绝置评。贝莱德没有回应置评请求。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victor Li, the chairman of CK Hutchison (and son of Li Ka-shing), said on Thursday in a statement accompanying an earnings release that the environment for CK Hutchison’s businesses could be “both volatile and unpredictable” this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;李嘉诚之子、长江和记主席李泽钜周四在一份财报附带声明中表示，今年长江和记的业务环境可能“动荡而又不可预测”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scorn and warnings heaped on CK Hutchison are reminiscent of “Cultural Revolution-style criticism” that will scare off foreign investors, said Lew Mong-hung, a former Chinese political adviser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;前中国政治问题顾问刘梦熊表示，对长江和记的轻蔑和警告让人想起“文革式的批评”，会吓跑外国投资者。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-03-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-03-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;在中美就巴拿马运河港口问题对峙之际，李嘉诚完成了一项价值190亿美元的交易，将其业务出售给主要投资者。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-03-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-03-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;在中美就巴拿马运河港口问题对峙之际，李嘉诚完成了一项价值190亿美元的交易，将其业务出售给主要投资者。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Enea Lebrun/Reuters&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Who would dare to come to Hong Kong?” said Mr. Lew, a former finance professional. “If you don’t obey, don’t want to make a political sacrifice and don’t want to be a political tool, you will be criticized and persecuted. Who will come to invest?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“谁还敢来香港？”曾是金融专业人士的刘梦熊说。“如果不服从，不作牺牲品，不作政治工具，就要批斗你、整你。谁还会来投资呢？”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chan King Cheung, a professor of media ethics at Hong Kong Baptist University and a former chief editor of the Hong Kong Economic Journal, wrote in a Hong Kong newspaper this week that the increasing intervention by Beijing in the city’s business community — through comments and visits made by Chinese officials to pressure business leaders to be patriotic — was a sign that it was getting harder to detach Hong Kong companies from Chinese politics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;香港浸会大学媒体伦理教授、《信报财经新闻》前主编陈景祥本周在一份香港报纸上写道，北京方面对香港商界的干预越来越多——通过中国官员的言论和访问向商界领袖施压，要求他们爱国——这表明香港公司越来越难以同中国的政治分离。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The attention Beijing has put on the Panama Canal deal was just another example that “‘great’ entrepreneurs must be patriots,” Mr. Chan wrote. “It has been proven that the days when Hong Kong companies considered issues purely based on economic or commercial interests are over,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;陈景祥写道，北京对巴拿马运河交易的关注只是“‘伟大’的企业家必须是爱国者”的又一个例子。他还写道：“事实证明，香港公司纯从经济效益或商业角度考量问题的日子已经过去。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concern among business leaders cuts to the heart of the question facing Hong Kong: Are its companies free to make their own business decisions, or must they consider China’s broader national interests as do mainland Chinese firms?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;商界领袖的担忧直指香港面临的核心问题：香港公司是否可以自由做出自己的商业决策，还是必须像内地企业那样考虑中国更广泛的国家利益？&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many, the answer will determine whether Hong Kong can still operate separately from the rest of China. Hong Kong’s autonomy in free speech and civil society has already been eroded after the shutdown of local media outlets; the arrest of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/19/world/asia/jimmy-lai-hong-kong-trial.html&quot;&gt;Jimmy Lai&lt;/a&gt;, a Hong Kong newspaper publisher; and the arrests and trials of dozens of pro-democracy leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;对很多人来说，这个答案将决定香港是否仍能与中国其他地区分开运作。在香港本地媒体机构被关闭、报纸出版人&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/19/world/asia/jimmy-lai-hong-kong-trial.html&quot;&gt;黎智英&lt;/a&gt;遭逮捕，以及数十名民主运动领袖遭到逮捕和审判之后，香港在言论自由和公民社会方面的自主权已经受到侵蚀。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s one thing to go after Jimmy Lai and Apple Daily, but quite another to go after ‘Superman’ KS Li and his companies, the most successful international business H.K. has ever produced,” said Mark L. Clifford, a former board member at Mr. Lai’s Next Digital and president of the Committee for Freedom in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“打击黎智英和《苹果日报》是一回事，但打击‘超人’李嘉诚和他的公司——香港有史以来最成功的国际企业——则是另一回事，”祈福德(Mark L. Clifford)说，他是黎智英壹传媒的前董事会成员，也是香港自由委员会基金会主席。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To Beijing and its supporters, the Trump administration has already politicized business transactions, thwarting investment and imposing tariffs in the name of national security. In an opinion article, Mr. Hu, the former Chinese tabloid editor, argued that former President Joseph R. Biden Jr. also did this when his administration stopped a deal between Japan’s Nippon Steel and U.S. Steel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;对北京及其支持者来说，特朗普政府将商业交易政治化，阻挠投资，并以国家安全的名义征收关税。胡锡进在评论文章中指出，拜登前总统在其政府阻止日本新日铁和美国钢铁公司之间的交易时也这么做过。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-04-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-04-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;香港媒体大亨黎智英是著名的中国政府批评者，自2020年以来一直被监禁。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/HK-Panama-Tycoon-04-pqkc/HK-Panama-Tycoon-04-pqkc-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;香港媒体大亨黎智英是著名的中国政府批评者，自2020年以来一直被监禁。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Agence France-Presse — Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beijing has reason to be concerned, he added. The Trump administration “wants to use the ports to charge extra fees to Chinese ships arriving at the port and hit China’s shipbuilding and shipping industries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;他还称，北京方面有理由感到担忧。特朗普政府“要在美国港口对所有到岸的中国船只加收额外费用，打击中国航运和造船业”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Others argued that China’s condemnation of CK Hutchison for supposedly not acting in China’s national interests has effectively ratified Mr. Trump’s original claim that the company was controlled by China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;也有人认为，中国谴责长江和记所谓的不符合中国国家利益的行为，实际上证实了特朗普最初关于该公司受中国控制的说法。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“China’s reaction to the deal implicitly concedes the Trump administration’s point that control of major ports, here just the Panama Canal, constitutes a security threat to the United States,” said Lester Ross, the partner in charge of the Beijing office of the law firm Wilmer Hale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“中国对该交易的反应默认了特朗普政府的观点，即控制主要港口——这里仅指巴拿马运河——对美国构成了安全威胁，”威尔默黑尔律师事务所北京办事处主管合伙人莱斯特·罗斯说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It may also bring the Hong Kong business community as a whole even more tightly under Beijing’s thumb.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“这也可能使整个香港商界受到北京更紧密的控制。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;艾莎(Alexandra Stevenson)是《纽约时报》上海分社社长，报道中国经济和社会新闻。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/alexandra-stevenson&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/business/trump-panama-canal-china-hong-kong.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250321/trump-panama-canal-china-hong-kong/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/business/20250321/trump-panama-canal-china-hong-kong/dual</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 20:40:26 GMT</pubDate><author>艾莎,JOY DONG</author></item><item><title>「中英」五角大楼为马斯克安排对中国作战计划简报会</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-hqpg/20dc-musk-pentagon-hqpg-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;特朗普总统与埃隆·马斯克、马斯克的儿子X本月在白宫。目前尚不清楚向马斯克提供如此敏感的简报的原因是什么。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;特朗普总统与埃隆·马斯克、马斯克的儿子X本月在白宫。目前尚不清楚向马斯克提供如此敏感的简报的原因是什么。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Doug Mills/The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pentagon is scheduled on Friday to brief Elon Musk on the U.S. military’s plan for any war that might break out with China, two U.S. officials said on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;两名美国官员周四表示，五角大楼定于周五向埃隆·马斯克做简报，介绍美国军方针对美中开战的可能情形制定的作战计划。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another official said the briefing will be China focused, without providing additional details. A fourth official confirmed Mr. Musk was to be at the Pentagon on Friday, but offered no details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;另一名官员称，这次简报将以中国为重点，但没有提供更多细节。第四名官员证实，马斯克周五会前往五角大楼，但也没有透露任何细节。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hours after news of the planned meeting was published by The New York Times, Pentagon officials and President Trump denied that the session would be about military plans involving China. “China will not even be mentioned or discussed,” Mr. Trump said in a late-night social media post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;时报报道本次会面计划几小时后，五角大楼官员和特朗普总统做出了否认，称该会面与涉及中国的军事计划无关。“甚至不会提到或谈论中国，”特朗普深夜在社媒上发帖说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was not clear if the briefing for Mr. Musk would go ahead as originally planned. But providing Mr. Musk access to some of the nation’s most closely guarded military secrets would be a dramatic expansion of his already extensive role as an adviser to Mr. Trump and leader of his effort to slash spending and purge the government of people and policies they oppose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;目前尚不清楚马斯克的简报会是否会按原计划进行。但让马斯克获取这个国家的最高军事机密意味着他的身份再一次得到大幅扩展，此前他作为特朗普的顾问，领导了一场裁减支出，对政府中他们不认可的人和政策进行清洗的行动，本身就已经扮演了一个非常宽泛的角色。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would also bring into sharp relief the questions about Mr. Musk’s conflicts of interest as he ranges widely across the federal bureaucracy while continuing to run businesses that are major government contractors. In this case, Mr. Musk, the billionaire chief executive of both SpaceX and Tesla, is a leading supplier to the Pentagon and has extensive financial interests in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;由于马斯克广泛涉足联邦政府的各个部门，同时还继续经营着作为政府主要承包商的企业，也将凸显出他身上存在的利益冲突问题。具体来说，作为SpaceX和特斯拉的首席执行官，有亿万身家的马斯克不仅是五角大楼的主要供应商，还在中国拥有广泛的经济利益。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pentagon war plans, known in military jargon as O-plans or operational plans, are among the military’s most closely guarded secrets. If a foreign country was to learn how the United States planned to fight a war against them, it could reinforce its defenses and address its weaknesses, making the plans far less likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;五角大楼的作战计划——用军事术语来说就是所谓的“O计划”或“行动计划”——属于军方最高级别的机密之一。如果某外国了解到美国计划如何对其发动战争，它就可以加强防御并弥补弱点，从而大大降低这些计划取得成功的可能性。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The top-secret briefing for the China war plan has about 20 to 30 slides that lay out how the United States would fight such a conflict. It covers the plan beginning with the indications and warning of a threat from China to various options on what Chinese targets to hit, over what time period, that would be presented to Mr. Trump for decisions, according to officials with knowledge of the plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;对华作战计划的绝密简报有大约20到30张幻灯片，阐述了美国将如何应对此类冲突。据知情官员称，这份计划涵盖的内容从中国威胁的迹象和预警，到在什么时候打击中国目标的各种方案，这些内容都会呈交给特朗普供其决策时参考。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A White House spokesman did not respond to an email seeking comment about the purpose of the visit, how it came about, whether Mr. Trump was aware of it, and whether the visit raises questions of conflicts of interest. The White House has not said whether Mr. Trump signed a conflicts of interest waiver for Mr. Musk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;白宫发言人没有回复请求置评的邮件，提问包括马斯克此次到访五角大楼的目的、此行如何促成、特朗普是否知情，以及是否引发利益冲突问题。白宫也未说明特朗普是否为马斯克签署了利益冲突豁免书。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chief Pentagon spokesman, Sean Parnell, initially did not respond to a similar email seeking comment about why Mr. Musk was to receive a briefing on the China war plan. Soon after The Times published this article on Thursday evening, Mr. Parnell gave a short statement: “The Defense Department is excited to welcome Elon Musk to the Pentagon on Friday. He was invited by Secretary Hegseth and is just visiting.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;另一封类似的邮件询问了马斯克为何将接受有关对华作战计划的简报，对此五角大楼首席发言人肖恩·帕内尔起初也没有回应。但在时报于周四晚间发布相关报道后不久，帕内尔发表了一份简短声明：“国防部很高兴在周五欢迎埃隆·马斯克来到五角大楼。他是受国防部长赫格塞思邀请，仅仅是来访。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-gwbt/20dc-musk-pentagon-gwbt-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;国防部长赫格塞思已经听取了对华作战计划的部分内容，预计他将与美国政府和军方高级官员一起向马斯克介绍这些信息。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-gwbt/20dc-musk-pentagon-gwbt-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;国防部长赫格塞思已经听取了对华作战计划的部分内容，预计他将与美国政府和军方高级官员一起向马斯克介绍这些信息。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Kenny Holston/The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;About an hour later, Mr. Parnell posted&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/seanparnellatsd/status/1902899998792016137?s=46&amp;amp;t=JnnGaUK4QSN-wmehEEH1lA&quot;&gt;a message&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on his X account: “This is 100% Fake News. Just brazenly &amp;amp; maliciously wrong. Elon Musk is a patriot. We are proud to have him at the Pentagon.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;大约一个小时后，帕内尔的X账户发布了一条消息：“这完全是100%假新闻，公然且恶意地错误解读。埃隆·马斯克是爱国者，我们为他来到五角大楼感到自豪。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth also&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/PeteHegseth/status/1902911311102820635&quot;&gt;commented on X&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;late on Thursday, saying: “This is NOT a meeting about ‘top secret China war plans.’ It’s an informal meeting about innovation, efficiencies &amp;amp; smarter production. Gonna be great!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;国防部长皮特·赫格塞思也在周四晚些时候在X上发表评论称：“这不是一场关于‘绝密中国作战计划’的会议，而是一场围绕创新、效率和更智能生产的非正式会谈。一定会很棒！”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roughly 30 minutes after that social media post, The Wall Street Journal&amp;nbsp;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/musk-to-receive-top-secret-briefing-on-u-s-war-plans-for-china-922eafdf?mod=hp_lead_pos1&quot;&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that Mr. Musk had been scheduled to be briefed on the war planning for China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这条推文发布大约30分钟后，《华尔街日报》证实，马斯克原定听取有关对中国作战计划的简报。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whatever the meeting will now be about, the planning reflected the extraordinary dual role played by Mr. Musk, who is both the world’s wealthiest man and has been given broad authority by Mr. Trump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;无论这次会议最终将涉及什么内容，其筹备过程都反映出马斯克所扮演的极为重要的双重角色——他既是全球最富有的人，又被特朗普赋予了广泛的权力。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Musk has a security clearance, and Mr. Hegseth can determine who has a need to know about the plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;马斯克拥有安全许可，国防部长赫格塞思也有权决定谁需要了解这份计划。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Hegseth; Adm. Christopher W. Grady, the acting chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff; and Adm. Samuel J. Paparo, the head of the military’s Indo-Pacific Command, are set to present Mr. Musk with details on the U.S. plan to counter China in the event of military conflict between the two countries, the officials said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;上述知情官员表示，赫格塞思、参谋长联席会议代理主席克里斯托弗·格雷迪上将，以及美军印太司令部司令塞缪尔·帕帕罗上将，将向马斯克介绍在中美发生军事冲突的情况下，美国将如何应对中国的具体方案。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operational plans for major contingencies, like a war with China, are extremely difficult for people without extensive military planning to understand. The technical nature is why presidents are typically presented with the broad contours of a plan, rather than the actual details of documents. How many details Mr. Musk will want or need to hear is unclear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;像美中战争这样的重大突发事件的作战计划，对于没有丰富军事规划经验的人来说是极难理解的。正是因为其技术层面的复杂性，总统通常只会听取计划的大致轮廓，而非文件的实际细节。目前尚不清楚马斯克想要或需要了解多少细节。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Hegseth received part of the China war plan briefing last week and another part on Wednesday, according to officials familiar with the plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;据熟悉该计划的官员称，赫格塞思上周听取了有关与中国作战计划部分内容的简报，周三听取了另外一部分。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was unclear what the impetus was for providing Mr. Musk such a sensitive briefing. He is not in the military chain of command, nor is he an official adviser to Mr. Trump on military matters involving China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;目前尚不清楚向马斯克提供如此敏感的简报的原因是什么。他不在军事指挥系统中，也不是特朗普在涉及中国的军事事务方面的正式顾问。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-gvzb/20dc-musk-pentagon-gvzb-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;马斯克的公司SpaceX对五角大楼来说已经变得如此重要，以至于中国政府表示，如果爆发战争，它可能会把SpaceX的资产作为目标。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-gvzb/20dc-musk-pentagon-gvzb-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;马斯克的公司SpaceX对五角大楼来说已经变得如此重要，以至于中国政府表示，如果爆发战争，它可能会把SpaceX的资产作为目标。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Valerie Plesch for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there is a possible reason Mr. Musk might need to know about the war plan. If Mr. Musk and his team of cost cutters from the Department of Government Efficiency, or DOGE, want to trim the Pentagon budget in a responsible way, they may need to know what weapons systems the Pentagon plans to use in a fight with China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但有一个可能的原因是，马斯克需要了解作战计划。如果马斯克和他的政府效率部成本削减团队想以负责任的方式削减五角大楼的预算，他们可能需要知道五角大楼计划在与中国的冲突中使用哪些武器系统。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, aircraft carriers. Cutting back on future aircraft carriers would save billions of dollars, money that could be spent on drones or other weaponry. But if the U.S. war strategy relies on using aircraft carriers in innovative ways that would surprise China, mothballing existing ships or stopping production on future ships could cripple that plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;以航母为例。削减未来的航母数量将节省成百上千亿美元，这些钱可以用于购买无人机或其他武器装备。但是，如果美国的战争策略依赖于以创新的方式使用航母达到令中国措手不及的目的，那么封存现有的航母或停止建造未来的航母可能会使该计划陷入瘫痪。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Planning for a war with China has dominated Pentagon thinking for decades, well before a possible confrontation with Beijing became more conventional wisdom on Capitol Hill. The United States has built its Air Forces, Navy and Space Forces — and even more recently its Marines and Army forces — with a possible fight against China in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;几十年来，与中国开战的计划一直主导着五角大楼的思路，远在与北京对抗的可能性在国会山成为普遍看法之前就已经如此。美国在建立空军、海军和太空部队——甚至最近的海军陆战队和陆军部队——都考虑到了可能与中国发生的冲突。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Critics have said the military has invested too much in big expensive systems like fighter jets or aircraft carriers and too little in midrange drones and coastal defenses. But for Mr. Musk to evaluate how to reorient Pentagon spending, he would want to know what the military intends to use and for what purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;批评人士称，军方在战斗机或航母等昂贵的大型系统上投入太多，而在中程无人机和海岸防御系统上投入太少。但对于马斯克来说，要评估如何调整五角大楼的支出方向，他需要知道军方打算使用什么装备以及出于什么目的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Musk has already called for the Pentagon to stop buying certain high-priced items &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/06/us/politics/air-force-fighter-jets-ai.html&quot; title=&quot;Link: https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/06/us/politics/air-force-fighter-jets-ai.html&quot;&gt;like F-35 fighter jets&lt;/a&gt;, manufactured by one of his space-launch competitors, Lockheed Martin, in a program that costs the Pentagon more than &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/R48304&quot;&gt;$12 billion&lt;/a&gt; a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;马斯克已经呼吁五角大楼停止采购某些高价装备，像是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/06/us/politics/air-force-fighter-jets-ai.html&quot;&gt;F-35战机&lt;/a&gt;。该战斗机由他的太空发射竞争对手之一洛克希德·马丁公司制造，这个采购项目每年让五角大楼花费超过&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/R48304&quot;&gt;120亿美元&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet Mr. Musk’s extensive business interests make his access to strategic secrets about China a serious problem in the view of ethics experts. Officials have said revisions to the war plans against China have focused on upgrading the plans for defending against space warfare. China has developed a suite of weapons that can attack U.S. satellites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;然而，在商业操守专家看来，马斯克广泛的商业利益使得他接触有关中国的战略机密成为一个严重的问题。官员们表示，对华作战计划的修订侧重于升级抵御太空战的计划。中国已经研发出了一系列能够攻击美国卫星的武器。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Musk’s constellations of low-earth orbit Starlink satellites, which provide broadband data and communications services from space, are considered more resilient than traditional satellites. But he could have an interest in learning about whether or not the United States could defend his satellites in a war with China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;马斯克的近地轨道星链卫星群从太空提供宽带数据和通信服务，被认为比传统卫星有更强的适应力。但他可能有兴趣了解美国是否能在与中国的战争中保护他的卫星。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Participating in a classified briefing on the China threat with some of the most senior Pentagon and U.S. military officials would be a tremendously valuable opportunity for any defense contractor seeking to sell services to the military.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;对于任何一家试图向军方出售服务的国防承包商来说，与五角大楼和美国军方一些最高级别官员一起参加关于中国威胁的机密简报会，都是一个极为宝贵的机会。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Musk could gain insight into new tools that the Pentagon might need and that SpaceX, where he remains the chief executive, could sell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;马斯克可以深入了解五角大楼可能需要的新工具，而他仍然担任首席执行官的SpaceX可以出售这些工具。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Contractors working on relevant Pentagon projects generally do have access to certain limited war planning documents, but only once war plans are approved, said Todd Harrison, a senior fellow at the American Enterprise Institute, where he focuses on defense strategy. Individual executives rarely if ever get exclusive access to top Pentagon officials for a briefing like this, Mr. Harrison said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;美国企业研究所主要研究国防战略的高级研究员托德·哈里森表示，参与五角大楼相关项目的承包商通常确实可以接触到某些有限的战争计划文件，但只有在战争计划获得批准后才可以。哈里森说，高管个人很少有机会单独接触五角大楼的高级官员，听取这样的简报。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Musk at a war-planning briefing?” he said. “Giving the CEO of one defense company unique access seems like this could be grounds for a contract protest and is a real conflict of interest.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“马斯克出席战争规划简报会？”他说。“让一家国防公司的首席执行官独家获取这样的信息，似乎已经构成发起竞标抗议的依据，这是实打实的利益冲突。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;article-inline-photo large&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;img-box&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-hcqm/20dc-musk-pentagon-hcqm-master1050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;得州博卡奇卡的SpaceX Starbase。五角大楼的简报可以帮助埃隆·马斯克了解五角大楼可能需要哪些新工具，同时他仍然担任首席执行官的SpaceX可以出售这些工具。&quot; data-src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20dc-musk-pentagon-hcqm/20dc-musk-pentagon-hcqm-master1050.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;得州博卡奇卡的SpaceX Starbase。五角大楼的简报可以帮助埃隆·马斯克了解五角大楼可能需要哪些新工具，同时他仍然担任首席执行官的SpaceX可以出售这些工具。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Callaghan O&#39;Hare for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Musk’s SpaceX is already being paid billions of dollars by the Pentagon and federal spy agencies to help the United States build new military satellite networks to try to confront rising military threats from China. SpaceX launches most of these military satellites for the Pentagon on its Falcon 9 rockets, which take off from launchpads SpaceX has set up at military bases in Florida and California.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;马斯克的SpaceX公司已经从五角大楼和联邦间谍机构获得了数十亿美元的资金，以帮助美国建立新的军事卫星网络，应对来自中国日益增长的军事威胁。SpaceX为五角大楼发射的大部分军用卫星都是用猎鹰9号火箭发射的，它们从SpaceX在佛罗里达州和加利福尼亚州的军事基地设立的发射台起飞。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company separately has been paid hundreds of millions of dollars by the Pentagon that now relies heavily on SpaceX’s Starlink satellite communications network for military personnel to transmit data worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;五角大楼已经分别向该公司支付了多笔巨额资金，目前严重依赖SpaceX的星链卫星通信网络，供军事人员在全球范围内传输数据。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, SpaceX was granted about $1.6 billion in Air Force contracts. That does not include classified spending with SpaceX by the National Reconnaissance Office, which has hired the company to build it a new constellation of low-earth orbit satellites to spy on China, Russia and other threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2024年，SpaceX获得了约16亿美元的空军合同。这还不包括美国国家侦察局对SpaceX的机密支出，该局已聘请SpaceX为其建造一个新的低地球轨道卫星群，以监视中国、俄罗斯和其他威胁。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Trump has already proposed that the United States build a new system the military is calling &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4127682/dods-acquisition-community-already-working-on-golden-dome-big-team-effort-requi/&quot;&gt;Golden Dome&lt;/a&gt;, a space-based missile defense system that recalls what President Ronald Reagan tried to deliver. (The so-called Star Wars system Mr. Reagan had in mind was never fully developed.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;特朗普提议美国建立一个新系统，军方称之为“&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4127682/dods-acquisition-community-already-working-on-golden-dome-big-team-effort-requi/&quot;&gt;金穹&lt;/a&gt;”，这是一个天基导弹防御系统，让人想起罗纳德·里根总统试图带来的东西。（里根心目中所谓的星球大战系统从未完全开发出来。）&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perceived missile threats from China — be it nuclear weapons or hypersonic missiles or cruise missiles — are a major factor that led Mr. Trump to sign an executive order recently instructing the Pentagon to start work on Golden Dome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;来自中国的导弹威胁——无论是核武器、高超音速导弹还是巡航导弹——是导致特朗普最近签署行政命令，指示五角大楼启动“金穹”的一个主要因素。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even starting to plan and build the first components of the system will cost tens of billions of dollars, according to Pentagon officials, and most likely create large business opportunities for SpaceX, which already provides rocket launches, satellite structures, and space-based data communications systems, all of which will be required for Golden Dome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;五角大楼官员表示，即使是开始规划和建造该系统的第一个组件就将花费数百亿美元，这很可能为SpaceX创造巨大的商机，该公司已经提供火箭发射、卫星结构和天基数据通信系统，所有这些都是“金穹”所需要的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Separately, Mr. Musk has been the focus of an investigation by the Pentagon’s inspector general over questions about his compliance with his top-secret security clearance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;另外，马斯克一直是五角大楼监察长的重点调查人物，原因是有人质疑他是否遵守了绝密安全许可。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/17/technology/elon-musk-spacex-national-security-reporting.html&quot;&gt;The investigations&lt;/a&gt; started last year after some SpaceX employees complained to government agencies that Mr. Musk and others at SpaceX were not properly reporting contacts or conversations with foreign leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/17/technology/elon-musk-spacex-national-security-reporting.html&quot;&gt;调查&lt;/a&gt;始于去年，当时一些SpaceX员工向政府机构投诉称，马斯克和SpaceX的其他人没有合规报告与外国领导人的接触或对话。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Air Force officials, before the end of the Biden administration, started their own review, after Senate Democrats &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/documenttools/141bfff8333e1dc6/777e22e6-full.pdf&quot;&gt;asked questions&lt;/a&gt; about Mr. Musk and asserted that he was not complying with security clearance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;在参议院民主党人提出有关马斯克的&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/newsgraphics/documenttools/141bfff8333e1dc6/777e22e6-full.pdf&quot;&gt;问题&lt;/a&gt;并声称他没有遵守安全审查要求后，空军官员在拜登政府&lt;/span&gt;末期前开始了自己的审查。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Air Force, in fact, had denied a request by Mr. Musk for an even higher level of security clearance, known as Special Access Program, which is reserved for extremely sensitive classified programs, citing potential security risks associated with the billionaire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;事实上，空军拒绝了马斯克要求获得更高级别安全许可的请求，（即所谓的“特殊访问计划”，专为极度敏感的机密项目预留，）理由是与这位亿万富翁有关的潜在安全风险。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, SpaceX has become so valuable to the Pentagon that the Chinese government has said it considers the company to be an extension of the U.S. military.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SpaceX实际上对五角大楼来说已经变得如此重要，以至于中国政府表示将该公司视为美国军方的延伸。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Starlink Militarization and Its Impact on Global Strategic Stability” was the headline of one &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://interpret.csis.org/chinese-assessments-of-starlink-and-u-s-china-space-relations/&quot;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt; released last year from China’s National University of Defense Technology, according to a translation of the paper prepared by the Center for Strategic and International Studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;根据战略与国际研究中心的译文，中国国防科技大学去年发表了一篇&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://interpret.csis.org/chinese-assessments-of-starlink-and-u-s-china-space-relations/&quot;&gt;论文&lt;/a&gt;，题为“星链军事化及其对全球战略稳定的影响”。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Musk and Tesla, an electric vehicle company he controls, are heavily reliant on China, which houses one of the auto maker’s flagship factory in Shanghai. Unveiled in 2019, the state-of-the-art facility was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/27/world/asia/elon-musk-tesla-china.html&quot;&gt;built with special permission&lt;/a&gt; from the Chinese government, and now accounts for more than half of Tesla’s global deliveries. Last year, the company said in &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://ir.tesla.com/_flysystem/s3/sec/000162828025003063/tsla-20241231-gen.pdf&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;source=docs&amp;amp;ust=1742517143839856&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw12SwJa9Lp-zjW3-zY3Xz2b&quot;&gt;financial filings&lt;/a&gt; that it had a $2.8 billion loan agreement with lenders in China for production expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;马斯克和他控制的电动汽车公司特斯拉严重依赖中国，这家汽车制造商的旗舰工厂之一就设在上海。这座最先进的工厂于2019年揭幕，是在中国政府的&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20240328/elon-musk-tesla-china/&quot;&gt;特别许可&lt;/a&gt;下建造的，目前占特斯拉全球交付量的一半以上。去年，该公司在&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://ir.tesla.com/_flysystem/s3/sec/000162828025003063/tsla-20241231-gen.pdf&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;source=docs&amp;amp;ust=1742517143839856&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw12SwJa9Lp-zjW3-zY3Xz2b&quot;&gt;财务文件&lt;/a&gt;中表示，它与中国的贷款机构达成了一项28亿美元的贷款协议，用于生产开支。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In public, Mr. Musk has avoided criticizing Beijing and signaled his willingness to work with the Chinese Communist Party. In 2022, he wrote &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://beijingchannel.substack.com/p/elon-musks-article-in-china-cyberspace&quot;&gt;a column&lt;/a&gt; for the magazine of the Cyberspace Administration of China, the country’s censorship agency, trumpeting his companies and their missions of improving humanity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;在公开场合，马斯克避免批评北京，并表示愿意与中国共产党合作。2022年，他为中国的审查机构——国家互联网信息办公室旗下的杂志撰写了一篇&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://beijingchannel.substack.com/p/elon-musks-article-in-china-cyberspace&quot;&gt;专栏文章&lt;/a&gt;，大肆宣扬他的公司及其&lt;/span&gt;为人类谋福利的使命。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;That same year, the billionaire told the &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/5ef14997-982e-4f03-8548-b5d67202623a&quot; title=&quot;Link: https://www.ft.com/content/5ef14997-982e-4f03-8548-b5d67202623a&quot;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt; that China should be given some control over Taiwan by making a “special administrative zone for Taiwan that is reasonably palatable,” an assertion that angered politicians of the independent island. In that same interview, he also noted that he gave Beijing assurances that he would not sell Starlink in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;同年，这位亿万富翁向英国《&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/5ef14997-982e-4f03-8548-b5d67202623a&quot;&gt;金融时报&lt;/a&gt;》表示，中国应该通过“在台湾设立一个合理可接受的特别行政区”，来获得对台湾的一些控制权，这一主张激怒了这个独立岛屿的政界人士。在同一次采访中，他还指出，他向北京保证，不会在中国出售星链。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following year at &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RwsngXbLF5I&quot;&gt;a tech conference&lt;/a&gt;, Mr. Musk called the democratic island “an integral part of China that is arbitrarily not part of China,” and compared the Taiwan-China situation to Hawaii and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;次年，在一次&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RwsngXbLF5I&quot;&gt;科技会议&lt;/a&gt;上，马斯克称台湾这个民主的岛屿是“中国&lt;/span&gt;不可分割的一部分，但被擅自认定不属于中国”，并将台湾和中国的情况比作夏威夷和美国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On X, the social platform he owns, Mr. Musk has long used his account to praise China. He has said the country is “by far” &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1895404990971474227&quot;&gt;the world leader&lt;/a&gt; in electric vehicles and solar power, and has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1663231259785723904&quot;&gt;commended&lt;/a&gt; its space program for being “far more advanced than people realize.” He has &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1753841586213904820&quot;&gt;encouraged&lt;/a&gt; more people to visit the country, and &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1628955011416743936&quot;&gt;posited&lt;/a&gt; openly about an “inevitable” Russia-China alliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;在他拥有的社交平台X上，马斯克长期以来一直使用自己的账户赞扬中国。他说，到目前为止，中国在电动汽车和太阳能方面处于&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1895404990971474227&quot;&gt;世界领先地位&lt;/a&gt;，并&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1663231259785723904&quot;&gt;称赞&lt;/a&gt;其太空计划“比人们意识到的要先进得多”。他&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1753841586213904820&quot;&gt;鼓励&lt;/a&gt;更多的人到中国旅游，并公开&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1628955011416743936&quot;&gt;表示&lt;/a&gt;，中俄结盟是“不可避免的”。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aaron Kessler对本文有报道贡献。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eric Schmitt是《纽约时报》国家安全记者，主要关注美军事务以及海外反恐议题，他报道此类新闻已超过30年。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/eric-schmitt&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eric Lipton是&lt;span&gt;《纽约时报》调查记者，他深入挖掘了从五角大楼支出到有毒化学品等一系列话题。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/eric-lipton&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Julian E. Barnes是一名国家安全记者，常驻华盛顿，报道情报机构新闻。2018年加入时报之前，他为《华尔街日报》报道安全相关议题。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/julian-e-barnes&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ryan Mac报道全球科技行业的企业责任相关议题。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/ryan-mac&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maggie Haberman是《纽约时报》白宫记者，报道特朗普第二任期。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/maggie-haberman&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/20/us/politics/musk-pentagon-briefing-china-war-plan.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250321/musk-pentagon-briefing-china-war-plan/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250321/musk-pentagon-briefing-china-war-plan/dual</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 20:04:38 GMT</pubDate><author>ERIC SCHMITT,ERIC LIPTON,JULIAN E. BARNES,RYAN MAC,MAGGIE HABERMAN</author></item><item><title>「中英」美国华侨富商因参与“猎狐行动”获刑</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/19/multimedia/19met-edny-sentencing-zphf/19met-edny-sentencing-zphf-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;安全忠将被处以500万美元罚金，其中包括向他所针对的那名男子以及另外两名受害人支付100多万美元的赔偿。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;安全忠将被处以500万美元罚金，其中包括向他所针对的那名男子以及另外两名受害人支付100多万美元的赔偿。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Dave Sanders for The New York Times&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The script was familiar. For more than five years, a wealthy Queens businessman forcefully delivered the same message to a man wanted by China. Return to the homeland, or you — and your family — will face the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;这是个似曾相识的剧本。在长达五年多的时间里，皇后区的一名富商强硬地向一名遭到中国通缉的男子传达同样的信息：回到祖国，否则你——还有你的家人——将承担后果。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, he was sentenced to prison for those threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;本周三，他因这些威胁行为被判入狱。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The businessman, An Quanzhong, will spend about 13 months behind bars for trying to harass a U.S. resident into leaving for China to face charges for purported crimes. Mr. An pleaded guilty last May to working as an unauthorized agent for a foreign country, while his daughter, An Guangyan, pleaded guilty to an additional charge of visa fraud conspiracy. Ms. An is yet to be sentenced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;因试图骚扰一名美国居民、迫使其前往中国接受所谓的犯罪指控，这位名叫安全忠的商人将入狱约13个月。去年5月，安全忠承认&lt;span&gt;为外国担任未经授权的代理人&lt;/span&gt;，他的女儿安光阳则承认了另一项签证欺诈阴谋的指控，但尚未宣判。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government refers to Mr. An with his given name first, though Chinese naming conventions place his family name, An, first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;政府在提到安全忠时采用名前姓后的方式，但按照华人的习惯，姓氏在前。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. An has also been ordered to pay $5 million in penalties, including more than $1 million in restitution to the person he targeted and to two other victims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;安全忠还被处以500万美元罚金，其中包括向他所针对的那名男子以及另外两名受害人支付100多万美元的赔偿。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. An, 58, appeared before Judge Kiyo A. Matsumoto in Brooklyn federal court and listened to his sentencing through a Mandarin-speaking interpreter, with several relatives and supporters in attendance. He has been on home confinement since May 2023 after spending seven months at the Metropolitan Detention Center in Brooklyn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;58岁的安全忠在几位亲属和支持者的陪同下，在布鲁克林联邦法院通过一名中文翻译听取了法官松本清（Kiyo A. Matsumoto，音）的判决。自2023年5月以来，他一直处于居家监禁状态，之前他在布鲁克林大都会拘留中心度过了七个月。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In deciding Mr. An’s sentence, Judge Matsumoto said she had considered Mr. An’s difficult upbringing, his prominent status in the Chinese American community in Queens and the wretched conditions he faced at the detention center after he was detained in 2022. His time at the troubled jail, Judge Matsumoto said, warranted “a discount off his sentence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在对安全忠进行量刑时，松本法官表示，她考虑到了其艰难的成长经历、他在皇后区华裔美国人社区中的显赫地位，以及他在2022年遭拘留后在拘留中心面临的恶劣条件。松本法官称，考虑到他在那所问题重重的监狱里度过的时间，“应该在量刑时予以酌情从轻处理。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But she said a sentence was necessary to deter transnational repression by the Chinese government, which she described as widespread. She noted the harm he had caused the people he sought to repatriate, who remain in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但她表示，为了阻止中国政府的跨国镇压，判刑是必要的，她认为这种镇压普遍存在。她指出，安全忠对他试图遣返的人造成了伤害，这些人目前仍在美国。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Mr. An’s conduct presents a serious threat to national security,” Judge Matsumoto said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“安全忠的行为对国家安全构成了严重威胁，”松本法官说道。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ben Brafman, a lawyer for Mr. An, said in an interview after the proceeding that the 20-month sentence with credit for the seven months already served was about the best he could have hoped for, given the seriousness of the crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;安全忠的律师本·布拉夫曼在宣判后接受采访时表示，考虑到这一罪行的严重性，20个月的刑期减去已经服刑的七个月，这是他所能期望的最好结果了。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2022, prosecutors in the Eastern District of New York indicted the Ans and five others in connection with Operation Fox Hunt, the Chinese government’s clandestine campaign to repatriate dissidents abroad. The Chinese Communist Party under its leader, Xi Jinping, started the operation in 2014, claiming it was meant to make fugitives face justice for corruption. U.S. officials have said it is merely autocratic repression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2022年，纽约东区的检察官起诉安氏父女以及另外五人，指控他们与中国政府的“猎狐行动”有关，这是中国政府开展的一项秘密行动，目的是将在国外的持不同政见者遣送回国。中共在习近平的领导下，于2014年启动了这一行动，声称这是为了让一些逃亡贪腐分子接受法律制裁。美国官员称，这不过是专制镇压行为。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sentencing was the latest example of Eastern District prosecutors’ crackdown on China’s efforts to harass U.S. residents and influence public officials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;此次宣判是纽约东区检察官打击中国骚扰美国居民、影响政府官员行为的最新案例。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June 2023, three men, including a former New York police officer, were convicted of stalking a former Chinese government official. In September, a former aide to New York governors, Linda Sun, was indicted on charges that she had used her position to benefit China in exchange for lavish gifts. In December, a man pleaded guilty in Brooklyn federal court to working as an agent of a foreign government after he was charged with running a Chinese police outpost in Lower Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2023年6月，包括一名前纽约警官在内的三名男子因跟踪一名前中国政府官员而被定罪。去年9月，纽约州州长的前助手孙雯遭到起诉，她被指控利用职务之便为中国谋取利益，以换取奢侈的礼物。12月，一名男子在布鲁克林联邦法院承认充当外国政府的代理人，他被控在曼哈顿下城管理一个中国警务站。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government since 2002 had targeted the man in the An case, who was not named, accusing him of stealing hundreds of thousands of dollars from a state-owned company, prosecutors said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;检察官表示，自2002年以来，中国政府就盯上了安全忠一案中的男子（未透露姓名），指控他从一家国企盗取大量资产。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2017, Mr. and Ms. An tried to induce him to return to China, prosecutors said, including by forcing a relative in China to travel to the U.S. to persuade him to return. On one occasion, Mr. An told the man’s son that the Chinese government had “targeted and monitored” the man’s family in China, and that “all of your relatives will be involved,” according to the indictment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;检方还称，从2017年开始，安氏父女就试图诱使他返回中国，包括强迫他在中国的一名亲属前往美国劝说他回国。根据起诉书内容，有一次，安全忠告诉这名男子的儿子，中国政府已经“盯上并监视”了他在中国的家人，而且“你所有的亲属都会遭到牵连”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2019, the company that accused the man of stealing sued in State Supreme Court, and Mr. An told the man he could make the case go away if he returned to China, prosecutors said. In that event, Mr. An said, not only he would pay the Chinese government to drop the suit, but he would provide the man with housing, according to the indictment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;检方称，2019年，那家指控该男子盗窃的公司向州最高法院提起诉讼，安全忠告诉那名男子，如果他返回中国，这起案件就能了结。根据起诉书内容，安全忠当时表示，他不仅会出钱让中国政府撤销诉讼，而且还会为那名男子提供住房。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the person didn’t return, Mr. An said, the suit would remain open. He also promised that the fugitive would not face prison in China, according to the indictment. In the courtroom on Wednesday, prosecutors said that lawsuit was still active.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;起诉书显示，安全忠还说，如果那个人不回国，诉讼就会继续进行。他还承诺，那名逃犯回国后不会在中国面临牢狱之灾。周三在法庭上，检察官表示，这起诉讼目前仍在进行中。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. An’s businesses and political influence spanned his native China and the United States, where he was a permanent resident, according to court papers. He founded the Anqiao Group, a real estate company based in Zaozhuang, a city in eastern China’s Shandong province that by 2015 had about $800 million in assets, Chinese state media reported. In 2014, Mr. An, through the Anqiao Group, opened the 96-room Parc Hotel in Flushing, Queens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;法庭文件显示，安全忠的生意和政治影响力横跨他的祖国中国和美国，他本人是美国的永久居民。据中国官方媒体的报道，他创办了安侨集团，这是一家总部位于中国山东枣庄的房地产公司，截至2015年，该公司资产约为8亿美元。2014年，安全忠通过安侨集团在皇后区法拉盛开设了拥有96间客房的安侨酒店(Parc Hotel)。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr. An was the president of the New York Shandong Association, an organization in Flushing for immigrants from that province, and enjoyed close ties to Representative Grace Meng, a Democrat whose district includes Flushing. She declared Oct. 6, 2015, “An Quanzhong Day.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;安全忠曾是纽约山东同乡会会长，该同乡会是法拉盛的一个为山东移民设立的组织，他与国会民主党众议员孟昭文关系密切。她将2015年10月6日设为“安全忠日”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement, a spokesman for Ms. Meng noted that the declaration took place before Mr. An’s crimes, and that she was “totally against any foreign government influencing or manipulating our democracy,” including China’s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;孟昭文的发言人在一份声明中指出，这件事发生在安全忠的犯罪行为之前，并且她“完全反对任何外国政府影响或操纵我们的民主制度”，包括来自中国政府的影响或操纵行为。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back home in China, Mr. An was named in 2015 as a member of a government advisory committee in Zaozhuang, a city of about 3.9 million people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在中国国内，安全忠于2015年成为枣庄市政协常委，枣庄是一座人口约390万的城市。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, he was named to the standing committee of the All-China Federation of Returned Overseas Chinese, an organization that is an essential part of the Communist Party’s United Front, which seeks to extend its influence both within China and among the tens of millions of ethnic Chinese people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013年，他被推选为中华全国归国华侨联合会常务委员会委员，该组织是是中共领导的统一战线工作的重要组成部分，致力于在中国国内以及全球数千万华侨华人中扩大影响力。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In arguing for a lighter sentence, Mr. Brafman said that Mr. An had sought to repatriate the man out of genuine concern, and that his promise to protect him from incarceration in China showed he was looking out for him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;在为安全忠争取从轻量刑时，布拉夫曼称，他的当事人试图将那名男子遣送回国是出于真心的关切，而且他承诺让那名男子回国后不被监禁，这表明他是在为对方着想。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Alex Solomon, an assistant U.S. attorney, said in court on Wednesday that Mr. An had more sinister intentions and “fundamentally undermined” American national security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;但美国助理检察官亚历克斯·所罗门周三在法庭上说，安全忠并非出于好意，并“从根本上破坏了”美国的国家安全。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This was an extremely coercive situation,” Mr. Solomon said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;所罗门表示：“这是一种极具胁迫性的情况。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Santul Nerkar是时报记者，报道布鲁克林联邦法院。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/santul-nerkar&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于他的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/nyregion/chinese-repression-sentence-an-quanzhong.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250320/chinese-repression-sentence-an-quanzhong/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/usa/20250320/chinese-repression-sentence-an-quanzhong/dual</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:11:55 GMT</pubDate><author>SANTUL NERKAR</author></item><item><title>「中英」加拿大谴责中国以涉毒罪名处决四名加拿大公民</title><description>&lt;figure class=&quot;article-span-photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static01.nyt.com/images/2025/03/20/multimedia/20int-china-canada-zfqj/20int-china-canada-zfqj-master1050.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1050&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; alt=&quot;加拿大外交部长赵美兰在上周的新闻发布会上。&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;加拿大外交部长赵美兰在上周的新闻发布会上。&lt;/span&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Adrian Wyld/The Canadian Press, via Associated Press&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China has executed four Canadians over drug-related convictions, Canada’s foreign affairs minister said Wednesday, a development that threatens to worsen an already tense relationship between the countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;加拿大外交部长于周三表示，中国以涉毒罪名处决了四名加拿大人。这一事态发展可能会使两国之间本已紧张的关系进一步恶化。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mélanie Joly, the Canadian minister, told reporters that she condemned the executions, and that the government would still seek clemency for others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;加拿大外交部长赵美兰(Mélanie Joly)告诉记者，她谴责了这些处决行为，政府仍将为其他人寻求宽大处理。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We will continue to engage with China as we’ll continue to not only strongly condemn but also ask for leniency for other Canadians that are facing similar situations,” Ms. Joly said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“我们将继续与中国接触，我们不仅会继续强烈谴责，还会继续为其他面临类似情况的加拿大人争取宽大处理，”赵美兰说。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese Embassy in Ottawa did not provide details on the executions but defended Beijing’s strict penalties on drug-related crimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国驻渥太华大使馆没有提供处决的细节，但为北京对涉毒犯罪的严厉惩罚进行了辩护。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The executions were first reported by The Globe and Mail. The newspaper said that the executions had taken place earlier this year, citing Canada’s Department of Global Affairs as saying so on Wednesday in response to a question from the news outlet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;《环球邮报》首先报道了这些处决。该报援引加拿大全球事务部周三在回应该报提问时的话称，这些处决是在今年早些时候进行的。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Joly told reporters that she and the former prime minister, Justin Trudeau, had asked Beijing for leniency in recent months to try to prevent the executions. She said those involved were dual nationals of Canada and China. (China, however, does not recognize dual citizenship.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;赵美兰告诉记者，她和前总理特鲁多最近几个月曾请求北京宽大处理，以阻止处决。她说，涉案人员拥有加拿大和中国双重国籍。（但中国不承认双重国籍。）&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Globe and Mail cited a statement from Ottawa condemning the killings as “inconsistent with basic human dignity.” The department did not immediately respond to a request for comment from The New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;《环球邮报》援引渥太华的一份声明，谴责这些处决“不符合人类的基本尊严”。该部门没有立即回应《纽约时报》的置评请求。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Kamm, the founder of the Dui Hua Foundation, a human rights group in San Francisco that has campaigned for people on death row in China, said he had been helping to lobby China on behalf of the four individuals but was unable to share their details for privacy reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;旧金山人权组织对话基金会的创始人康原(John Kamm)表示，他一直在代表这四个人帮助游说中国，但出于隐私原因无法分享他们的详细信息。对话基金会一直在为中国的死刑犯争取利益。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said the four were men and that their cases were handled in the southern province of Guangdong. Mr. Kamm noted that it was “highly unusual” for China to execute four foreigners within a short time frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;他说，这四人都是男性，他们的案件在南方的广东省处理。康原指出，中国在短时间内处决四名外国人是“极不寻常的”。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The four Canadians’ cases had been under judicial review in China for two years before they were executed, Mr. Kamm said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;康原说，四名加拿大人被处决前，他们的案件在中国接受了两年的司法审查。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canada’s relationship with China has deteriorated since late 2018, when the Chinese government &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/25/world/asia/meng-wanzhou-china.html&quot;&gt;jailed Michael Spavor and Michael Kovrig&lt;/a&gt;, two Canadians in China. That move came after Canada arrested Meng Wanzhou, an executive at the Chinese telecommunications giant Huawei, in Vancouver, at the request of the United States government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;加拿大与中国的关系自2018年底以来出现恶化，当时中国政府&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20210926/meng-wanzhou-china/&quot;&gt;监禁了迈克尔·斯帕弗和康明凯(Michael Kovrig)&lt;/a&gt;这两名在中国的加拿大人。此前，应美国政府的要求，加拿大在温哥华逮捕了中国电信巨头华为的高管孟晚舟。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s detention of Mr. Kovrig and Mr. Spavor was widely condemned in Canada as hostage diplomacy. In 2021, Mr. Spavor and Mr. Kovrig were released after Ms. Meng was allowed to return to China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国监禁康明凯和斯帕弗的行为在加拿大受到广泛谴责，被视为人质外交。2021年，在孟晚舟获准返回中国后，康明凯和斯帕弗获释。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the former prime minister, Mr. Trudeau, and senior members of his cabinet have increasingly criticized China publicly over human rights issues. Concerns have also grown over Chinese interference in Canadian affairs, including allegations that candidates in an election had received &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://globalnews.ca/news/9253386/canadian-intelligence-warned-pm-trudeau-that-china-covertly-funded-2019-election-candidates-sources/&quot;&gt;secret, illegal funding&lt;/a&gt; from China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;近年来，前总理特鲁多及其内阁高级成员越来越多地在人权问题方面公开批评中国。人们对中国干涉加拿大事务的担忧也与日俱增，其中包括指控某次选举中的候选人接受了来自中国的&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://globalnews.ca/news/9253386/canadian-intelligence-warned-pm-trudeau-that-china-covertly-funded-2019-election-candidates-sources/&quot;&gt;秘密非法资助&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Joly, the foreign minister, had called China an “increasingly disruptive global power” and warned Canadian companies about the potential risks in doing business there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;外交部长赵美兰称中国是一个“日益具有破坏性的全球大国”，并警告加拿大公司在中国开展业务的潜在风险。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;More recently, Canada has faced growing concerns that Chinese goods were flooding into Canada. Mr. Trudeau last year announced that Canada would impose 100 percent tariffs on Chinese electric vehicles, aligning Canada with the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;最近，加拿大越来越担心中国商品涌入加拿大。特鲁多去年宣布，加拿大将对中国电动汽车征收100%的关税，从而使加拿大与美国保持一致。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Ms. Joly said that the details of the four Canadians who were executed were not being revealed at the request of their families. She said they had been facing criminal charges linked to drugs, according to China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;周三，赵美兰表示是应家人要求不公布四名被处决的加拿大人的详情。她说，据中国报道，他们面临的刑事指控与毒品有关。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese Embassy, without providing details, said that the cases were handled according to law. “The facts of the crimes committed by the Canadian nationals involved in the cases are clear, and the evidence is solid and sufficient,” it said. The embassy urged Canada to respect China’s judicial sovereignty and “stop making irresponsible remarks.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;中国大使馆表示，这些案件是依法处理的，但没有提供细节。声明称：“涉案加拿大公民犯罪事实清楚，证据确凿充分。”使馆敦促加拿大尊重中国司法主权，“停止发表不负责任的言论。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-partial&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-body-item col-lg-5&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least one other Canadian faces the death penalty in China, Robert Lloyd Schellenberg, who has been convicted of drug trafficking. He had initially been sentenced to 15 years in prison. But in 2019 he was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/14/world/asia/china-canada-schellenberg-retrial.html&quot;&gt;handed a death sentence in a one-day retrial&lt;/a&gt;, one month after the Canadian authorities had arrested Ms. Meng, the Huawei executive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;至少还有一名加拿大人在中国面临死刑，此人名叫&lt;span&gt;罗伯特·劳埃德·谢伦伯格，被判犯有贩毒罪，最初被判处15年有期徒刑。但2019年加拿大当局逮捕华为高管孟晚舟一个月后，他&lt;a href=&quot;https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20190115/china-canada-schellenberg-retrial/&quot; title=&quot;Link: https://cn.nytimes.com/china/20190115/china-canada-schellenberg-retrial/&quot;&gt;在为期一天的重审中被判处死刑&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Foreigners, like every person in China, are at risk of all kinds of arbitrary detentions and unfair trials,” said Maya Wang, the associate China director at Human Rights Watch. “The universe of cases is really big and we only hear about some of them occasionally.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;“就像中国的每一个人一样，外国人面临着各种任意拘留和不公正审判的风险，”人权观察组织中国部副主任王松莲说。“案件的范围非常广泛，我们只是偶尔听到其中一些。”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the release of the two Michaels, people had hoped for a thaw in relations, but that has not taken place on a substantive scale, said Lynette Ong, a professor in Chinese politics at the University of Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;多伦多大学研究中国政治的教授王慧玲表示，在康明凯和斯帕弗获释后，人们曾希望两国关系解冻，但这并没有在实质层面实现。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;row article-dual-body-item&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The timing of these executions is a way for Beijing to keep up the pressure and keep up the leverage over Canada in bilateral discussions, Ms. Ong said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;article-paragraph&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;王慧玲说，这个时候处决犯人是北京在双边谈判中对加拿大保持压力和影响力的一种方式。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;footer class=&quot;author-info&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joy Dong自香港、Vjosa Isai自多伦多对本文有报道贡献。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meaghan Tobin是时报科技记者，常驻台北，报道亚洲地区的商业和科技新闻，重点关注中国。&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/by/meaghan-tobin&quot;&gt;点击查看更多关于她的信息。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;翻译：纽约时报中文网&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/19/world/asia/china-canada-drug-executions.html&quot;&gt;点击查看本文英文版。&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;</description><link>https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20250320/china-canada-drug-executions/dual</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://cn.nytimes.com/world/20250320/china-canada-drug-executions/dual</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:31:18 GMT</pubDate><author>MEAGHAN TOBIN</author></item></channel></rss>