<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News posts on daily.dev</title><link>https://app.daily.dev/sources/hn</link><atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:1200/daily/source/hn" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>Hacker News is a community-driven platform for sharing and discussing technology news, startups, and programming-related topics. Through user submissions and comments, Hacker News offers insights into emerging technology trends, industry developments, and entrepreneurial ventures. Readers can participate in discussions, share their insights, and stay informed about the latest advancements in technology and innovation. - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-us</language><image><url>https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/t_logo,f_auto/v1/logos/hn</url><title>Hacker News posts on daily.dev</title><link>https://app.daily.dev/sources/hn</link></image><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 23:02:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>ikemen-engine/Ikemen-GO: An open-source fighting game engine that supports MUGEN resources.</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/d0c8e28d819b55c643573f1606609cc2?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Ikemen GO is an open-source fighting game engine written in Go, compatible with M.U.G.E.N resources and expanding on its features. It offers builds for Windows, macOS, and Linux, with instructions for custom development and resource creation. The engine can be compiled using Docker and debugging is supported via GoLand or Visual Studio Code. The source code is licensed under the MIT License. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/ikemen-engine-ikemen-go-an-open-source-fighting-game-engine-that-supports-mugen-resources--casqr5lvs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/Casqr5Lvs</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:56:44 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/d0c8e28d819b55c643573f1606609cc2?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>open-source</category><category>game-development</category><category>golang</category><category>docker</category></item><item><title>Fine-tune Gemma 3 with Unsloth</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/a8848e716bb46d7bf6ce6890eb2990c9?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Google&#39;s Gemma 3 multimodal models, available in various sizes, can now be fine-tuned and run using Unsloth. Unsloth offers significant performance improvements, including faster fine-tuning, reduced VRAM usage, and longer context windows. It supports various models and training algorithms and provides extensive documentation and resources for effective use. Key fixes and updates for training Gemma 3 on different GPUs are also discussed. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/fine-tune-gemma-3-with-unsloth-bzzpfmuer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/BzZPfMueR</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:26:08 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/a8848e716bb46d7bf6ce6890eb2990c9?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>ai</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>google</category><category>multimodal</category></item><item><title>AI Blindspots</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/s--2-1xRawN--/f_auto/v1722860399/public/Placeholder%2011&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Explores various blindspots encountered while coding with LLMs, with a focus on the Sonnet family. Includes potential solutions like Cursor rules. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/ai-blindspots-erysspgwi</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/erYsSpgWi</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:24:46 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/s--2-1xRawN--/f_auto/v1722860399/public/Placeholder%2011"></itunes:image><category>ai</category><category>machine-learning</category><category>devtools</category></item><item><title>Google to pay $28m to settle claims it favoured white and Asian employees</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/1a7ee652a2d1039f8a385e432c4525d4?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Google has agreed to pay $28 million to settle a lawsuit alleging it favored white and Asian employees on pay and career opportunities. The settlement, approved by a California judge, covers over 6,600 employees. Google disputes the allegations but remains committed to fair treatment of all employees. The lawsuit, led by Ana Cantu, claimed discrimination against Hispanic, Latino, Indigenous, Native American, and other minority employees. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/google-to-pay-28m-to-settle-claims-it-favoured-white-and-asian-employees-qvfetrg7r</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/qVFetRg7R</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:52:33 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/1a7ee652a2d1039f8a385e432c4525d4?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>tech-news</category><category>google</category><category>diversity-and-inclusion</category></item><item><title>How Fast the Days Are Getting Longer – Joe Antognini</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/91af6539c0b360df6bfa37898d127c8f?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   In the northern hemisphere, the days start getting longer after the vernal equinox. An interactive graph shows how the length of daylight changes with latitude, highlighting that near the Arctic circle, the length of days forms a zigzag pattern. The post also delves into the mathematics and calculations behind the changing daylight hours and the effects of spherical astronomy, atmospheric refraction, the solar limb, and Earth&#39;s elliptical orbit on these changes. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/how-fast-the-days-are-getting-longer-joe-antognini-umh0xwfz8</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/uMH0xwfz8</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:51:43 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/91af6539c0b360df6bfa37898d127c8f?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>science</category><category>math</category></item><item><title>Selective asynchronous commits in PostgreSQL - balancing durability and performance</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/b9031d4dba22f0bc4e125e209f86286d?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   Selective asynchronous commits in PostgreSQL can significantly improve performance by reducing I/O and CPU contention, increasing TPS by 30%. By default, PostgreSQL uses synchronous commit to ensure transaction durability, but this can be a bottleneck. Asynchronous commit acknowledges transactions before writing to disk, sacrificing some durability for better throughput. It is possible to toggle this setting per session or transaction, allowing critical transactions to remain durable while improving performance for less critical operations. Intermediate settings are available to balance performance and durability differently. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/selective-asynchronous-commits-in-postgresql---balancing-durability-and-performance-1ya4etwbd</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/1ya4etWBd</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:20:39 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/b9031d4dba22f0bc4e125e209f86286d?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>performance</category><category>backend</category><category>postgresql</category><category>rails</category></item><item><title>CVE-2024-9956 - PassKey Account Takeover in All Mobile Browsers</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/e9069d15291f5cc346e5223fcfbed862?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   A vulnerability (CVE-2024-9956) has been discovered in major mobile browsers allowing attackers within Bluetooth range to hijack PassKeys through FIDO intents. This flaw enables attackers to initiate a PassKeys authentication request from an attacker-controlled page, resulting in the hijacking of legitimate PassKeys credentials. Major browsers such as Safari, Chrome, and Firefox have patched the vulnerability. The post explores the specifics of the attack, its implications, and potential attack scenarios. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/cve-2024-9956---passkey-account-takeover-in-all-mobile-browsers-bwiqre1v1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/BwIqre1V1</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 17:20:39 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/e9069d15291f5cc346e5223fcfbed862?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>security</category><category>vulnerability</category></item><item><title>Video game workers in North America now have an industry-wide union</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/29f3a4a6ae38b6f9eb720187890efb9d?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The United Videogame Workers-CWA (UVW-CWA) is a newly established industry-wide union for video game workers in the US and Canada. Its mission is to unite various workers, including artists, writers, designers, QA testers, and freelancers, to build worker power across the industry. The union made its debut at a GDC panel, addressing significant issues such as industry layoffs. It allows direct joining without traditional unionization processes. The formation of this union is part of a growing movement, with other notable unions forming within major companies like Activision and ZeniMax Online Studios. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/video-game-workers-in-north-america-now-have-an-industry-wide-union-vljoh4tby</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/vlJoh4tBy</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:49:29 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/29f3a4a6ae38b6f9eb720187890efb9d?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image></item><item><title>For Delivery Workers in Latin America, Affordable E-Bikes Are a Superpower</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/36785477b5ce2baad17869230620f9a8?_a=AQAEuj9&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   E-bikes are becoming a popular choice for delivery workers in Latin America due to their efficiency, low environmental impact, and the financial advantages they offer. Start-ups like Guajira and Roda are providing affordable e-bike financing options, making it easier for migrant workers to switch from motorbikes to e-bikes and increase their earnings. Additionally, initiatives like Nippy are supporting delivery drivers by offering various benefits and creating a sense of community. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/for-delivery-workers-in-latin-america-affordable-e-bikes-are-a-superpower-ecpon7mxj</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/eCPoN7mXJ</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:19:19 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/posts/36785477b5ce2baad17869230620f9a8?_a=AQAEuj9"></itunes:image><category>startup</category><category>sustainability</category></item><item><title>The Internet Slum</title><description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/s--0_ODbtD2--/f_auto/v1722860399/public/Placeholder%2008&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;   The Internet, once a frontier of possibility, has transformed into a &#39;slum&#39; plagued by spam, cyber attacks, and diminishing user quality due to broader accessibility. The author compares living with the internet&#39;s modern threats to residing in a dangerous neighborhood. Efforts to create secure barriers, like &#39;trusted door&#39; schemes or the fragmentation of the web into more exclusive &#39;gated communities,&#39; are being considered as solutions. Despite these troubles, completely abandoning the Internet remains a debated topic, with some already opting out due to the growing risks. </description><link>https://app.daily.dev/posts/the-internet-slum-sufelsm3l</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://api.daily.dev/r/SUFelsm3L</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:19:19 GMT</pubDate><itunes:image href="https://media.daily.dev/image/upload/s--0_ODbtD2--/f_auto/v1722860399/public/Placeholder%2008"></itunes:image><category>security</category><category>cyber</category></item></channel></rss>