<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>News - Followin</title><link>https://followin.io/en/news</link><atom:link href="http://rsshub.rssforever.com/followin/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>News - Followin - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en</language><image><url>https://followin.io/favicon.ico</url><title>News - Followin</title><link>https://followin.io/en/news</link></image><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:20:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><item><title>Powell: We are at a stage where we can cut interest rates or maintain the current clearly tight policy stance</title><description>&lt;p&gt;ChainCatcher news, Fed Chair Powell: We are now in a stage where we can cut interest rates or maintain the current clearly tightening policy stance.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934402</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934402</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Economists: Be cautious when betting on Fed rate cuts</title><description>Odaily News reports that Casey Bostic, an observer of the Federal Reserve and chief economist at the UK mortgage company Nationwide, has warned people to be cautious about betting on the Federal Reserve&#39;s rate cuts. She believes that investors are too eager to digest the impact of rate cuts, and as concerns about a sharp economic slowdown intensify, they generally expect the Federal Reserve&#39;s &quot;Fed put&quot; to cushion economic activity. Even if it is assumed that economic activity does not decline sharply, persistent high inflation and inflationary pressures from tariffs may cause the Federal Reserve to remain on hold for longer than the market expects. (Gold Ten)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934376</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934376</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Powell: Slowing the balance sheet reduction means it will happen at a slower pace but last longer</title><description>On March 20, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell said that slowing the balance sheet reduction means it will be done at a slower pace, but the duration will be longer. (Gold Ten)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16934001</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16934001</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:06:34 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item><item><title>Powell: There will be decisions and clarity in the coming months and throughout this year, and policies will be adjusted according to circumstances</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher news, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell: There will be decisions and clarity in the coming months and throughout this year, and we will adjust our policies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933978</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933978</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>In the past 4 hours, the entire network has liquidated 104 million US dollars, mainly short orders</title><description>Odaily Odaily reports that according to Coinglass data, the entire network has seen &amp;lt;1.04 billion USD&amp;gt; in liquidations over the past 4 hours, of which &amp;lt;337.472 million USD&amp;gt; were long positions and &amp;lt;702.417 million USD&amp;gt; were short positions.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933957</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933957</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:58:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Bitcoin breaks through $85,000</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 20, according to HTX market data, Bitcoin surged above $85,000, currently quoted at $85,145.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933869</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933869</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:53:54 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title>Powell: If inflation subsides on its own, monetary policy should not be tightened</title><description>Federal Reserve Chairman Powell: If inflation subsides on its own, there is no need to tighten monetary policy.</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933891</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933891</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>BTC breaks through 85,000 USDT, up 3.81% in 24 hours</title><description>Odaily Odaily News OKX market shows that BTC has broken through 85,000 USDT and is now at 85,005.3 USDT, with a 24-hour increase of 3.81%. (This newsletter is generated by AI)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933890</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933890</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category></item><item><title>Bitcoin breaks through 85,000 USDT</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Foresight News reports that according to Bitget market data, Bitcoin has broken through 85,000 USDT, currently trading at 85,057.80 USDT, with a daily increase of 2.84%.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933889</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933889</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate><author>Foresight News</author><category>Bitcoin</category><category>Halving Tokens</category><category>Stablecoin</category></item><item><title>Powell mentions &quot;tariffs&quot; and admits that Trump&#39;s policies affect the economy</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher&#39;s message, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell first mentioned the &quot;tariff&quot; issue at the press conference. When asked about the revision of inflation forecasts and the extent to which tariffs have affected inflation forecasts, he said it was difficult to analyze how much inflation was driven by tariff policies, but they would strive to figure it out: &quot;It&#39;s clear that a large part of it comes from tariffs.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, Powell pointed out that the policies of the new Trump administration would affect the economy, but he would cautiously avoid making too explicit judgments about this impact. Analysts pointed out that this might be his attempt, and he said he would closely monitor the monthly data to avoid the outside world&#39;s expectations about how all this would develop.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933892</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933892</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:50:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Data: Spot gold hits a new high of $3,047</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to ChainCatcher news, spot gold has refreshed its historical high to $3,047.52 per ounce, up 0.44% intraday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933581</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933581</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Gold hits record high after interest rate decision, US stocks rise</title><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 20, after the announcement of the Federal Reserve&#39;s March interest rate decision, spot gold hit a new high of $3,047 per ounce, up 0.44% intraday. U.S. stocks continued to rally, with the S&amp;amp;P 500 index up 1%, the Nasdaq up 1.47%, and the Dow Jones up 0.77%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933500</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933500</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:47:02 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item><item><title>Powell: The economy is strong, slowing the balance sheet reduction is a &quot;technical&quot; decision</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher news, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell stated in a press conference that the U.S. economy is strong, and the decision to slow the pace of quantitative tightening (QT) is a &quot;technical&quot; one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powell said he is currently evaluating economic data, and while recent data shows consumer spending has slowed and household uncertainty has increased, he added that this is occurring on the basis of rapid growth in recent years. Powell also stated that the labor market conditions remain solid.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933493</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933493</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:42:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Powell: Survey shows tariffs drive inflation expectations, no need to rush to adjust policy stance</title><description>On March 20, Federal Reserve Chairman Powell said in his speech that the Fed&#39;s survey showed that tariffs have driven up inflation expectations; there is currently no need to urgently adjust the policy stance, and some signs of tightening in the money market have already been seen. (Jinshi)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933401</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933401</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:37:05 GMT</pubDate><author>Blockbeats</author></item><item><title>Analyst: The next Fed rate cut window may be in May or later</title><description>Odaily reports that Matthias Scheiber, head of Allspring&#39;s global multi-asset solutions team, said that given the growing concerns about tariffs and their potential impact on US economic growth and inflation, the Fed has taken a generally expected &#39;wait-and-see&#39; attitude towards interest rates. We believe the next possible window for the Fed to cut rates will be in May or later, with some market analysts now expecting three rate cuts in 2025, rather than the two expected a month ago. The interest rate market currently expects the Fed to lower rates to around 3.75% by the end of the year. This largely depends on how the balance between inflation and growth tilts, and the economy may continue to weaken, potentially requiring the Fed to cut rates more aggressively than expected. (Gold Ten)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16933093</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16933093</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:27:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Analysts: The Fed&#39;s interest rate decision is dovish</title><description>Odaily Odaily News reports that Neil Dutta of Renaissance Macro believes the Fed&#39;s latest decision appears dovish. The Fed believes tariffs are detrimental to economic growth, unemployment and inflation. However, while the Fed raised its core inflation forecast by 0.3 percentage points, the median interest rate did not change, still indicating two rate cuts within the year. If the core inflation rate is lower than the current forecast, there is room for rate cuts from 2026 to 2025. (Gold Ten)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16932982</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16932982</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:20:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author></item><item><title>Fed Governor Waller opposes adjusting the pace of balance sheet reduction</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;According to ChainCatcher, the FOMC statement of the Federal Reserve showed that Federal Reserve Governor Waller dissented from the interest rate decision. He supported keeping the policy rate unchanged, but was more inclined to maintain the pace of balance sheet reduction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16932927</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16932927</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:16:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>Fed dot plot: The cumulative interest rate cut will be 50 basis points in 2025, and 4 officials support no interest rate cut this year</title><description>&lt;p&gt;According to ChainCatcher&#39;s message, the Fed&#39;s dot plot shows that among the 19 officials, 4 officials believe that there should be no rate cuts in 2025 (1 in December), 4 officials believe that there should be a cumulative 25 basis point rate cut in 2025, i.e., 1 rate cut (3 in December), 9 officials believe that there should be a cumulative 50 basis point rate cut in 2025, i.e., 2 rate cuts (10 in December), 2 officials believe that there should be a cumulative 75 basis point rate cut in 2025, i.e., 3 rate cuts (3 in December), no officials believe that there should be a cumulative 100 basis point rate cut in 2025 (1 in December), and no officials believe that there should be a cumulative 125 basis point rate cut in 2025 (1 in December).&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16932551</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16932551</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:09:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item><item><title>ETH falls below 2000 USDT</title><description>Odaily Odaily News OKX market data shows that ETH fell below 2000 USDT and is now at 1999.18 USDT, a 24-hour drop of 6.51%. (This newsletter is generated by AI)</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16932573</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16932573</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:07:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ODAILY</author><category>Ethereum</category><category>Smart Contracts</category><category>Layer 1</category></item><item><title>The Federal Reserve lowered its economic growth forecasts across the board</title><description>The Federal Reserve FOMC economic outlook: the median GDP growth rate forecast for the end of 2025, 2026, and 2027 is 1.7%, 1.8%, and 1.8% respectively. (The December forecast was 2.1%, 2.0%, and 1.9% respectively).</description><link>https://followin.io/feed/16932552</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://followin.io/feed/16932552</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 18:06:00 GMT</pubDate><author>ChainCatcher</author></item></channel></rss>