<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>L&#39;Orient Today - Lebanon</title><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/section/977-lebanon</link><atom:link href="http://127.0.0.1:1200/lorientlejour/977-lebanon" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><description>L&#39;Orient Today - Lebanon - Powered by RSSHub</description><generator>RSSHub</generator><webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:38:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Army multiplies operations at the Lebanese-Syrian border with arrests and crossing closures</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Smuggled fuel, food, and weapons were seized during army operations in Hermel and northern Bekaa, as the state seeks to strengthen its miliary&#39;s presence in the area.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/Capturedecran2025-03-24a095140_929979_976109.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The border between Lebanon and Syria at Qasr, a village in Hermel, on February 13, 2025. (Credit:Matthieu Karam/L’Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;BEIRUT — The Lebanese Army closed six illegal crossing points along the Lebanese-Syrian border in Hermel district on Monday afternoon and arrested several suspected traffickers, as part of several announced operations cracking down on smuggling between the two countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to a statement published on the army&#39;s X account, authorities arrested five citizens and one Syrian national having received information about illegal smuggling operations in the Mashrouat al-Qaa area. They also seized a vehicle loaded with &quot;fuel and foodstuffs intended for smuggling.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another patrol, the statement continues, raided the homes of &quot;wanted individuals,&quot; resulting in the arrest of a man wanted for &quot;smuggling, opening illegal crossing points,&quot; and reopening those previously closed by the army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These raids and arrests come as Lebanese authorities are stressing the importance of strengthening the Lebanese Army, historically underfunded, to address issues related to the Lebanese-Syrian border, which has also seen deadly clashes between clans and new Syrian forces in the last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Army pistols and smuggled goods were also seized and then handed over to the relevant authorities. Efforts continue to arrest all of the individuals involved.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Earth embankments and bulldozers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the day, the Lebanese Army announced having closed six illegal crossing points in Hermel, at the Lebanese-Syrian border. These cross-border passages, closed by bulldozers creating earth embankments, are located in the regions of Hoch al-Sayyed Ali, Mashrouat al-Qaa, and Qabech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ministerial committee tasked with examining measures to secure the borders and combat smuggling had recommended on March 20 to &quot;strengthen the army&#39;s capacities,&quot; in army equipment and manpower, to enable it to combat the smuggling more effectively. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Participants in this ministerial meeting also requested Defense Minister Michel Menassa &quot;to continue contacts with his Syrian counterpart to address the causes of recent border clashes and prevent their recurrence,&quot; a prelude to the announcement made Monday morning by an anonymous source to AFP of a visit to Damascus by Menassa on Wednesday, the first minister in Salam&#39;s government to visit Syria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most recent upheaval at the Lebanese-Syrian border occurred on March 16, following an incident that the Lebanese side describes as an &quot;infiltration&quot; of Syrian soldiers into Lebanon, at the village of al-Qasr, while Damascus speaks of an ambush and the &quot;liquidation&quot; of Syrian soldiers &quot;by Hezbollah.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hezbollah has denied any involvement. Exchanges of gunfire involving the Lebanese Army, which also used heavy artillery, were reported in the area. The next day, March 17, a cease-fire was reached between Lebanon and Syria.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453157/arrests-and-closure-of-illegal-crossings-army-multiplies-operations-at-the-lebanese-syrian-border.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453157/arrests-and-closure-of-illegal-crossings-army-multiplies-operations-at-the-lebanese-syrian-border.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:16:39 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today</author><category>Live</category><category>Lebanon</category></item><item><title>Unknown individuals open fire on public hospital in Akkar, assault doctor</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nawaf Salam is set to chair two security meetings in Northern Lebanon on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/WhatsAppImage2025-03-24at105110_420826_910945.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;An armed man in the parking lot of the Abdallah al-Rassi Governmental Hospital in Halba on March 23, 2025. (Photo sent to L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s correspondent Michel Hallak)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;A group of individuals assaulted a doctor and opened fire on Sunday at the Abdallah al-Rassi Government Hospital in Halba (Akkar), without causing any casualties, according to information from medical staff and patients received by L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s correspondent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The assault targeted a surgeon inside the facility who refused to operate on a patient in the absence of an X-ray, insisting on adhering to medical procedures. The attackers, whose identities were still unknown, then opened fire on several floors of the hospital, including towards the operating room. The condition of the assaulted doctor remains unknown at this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Condemnation by the Health Ministry&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on this assault, the Health Ministry stated that security services intervened &quot;quickly&quot; to contain the shooting. It condemned &quot;in the strongest terms the violent attacks against a public hospital and one of its doctors.&quot; The ministry later demanded that maximum penalties be &quot;imposed on the attackers&quot; to ensure that such violations do not occur again and to reaffirm its &quot;rejection of any aggression or violation of the sanctity of hospitals and health establishments under any circumstances.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The medical, health and administrative staff of al-Habtoor Hospital in Harar (Akkar) organized a solidarity sit-in in support of their colleagues, to condemn the &quot;heinous&quot; attack on the neighboring government hospital, which constituted a &quot;direct threat to the lives of patients and the staff of the establishment.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a joint statement, the medical staff of al-Habtoor Hospital insisted on the necessity of ensuring permanent protection for hospitals so that they can fulfill their humanitarian mission without any threat or pressure. The text also recalls that hospitals must remain &quot;safe havens for patients.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2021, after a series of assaults on doctors and medical staff in different regions of Lebanon, notably linked to the socio-economic crisis, Parliament adopted a law aimed at protecting doctors. The law sentences those found guilty for up to six months in prison and a fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Nawaf Salam&#39;s tour in Northern Lebanon on Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The assault at the Abdallah al-Rassi Hospital followed another incident earlier on Sunday concerning a traffic priority issue in Mouhammara, at the southern entrance of Akkar, between groups of young men from Bebnine and Mouhammara, according to L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s correspondent who gathered statements from those present during the events. The quarrel quickly escalated into a brawl, followed by gunfire that hit a car transporting a family. Two people were injured, a woman and a child, both of whom were urgently transferred to the Abdallah al-Rassi Government Hospital. The condition of the former was deemed critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Northern Lebanon regularly witnesses clashes or violence, notably linked to new developments in Syria since the fall of the Assad regime or family disputes. In response to these tensions, the new interior minister, security forces, and local authorities have implemented yet another security plan for the city, coinciding with the start of Ramadan, but have been unable to prevent deadly shootings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Nawaf Salam is set to chair two security meetings tomorrow Tuesday, in Tripoli and Akkar, during a tour of Northern Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453150/unknown-individuals-open-fire-on-public-hospital-in-akkar-assault-doctor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453150/unknown-individuals-open-fire-on-public-hospital-in-akkar-assault-doctor.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:30:59 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Society</category><category>Live</category></item><item><title>Interior Ministry officially announces municipal election dates across Lebanon</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Voting will kick off on May 4 in Mount Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/AMUNIC_194588_533616_123093_452561_748690_985764.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Lebanese security forces monitoring the conduct of the municipal elections in Beirut, on May 8, 2016. (Credit: Anwar Amro/AFP)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;The Lebanese Interior Ministry officially set on Monday the dates for municipal elections across Lebanon, which will take place every Sunday in May in different regions of the country. These elections have been postponed since 2022 by Parliament due to the socio-economic crisis and later, in 2024, due to the war in the south.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The elections will be held as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- On May 4 in Mount Lebanon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- On May 11 in North Lebanon and Akkar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- On May 18 in Beirut, the Bekaa Valley, and Baalbeck-Hermel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- And on May 25 in South Lebanon and Nabatieh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interior Minister Ahmad Hajjar stated at the beginning of March that he intends to organize municipal elections in southern Lebanon, despite the massive destruction it has suffered due to Israeli strikes in the region. Despite the cease-fire between Israel and Hezbollah, Israel continues to conduct raids in the South and the Bekaa against alleged members of Hezbollah.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several political parties have started preparations for this deadline and announced various alliances based on the regions. The Amal Movement, in particular, announced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lorientlejour.com/article/1449886/listes-communes-amal-hezbollah-aux-municipales.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;its alliance&lt;/a&gt; with Hezbollah, across all regions, for this election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last municipal elections in Lebanon took place in 2016, and councils were elected for six years. A significant number of municipal councils have since resigned or are unable to carry out their duties effectively due to a lack of financial and human resources.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453141/interior-ministry-officially-announces-municipal-election-dates-across-lebanon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453141/interior-ministry-officially-announces-municipal-election-dates-across-lebanon.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 11:41:56 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today</author><category>Live</category><category>Lebanon</category></item><item><title>Lebanon led ‘intensive’ contacts to prevent strikes on Beirut during Saturday escalation</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Joseph Aoun and Nawaf Salam &quot;conducted diplomatic contacts with France and the United States, as well as the U.N. to achieve de-escalation,&quot; according to a Lebanese official.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/WhatsAppImage2025-03-23at1632401_985672_952581.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Pedestrians observing the damage caused by a deadly Israeli strike on a building in Sour, south Lebanon, on March 23, 2025. (Credit: Matthieu Karam/L&#39;Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;BEIRUT — Lebanese officials engaged in intensive discussion with the U.S. and France to prevent Israel from bombing Beirut amid its heavy strikes against southern Lebanon over the weekend, a Lebanese official who requested anonymity told AFP on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Israeli air force bombed dozens of sites across southern Lebanon on Saturday, killing eight people, in retaliation to rocket fire targeting its territory for the first time since a cease-fire began on Nov. 27, except for a rocket fired toward the disputed Shebaa Farms and a reconnaissance drone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz said Saturday, following these attacks on Metula in northern Israel, but intercepted by anti-aircraft defense, that &quot;the fate of Metula is the same as that of Beirut.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the full-scale war, which took place from Sept. 23 and Nov. 27, 2024, the southern suburbs of Beirut were targeted almost daily, while other neighborhoods in the capital were also targeted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;France and the United States&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the threats from the Israeli minister, Lebanese President Joseph Aoun and Prime Minister Nawaf Salam &quot;conducted diplomatic contacts with France and the United States, sponsors of the truce agreement, as well as with the U.N. to achieve de-escalation after Israeli threats to target Beirut,&quot; the official said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prime minister &quot;emphasized the need to ensure security and prevent the recurrence of rocket fire&quot; against Israel, he added. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The state-run National New Agency reported that Salam told reporters that the Lebanese government had only made contacts to &quot;follow up on the issue&quot; and that he hoped they would be &quot;more active&quot; moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;There have been some remarks on the positions expressed by the foreign minister in the media regarding the latest developments at the border. Colleagues have also commented on these statements, and we will continue the discussion with the Minister of Foreign Affairs,&quot; Salam said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No one claimed responsibility for the rocket fire, which, according to a military source, was launched from a region north of the Litani River, between the villages of Kfar Tebnit and Arnoun, adjacent to the area covered by the cease-fire agreement. The truce came into effect on Nov. 27, ending a deadly war between Israel and Hezbollah in which the Israeli air force killed close to 4,000 people in Lebanon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cease-fire agreement stipulated that only the Lebanese Army and U.N. peacekeepers were to be deployed south of the Litani River and that Hezbollah dismantle its infrastructure and withdraw north of the river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The party firmly denied &quot;any involvement&quot; in the rocket fire. The Lebanese Army later announced that it dismantled &quot;three improvised rocket launchers&quot; in the area, about six kilometers from the border with Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The military source told AFP that the army &quot;arrested two Syrians who worked as guards at a nearby farm near the rocket launch site.&quot; These witnesses &quot;claimed to have seen a car from which several men emerged to set up the launchers and fire the rockets before leaving.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Ortagus points the finger at Lebanese Army&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The war has greatly weakened Hezbollah, which continues to be targeted by Israeli strikes despite the truce agreement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. envoy Morgan Ortagus, who is expected in Beirut soon, appeared to be taking a critical stance against the Lebanese Army, to which Washington is a strategic partner and which the U.S. provides substantial support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responding to a reporter&#39;s question about Israeli violations in southern Lebanon, the envoy was quoted by the Lebanese website Asas as saying: &quot;This question is wrong. The real question is, &#39;Why does the Lebanese Army continue to allow rockets to be launched from Lebanese territory? And what can it do to enforce the cease-fire and disarm Hezbollah in the South?&#39;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EU Foreign Minister Kaja Kallas called for restraint during her visit to Israel, arguing that the strikes on Lebanon and Syria risk leading to &quot;further escalation&quot; in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French in L&#39;Orient-Le Jour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453136/lebanon-led-intensive-contacts-to-prevent-strikes-on-beirut-during-saturday-escalation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453136/lebanon-led-intensive-contacts-to-prevent-strikes-on-beirut-during-saturday-escalation.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 11:25:47 GMT</pubDate><category>Politics</category><category>Live</category></item><item><title>After breaking apart, Michel Moawad’s bloc towards a ‘renewal’?</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The bloc presented a unique model in Parliament but collapsed under the weight of internal disagreements. But the Zgharta MP still believes in it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/ScreenShot2025-03-24at21837PM_614779.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;From left to right: Achraf Rifi, Michel Moawad, Fouad Makhzoumi and Adib Abdel Massih, members of the Renewal bloc, May 28, 2023. (Credit: The group&#39;s X account)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     Michel Moawad does not give up. After his parliamentary bloc (the Renewal bloc) crumbled due to internal disagreements, the former presidential candidate is working to piece it back together.When it was formed, following the 2022 legislative... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453135/after-breaking-apart-michel-moawads-bloc-towards-a-renewal.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453135/after-breaking-apart-michel-moawads-bloc-towards-a-renewal.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 11:21:33 GMT</pubDate><author>Yara ABI AKL</author><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Lebanese Forces say Hezbollah should thank those seeking to protect Lebanon from war</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/Capturedecran2025-03-24a113003AM_252664_259087.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The leader of the Lebanese Forces (LF), Samir Geagea in Meerab in 2022. (Credit: Joseph EID / AFP)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;The Lebanese Forces (LF) asserted Monday that Lebanon&#39;s stability can only be achieved through the &quot;total respect of international resolutions,&quot; stating that Hezbollah should &quot;thank&quot; officials who want to protect Lebanon from another war. This statement come amid a backdrop of mutual accusations between the two political factions. While Samir Geagea&#39;s LF fiercely criticize Hezbollah&#39;s stance regarding its arsenal, as well as its justification for opening a so-called &quot;support front&quot; to Gaza, Hezbollah for its part believes that LF officials and Foreign Minister Joe Raggi are playing into Israel&#39;s hands with their criticism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Those calling for the implementation of international resolutions and a cease-fire, notably Prime Minister Nawaf Salam and the foreign minister&quot; — appointed by the LF party — are acting, according to the party&#39;s statement, &quot;in the interest of Lebanon and its people, to protect them from the dangers of a new military escalation.&quot; &quot;These voices are however confronted with vilification campaigns, in an attempt to silence those who advocate for strengthening the country&#39;s sovereignty,&quot; the statement adds. Therefore, Hezbollah should &quot;thank these &#39;patriotic&#39; voices who seek to protect Lebanon from the dangers of war.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Monopoly on arms, Resolution 1701&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LF also once again pleaded for &quot;the respect of international resolutions, the strengthening of the Lebanese state&#39;s role in extending its sovereignty over the entire territory, and the monopoly on arms, so that the state is the only entity responsible for the decision of war, while taking charge of the security and the future of the Lebanese people.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concerning the U.N. Security Council&#39;s Resolution 1701, adopted in 2006, Samir Geagea&#39;s party stated that &quot;had it been fully implemented, the so-called support war would not have taken place,&quot; while adding that should it not be respected &quot;tensions and instability on the southern border will turn Lebanon into a battlefield.&quot; This resolution was concluded between Israel and Lebanon after the war in July 2006, granting explicit authority to the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL) and the Lebanese army along the Blue Line separating Lebanon and Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This new LF stance came two days after the firing of three rockets from south Lebanon towards the Israeli town of Metula, immediately intercepted by the Israeli defense system. In retaliation, Israel bombed several dozen targets in South Lebanon and the Bekaa, killing eight people and injuring several others. Although Israeli violations occur daily, Saturday&#39;s episode is among the most violent and deadly since the November 2024 cease-fire, which ended the war between Hezbollah and Israel. &lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453118/lebanese-forces-say-hezbollah-should-thank-those-seeking-to-protect-lebanon-from-war.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453118/lebanese-forces-say-hezbollah-should-thank-those-seeking-to-protect-lebanon-from-war.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 10:11:20 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today</author><category>Live</category><category>Lebanon</category></item><item><title>Agriculture Minister declares state of emergency for forest conservation</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nizar Hani announced, among other measures, a freeze on pruning and charcoal production permits for 2025.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/arbres_750974_955358.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Trees cut down in one of the Qamouaa forests in Akkar, in August 2024. (Credit: Photo provided by a witness)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;Lebanese Agriculture Minister Nizar Hani declared a state of emergency on Sunday for the conservation of Lebanon&#39;s forests, &quot;threatened by climate change, repeated fires, illegal and massive tree felling, destruction resulting from the Israeli war in south Lebanon and North Bekaa, as well as concrete encroachments and urban chaos.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hani spoke during an event organized on the International Day of Forests (which falls on March 21) by the agricultural center of Deir al-Qamar (Chouf), in the village&#39;s public library. &quot;Despite all efforts by the Agriculture Ministry in cooperation with other administrations, challenges are increasing, and stricter measures are indispensable,&quot; he declared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the measures recently taken, the minister mentioned cooperation with the Defense Ministry to deploy law enforcement forces in areas experiencing massive tree felling. He also stated that he was coordinating with the Justice Ministry to ask judges to expedite the issuance of deterrent judgments against violators. He lastly recommended strengthening field surveillance in cooperation with the Interior Ministry, by creating a central chamber to control violations, in coordination with forest protection centers and forest rangers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for decisions made within his administration, Hani announced a freeze on pruning permits for the year 2025 starting April 1, a freeze on granting and renewing charcoal production permits starting June 1, intensifying patrols and reports against violators in coordination with the army and law enforcement, reviewing agricultural land improvement permits to ensure their compliance with sustainable agriculture criteria, and a freeze on construction in forest areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Violators often use pruning or charcoal production permits as a pretext to simply cut down trees in forest areas, including species threatened or protected by law, such as conifers. These destructive practices have been common in Lebanon for decades and have never been effectively regulated by the authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This concept of forest sustainability will be at the center of the Ministry&#39;s policies, assured Nizar Hani, former director of the Chouf Reserve. He advocated for the concept of sustainable agriculture in forest areas, to improve the relationships between local communities and forests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The slogan of this year&#39;s International Day of Forests is that of forests and food, due to the pivotal role of the forest environment in global food security, as five billion people in the world rely on the forests for food, directly or indirectly,&quot; he concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was translated from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lorientlejour.com/article/1453017/le-ministre-de-lagriculture-decrete-letat-durgence-pour-la-sauvegarde-des-forets.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;L&#39;Orient-Le Jour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453110/agriculture-minister-declares-state-of-emergency-for-forest-conservation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453110/agriculture-minister-declares-state-of-emergency-for-forest-conservation.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:49:20 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>Defense Minister Michel Menassa to visit Damascus on Wednesday</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;This marks the first Lebanese official to visit Syria since the Lebanese government was formed in February.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/WhatsAppImage2025-02-16at171806_123627_ed474724322deb8d8f28eabe238b2ff5_613133_649592_941891.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;View of Syria from a house in Qanafez in Hermel, Feb. 13, 2025. (Credit: Matthieu Karam/L’Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;Defense Minister Michel Menassa will travel to Damascus on Wednesday to discuss recent tensions at the border between the two countries, a Lebanese official who requested anonymity told AFP on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The defense minister will lead a security delegation to Damascus to meet with his counterpart Mourhaf Abou Qasra,” the source specified. This is the first Lebanese official to visit Syria since a government was formed in Lebanon in February, while a coalition led by Islamists took power in Damascus in December.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The visit aims to “discuss ways to control the border situation, enhance bilateral coordination, and prevent aggressions from both sides,” the same source added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the visit, Menassa received newly appointed Lebanese Army Commander-in-Chief General Rodolphe Haykal in his office in Yarzeh to&amp;nbsp;discuss the missions carried out by the army to maintain security and stability in all Lebanese regions, particularly on the southern and northeastern borders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mid-March, clashes erupted in the border area between the two countries, in eastern Lebanon, resulting in ten deaths. Damascus accused Hezbollah, a former ally of ousted President Bashar al-Assad, of kidnapping three Syrian soldiers and killing them, which the party denied. Seven Lebanese were later killed in shelling from Syria, according to authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Lebanese security source told AFP that Syrian forces bombed the border area in Lebanon after the three Syrian soldiers were killed by armed Lebanese involved in smuggling. The two countries later announced they had reached a cease-fire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lebanon shares a 330-kilometer border with Syria with no official demarcation in several areas, making it porous and conducive to smuggling. The new Syrian authorities announced at the beginning of February the launch of a security operation in the Homs border region to “close smuggling routes for arms and goods.” Hezbollah, which fought alongside Assad&#39;s troops during the conflict in Syria, exerted its influence over large portions of the Lebanese-Syrian border. It has been weakened by the recent war with Israel.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453111/defense-minister-michel-menassa-to-visit-damascus-on-wednesday.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453111/defense-minister-michel-menassa-to-visit-damascus-on-wednesday.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:33:27 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Politics</category><category>Live</category></item><item><title>Lebanese army closes six illegal crossing points with Syria</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/Capturedecran2025-03-24a095140_929979_605036.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The border between Lebanon and Syria at Qasr, a village in Hermel, on February 13, 2025. (Credit: Matthieu Karam/L&#39;Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;The Lebanese army closed six illegal crossing points in Hermel, along the Lebanese Syrian border, in order to combat smuggling and infiltration, the troops announced on their X account. These cross-border passages, closed by bulldozers are located in the regions of Hoch al-Sayyed Ali, Mashrouat al-Qaa, and Qabech. This region has seen tensions from February until mid-March, involving Lebanese &#39;groups&#39; alleged to be close to Hezbollah and the new Syrian authorities. A few days ago, the Lebanese army also claimed to have closed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lorientlejour.com/article/1452630/larmee-libanaise-ferme-trois-passages-illegaux-a-la-frontiere-avec-la-syrie.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;three illegal crossing points&lt;/a&gt; in the Qaa region, as well as in the Mashrafeh and Doura - Hermel areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most recent clashes erupted on Sunday, March 16, following an incident that the Lebanese side described as an &quot;infiltration&quot; of Syrian soldiers into Lebanon at the village of al-Qasr, while Damascus refers to it as an ambush and the &quot;liquidation&quot; of Syrian soldiers &quot;by Hezbollah.&quot; The party denied any involvement. Exchanges of gunfire involving the Lebanese army, which also used heavy artillery, were reported in the region. The following day, a cease-fire was reached between Lebanon and Syria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ministerial commission tasked with considering measures to secure borders and combat smuggling &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lorientlejour.com/article/1452571/la-commission-ministerielle-des-frontieres-recommande-de-renforcer-les-capacites-de-larmee.html&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;recommended&lt;/a&gt; last Thursday to &quot;strengthen the army&#39;s capabilities in equipment and manpower to enable it to fight smuggling more effectively and apprehend smugglers.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453108/lebanese-army-closes-six-illegal-crossing-points-with-syria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453108/lebanese-army-closes-six-illegal-crossing-points-with-syria.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:20:39 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today</author><category>Live</category><category>Lebanon</category></item><item><title>Who is behind the rocket fire toward Israel?</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;While Hezbollah denied involvement in this incident, differences within the party cast doubt.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/ScreenShot2025-03-24at105241AM_689379.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;A cloud of smoke after an Israeli bombardment in Touline, southern Lebanon, March 22, 2025. (Credit: Rabih Daher/AFP)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     The situation nearly escalated. On Saturday morning, three rockets fired from southern Lebanon were intercepted over the town of Metula in northern Israel, jeopardizing the status quo that the cease-fire agreement, which ended the Israel-Hezbollah... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453088/who-is-behind-the-rocket-fire-toward-israel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453088/who-is-behind-the-rocket-fire-toward-israel.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 07:55:11 GMT</pubDate><author>Salah HIJAZI</author><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>‘I used to think the resistance was protecting us&#39;</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;After the deadly Israeli strike in the heart of Sour, the population is distraught. Some blame Israel, some the Lebanese state, but others also criticize Hezbollah.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/L1001260_549170_359686.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;A building damaged by Israeli aviation in the center of Sour on March 23, 2025, the day after the attack. (Credit: Matthieu Karam/L&#39;Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     In the gutted living room of a building in central Sour, velvet red sofas clung dangerously close to the void. Standing on the debris of his neighbor&#39;s apartment, Ahmad* still hasn&#39;t processed what happened to him the previous day. &quot;I... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453073/i-used-to-think-the-resistance-was-protecting-us.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453073/i-used-to-think-the-resistance-was-protecting-us.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 06:42:29 GMT</pubDate><author>Lyana ALAMEDDINE</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>Israel launches punishing air campaign following rocket fire from south Lebanon: Everything you need to know this Monday</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here is what happened over the weekend and what to expect today, Monday, March 24.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/37JQ3VZ-highres-min_222704.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;This picture shows the damage caused to a building following an Israeli strike that targeted a neighborhood in the southern Lebanese city of Sour on March 22, 2025. (Credit: Kawnat Haju/AFP)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     Want to get the Morning Brief by email? Click here to sign up.Catch up on yesterday&#39;s live coverage.Monday, March 24, 2025Compiled by Abbas Mahfouz.Some key things to watch today:Developments in Gaza amid the renewed Israeli offensive.The... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453043/israel-launches-punishing-air-campaign-following-rocket-fire-from-south-lebanon-everything-you-need-to-know-this-monday.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453043/israel-launches-punishing-air-campaign-following-rocket-fire-from-south-lebanon-everything-you-need-to-know-this-monday.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 06:09:15 GMT</pubDate><author>Abbas Mahfouz</author><category>Morning Brief</category></item><item><title>Tension eases in southern Lebanon after Israeli escalation Saturday</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Foreign Minister Joe Rajji stated that diplomatic contacts were made to exert pressure on Israel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/WhatsAppImage2025-03-23at43208PM1_139078_833063.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The location targeted by an Israeli strike on Saturday in central Sour, March 23, 2025. (Credit: Matthieu Karam/L&#39;Orient Today)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;After a day that raised fears for the cease-fire between Israel and Hezbollah, in effect since Nov. 27, tension in southern Lebanon eased Sunday, despite a few new incidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most severe incident occurred in the morning. An Israeli drone targeted a car in Aita al-Shaab (Bint Jbeil) killing its occupant, Hassan Nehmeh al-Zein, according to L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s correspondent in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man owned a café that was targeted by artillery fire overnight. According to locals, he went to inspect the damage Sunday morning when a drone pursued him before firing a missile at his vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was still unclear whether this man was a civilian or a combatant. However, the Israeli army claimed responsibility for the strike in the afternoon, stating that they had killed a member of Hezbollah. He is the ninth person killed by the numerous Israeli strikes conducted since Saturday in response to rockets fired from Lebanon, according to Israel, intercepted before reaching Metula. No group claimed responsibility for these attacks and Hezbollah firmly denied any involvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israel responded Saturday to these attacks with two successive waves of strikes in the early afternoon and evening, which killed eight and injured several others. A Hezbollah member, Radwan Salim Awada, was killed in Qlayleh (Sour). Five other people, including a Syrian and his daughter, were killed in Touline (Marjayoun) and two other civilians in Sour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Statement from the Lebanese army&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two victims of this strike, which partially destroyed a building Saturday night, were a 61-year-old man named Safi and a 37-year-old mother of two, Rania Abbas Houmani, L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s journalists on the scene reported. One of Houmani&#39;s daughters, aged 12, was also injured by the strike, according to relatives of the victim, who stated their commitment to Hezbollah&#39;s &quot;resistance.&quot; The funeral for the mother was to be held on Sunday. Safi&#39;s is scheduled for a later date, pending the arrival of his two children living in Abidjan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Association of Traders in Sour announced Sunday afternoon the cancellation of the market opening ceremony &quot;following the brutal aggression of the city.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lebanese army, deployed in southern Lebanon, issued a statement saying that &quot;the Israeli enemy has increased the frequency of its attacks against Lebanon since [Saturday] under various pretexts, conducting dozens of raids to the south and north of the Litani, up to the Bekaa, which have caused deaths and injuries and significant property damage.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The army statement also denounced &quot;the encroachment of Israeli bulldozers into Lebanese territory this morning (Sunday) to clear entire areas in Wadi Qatmoun, near Rmaish (Bint Jbeil), not to mention a deployment of enemy soldiers in this area, blatantly violating United Nations Resolution 1701.&quot; The army mentioned in its statement the strengthening its presence in the concerned area and conducting patrols with the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL) to document the Israeli violations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, President Joseph Aoun, and the prime minister, Nawaf Salam, both reacted to the Israeli strikes. The former warned against a return to the &quot;spiral of violence,&quot; while the latter emphasized the need for the Lebanese state to be the sole decision-maker regarding &quot;war and peace.&quot; Foreign Minister Joe Rajji stated he made diplomatic contacts to pressure Israel to calm tensions at the Lebanese-Israeli border. He notably contacted the Secretary General of the Arab League, Ahmed Aboul Gheit, and the European foreign affairs chief, Kaja Kallas, who is visiting Israel on Monday to advocate for the restoration of the cease-fire in Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Statements from Geagea and Fadlallah&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, the Lebanese Forces leader, Samir Geagea, said that the rocket fire from Lebanon towards Israel on Saturday was sufficient to &quot;reshuffle the cards.&quot; Hezbollah MP Hassan Fadlallah stated that Israel was exploiting &quot;the weakness of the [Lebanese] state, its limited means, and its lack of courage,&quot; as well as &quot;some internal Lebanese voices that ... promote the Israeli war against Lebanon, considering it an opportunity to get rid of the &#39;resistance.&#39;&#39;&#39;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, an Israeli drone fired at a prefabricated house in Naqoura (Sour), then at three houses in Shihine (Sour), early in the morning, without causing supposed victims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israeli drones and planes flew over Beirut and Saida, as well as the south in the districts of Marjayoun and Hasbaya. Planes also flew over the Bekaa, according to L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s correspondent in this region. In the afternoon, a man was injured by a bomb dropped by an Israeli drone on a bulldozer near him in the village of Yaroun (Bint Jbeil). The bulldozer was used to clear debris from houses destroyed by the war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French in L&#39;Orient-Le Jour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453026/tension-eases-in-southern-lebanon-after-israeli-escalation-saturday.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453026/tension-eases-in-southern-lebanon-after-israeli-escalation-saturday.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:50:24 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Politics</category><category>Live</category></item><item><title>Emotional funeral for L&#39;Orient-Le Jour&#39;s correspondent Hoda Chedid</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;A crowd of journalists and political and social personalities joined the journalist&#39;s family for a final farewell at St. George Cathedral in downtown Beirut.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/WhatsAppImage2025-03-23at32027PM1_952686_990007.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The funeral of L&#39;Orient-Le Jour correspondent Hoda Chedid took place at Saint George&#39;s Cathedral in downtown Beirut. (Credit: Chady Souaid)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/Hoda_945246_730229.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hoda Chedid at Baabda Palace where she was a correspondent for about 30 years. (Photo taken from her Facebook page)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;For the final farewell to journalist Hoda Chedid, who was part of the LBCI family as well as a correspondent for L’Orient-Le Jour for many years, a crowd of colleagues and political and social figures joined her friends and family on Sunday, notably her father, her two brothers, and her six sisters, to mourn her passing and celebrate her life and long career. The funeral took place at St. George Cathedral in downtown Beirut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The funeral mass was given by Maronite Archbishop of Beirut Boulos Abdel Sater, representing Maronite Patriarch Béchara Raï, before the burial in Hoda Chedid&#39;s native village, Kefraya, in the Zghorta district (North Lebanon). Information Minister Paul Morcos represented President of the Republic Joseph Aoun, Speaker of Parliament Nabih Berry, and Prime Minister Nawaf Salam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LBCI broadcast emotional testimonials from individuals attending the church to offer condolences to the family, all emphasizing the professionalism, kindness, humility and unifying nature of the late journalist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chedid was first diagnosed with cancer in 2014, a challenge she overcame after several chemotherapy sessions, before experiencing a period of remission. However, in recent years, she had to face this illness again. Born in 1965, Hoda married Ziad Saadeh at the age of 22, who died a few months later from cancer. She then embarked on a long journalism career that spanned three decades. She served as a correspondent at the presidential palace in Baabda, as well as an exceptional field journalist covering all significant events throughout these years. President Joseph Aoun paid a heartfelt tribute to her just two weeks ago at Baabda Palace, in the presence of her relatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A culture of peace&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The speech by Maronite Patriarch Bechara al-Rai was read during the ceremony, summarizing the journalist&#39;s journey from her birth and childhood in the Zghorta district, to her brief marriage and widowhood, then her career that made her a respected face in Lebanese media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her brother Tony Chedid spoke on behalf of the family. He emphasized his sister&#39;s unifying nature, who was surrounded by people from different communities and regions of the country, all of whom had a steadfast friendship with her. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I see the love you had for Hoda, and which will continue with you,&quot; he said. He paid tribute to his sisters and father, thanking the CEO of LBCI, Pierre Daher, for all his support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I am sure that the culture of peace dear to Hoda will ultimately triumph, which is why the love she sowed today drowns out the noises of war, because Lebanon desires nothing but peace,&quot; he declared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daher, visibly moved, also spoke. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hoda is no longer among us, but the example she set for people in the profession remains, and we will often say follow the example of Hoda Chedid,&quot; he said. He paid tribute to her sense of precision, the sense of responsibility that characterized &quot;Hoda the exceptional,&quot; and her professionalism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French in L&#39;Orient-Le Jour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453011/emotional-funeral-for-lorient-le-jours-correspondent-hoda-chedid.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453011/emotional-funeral-for-lorient-le-jours-correspondent-hoda-chedid.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 13:08:24 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>I didn&#39;t have time to say goodbye...</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1454/FB_IMG_1742673346469_196207_440331.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hoda Chedid and her unforgettable smile. (Facebook photo)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;It is no coincidence you left for Mother&#39;s Day... God wanted you to celebrate this day with your own mother and find rest in her arms. Now every March 21, I will inevitably think of you first, of the mother you were to all those who held you dear. A mother who wrapped us all in her love, smiled at us despite her pain and offered us her tenderness and affection every time we knocked at her door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I called you almost every day to check on you and give you strength, yet it was I who ended up drawing it from you. &quot;We, the girls from the North, we are fighters,&quot; you always told me. &quot;You’re so much like me, Ratrout: You always think of others first, you give your all to your job, you often get carried away by emotion, stress, or sorrow... But all that made me sick, don’t be like me.&quot; I don’t really know if or to what extent I resemble you. But what is certain is that you have always been a role model to me. In this profession, where you established yourself as an exceptional figure, everyone&#39;s friend yet you never lost your objectivity, the brave reporter who ran towards danger instead of fleeing it, the trusted correspondent whom the scoop found, the moderator who lit up the screen with each appearance... always beautiful (whether with your hair square, a wig, or a scarf), always elegant, always smiling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But especially in life. This life that was not kind to you, but which you faced with courage. And above all, with dignity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will never forget the last time I saw you. You hugged me tightly. And as usual, you emptied your fridge to set the table. &quot;You surely haven’t eaten anything! I have moujaddara. I also have stuffed zucchini. And Moni’s pickles, as spicy as you like them.&quot; That day, I had already eaten, but I lied to you: I had learned from your sister that you hadn’t eaten anything all day, and I told you I couldn’t eat unless you joined me. And there we were, the two of us, forcing our appetites so the other could eat as well... Without saying a word. Until you suddenly said, &quot;I’m tired ya Ratrout... I no longer have the desire or strength to fight.&quot; How could I answer you? I didn’t know. I first opted for &quot;Do you have olives?&quot; You smiled. &quot;I’m not afraid to leave, I’m afraid of making you sad.&quot; I then told you, looking you in the eye: &quot;You have to fight for us. There are many of us who love you and don’t want to let you go. Yes, we might be selfish, but you never have been...&quot; You sighed, then offered me dessert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That day, maybe you knew it was the last time you’d see me. &quot;What can I leave you of myself?&quot; you asked me, your eyes bright. &quot;Stop talking like that!&quot; I replied. But you didn&#39;t listen. You opened your bag and pulled out a relic of Saint Charbel. &quot;It’s my most precious possession. Keep it in your wallet always.&quot; The relic is in my wallet, and you, you will stay in my heart, my Hoda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forgive me. On Monday, you told me and insisted: &quot;Come see me before or after work, I miss you.&quot; But my week was busy. I was overwhelmed by the news and this profession to which we both gave everything. And I kept saying, &quot;Tomorrow, for sure.&quot; I planned to come on Saturday, you know? It was my day off and I could stay without checking my watch every two minutes... But I didn’t have time... Why didn’t you wait for me? Why didn’t I understand? Even leaving this world, you taught me a lesson at my own expense: to no longer postpone anything until tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sad that you left. On the contrary. Now, you are with Ziad, the man of your life whom you chose to marry against all odds, the illness, the will of your parents... to become a widow five months later. With your mother, whom you missed terribly. &quot;I regret greatly the worry I caused her and the years I spent away from her,&quot; you told me. And with Charbel, whom you regularly visited in Annaya to find peace. You are in a place that resembles you. A place of serenity, of purity... where you no longer have to fight against anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sad because I’m left in a world that has become much uglier and colder... without you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love you, Hodhod.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453004/i-didnt-have-time-to-say-goodbye.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453004/i-didnt-have-time-to-say-goodbye.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 11:43:06 GMT</pubDate><author>Rita SASSINE</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>Ranked 145th out of 147 in a global report, Lebanon is one of the most unhappy countries in the world</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the World Happiness Report 2025, Finland lead the ranking while Afghanistan was at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/WhatsAppImage2024-11-29at181221_135330_8f034c41220214e1023c324da842038b_681243_426a5d970fa2078cea597c660bcefd76_278519_937922.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;A family walks down a street in Sour, amidst destroyed buildings, on Nov. 29, 2024. (Credit: Mohammad Yassin/ L&#39;Orient Today)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;Before Sierra Leone and Afghanistan, Lebanon is one of the most unhappy countries in the world, ranked 145 out of 147 countries in the new World Happiness Report for 2025, released on March 21. Malawi and Bangladesh were ranked higher than Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, Lebanon was in second to last place in the rankings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year, among the Arab countries at the bottom of the ranking, Yemen was ranked 140, Egypt 135, Jordan 128, Palestine 108 and Iraq 101. Better ranked are Oman at 52, Saudi Arabia at 32 and the United Arab Emirates at 21, the highest ranking among Arab countries. Syria was not included in this year&#39;s report. Israel was 8 globally, Iran 99 and Turkey 94.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Globally, Finland remained at the top, followed by Denmark, Iceland and Sweden; these four countries have been ranked in this order in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The World Happiness Report has been regularly published since 2012 by the Sustainable Development Solutions Network, to highlight happiness as a criterion for ranking countries. According to its authors, it is based on statistics from the Gallup World Poll, which surveys a representative sample of a thousand people in each country over a three-year period – for the 2025 version, the years 2022, 2023, and 2024 were considered. It primarily relies on the perception of happiness expressed by the inhabitants of the countries, what its authors call &quot;life evaluations.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gallup Poll asked respondents a question based on the image of a ladder, asking them to evaluate their life from 0 to 10. Questions were then asked about positive emotions, such as laughter, amusement and interest, and negative emotions, such as worry, sadness and anger. The report noteed that decisions made at the national or governmental level in a country impacted the well-being of its population, particularly when they reinforce or destroy feelings of security and peace. Life evaluations were particularly low in countries affected by violence, like in Afghanistan or Lebanon, which was at war with Israel throughout 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For each country, seven variable factors are used to explain the degree of happiness expressed by the people: GDP (gross domestic product) per capita, social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make life choices, generosity, the perception of corruption in the state, as well as positive and negative effects. The report also included a table of countries hosting the most refugees on their territory. The potential positive effects associated with providing a haven to refugees are negated by the additional pressure that reflects on a local population often already lacking basic means of subsistence. In this ranking, Lebanon is 1, hosting 818,861 refugees, which is 14.9 percent of its population, ahead of Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French in L&#39;Orient-Le Jour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453000/ranked-145th-out-of-147-in-a-global-report-lebanon-is-one-of-the-most-unhappy-countries-in-the-world.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1453000/ranked-145th-out-of-147-in-a-global-report-lebanon-is-one-of-the-most-unhappy-countries-in-the-world.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 11:05:36 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>Geagea: Rockets launched from Lebanon dangerously reshuffle the cards</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The leader of the Lebanese Forces (LF) wondered why this dangerous development occurred, while &quot;the state remains absent&quot; and efforts continue for its construction.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/Geagea_674462_335656.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The leader of the Lebanese Forces, Samir Geagea. (Credit: National News Agency)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;The head of the Lebanese Forces (LF) Samir Geagea commented on Sunday on the rocket launch from Lebanon towards Israel on Saturday, considering that the incident is enough to &quot;reshuffle the cards.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;New rockets were launched from Lebanon, whether one, two, or three, it is enough to reshuffle the cards again and cause even more human and material losses while the state remains absent,&quot; he stated in Maarab on the occasion of Mother&#39;s Day, during a celebration held in honor of the mothers of fallen LF members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning, three rockets were fired from southern Lebanon toward the Israeli town of Metoula, immediately intercepted by the Israeli defense system. In retaliation, Israel bombed at least six villages in the South and 18 sites in this region and the Bekaa, killing and injuring several people. Although Israeli violations are daily occurrences, Saturday&#39;s events are the most serious since the cease-fire of November 2024, which ended the war between Hezbollah and Israel. Hezbollah, for its part, denied any involvement in the incident, and the Lebanese Army found wooden platforms used for launching the rockets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Lebanon should have turned the page of disasters, and we are in a new phase, which is the hope of coming out of the situation we are in,&quot; Geagea continued. He added, &quot;We have campaigned in recent years for the building of an effective state in Lebanon, and we succeeded in our bet with the election of Joseph Aoun as President of the Republic, the appointment of Nawaf Salam as head of the Parliament, and by forming the government.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In crisis since 2019, Lebanon experienced an extremely dangerous period, exacerbated by the outbreak of clashes between Hezbollah and Israel, which began on Oct. 8, 2023, the day after the Gaza war began. These clashes escalated into a near-total war last September, before a cease-fire was agreed upon and took effect on Nov. 27, under the aegis of the United States and France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, this cease-fire has been marked by numerous incidents, strikes and violations, notably Israeli ones. The Israeli military refused to withdraw from five strategic sites, as it was supposed to by Feb. 18, and Hezbollah has not yet disarmed. The World Bank estimated $11 billion in financing necessary to rebuild the country.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452992/geagea-rockets-launched-from-lebanon-dangerously-reshuffle-the-cards.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452992/geagea-rockets-launched-from-lebanon-dangerously-reshuffle-the-cards.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 10:14:33 GMT</pubDate><category>Live</category><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Controversial construction project in Sour: Underwater archaeological treasures at risk</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Committee for the Preservation of Sour denounced the considerable damage that edificed on vast lands adjacent to the city&#39;s marine reserve could inflict on sites yet to be excavated.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/PHOTO-2025-03-14-17-44-25_238902_360360.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Construction is already rising in this region, which is very sensitive both ecologically and culturally. (Photo sent by the Committee for the Safeguarding of Sour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     For several weeks now, work on land in Sour, including one adjacent to the marine nature reserve, sparked an outcry among many activists who fear for the coastal site, whose buffer zone is already being impacted by excavation. However, the Committee... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452988/controversial-construction-project-in-sour-underwater-archaeological-treasures-at-risk.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452988/controversial-construction-project-in-sour-underwater-archaeological-treasures-at-risk.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 09:45:09 GMT</pubDate><author>Suzanne BAAKLINI</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>Have Syrians living in the southern suburbs of Beirut been ordered to leave?</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;L&#39;Orient-Le Jour contacted several local and municipal officials in the southern suburbs of Beirut to verify the reliability of these warnings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/WhatsAppImage2024-11-27at62949PM_999055_4b260a21d945f0a351160a4e09be8090_688534_170734.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;A woman walks in the rain on the first day of the cease-fire, in the southern suburbs of Beirut, on Nov. 27, 2024. (Credit: Mohammad Yassin/L&#39;Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &quot;It is strictly forbidden for any Syrian to remain in Chiyeh and the southern suburbs of Beirut from Sunday, March 23.&quot; This warning, which circulated Thursday night on several groups online reporting local news in Lebanon and signed... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452983/have-syrians-living-in-the-southern-suburbs-of-beirut-been-ordered-to-leave.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452983/have-syrians-living-in-the-southern-suburbs-of-beirut-been-ordered-to-leave.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 09:26:53 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>&#39;The page on Hezbollah&#39;s arms has been turned,&#39; says Salam</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Jaafarite mufti, Sheikh Ahmad Qabalan, responded to the prime minister&#39;s remarks by stating that &quot;erasing the resistance would mean erasing Lebanon and its sovereignty.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/nawaf_992755_204172.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Prime Minister Nawaf Salam in Baabda on Jan. 29, 2025. (Photo taken from the Lebanese President&#39;s X account)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;Lebanese Prime Minister Nawaf Salam stated on Friday that &quot;the page on Hezbollah&#39;s arms has been turned,&quot; as the issue of the party&#39;s arsenal is at the forefront of Lebanon&#39;s political scene.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The page has been turned regarding Hezbollah&#39;s arms after the ministerial declaration. The phrase &#39;people, army, resistance,&#39; is now a thing of the past,&quot; Salam said in an interview with the Saudi pan-Arab channel Al-Arabiya. He also pointed out that &quot;the ministerial declaration clearly states the monopoly of arms within state institutions, and everyone is committed to this, no one opposes it.&quot; However, he specified that &quot;concentrating the armament in the hands of the state will not happen overnight.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Salam government&#39;s ministerial declaration, which followed the inaugural speech of President Joseph Aoun, was the first ministerial declaration since Taif not to mention the &quot;people&#39;s right to resist by all means against Israeli occupation.&quot; Instead, the new ministerial team said that &quot;the state is entirely responsible for defending its territory&quot; and must &quot;hold the monopoly on arms.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since forming Prime Minister Nawaf Salam&#39;s government in February, Hezbollah linked discussions about its arsenal to dialogue and a national defense strategy. During a government on March 13, the debate over the arsenal of the Party of God was initiated by the Lebanese Forces and Kataeb, who called for establishing a timeline for disarmament. Shortly after, ministers from the Amal Movement, Tamara al-Zein (Environment) and Yassine Jaber (Finance), in the cabinet, expressed their opposition to any disarmament of Hezbollah as long as Israel occupies five points in southern Lebanon. On Wednesday, an exchange of statements on the subject also opposed an Amal MP, Qassem Hashem, to one of his Lebanese Forces colleagues, Fadi Karam.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During his interview Friday, Salam also said that &quot;Israel uses Hezbollah&#39;s arms as a pretext to maintain a presence in southern Lebanon, while this presence is illegal under international law and all agreements.&quot; He stated that &quot;Israel must completely withdraw from southern Lebanon, and we are pressing for this.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Only the state is responsible for liberating Lebanese territories from Israel,&quot; he added. &quot;The international community recognizes the effective role of the Lebanese army in southern Lebanon.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The resistance, a guarantee&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Jaafarite mufti, Sheikh Ahmad Qabalan, close to Hezbollah, reacted to Salam&#39;s remarks by stating that &quot;erasing the resistance would mean erasing Lebanon and its sovereignty&quot; and that &quot;no one will be able to erase it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;You are leading the government of a country that the resistance has liberated and continues to defend with all its strength and sacrifices to preserve its existence, sovereignty, and entity,&quot; he said, emphasizing that &quot;for decades, Lebanon&#39;s existence, sovereignty, and weight have rested on the sacrifices of the resistance and the power of its capabilities.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The resistance represents half a century of sovereign sacrifices, meaning it is equivalent to half the age of Lebanon since its foundation,&quot; the mufti continued. &quot;Erasing it would mean erasing Lebanon and its sovereignty. Without the sacrifices of the last war and the defeat of the [Israeli] army at the edge of Khiam and other front villages, there would be no country, no capital, no sovereignty, no independence.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qabalan argued that &quot;monopolizing weapons involves acquiring national power capable of containing Israel&#39;s strength and breaking its hegemony, not remaining spectators in the face of its aggression and occupation.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He stated that &quot;the resistance is ... an existential guarantee for Lebanon. No one in the world can erase it&quot; and that the solution was to exploit the resistance &quot;through a defense policy, not to eliminate the greatest sovereign force guaranteeing Lebanon&#39;s existence.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hussein Hajj Hassan, a Hezbollah MP and former minister, also stated on Friday evening on LBCI that &quot;the issue of handing over Hezbollah&#39;s weapons to the state is still not approved by the party&quot; and that this debate must take place &quot;within the framework of the defense strategy and a national debate.&quot; He emphasized that Hezbollah &quot;cooperates with the Lebanese army in the south and north of the Litani&quot; and that &quot;the decision of war or peace ... is in Israel&#39;s hands,&quot; and not Hezbollah&#39;s as it is accused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hezbollah was significantly weakened after its war with Israel, which began by opening a support front with Gaza in October 2023 and ended with a cease-fire in November 2024. The cease-fire agreement stipulates the disarmament of the party and its withdrawal from the area south of the Litani, where the Lebanese army is already deployed. However, the Israeli army retains five points on Lebanese territory and continues its operations against Hezbollah members daily, notably in southern Lebanon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French in L&#39;Orient-Le Jour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452981/the-page-on-hezbollahs-arms-has-been-turned-says-salam.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452981/the-page-on-hezbollahs-arms-has-been-turned-says-salam.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 09:13:15 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Rocket fire towards Israel: Lebanese officials warn against a new &#39;spiral of violence&#39;</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hezbollah denied any involvement and reaffirmed its &quot;commitment&quot; to the cease-fire agreement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/temp_medias_966238_138896.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;An Israeli strike on Kfar Kila, in southern Lebanon, seen from Israel, on March 22, 2025. (Credit: Jalaa Marey/AFP)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;The rocket fire from southern Lebanon towards Israel early Saturday morning prompted a series of unanimous calls for restraint and denunciations of Israeli cease-fire violations from Lebanese officials. Hezbollah itself reaffirmed its commitment to the truce between Lebanon and Israel, while its traditional ally, the Speaker of Parliament and leader of the Amal Movement, Nabih Berri, urged &quot;all Lebanese parties&quot; to unite around the state and its institutions, including the army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before 8 a.m., the Israeli army claimed to have intercepted three rockets heading towards the town of Metula. While residents of southern Lebanon told L&#39;Orient Today&#39;s correspondent they did not hear any rockets fired, the Lebanese army said it found &quot;improvised&quot; rocket launchers near Arnoun (Nabatieh), north of the Litani. These attacks prompted a disproportionate Israeli air force response, which conducted 18 strikes in several southern regions, killing at least two people, including a young girl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Hezbollah&#39;s &#39;commitment&#39; to the cease-fire agreement&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hezbollah quickly denied any involvement. It denounced Israeli &quot;excuses&quot; to &quot;continue the attacks&quot; and reaffirmed its &quot;commitment to the cease-fire agreement,&quot; while &quot;supporting the Lebanese state to face this dangerous Zionist escalation against Lebanon.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The military branch of the Syrian Social Nationalist Party (SSNP) also denied any involvement in the rocket fire. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;False information attributed to a television channel is circulating and claims that the party&#39;s military branch claimed responsibility for launching rockets from southern Lebanon&quot; towards Israel, the SSNP said in a statement. &quot;We strongly want to emphasize that this information is entirely false and that the SSNP&#39;s military branch rejects any link to any rocket fire. It asserts the predominance of the role of the state, government, and army in stopping Israeli attacks against Lebanon and in any security plan.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first to react, Lebanese Prime Minister Nawaf Salam warned against &quot;the resumption of military operations on the southern border, as they risk dragging the country into a new war, which would be disastrous for Lebanon and the Lebanese.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a call with Defense Minister Michel Menassa, he emphasized the need to take all necessary security and military measures to ensure that &quot;only the state has the power to decide on war and peace.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Oct. 8, 2023, following the deadly Hamas attack in Israel and the beginning of the bloody Israeli offensive on Gaza, Hezbollah opened its &quot;support&quot; front by firing rockets and artillary towards northern Israel. The war escalated in September 2024, with a massive Israeli air campaign on several regions of Lebanon until a cease-fire took effect on Nov. 27, 2024. Despite this agreement, which notably called for its complete withdrawal from southern Lebanon, the Israeli army continues to occupy at least five positions it deems &quot;strategic&quot; in Lebanese territory. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salam also contacted the U.N. coordinator in Lebanon, Jeanine Hennis-Plasschaert, to ask her that the United Nations &quot;double their international pressure on Israel, so that it withdraws completely from the still-occupied Lebanese territories.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&#39;Avoid any violation&#39; that could threaten Lebanon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lebanese President Joseph Aoun condemned the &quot;attempts to bring Lebanon back into the spiral of violence,&quot; according to a statement. Aoun stated that what happened on Saturday in the south, and the violations observed there since Feb. 18, the deadline for the Israeli withdrawal, are a &quot;persistent attack on Lebanon.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also requested all concerned forces in southern Lebanon, particularly the cease-fire monitoring committee, and the army, to follow the events with &quot;the utmost seriousness to avoid any repercussions and to put an end to any violation that could threaten the country under these delicate circumstances.&quot; He finally asked the commander of the army, General Rodolphe Haykal, to take necessary measures on the ground to preserve the security of citizens and investigate the circumstances of the shootings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Berri called on all parties in Lebanon not to &quot;create excuses for the [Israeli] enemy&quot; and to &quot;rally around the state and its institutions,&quot; particularly military ones, after the rocket fire from the south towards Israel. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;All Lebanese, especially political forces, must purify their political discourse, rally around the state and its constitutional, judicial, military and security institutions, and be aware of the dangers resulting from creating excuses for the enemy by stirring up conflicts,&quot; he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his statement, Berri said that &quot;the first and last beneficiary of dragging Lebanon and the region into a major spiral of violence is Israel and its security and military bodies,&quot; emphasizing that Israel has committed &quot;more than 1,500 cease-fire violations,&quot; &quot;while Lebanon and its resistance have fully committed to all the provisions of this agreement.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Reclaim Hezbollah&#39;s weapons &#39;by force or by consensus&#39;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The defense minister stressed Lebanon&#39;s refusal to &quot;return to the situation that prevailed before the ceasefire of November 2024&quot; and stated &quot;firm opposition to attempts to undermine the state&#39;s efforts to consolidate security and stability throughout Lebanese territory, particularly on the southern and eastern borders,&quot; respectively with Israel and Syria. He said that the Lebanese army launched an investigation into the circumstances of the rocket fire from southern Lebanon and called on the &quot;sponsors&quot; of the cease-fire agreement to dissuade Israel from continuing its &quot;violations and attacks under false pretenses.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The foreign minister, Joe Rajji, made diplomatic contacts to press Israel to calm the tension at the Lebanon-Israel border. He notably spoke with his Jordanian, Egyptian, European and French counterparts, as well as the U.S. deputy special envoy for Middle East peace, Morgan Ortagus, and the U.S. Deputy Secretary of State for Middle East affairs, Natasha Franceschi. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I asked for pressure on Israel to end the escalation,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The leader of the Progressive Socialist Party (PSP), Taymour Joumblatt, stated that &quot;compliance with the cease-fire agreement and the implementation of resolution 1701 are the only means not to enter into new military conflicts that could push Lebanon to war again.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an interview on Voice of Lebanon, MP Ghassan Hasbani (Lebanese Forces) said that the rocket fire from Lebanese territory towards Israel is &quot;an attempt to draw Lebanon into a new war, inflame the border and put the army and the state on the front line.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hasbani stated that &quot;the army must reclaim Hezbollah&#39;s weapons by force or by consensus; otherwise, this process will be entrusted to the Israelis in the South and to the Syrians in the East, which is unacceptable for any Lebanese, as it affects national sovereignty.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in French in L&#39;Orient-Le Jour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452977/rocket-fire-towards-israel-lebanese-officials-warn-against-a-new-spiral-of-violence.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452977/rocket-fire-towards-israel-lebanese-officials-warn-against-a-new-spiral-of-violence.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 08:56:28 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Politics</category><category>Live</category></item><item><title>Why is the Lebanon-Syria border so blurred?</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;This situation dating back to the French Mandate affects about a dozen Syrian villages populated by Lebanese, as well as one town that sits right on the otherwise murky border between the two countries.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/PhotoAl-Qasr_349892_678319_384370.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gas canisters and a burned vehicle on March 20, 2025, three days after clashes between Lebanese clans and Syrian forces in the Lebanese village of Qasr, near Hosh al-Sayyed Ali in Hermel. (Credit: Emmanuel Haddad/L&#39;Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     Is Hosh al-Sayyed Ali a Lebanese village? Or a Syrian one? The village partly in northern Lebanon&#39;s Hermel district is split in two, straddling the albeit murky border line between the two countries. Its tenuous territorial position became a... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452923/why-is-the-lebanon-syria-border-so-blurred.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452923/why-is-the-lebanon-syria-border-so-blurred.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 14:28:45 GMT</pubDate><author>Nemtala EDDÉ</author><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Calls for revenge against Damascus ring out from wounded Hermel</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a new surge of violence at the Lebanese-Syrian border, clans involved in combat against Syrian forces blame Hezbollah for its absence and brace for the worst.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/WhatsAppImage2025-03-21at165752_693184_916677.jpeg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Destruction caused by a strike launched from Syria onto the Lebanese border village of Qasr on March 20. (Credit: Emmanuel Haddad/L’Orient-Le Jour)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     It&#39;s almost noon on March 20 in Qasr, a Hermel-district village bordering Syria, when the stormy air is pierced by gunfire. In a plush living room where a portrait of his ancestor sits beside that of former Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, framed... </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452895/calls-for-revenge-against-damascus-ring-out-from-wounded-hermel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452895/calls-for-revenge-against-damascus-ring-out-from-wounded-hermel.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 10:08:23 GMT</pubDate><author>Emmanuel HADDAD</author><category>Society</category></item><item><title>8 killed in Israeli strikes on Lebanon after rockets hit Metula</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hezbollah denied &quot;any involvement&quot; in the attack, which remains unclaimed, and the Lebanese Army found three homemade rocket launchers near Arnoun, north of the Litani but only 6 km from Israel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/Screenshot2025-03-22at22-47-34temp_medias_427889webpWEBPImage37372491pixelsScaled35_521986.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Smoke rises from the site of an Israeli attack against the southern Lebanese village of Yohmor al-Shakif on March 22, 2025. (Credit: Rabih Daher/AFP)

&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/temp_medias_656438_558818.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;A vehicle in front of buildings destroyed by Israeli strikes in Ramieh, southern Lebanon, on March 5, 2025. (Credit: Mahmoud Zayyat/AFP)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;BEIRUT — Israel intensified its attacks against southern Lebanese villages on Saturday killing at least eight people, including a young girl. The escalation followed the Israeli army&#39;s announcement Saturday morning that it intercepted three rockets fired from Lebanese territory that triggered sirens in Metula, opposite the Lebanese village of Odaisseh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shortly after, the Israeli army fired on the border village of Yohmor al-Shakif (Nabatieh district), followed by a statement from Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz saying he had instructed the Israeli army to &quot;respond accordingly.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By 11 a.m. the Israeli army had targeted five more Lebanese border villages with artillery fire and machine guns including Arnoun and Khiam, both in Nabatieh district, and Hula, Markaba and Kfar Kila, in Marjayoun district, and by early afternoon the Israeli army had bombed 18 more sites in southern Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hezbollah denied &quot;any involvement&quot; in the rockets fired from southern Lebanon and accused Israel of using it as a &quot;pretext&quot; to continue its attacks on Lebanon &quot;which have not ceased since the announcement of the cease-fire” on Nov. 27, 2024. While accusing Hezbollah of violating the cease-fire, Israel has violated its hundreds of times, killing more than 100 people since signing the agreement and razing entire villages to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Hezbollah reaffirms its commitment to the cease-fire agreement and assures that it stands behind the Lebanese state in confronting this dangerous Zionist escalation against Lebanon,” Hezbollah&#39;s statement reads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By mid-afternoon, responsibility for the attacks still had not been claimed by any group in Lebanon. A source from the Lebanese Army told Al-Arabiya al-Jadeed that the military was patrolling the area where the rockets were supposedly launched from and investigating into the circumstances surrounding the attack against Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lebanese Army later announced that it had found three homemade rocket launchers in an area near Arnoun, north of the Litani River, around six kilometers from the Israeli border, and “dismantled them.” Artillery and machine gun fire was in several areas on Saturday morning, notably in Arnoun and the eastern part of the border zone, in the Marjayoun district.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Casualties and consequences&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dozens of air raids targeted several areas north and south of the Litani River, in the districts of Jezzine, Saida, Nabatieh, Hasbaya, Bint Jbeil and Sour. These strikes killed at least four people in Touline, in the Nabatieh district, according to the village’s mayor and the Ministry of Health reported two deaths in Touline, including a young girl. The victims were a Syrian man at a local gas station and his daughter. The Health Ministry also reported eight injuries in Touline and one person wounded in Yohmor al-Shakif, in the same region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Israeli government has had difficulty convincing displaced residents of the north to return home following the cease-fire and local municipal leaders often criticized the Israeli government for failing to secure their safety. &quot;We promised the Galilee communities security — and that is exactly what will happen,&quot; Katz declared in his statement. Around 60,000 people fled northern Israel and only a portion have returned, while in Lebanon, over one million people fled the South, with around 100,000 still displaced, according to the U.N.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his statement, Katz also laid responsibility for any attacks launched from Lebanese territory on the Lebanese government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lebanese government, for its part, has warned entreatingly against the situation spiralling out of control. Prime Minister Nawaf Salam released a statement urging for calm along the border and calling on the Defense Ministry and the U.N. to collaborate with him in trying to thwart another outbreak of violence, saying that it &quot;risks dragging the country into a new war, which would be disastrous for Lebanon and the Lebanese.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salam communicated with Defense Minister Michel Menassa on the need to take all necessary security and military measures to ensure that “only the State has the power to decide on war and peace,&quot; and with U.N. coordinator in Lebanon, Jeanine Hennis-Plasschaert, asking that the U.N. “redouble its international pressure on Israel to withdraw completely from the occupied Lebanese territories,&quot; citing U.N. Resolution 1701 and Israel&#39;s ongoing violation of its terms through this occupation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNIFIL expressed concern over a “possible escalation,” while President Joseph Aoun condemned what he called Israel’s “continued aggression” and accused it of attempting to “drag Lebanon back into the spiral of violence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNIFIL spokesperson Andrea Tenenti urged all parties to “refrain from actions that could compromise recent progress, especially in light of the ongoing threat to civilian lives and the region’s fragile stability.” Any new escalation could have “grave consequences,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452881/israel-says-intercepted-three-rockets-from-lebanon-and-shells-border-villages.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452881/israel-says-intercepted-three-rockets-from-lebanon-and-shells-border-villages.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 08:26:20 GMT</pubDate><author>L&#39;Orient Today staff</author><category>Live</category><category>Politics</category></item><item><title>Pregnant mother under bombs: Our correspondent&#39;s account from Bekaa</title><description>&lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;For Mother&#39;s Day, Sarah Abdallah, a correspondent for L&#39;Orient-Le Jour in the Bekaa, shared her experience as a mother of two little girls and pregnant with a third under the bombs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;     &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s.lorientlejour.com/storage/attachments/1453/blob_944859_105989.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our correspondent in the Bekaa, Sarah Abdallah, with her children. (Credit: Rights reserved)&lt;/figcaption&gt;  &lt;/figure&gt;     &lt;p&gt;Pregnant during the war and a mother of two little girls, I went through months of constant psychological pressure, marked by fear, anxiety and pervasive tension, as well as a profound sense of insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This situation also led to difficulties in maintaining a healthy and balanced diet. I lost my appetite and weight and no longer regularly took the dietary supplements prescribed for pregnant women as I had during my previous pregnancies. To the extent that by the eighth month, my doctor began to fear a premature birth or miscarriage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I continued to work as a war journalist, surrounded by the incessant noise of drones and fighter jets. I also experienced an internal conflict, torn between my professional responsibilities and my role as a mother. I felt guilty both towards the child I was carrying and in my professional life, as I could no longer do my job with the same passion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Bekaa started to undergo bombings, I left Qalia, my village in West Bekaa, where many homes were hit. The thought of losing the house my husband and I built with so much effort terrified me. We moved to a small apartment in Zahle at my parents’ place, as the area seemed safer. We still live there, and my daughters have joined a school in this town, where the cease-fire is intermittent. The Israeli strikes continue, and I refuse to expose them to danger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried to protect my daughters from stress and anxiety-inducing information, which is not easy, given that their father and I both work in journalism. In our apartment in Zahle, we all share the same space when we work, which means the little ones are exposed to the flood of news. In the village, we had more space for them, which allowed us to better protect them. Due to the war, they have been affected by the information and the disruption of their daily lives, as they were deprived of outings and leisure activities they were used to.&lt;/p&gt; </description><link>https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452826/pregnant-mother-under-bombs-our-correspondents-account-from-bekaa.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1452826/pregnant-mother-under-bombs-our-correspondents-account-from-bekaa.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 16:17:30 GMT</pubDate><author>Sarah ABDALLAH</author><category>Live</category><category>Society</category></item></channel></rss>