<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>RSSHub - program-update</title><description>RSS feeds for program-update category</description><item><title>0.59 (released 2007-01-24):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
PuTTY can now connect to local serial ports as well as making network
connections.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Windows PuTTY now supports "local proxying", where a network
connection is replaced by a local command. (Unix PuTTY has supported
this since it was first released in 0.54.) Also, Plink has gained a
"&lt;code&gt;-nc&lt;/code&gt;" mode where the primary channel is replaced by an
SSH tunnel, which makes it particularly useful as the local command
to run.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Improved speed of SSH on Windows (particularly SSH-2 key exchange and
public-key authentication).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Improved SFTP throughput.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Various cryptographic improvements in SSH-2, including SDCTR cipher
modes, a workaround for a weakness in CBC cipher modes, and
Diffie-Hellman group exchange with SHA-256.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for the Arcfour cipher in SSH-2.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for sending terminal modes in SSH.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
When Pageant is running and an SSH key is specified in the
configuration, PuTTY will now only try Pageant authentication with
that key. This gets round a problem where some servers would only
allow a limited number of keys to be offered before disconnecting.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for SSH-2 password expiry mechanisms, and various other
improvements and bugfixes in authentication.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
A change to the SSH-2 password camouflage mechanism in 0.58 upset some
Cisco servers, so we have reverted to the old method.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The Windows version now comes with documentation in HTML Help
format. (Windows Vista does not support the older WinHelp format.
However, we still provide documentation in that format, since Win95
does not support HTML Help.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
On Windows, when pasting as RTF, attributes of the selection such as
colours and formatting are also pasted.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Ability to configure font quality on Windows (including antialiasing
and ClearType).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The terminal is now restored to a sensible state when reusing a window
to restart a session.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
We now support an escape sequence invented by xterm which lets the
server clear the scrollback (CSI 3 J). This is useful for applications
such as terminal locking programs.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Improvements to the Unix port:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
now compiles cleanly with GCC 4
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
now has a &lt;code&gt;configure&lt;/code&gt; script, and should be portable to
more platforms
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: 0.58 utterly failed to run on some installations of
Windows XP.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: PSCP and PSFTP now support large files (greater than 4
gigabytes), provided the underlying operating system does too.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: PSFTP (and PSCP) sometimes ran slowly and consumed lots of
CPU when started directly from Windows Explorer.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: font linking (the automatic use of other fonts on the
system to provide Unicode characters not present in the selected
one) should now work again on Windows, after being broken in 0.58.
(However, it unfortunately still won't work for Arabic and other
right-to-left text.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: if the remote server saturated PuTTY with data, PuTTY could
become unresponsive.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: certain large clipboard operations could cause PuTTY to
crash.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: SSH-1 connections tended to crash, particularly when using
port forwarding.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: SSH Tectia Server would reject SSH-2 tunnels from PuTTY due
to a malformed request.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: SSH-2 login banner messages were being dropped silently under
some circumstances.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the cursor could end up in the wrong place when a server-side
application used the alternate screen.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: on Windows, PuTTY now tries harder to find a suitable place
to store its random seed file &lt;code&gt;PUTTY.RND&lt;/code&gt; (previously it
was tending to end up in &lt;code&gt;C:\&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;C:\WINDOWS&lt;/code&gt;).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: IPv6 should now work on Windows Vista.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Numerous other bugfixes, as usual.
&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.59.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.59.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.58 (released 2005-04-05):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Wildcards (&lt;code&gt;mput&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;mget&lt;/code&gt;) and recursive file
transfer in PSFTP.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
You can now save your session details from the Change Settings
dialog box, &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; you've started your session.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Various improvements to Unicode support, including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
support for right-to-left and bidirectional text (Arabic, Hebrew
etc). Thanks to
&lt;a href="http://www.arabeyes.org/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;arabeyes.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
for design and most of the implementation.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
support for Arabic text shaping, again thanks to
&lt;code&gt;arabeyes.org&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;support for Unicode combining characters.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for the &lt;code&gt;xterm&lt;/code&gt; 256-colour control sequences.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Port forwardings can now be reconfigured in mid-session.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for IPv6. Thanks to
&lt;a href="http://unfix.org/"&gt;&lt;code&gt;unfix.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
for having patiently maintained the patch for this until we were
finally ready to integrate it.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
More configurability and flexibility in SSH-2 key exchange. In
particular, PuTTY can now initiate repeat key exchange during the
session, which means that if your server doesn't initiate it (some
servers don't bother) you can still have the cryptographic benefits.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: display artefacts caused by characters overflowing their
character cell should now all be gone. (This would probably have
bothered Windows ClearType users more than anyone else.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: keepalives are now supported everywhere. (Previously they
were supported by Windows GUI PuTTY, but were missing in Plink,
PSFTP and the Unix port.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Miscellaneous improvements for CJK/IME users; many thanks to Hung-Te
Lin for assistance.
&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.58.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.58.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2005 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.57 (released 2005-02-20):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Security fixes: two vulnerabilities discovered by iDEFENSE,
potentially allowing arbitrary code execution on an SFTP client by a
malicious SFTP server (but only after host key verification), have
been fixed. See
&lt;a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/wishlist/vuln-sftp-readdir.html"&gt;vuln-sftp-readdir&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/wishlist/vuln-sftp-string.html"&gt;vuln-sftp-string&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fixed small bug with X forwarding to local displays.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fixed crashing bug with remote port forwarding.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fixed handling of SSH-2 debug messages (embarrassingly, a bug
introduced when fixing the previous vulnerability - it was more
secure but didn't work any more!).
&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.57.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.57.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2005 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.56 (released 2004-10-26):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Security fix: a vulnerability discovered by iDEFENSE,
potentially allowing arbitrary code execution on the client by a
malicious SSH-2 server &lt;em&gt;before host key verification&lt;/em&gt;, has been
fixed. See
&lt;a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/wishlist/vuln-ssh2-debug.html"&gt;vuln-ssh2-debug&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to restart a session within an inactive window, via a new
menu option.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Minimal support for not running a shell or command at all in SSH
protocol 2 (equivalent to OpenSSH's "-N" option). PuTTY/Plink still
provide a normal window for interaction, and have to be explicitly
killed.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Transparent support for CHAP cryptographic authentication in the
SOCKS 5 proxy protocol. (Not in PuTTYtel.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More diagnostics in the Event Log, particularly of SSH port
forwarding.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to request setting of environment variables in SSH (protocol
2 only). (However, we don't know of any &lt;em&gt;servers&lt;/em&gt; that support
this.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to send POSIX signals in SSH (protocol 2 only) via the
"Special Commands" menu. (Again, we don't know of any servers
supporting this.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: The PuTTY tools now more consistently support usernames
containing "@" signs.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for the Polish character set "Mazovia".
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When logging is enabled, the log file is flushed more frequently, so
that its contents can be viewed before it is closed.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More flexibility in SSH packet logging: known passwords and session
data can be omitted from the log file. Passwords are omitted by
default. (This option isn't perfect for removing sensitive details;
you should still review log files before letting them out of your
sight.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unix-specific changes:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to set environment variables in pterm.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PuTTY and pterm attempt to use a UTF-8 line character set by
default if this is indicated by the locale; however, this can be
overridden.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.56.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.56.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2004 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.55 (released 2004-08-03):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Security fix: a vulnerability discovered by Core Security
Technologies (advisory number
&lt;a href="http://www.coresecurity.com/common/showdoc.php?idx=417&amp;amp;idxseccion=10"&gt;CORE-2004-0705&lt;/a&gt;),
potentially allowing arbitrary code execution on the client by a
malicious server &lt;em&gt;before host key verification&lt;/em&gt;, has been
fixed.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: General robustness of the SSH-1 implementation has been improved,
which may have fixed further potential security problems although we
are not aware of any specific ones.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: Random noise generation was hanging some computers and
interfering with other processes' precision timing, and should now
not do so.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: dead key support should work better.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: a terminal speed is now sent to the SSH server.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: removed a spurious diagnostic message in Plink.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: the `-load' option in PSCP and PSFTP should work better.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: X forwarding on the Unix port can now talk to Unix
sockets as well as TCP sockets.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix: various crashes and assertion failures fixed..
&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.55.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.55.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2004 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.54 (released 2004-02-12):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Port to Unix!
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Dynamic SSH port forwarding.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Ability to leave DNS lookups to the proxy, when using a proxy.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Sped up PSFTP.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fixed various bugs, notably one which was impeding port-forwarding
of SMB.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Some default settings changes: SSH and SSH-2 are now default, BCE is
off.
&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.54.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.54.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2004 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.53b (released 2002-11-12):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Fixed an embarrassing command-line bug: the -P option didn't work at
all.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Security fix: the vulnerability found by the Rapid7 SSHredder test
suite is now believed fixed. See CERT advisory
&lt;a href="http://www.cert.org/advisories/CA-2002-36.html"&gt;CA-2002-36&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Security fix: an improvement in random number policy when running
more than one PuTTY at the same time.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.53b.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.53b.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2002 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.53 (released 2002-10-01):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
The feature everyone's been asking for: ANSI printer support.
Currently this sends data to the printer in completely raw mode,
without benefit of Windows GDI or the printer driver; so it will be
fine for anyone whose server already knows what type of printer it
expects to be talking to, but probably not ideal for someone who
wants to print a text file and have it look nice. A less raw mode of
printer access is still on the Wishlist, but is quite a big piece of
coding work so it's in the Implausible section.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; feature everyone's been asking for: PuTTYgen can
now import and export OpenSSH and ssh.com SSH-2 private keys, as well
as PuTTY's own format.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
We now ship the PuTTY tool set as an installer, created using Jordan
Russell's excellent and easy-to-use
&lt;a href="http://www.jrsoftware.org/isinfo.php"&gt;Inno Setup&lt;/a&gt;.
(For the other half of our users, who felt the best thing about
PuTTY was that they &lt;em&gt;didn't&lt;/em&gt; have to mess around with
installers, we still ship the single executables and the zip file,
so nobody has to use the installer if they don't want to.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
PuTTY now has a default file extension for private key files:
&lt;code&gt;.PPK&lt;/code&gt; (PuTTY Private Key). The installer associates this
file extension with Pageant and PuTTYgen.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
PuTTY now natively supports making its connection through various
types of proxy. We support SOCKS 4 and 5, HTTP CONNECT (RFC 2817),
and the common ad-hoc type of proxy where you telnet to the proxy
and then send text of the form "&lt;code&gt;connect host.name 22&lt;/code&gt;".
Basic password authentication is supported in SOCKS and HTTP
proxies. Many thanks to Justin Bradford for doing most of the work
here.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
PuTTY now supports a standard set of command-line options across all
tools. Most of these options are ones that Plink has always
supported; however, we also support a number of new options similar
to the OpenSSH ones (&lt;code&gt;-A&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-a&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code&gt;-X&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-x&lt;/code&gt;, and similar things; also the
&lt;code&gt;-i&lt;/code&gt; option to specify a private key file).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The right-button menu on Pageant's System tray icon now offers the
option to start PuTTY (New Session plus the Saved Sessions submenu).
This feature is disabled if Pageant can't find the PuTTY binary on
startup. Thanks to Dominique Faure.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Added the Features control panel, allowing the user to disable some
of the more controversial terminal capabilities.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Added the Bugs control panel, allowing the user to manually control
PuTTY's various workarounds for SSH server bugs.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Various bug fixes, including (with luck) much greater stability in
high-traffic port forwarding situations.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.53.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.53.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2002 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.52 (released 2002-01-14):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
A full manual has been written, and is supplied as a Windows Help
file alongside the program executables.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for public keys in SSH-2, both RSA and DSA. Agent forwarding
is supported, but only to OpenSSH servers, because ssh.com have a
different agent protocol which they haven't published.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
(Yes, I know I've been claiming DSA is horrifically insecure for
ages, but now I've been told about a clever way to get round the
insecurity. Details are in &lt;code&gt;sshdss.c&lt;/code&gt; for anyone who's
interested; credit mostly goes to Colin Plumb for letting me know
about it. We still think RSA is better, and recommend you use it if
you have the choice.)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
PSCP now uses the new SFTP protocol if possible, and only falls back
to the old scp1 form if SFTP can't be found (for example, if your
connection is SSH-1). This should allow it to interoperate cleanly
with ssh.com's product, and is a security improvement besides.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
PSCP, in old-style scp1 mode, is now much tighter on security. It
will refuse to let the remote host write to a file that doesn't have
the same name as the file that was requested. &lt;b&gt;NOTE WELL&lt;/b&gt; that
this disallows remote-to-local wildcards such as "&lt;code&gt;pscp
server:*.c .&lt;/code&gt;". scp1's implementation of server-side wildcards
is inherently unsafe. If you are sure you trust your scp server not
to be malicious, you can use the "&lt;code&gt;-unsafe&lt;/code&gt;" command line
option to re-enable this behaviour. When using the new SFTP-based
back end none of this is a problem, because SFTP is better designed.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Generic port forwarding support is now supported, thanks to a very
comprehensive contribution from Nicolas Barry.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
X11 forwarding support. Thanks to Andreas Schultz for doing a large
part of the coding for this. Authentication munging is supported.
However, PuTTY does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; currently attempt to authenticate
connections to the local X server, because finding the
authentication data to do so is server-dependent and complex and I
thought I'd wait to see what servers people actually want to use
this with.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Added an SFTP client, for the improved file transfer protocol that
comes with SSH-2.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Full-screen mode, "like a DOS box". Not really like a DOS box, since
it works within the current graphics mode rather than shifting into
text mode, but it seems to work.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for resizing the font rather than the terminal when the user
changes the window size. Also supports a hybrid mode, in which
window resizes change the terminal size but maximising or going
full-screen changes the font size. Patch due to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Unicode support in the terminal emulator. In the first place this
allows us to support servers which actually send UTF-8 down their
terminal sessions; but the architecture changes also mean that
instead of specifying the local &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; remote character sets
in the Translation panel, you simply specify what character set you
expect the server to be talking, and PuTTY handles the rest
automatically. Many thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Experimental rlogin support. Thanks to Delian Delchev for the patch.
Note that this may fail because the rlogin protocol relies on TCP
Urgent data, which not all operating systems get right, and which
not all firewalls pass through correctly. Also, local flow control
is unsupported as yet, and the "flush" command is not handled
correctly. Despite all this, it worked fine for me!

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Improved support for local echo and local line editing. These are
now separate options, controllable independently. PuTTY will make
sensible guesses at the right settings, but those guesses can
&lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; be overridden by the user.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Improved bell support. There's now a whole configuration panel; you
can choose a bell that plays the Windows default sound, or plays a
sound of your choice, or flashes the window, or does nothing. In
addition the window's Taskbar entry can be made to flash if a bell
goes off when the window is minimised, and also there's an option
that disables all bells if it receives them too fast (so that if you
&lt;code&gt;cat&lt;/code&gt; a binary file into your terminal it won't bleep for
a week).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for AES in SSH-2.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Default Settings can now be used to save a default protocol and port
number.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Scrollback should now automatically scroll if you try to drag-select
off the top of the window (or off the bottom of the window when it's
scrolled back), so you can easily select more than a screenful.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
We now support rectangular-block selection, triggered by holding Alt
while you drag the mouse. (You can also configure rectangular
selection to be the default and Alt-drag to be conventional
line-by-line selection.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The mouse pointer can now be configured to disappear when the PuTTY
window is active and text is typed, and reappear when the mouse is
moved, à la MS Word. Particularly useful for those of us
using focus-follows-mouse, where the pointer is quite likely to be
inside the window and obscuring the view.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The cursor can now be displayed as an underline or as a vertical
line, as well as a block. When it's a vertical line, it does
something useful when not-quite-wrapping in the rightmost column.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Keepalive timeouts can now be specified in seconds rather than
minutes.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for Diffie-Hellman group exchange in SSH-2.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
If you don't supply a username, PSCP now guesses your remote
username to be the same as your local username. (On Win95/98, this
might not be useful to everybody, but it's at least no worse than
bombing out with a complaint. On WinNT, it might be seriously
useful.) Patch due to Christian Biesinger.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
You can now enter a service name such as "finger", in place of a
port number. Patch due to Christian Biesinger.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
It's now possible to invoke a second Pageant with some key files on
the command line and have it feed those key files to the first
Pageant. Also, you can make Pageant start another command once it's
initialised itself; for example, "&lt;code&gt;pageant -c
wincvs.exe&lt;/code&gt;" to start Pageant and then start WinCVS.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Scrollback on the terminal is no longer implemented by physically
copying a huge array. It should now be safe to use very large
scrollback buffers without suffering noticeable slowdown.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Patch due to Roman Pompejus: the "&lt;code&gt;-log&lt;/code&gt;" command line
option on PuTTY is gone, replaced by a proper GUI-configurable
logging facility.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Implemented a selection option to paste line drawing as the
underlying characters &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; as poor-man's. Thanks to to Robert
de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Ctrl+Alt can be configured to &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt; have the traditional
PuTTY behaviour (Ctrl+Alt+X is equivalent to ESC then Ctrl+X),
&lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; to behave like AltGr. Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Added SCO ANSI function key support (F1 is ESC [ M and F12 is ESC [
X, with all obvious points in between).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Font changes when the window is maximised now keep it maximised.
Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The Application key on Windows keyboards now behaves like a Compose
key all the time. Compose behaviour on AltGr can still be configured
on and off. Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The terminal driver now returns a configurable string when it sees
^E. Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The About box now has a button that brings up a browser pointing at
the PuTTY web site. Thanks to Eric Theriault.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the long-standing socket buffering bug should now be gone
forever. If PuTTY is receiving data faster than it can send it out,
it will attempt to slow down the entity it's receiving from rather
than continuing to grow its buffers without bound.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: AltGr should now be fixed. It was broken in 0.51.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: repeat key exchange in SSH-2 is now handled correctly. You
should no longer see "Server failed host key check" after your
session has been running for an hour.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: various socket-handling problems should be corrected.
Crashes on network errors, bad handling of TCP Urgent data in telnet
and rlogin, and truncation of output when the remote server sends a
lot of data and then immediately closes the connection. Thanks to
Robert de Bath for the TCP Urgent stuff.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the cascading-error-boxes bug should be fixed. (This
occurred when you had keepalives enabled and got Connection
Aborted.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix in the configuration box: controls in panels other than the
visible one should now not be able to get keyboard focus.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: Tab and accelerator keys now work in the Event Log and in
the About box while a session is running. Thanks to Roman Pompejus
for the fix.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.52.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.52.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2002 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.51 (released 2000-12-14):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Addition of PuTTYgen, an RSA key generation utility. Since PuTTY
uses the same RSA key file format as SSH 1, keys generated by
PuTTYgen are usable with SSH 1 as well.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
SSH compression is now implemented.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Security improvement: better collection of randomness for the
cryptographic random number generator. Thanks to Peter Gutmann of
&lt;a href="http://www.cs.auckland.ac.nz/~pgut001/cryptlib/"&gt;cryptlib&lt;/a&gt;
for ideas.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Security improvement: PSCP should now not be vulnerable to malicious
servers sending deliberately incorrect and harmful filenames down
the SCP connection. (The problem was reported in Bugtraq
&lt;a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/bid/1742"&gt;#1742&lt;/a&gt;.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Security improvement: the ssh client will not open agent forwarding
channels unless agent forwarding has genuinely been enabled, by the
user and the server. This allows a user to disable agent forwarding
if they suspect the server might abuse the agent. (The problem was
reported in Bugtraq
&lt;a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/bid/1949"&gt;#1949&lt;/a&gt;.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
New configurable option: the Compose key support is now off by
default and configurable on.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
New configurable option: whether or not Alt on its own brings up the
System menu.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
New configurable option: whether or not scrollback resets to the
bottom when the display changes. (Previously you could control
whether it reset on a keypress.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
New configurable options: application keypad mode and application
cursor keys mode can be completely disabled. (Independently.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
New configurable options: Always On Top for the PuTTY window, so you
can use it to keep system logs on-screen the whole time. (Might work
particularly well with a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; small font.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Better network error handling. All errors are now translated into
plain text: "Unexpected network error 10053" is a thing of the past.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Added a small patch to improve Chinese support. Thanks to Zhong
Ming-Xun.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: ISO8859-2 to Win1250 translation accidentally got broken in
the 0.50 release. It should be back to normal now.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: restore the SSH back end's ability to distinguish stderr
output from stdout output. This was breaking PSCP and potentially
also Plink.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: correct the "Lost connection while sending" problem when
pasting large amounts of data into PuTTY. This should also have
fixed random connection loss in Plink. &lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: some of my
experiments suggest that some SSH &lt;em&gt;servers&lt;/em&gt; are not entirely
happy with very large (80Kb or so) pastes, so if you still have
problems, they may not be PuTTY's fault.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: PuTTY proper now ignores trailing whitespace on the command
line (this was causing problems with
"&lt;code&gt;putty&amp;nbsp;@sessionname&amp;nbsp;&lt;/code&gt;" and similar.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the scrollbar is now reset to the bottom whenever the
scrollback is, so they don't end up out of sync any more.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: both PuTTY and Pageant, when trying to load a private key
file that turned out to be the wrong format, failed to close the
file, so you couldn't delete it until the app had shut down.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: some SSH-2 connections were reporting "Server failed host
key check" on session startup. This was a bug in PuTTY's DSA
implementation.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the "Default Settings" pseudo-saved-session was often
missing from the saved session list. This was causing chaos, as the
rest of the code assumed it was there and so treated the first item
in the list specially. It's now back.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: Plink and PSCP didn't load the Default Settings when
presented with a simple hostname. (So a default username, default
private key, etc, didn't get used.) Now they do.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: terminal resize events weren't being sent in SSH-2. Now they
are.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: although local terminal line discipline was being turned
off correctly on receipt of &lt;code&gt;IAC WILL ECHO&lt;/code&gt;, it wasn't
being turned on again on receipt of &lt;code&gt;IAC WONT ECHO&lt;/code&gt;. This
was breaking some BBS/MUD connections. Now fixed.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: pscp's GUI interface was computing wrong percentages for
very large files (within a factor of 100 of 2^32).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the Compose key now doesn't randomly trigger and cause
keystroke loss on switching back into the PuTTY window.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: the Colours panel now works again. (The RGB values weren't
updating when the selection changed in the list box.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: if you tried to use a local wildcard with PSCP (for
example, "&lt;code&gt;pscp * remotehost:&lt;/code&gt;", that wildcard would
match the special directories "&lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;" and
"&lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt;". It now doesn't; "&lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;" and
"&lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt;" can only be specified explicitly.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.51.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.51.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2000 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.50 (released 2000-10-16):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Keep-alives to prevent overzealous idle detectors in firewalls from
closing connections down. Done by sending Telnet NOP or
SSH_MSG_IGNORE, so as to avoid affecting the actual data stream.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
In PuTTY proper, in SSH mode, you can now specify a command to be
run at the remote end. (The SSH functionality was already there,
because it was required for PSCP and Plink. All it took was a bit of
GUI work to make it accessible from PuTTY itself.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
You can now configure the initial window title.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Running "&lt;code&gt;putty -cleanup&lt;/code&gt;" will now remove all files and
registry entries created by PuTTY. If you've used PuTTY on somebody
else's machine and don't want to leave any mess behind, you can run
this before deleting the PuTTY executable.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The Event Log now scrolls down when new events appear on it, so that
if you leave it up all the time you can watch things happen. Also,
you can select items from the Event Log and copy them to the
clipboard (should help for debugging).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
When using NT's opaque resize feature, resizing the window doesn't
send resize events at &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; step of the process, but
instead sends a single one at the end. (I'd have quite liked it to
do a resize event if the drag paused for maybe a second, but
WM_TIMER doesn't seem to get through in the middle of a resize. Oh
well, this is good enough.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Everyone's favourite trivial change: Shift+Ins pastes. (No
configurable option to control this: it wasn't doing anything
interesting anyway.)

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Included two extra Makefile options: &lt;code&gt;/DAUTO_WINSOCK&lt;/code&gt;
makes the build process assume that &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;windows.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
implicitly includes a WinSock header file, and
&lt;code&gt;/DWINSOCK_TWO&lt;/code&gt; makes PuTTY include
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;winsock2.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; instead of
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;winsock.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix for a bug &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; had ever noticed: if you hit About
twice, you only get one About box (as designed), &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt;
that if you open and close the Licence box then PuTTY forgets about
the About box, so it will then let you open another. Now the
behaviour is sane, and you can never open more than one About box.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: choosing local-terminal line discipline together with SSH
password authentication now doesn't cause the password to be echoed
to the screen.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: network errors now do not close the window if Close On Exit
isn't set.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: fonts such as 9-point (12-pixel) Courier New, which
previously failed to display underlines, now do so.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: stopped the saved-configuration-name box getting blanked
when you swap away from and back to the Connection panel.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: closing the About box returns focus to the config box, and
closing the View Licence box returns focus to the About box.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The moment you've &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; been waiting for: RSA public key
authentication is here! You can enter a public-key file name in the
SSH configuration panel, and PuTTY will attempt to authenticate with
that before falling back to passwords or TIS. Key file format is the
same as "regular" ssh. Decryption of the key using a passphrase is
supported. No key generation utility is provided, yet.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Created Pageant, a PuTTY authentication agent. PuTTY can use RSA
keys from this for authentication, and can also forward agent
communications to the remote end. Keys can be added and removed
either locally or remotely.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Created Plink, a command-line version of PuTTY suitable for use as a
component of a pipe assembly (for example, Windows NT CVS can use it
as a transport).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
SSH protocol version 2 support. This is disabled by default unless
you connect to a v2-only server. Public key authentication isn't
supported (this places PuTTY technically in violation of the SSH-2
specification).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Enable handling of &lt;code&gt;telnet://hostname:port/&lt;/code&gt; URLs on the
command line. With this feature, you can now set PuTTY as the
default handler for Telnet URLs. If you run the Registry Editor and
set the value in
&lt;code&gt;HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\telnet\shell\open\command&lt;/code&gt; to be
"&lt;code&gt;\path\to\putty.exe %1&lt;/code&gt;" (with the full pathname of your
PuTTY executable), you should find that clicking on telnet links in
your web browser now runs PuTTY.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Re-merge the two separate forks of the ssh protocol code. PuTTY and
PSCP now use the same protocol module, meaning that further SSH
developments will be easily able to affect both.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.50.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.50.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2000 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.49 (released 2000-06-28):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Stop the SSH protocol code from sending zero-length
&lt;code&gt;SSH_CMSG_STDIN_DATA&lt;/code&gt; packets when Shift is pressed.
These appear to be harmless to Unix sshd, but cause VMS sshd to
generate an Exit signal.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fix a small bug about using special port numbers in pscp; thanks to
Joris van Rantwijk.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Three security improvements. PuTTY now checks the CRC on incoming
packets, checks that the packet length and string length fields on
incoming &lt;code&gt;SSH_SMSG_*_DATA&lt;/code&gt; packets are consistent, and
outlaws attempts to set the terminal size too big by escape
sequences (countering the xterm DoS attack shown in bugtraq
&lt;a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/bid/1298"&gt;#1298&lt;/a&gt;).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
High-half characters (160 and above) are now supported in username
and password input.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Bug fix: RSA keys whose storage format used an odd number of bytes
(i.e. the bit length of the key, mod 16, was between 1 and 8
inclusive) were being handled incorrectly. An sshd with an 850-bit
server key wasn't able to accept connections from PuTTY as a result.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
pscp now has the "&lt;code&gt;-ls&lt;/code&gt;" option to get a directory
listing of a remote host. It does this by sending the command
"&lt;code&gt;ls -la &lt;/code&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;dirspec&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;", so it might well not work
on non-Unix ssh servers. It's mainly there to allow a useful
directory listing facility for potential GUI front ends.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Local line discipline is now invoked in more sensible circumstances,
and understands Telnet Erase Line. Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Blinking cursor support (off by default). Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
xterm mouse tracking support, thanks to Wez Furlong.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Hopefully vastly improved PuTTY's behaviour under load; also we can
process incoming data even during a window move/resize. Thanks to
Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Better handling of the bug in which underlines are drawn outside the
character cell. Now they don't get drawn at _all_, which is still
non-ideal but it's better than rampaging screen corruption. Thanks
to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Various terminal emulation upgrades. Thanks to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
By popular demand, Shift-Tab now sends ESC [ Z instead of being
indistinguishable from ordinary Tab.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
^C, ^Z and ^D now instruct the local-terminal line discipline to
send Telnet special control codes. The local line discipline can
also be enabled and disabled in mid-session without dropping data,
and it's also linked to the Telnet ECHO option. Patch due to Robert
de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Telnet SYNCH is now preceded by IAC, which it wasn't previously.
Patch due to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fixed the long-standing bug in which CSI ? Q and CSI Q were treated
identically for most values of Q. Patch due to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Pressing Return in a Telnet session now sends Telnet NL instead of
Telnet CR (in raw data, that's CR-LF not CR-NUL; ^J continues to
send just LF). Unix telnetds should not notice any difference;
others might suddenly start working. Patch due to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Much patchery in font selection code; with any luck, mixed OEM+ANSI
line drawing mode will now be more reliable. Patch due to Robert de
Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
An attempt has been made to deal with the dropping of incoming data
between decoding and display.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Replaced all the algorithms that weren't already my own code. The
DES, MD5, SHA, and CRC32 implementations used in PuTTY are now all
written by me and distributable under the PuTTY licence, instead of
being borrowed from a variety of other places. Better still, there
are &lt;em&gt;comments&lt;/em&gt;: the DES implementation contains a careful
description of how the algorithm given in the spec was transformed
into the optimised algorithm in the code, and the CRC32
implementation explains what a CRC is and how the table lookup
algorithm works.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Scrollback behaviour has changed. ANSI Delete Line at the top of the
screen now inserts the lines into the scrollback (previously, only
genuine scroll-up would do this). However, the scrollback is never
touched by scroll operations in the alternate screen.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The response to Ctrl-E is now "PuTTY" instead of the xtermalike
sequence it was previously.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
The command line option &lt;code&gt;-log&lt;/code&gt; will now cause all data
received from the remote host to be logged to a file
&lt;code&gt;putty.log&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
PSCP now doesn't try to "recurse" into the directories
&lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt; like it did before.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Add keyboard accelerators on the System menu.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
"Warn On Close" no longer applies to inactive windows: you can close
one of those without complaint.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
There is now a system to generate Borland and Cygnus makefiles from
the master makefile, so that people can build PuTTY with other
compilers but I still only have to maintain one makefile.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.49.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.49.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2000 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.48 (released 1999-11-18):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Cyrillic support: optional KOI8 to Win1251 translation, an internal
version of the Cyrillic key map for machines that don't have it
installed systemwide, and support for selecting a character set in
the font configuration. All thanks to Oleg Panashchenko.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for the TIS authentication option (to the client, this looks
much like a form of password authentication, so there's no local
state involved).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
SSH mode now shows an Event Log of all the initial protocol setup,
to match the Telnet negotiation log.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Alt-F4 as "close window" can be configured off. Alt-Space as System
menu is now an option and can be configured on, although it doesn't
work very well (you have to press Down after hitting Alt-Space).

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
NetHack keypad mode mapping (shift-with-)numeric-keypad to
(shift-with-)hjklyubn. Unfortunately Shift only works when NumLock
is off, which is a bit odd.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
An implementation of the &lt;em&gt;scp&lt;/em&gt; client, as a separate binary.
Many thanks to Joris van Rantwijk.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Change the default title bar format to "host.name - PuTTY" rather
than "PuTTY: host.name", so as to be more useful in the taskbar.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Warning box "are you sure you want to disconnect?" on hitting the
Close button or Alt-F4 or whatever.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Telnet mode was reported to drop char-255, presumably due to
mishandling IAC IAC. Fix due to Robert de Bath.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Add some keyboard accelerators in the configuration box.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
A raw-TCP connection option, alongside Telnet and SSH. Thanks to
Mark Baker.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
A local line-editing line discipline, which can be layered over any
of the back end connection options. Most usefully, this can be used
to make the raw-TCP back end suitable for talking to finger, SMTP,
POP, NNTP etc. servers.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
A small tool-tip that shows the size of the terminal window in
character cells while it's being resized, so you can drag it out to
a precise size. Many thanks to John Sullivan, who achieved this
despite other people supporting my belief that it was impossible.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Single DES as an SSH encryption option, as well as triple DES.
Thanks to Murphy Lam.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Support for using ssh by default: a &lt;code&gt;-ssh&lt;/code&gt; command line
option, a compile-time definition &lt;code&gt;SSH_DEFAULT&lt;/code&gt;, and the
ability to honour port and protocol (and host!) settings in the
"Default Settings" part of the registry if they've been manually
inserted.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Made stored sessions available as a submenu from the system menu.
Thanks to Owen Dunn.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Minimal Win32s compatibility, as a &lt;em&gt;compile-time&lt;/em&gt; option (so
it's not in the snapshot binaries but is in the snapshot source
releases). The configuration box apparently doesn't work, but the
actual sessions will run OK. Thanks to Owen Dunn.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.48.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.48.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 1999 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.47 (released 1999-08-27):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Fixed a potential security flaw in the random number generator.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.47.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.47.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 1999 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.46 (released 1999-07-09):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug causing hangs when an SSH window was resized after
the connection was closed. I'd never spotted it, because I never use
Close Window On Exit...

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Default mouse pointer inside the PuTTY window is now an I-beam.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for AltGr. As it turns out, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; possible to do
this without also changing the behaviour of Ctrl/LeftAlt. Many
thanks to &amp;lt;andre@via.ecp.fr&amp;gt; for inventing a way to achieve
this.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Resource/memory leaks are apparently fixed. I'm going to assume they
&lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; completely fixed, unless someone mails me to suggest
otherwise.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fixed the bug in the configuration box whereby double-clicking on a
saved session leaked the double click through to the window below.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
ESC[?9r was being interpreted just like ESC[9r, with disastrous
results (the former turns off mouse click reporting, which PuTTY
doesn't support yet anyway; the latter munges the scroll region
horribly). Fixed, in a temporary sort of way.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Added Blowfish encryption as an alternative to triple-DES.

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.46.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.46.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 1999 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>0.45 (released 1999-01-22):</title><description>&lt;li&gt;
Fix the GPF on maximise-then-restore.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Fix the delayed update of the window title when in
always-use-window-title mode and iconic.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Employ SetCapture() to allow drag-selects to continue to work when
the pointer drifts out of the window.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Some platforms apparently define the identifier "environ" as a
macro; stop using it inside PuTTY.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Add an option to ask SSH not to allocate a pty.

&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Add a terminal setting to cause LF to imply CR (useful with the
above).

&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.45.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/releases/0.45.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 1999 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>putty</provider_id><provider_name>PuTTY</provider_name><route_path>/changes</route_path><route_name>Change Log</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.19.1 (Beta)</title><description>&lt;h3&gt;New&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tab-Completion As You Type&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the back of cards, you’ll now get tab-completions to help you finish what you’re typing. They’ll automatically adjust based on what you’ve typed, to help save you time when writing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-5ed5451e463e02804d2e946e1028156d.gif" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;LaTeX Syntax Highlighting&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LaTeX expressions now have syntax highlighting!&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-f0a0ac3145a9cab4c1f9151a88393851.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Quick-Preview for Advanced Tables&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clicking the “open” button on an advanced table row opens a new quick-preview panel on the right. This makes it easier to look through the different rows in a table without losing your place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-e925d96e8c2684c574ffe1c445ee72ee.gif" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imported toggles from Notion now automatically turn into flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enabled cloze deletions inside inline code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Bugfixes &amp;amp; Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added email recovery setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed explanation popups appearing behind AI explanations in PDFs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed header misalignment when scrolling past tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top-aligned action buttons in table rows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overhauled several Flashcard Insights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moved cursor correctly after pressing Alt+Enter to create a new table row.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed “Open Image in Popup” for images inside table cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed AI tutor missing full webpage context from RemNote chat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polished various small table UI details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed AI text area issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed color inconsistency in background group highlights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automatically converted back-of-card tables into multi-line flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed AI generation placeholder showing for multi-line cards when AI is off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added file links in daily backup settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opened the right sidebar editor and focused the Rem when opening video Rems from search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed PDF summary generation failure when strings contain backslashes and percent signs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added error checking for empty elements in multiple-choice quiz generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed cluster card KB setting failing to disable cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved error handling for YouTube videos with missing transcripts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reworked split pane for notes and added persistent sizing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed popup overlay appearing when a simple table cell is focused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-19-1-beta</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-19-1-beta</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 11:13:29 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>🎉 1.19 - Tables V2: Simple Tables, Table Flashcards, and Advanced Tables! 🎉</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;RemNote 1.19 makes tables simpler and more useful, accelerating your learning and thinking:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple Tables: &lt;/strong&gt;Simple grids of cells that are perfect for flashcards, organized data, grids of information, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table Flashcards: &lt;/strong&gt;See the context of an entire table on a flashcard, while being tested on each cell individually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cell Formatting:&lt;/strong&gt; Align, highlight, and center content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Premium Elevenlabs Text-to-Speech&lt;/strong&gt;: Enable automatic text-to-speech for columns that generate flashcards (perfect for language learning).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standalone Advanced Tables: &lt;/strong&gt;Create tables that directly store their rows (no need to worry about tags).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Generate Tables: &lt;/strong&gt;Create entire tables just by pressing tab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="aspect-video my-3"&gt;&lt;div class="aspect-video my-3"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/otFpbccGgvc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="h-full w-full" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;🔲 &lt;strong&gt;Simple Tables&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now create &lt;em&gt;simple Tables&lt;/em&gt;! These are perfect for simple situations where you just want to put some information into rows and columns. Use them for flashcards, organized data, grids of information, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create one with &lt;code&gt;/simple table&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-e298c87e513769dc5da45357ccc6b945.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or use the bottom toolbar:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-cf8653fc3b2469f3b09bf8763a88de8b.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple tables are easy to manipulate. You can type directly in any cell, drag to add new rows/columns, format, add cards, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They’re also standalone: you can think of them as a single thing, with all the data located exactly where the table is. You don’t need to worry about tags, linking, rows in different places in your knowledge base, and so on. (If you do want those things, scroll down to “Advanced Tables” at the bottom of this changelog!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting Simple Tables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can add colors, highlights, text formats, text alignment, and more to your simple tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format entire rows/columns:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-ca09187090453d1bd3261c53126da777.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or drag to select and then format individual cells:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-fa7c34c5d677eea3aee6b0e2b209238b.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tables On Multi-Line Cards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can add simple tables on the back of a multi-line flashcard:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-b7fbc2b6774f14996a1ccc90ba502f77.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Header Rows/Columns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hide or show headers (the gray rows / columns) based on your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-05de5533633a4a904a1d9cd73d6f66d1.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;🗂️ Table Flashcards&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Show Entire Table” Mode&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to putting a simple table on the back of a card, you can also create flashcards that test individual cells of a table while showing the context of the whole table. From the “cards” menu on any table (simple or advanced), choose the “Show Entire Table” mode.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-62d6219cfd0ab6964c2445be769d521f.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On your first practice, you’ll be tested on the cells in order, one by one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-ebea1848f246ecc80337146b8e84e79b.gif" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each cell tracks its own spaced-repetition history and has its own schedule. If you get some cells wrong, the ones you need more practice on will come back individually later. RemNote will group together all the cards in a given table that you need to practice on the same day to minimize context-switching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling Individual Cells / Columns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can enable individual columns from the column’s &lt;strong&gt;…&lt;/strong&gt; menu:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-9e931e66309fb9123ceb8ed96165efe1.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;…or enable individual cells:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-8e5e9b038cc63b0bb679e2ae37245816.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;…or enable the entire table from the cards menu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the cards menu, you can choose which columns to practice, and whether you want to be tested in row/column order or in random order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-13de114a0cd2d95fafbea216b093a38d.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Type in Answer” and “Text to Speech” Options for Columns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a column’s “Configure Cards” menu, you can now enable “type in answer” and ”text to speech” at the columns level. All flashcards in this column will have these settings applied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-184112f141cb38ca3c1fac717bbb100f.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Premium Elevenlabs Text to Speech for Columns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For language learners, we’ve also added premium Elevenlabs text-to-speech to table columns. Enable the text-to-speech to have words and phrases pronounced on your flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: &lt;/strong&gt;This uses premium Elevenlabs voices to ensure high-quality pronunciation. These are expensive, so they use AI credits. 1000 characters (~100 words) cost 600 AI credits. We’ll only charge you for each word once the first time it’s pronounced; after that we’ll keep the audio around and reuse it. (Pro+AI subscribers get 20,000 monthly AI credits. We’re still providing all AI credits at cost – this is what Elevenlabs is charging us.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-bb1ad0d9e5b1a259d7916d76914bfe7e.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;📋 Advanced Tables&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides adding Simple Tables, we’ve redesigned the existing tables feature and renamed those tables to &lt;em&gt;Advanced Tables&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Look and Feel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced tables now have a cleaner top row. We’ve emphasized the title more, added an “Add Row” button, and redesigned the config buttons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-e29671622bbdbada3f4e69c58adfa72f.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, table rows now have the standard “zoom in” bullet instead of the “Open” button. This keeps the “name” column cleaner on tables where you don’t frequently zoom in to individual rows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-e312290ceeed9fe4a0f982d978e5b914.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For tables where you frequently zoom in to rows, we’ve added a “Turn Every Row into a Document” option. This brings back the “Open” button on each row and visually distinguishes them:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-89048fb6697d008859df57b259f469e1.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-694c8005cf5125184eb49a38e86b456c.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standalone Advanced Tables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced Tables are still powered by tags behind the scenes, but we’ve reduced the need to think about tags in many cases. (If you still like using tags, read below! Everything is still supported.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All rows for the table are now stored directly in the table itself, without creating a separate tag in the “Tags” page. When you zoom in to a table row, you’ll now see the document you came from in the breadcrumb at the top of your document. This makes navigation and table manipulation easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you create a table with &lt;code&gt;/table&lt;/code&gt;, it’s now treated as the special &lt;em&gt;primary table&lt;/em&gt; where the information is stored. If you create other views to the table’s tag (using &lt;code&gt;/existing table&lt;/code&gt;), a “&lt;strong&gt;↗” &lt;/strong&gt;arrow will appear to indicate that this is a &lt;em&gt;secondary table&lt;/em&gt;. You can click on this arrow to jump to the primary table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-c64bda47a0f30fe484ff51935f79fc3a.png" data-size="full" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using Tables and Tags&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you prefer creating a tag first and then creating a table from it, you can stick with that! Just make a document for your tag, then use the &lt;code&gt;/existing table&lt;/code&gt; command to make a table for it. We still think this is a great way to do things like organizing #Ideas or #Projects from across your knowledge base. Note that we’ve also simplified the “tags” pages, to help you focus on your own notes without extra elements on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bulk-Edit Rows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After clicking the checkboxes next to desired rows, you can bulk-edit their values from the new floating toolbar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-480d9ac4fba4f599152ccfa8cf370b5c.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;📋 New Table Creation Options&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy From the Web, ChatGPT, or the AI Tutor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now copy tables from outside RemNote and paste them into the editor to create a simple table. You can then enable flashcards or change the formatting if you like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-3f9ccc5daea0a0d7e1caf8393bde3984.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live AI Column Autofill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enable the “AI Autofill” option on any column except the initial &lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Name&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; column. When you fill in the &lt;em&gt;Name&lt;/em&gt; column, any columns with autofill on will be automatically pre-filled based on their column names.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-f8b5b1585f8ff15dff2d8e1c427955a3.gif" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Generated Tables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create entire table structures by pressing Tab. Just type the name of your table and see suggestions for columns based on that name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-ad77ee4a379e6579f704b92cffbb3689.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press Tab to accept them. Then press Tab again to add suggested rows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-31a7a676b7b2b58c45b9ef9c2e86be79.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After selecting rows, the entire table with all columns will be AI autofilled for you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-164b164edfe5a17230d447cbfd8aa42b.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating Tables from Images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paste in an image of a table (screenshot or handwritten), and press “AI Convert to Text” to get it automatically formatted as a table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-4d3df7b44af678f583b6c35f4732d534.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve also made hundreds of bug-fixes and smaller improvements since 1.18.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with all of our updates, we heavily prioritized these new changes based on our community feedback, on the feedback forum, discord, reddit, and elsewhere. Thank you for helping us to build the world’s best tool for learning and thinking! Even more is on the way 👀&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-19-tables-v2-simple-tables-table-flashcards-and-advanced-tables</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-19-tables-v2-simple-tables-table-flashcards-and-advanced-tables</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 11:37:36 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.59</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed ElevenLabs TTS failing with a 403 error despite having AI credits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved AI functionality in tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moved "Image" above "Right Floating Image" in slash commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed dark mode in the keyboard shortcut dialog and improved iconography.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed document content not rendering when switching documents from the sidebar while a PDF is open with the editor on the left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added basic undo/redo functionality to the omnibar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed new table cell list items becoming orphaned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed flashcards not appearing after a page reload.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed cloze cards not working properly in grid tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cleaned up custom scheduler settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved grid table portals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed flashcard counter tap issues in the queue on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed card table preview popup being cut off on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed merge columns in tables showing extra elements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-59</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-59</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 08:23:44 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.58</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where highlighting text in PDFs triggered the system Copy/Paste popup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved Markdown export by URL-encoding paths to Rems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enabled "Edit Now" for tables to work in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added Sonnet 3.7 (reasoning and non-reasoning) to the list of supported AI chat models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed a typo in the "Practice cards with images?" screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Updated the Magic Copy-Paste and Rewrite language dropdowns to use the standard language selector component.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed formatting issues on the 404 page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where the AI Tutor keyboard dismissed incorrectly on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-58</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-58</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 14:53:41 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.57</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed area highlight sometimes not working on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed issues preventing clicks on table properties in user knowledge bases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed definition card table type not responding to configuration changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed incorrect rendering of the horizontal scrollbar in grid tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed dark mode issue with filter input fields.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed inability to collapse long advanced tables with filters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disabled the "You can also press Tab to indent" message for tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added an insight for Explanation flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed multiple table-related issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed issue where selecting multiple files at once didn't upload all of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed resizing PDF area highlights causing them to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved language handling in magic copy-paste.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed flashcard indicator arrow disappearing in PDF viewer notes after creating a card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replaced grid table setting labels with tooltips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ensured the cursor stays in view when using horizontal keyboard navigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-57</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-57</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 19:26:32 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.55</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed a crash when enabling or disabling AI features while the PDF reader is open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added new table shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed various table issues and polished the UI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed stuck selection when dragging off the page while making a PDF area highlight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed PDF Annotator focusing on the left part of the PDF after zooming and resizing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed tag filters not working.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed all notes filters being hidden under the bottom bar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved tables with multiple bug fixes and UI enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed the "Practice All Flashcards in Order" option for the Cards Table practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed image cells not expanding fully in full-height tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hid "flashcard configuration" on the primary column.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-55</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-55</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 18:13:47 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.54</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improvements &amp;amp; Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add AI autofill for tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed slow loading on the web.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed the daily template selector not appearing reactively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prevented table occlusion cards from scrolling away when showing insights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue on mobile where applying too large a zoom caused the PDF annotator to jump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed a flickering issue when clicking on a yellow highlight in the "Create AI Cards" popup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cleaned up names of flashcard keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-54</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-54</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:51:17 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.53</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved iOS app stability when switching between apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed iOS sign-in getting stuck on step 3/3 for some larger knowledge bases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Made route change undo more meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed multiple issues with the Markdown exporter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed checkboxes not immediately appearing when converting a single-line card into a multi-line card in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed some cards incorrectly appearing with a flag despite no exam being set in the knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed a weird login message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed issues selecting some cards in the cards table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed React errors when scrolling in certain knowledge bases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved etymology parsing when adding cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed handling of multiple PDFs in the upload selector on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed PDF highlight previews mistakenly replacing newlines with an empty string.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed some tags not displaying when another tag is deleted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defaulted AI features to English.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Added support for AI converting images to tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed ElevenLabs English voices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Made it less annoying if you accidentally pick "Import" instead of "Upload" and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-53</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-53</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:16:44 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.52 (Labs) - Grid Tables, Occlusion Tables, and new Advanced Tables in Labs!</title><description>&lt;div class="callout red"&gt;Enable these new experimental features by going to &lt;strong&gt;Settings &amp;gt; Labs &amp;gt; Grid Tables Labs.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please share feedback on these experimental features in &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" href="https://discord.com/channels/689979930804617224/1344443305215131698"&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;! We have a number of additional upgrades to them coming shortly as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;New in Labs - Grid Tables&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now add a &lt;em&gt;Grid Table&lt;/em&gt;! These are perfect for flashcards, organized data, grids of information, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After enabling the “Grid Tables Labs” setting, add a grid table with &lt;code&gt;/grid table&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-8fd23a72d774ac6a8e40984efc25720f.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or, use the bottom toolbar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-a5372d7709cf4cadf002274267e8b7f5.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grid tables are easy to manipulate. You can type directly in any cell, drag to add new rows/columns, format, add cards, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grid tables are standalone - you can think of them as a self-contained grid of cells. You don’t need to worry about tags, linking, etc. (If you do want those, scroll down to “Advanced Tables” at the bottom of this changelog!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Formatting&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format grid tables with colors, highlights, text formats, text alignment, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-5ed697c6f5739d6ae0671eeec1784e5e.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Format entire rows/columns:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-87376cc99600f3c477589235b2312b8f.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or, drag to select and then format any individual cells:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-a7a27618934d79741adc775d174ba8ed.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tables On Multi-Line Cards&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add grid tables anywhere. For example, you can add them on the back of a multi-line flashcard, and they’ll appear in your flashcards queue:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-d48e9a3e1f10120cc99d33adcac9562f.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Headers Rows/Columns&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hide or show headers (the gray rows / columns) based on your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-df8fa66c885aa0393b78114ad5e97c37.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;New in Labs - Tables Flashcard Options&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;“Show Entire Table” Mode&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now test the entirety of a table on a flashcard! From the “cards” menu on your table, switch to “Show Entire Table”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-bcae7dec333672df184a5b0386314750.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’ll be tested on every cell, one by one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-b7e61e60e06a42946c0e54e47656c07f.gif" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each cell still tracks its own spaced repetition history, and has its own schedule. If you get some cells wrong, they’ll come back separately to test you on them, per their own spaced repetition schedule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Enabling Cards in Tables&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br&gt;You can enable individual cells from the cell’s “…” menu:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-1a535f059b2729504eebf00a4846d841.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or individual columns:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-4629bd2dd4278dd99b01ddf4e0cd87ed.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or the entire table from the "cards” menu! In the cards menu, you can quick-configure which columns to practice, and if you’ll be tested in order or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-40f013fe6e5a91ac8e87fc7eef9a96e6.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;“Type in Answer” and “Text to Speech” Options for Columns&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a column’s “Configure Cards” menu, you can now enable “type in answer” and ”text to speech” at the columns level. All flashcards in this column will have these settings applied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-9f3e22cb17a6ba09c36f5649ddd61e06.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Premium Text to Speech for Columns&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For language learners, we’ve also added premium Elevenlabs text to speech to tables. Enable the text-to-speech to learn the pronunciation of words in the language of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-dabb8c2196ada6c5aec5698035c93590.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;New In Labs - Advanced Tables&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve redesigned the existing tables feature, and renamed them “Advanced Tables”.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;New Look and Feel&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advanced tables now have a nicer top-row. We’ve emphasized the title more, added an easier “Add Row” button, and cleaned up the config buttons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-c81715b827bcce703553f832f1a87b32.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, table rows now have the standard “zoom in” bullet instead of the “Open” button. This keeps the “name” column cleaner on tables where you don’t frequently zoom in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-7b14428aa7a84be9e952442d76fbf5e4.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For tables where you frequently zoom in, we’ve added a “Turn Every Row into a Document” option. This brings back the “Open” button on each row, and visually distinguishes them:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-34d8adc35ee03f4fda14b87a614b6889.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-ba6e4417c6a97e144dd7b031fc91c3b9.png" data-size="small" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Standalone Advanced Tables&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tables are still powered by tags in the backend, but we’ve significantly de-emphasized tags in the new setup. (If you still like using tags, read below! Everything is still supported).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;All rows for the table are now stored directly in the table itself, without creating a separate tag in the “Tags” page. When you zoom into a table row, you’ll now see the document you came from in the breadcrumbs at the top of your document. This makes navigation and table manipulation easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you create a table with &lt;code&gt;/table&lt;/code&gt;, it’s now treated as a special “primary table” where the information is stored. If you create other views to the table’s tag (using &lt;code&gt;/existing table&lt;/code&gt;), a “&lt;strong&gt;↗” &lt;/strong&gt;arrow will appear to indicate that this is a “secondary” table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="https://vault.featureos.app/uploads/attachment/upload/thumb-f32fec93b202cba8a3ce6507c9126748.png" data-size="medium" referrerpolicy="no-referrer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Using Tables and Tags&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you prefer the existing setup where you create a tag first, you can stick with that! Just make a document for your tag, then use the &lt;code&gt;/existing table&lt;/code&gt; command to make a table to it. For example, we still think this is a great way to organize #Ideas, #Projects, etc. from across your knowledge base. Note that we’ve also simplified down the “tags” pages, to help you focus on your own notes without excessive extra elements on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-52-labs-grid-tables-occlusion-tables-and-new-advanced-tables-in-labs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-52-labs-grid-tables-occlusion-tables-and-new-advanced-tables-in-labs</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 22:56:43 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.18.51</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed labs setting referencing a removed settings option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fix routing getting stuck on web when a new version is available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved importing - allowed matching Obsidian documents based on their name without requiring the full path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed an issue where "Why True" was appearing even when not applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed the pricing tier grid not spanning the full width on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-51</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://feedback.remnote.com/changelog/1-18-51</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 18:03:25 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>remnote</provider_id><provider_name>RemNote</provider_name><route_path>/changelog</route_path><route_name>Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.10.5-dev</title><description>Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.10" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix error dialog when open md file from Explorer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support export toPDF with background and dark theme on Windows / Linux.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.10.5-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.10.5-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.10.3-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid to 11.4.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Toggle alert from menubar now follows the same logic as blockquote.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support convert to TextBundle when insert images.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix file contains some emojis are not detected as UTF-8 encode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix window fullscreen / maximize state not restored on Typora restart.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix typing on last line of code block may make the app hangs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix adding anchor link to headings with "+" character not work correctly after export.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.10.3-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.10.3-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.10.2-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid to 11.3 with new Packet and Architecture diagram and new flowchart shapes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Experiment support for TextBundle now comes to macOS dev version.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add url syntax support for code blocks. This syntax highlight an URL with its procotol, host, port, query and hash.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now all languages can select piclist as the image uploader.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better logic when user select “alert” from menubar, now it will convert selected parts into Github style alerts instead of always insert new one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow user to insert images with jfif extension.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Show mdx file in sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix mouse click on untitled filename in window titlebar not popping up file rename panel on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix file contains emoji cannot be correctly auto detected as UTF8 on Windows / Linux.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix select lists and toggle list type not work as expected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix lags when input at the last line of a code block.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.10.2-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.10.2-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.9.2-dev</title><description>Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.9" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to render gitlab / github style math block.&lt;/li&gt;\&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid library, add Block diagram support.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix parse rules to handle whitespace in code.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix anchor id for headers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other bug fix and improvements&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.9.2-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.9.2-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.8.3-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Update Update translation for Spanish, French, Galician, Slovenian, Vietnamese and Chinese.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix cursor position after inputting emoji.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix github alert icon.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix math equation export issue for docx.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use empety value for meta tag if referenced variables are undefined in YAML.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix YAML parse rule when key is quoted.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.8.3-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.8.3-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.8.3-dev</title><description>Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.8" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;New&lt;li&gt;Support github style alert.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option for zoom and zoom with mouse wheel.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade MermaidJS with XY Chart support.&lt;/li&gt;Improvements&lt;li&gt;Linux now support separate theme for light and dark mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Option to add “New Markdown” menu item in Windows Explorer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Typora now uses mermaid own dark theme when rendering mermaid in dark mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve performance and stability.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix window position in multiple monitor.&lt;/li&gt;Fix&lt;li&gt;Fix save as image for diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hide “copy as HTML” for unsupported blocks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add “copy as HTML” support for mermaid diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix “PicList not found” error when using PicList to upload images.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.8.3-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.8.3-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.8.1-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix PDF export on 1.8.0.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add support for Github style alert.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to add Markdown item in "New" context menu on Windows explorer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix upload images using PicList.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix "Copy as Image".&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hide copy as html when not supported.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other bug fix.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.8.1-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.8.1-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.7.2-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.7" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid to 10.3.1, supports Sankey diagrams and Quadrant Chart.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add menu item for outline popover.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix cursor jump after :emoji:.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix shift + down on task lists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix checkbox style on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix anchor link related issues.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.7.2-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.7.2-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.7.0-dev</title><description>Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.7" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;New&lt;li&gt;Add menu item to open outline popover (macOS) and Wordcount popover.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Larger scrollbar when hover on Windows/ Linux.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add Modelica language syntax support.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add delete diagram option in context menu.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add options to not save recent folders / files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add buttons to pin and remove recent folders from sidebar panel.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add variable &lt;code&gt;${outputFolder}&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;${outputFolderName}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;Improvements and Fix&lt;li&gt;Better paste list from Apple Notes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve open file with anchor locations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix sort order not saved after restart Typora.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Header and footers now respect page margins when export to PDF.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix exporting ordered list when using theme Whitey.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;typora-root-url&lt;/code&gt; now supports absolute image path on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix filename suggestion is improper when first heading is under editing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix indent in code blocks not kept when paste into other web apps on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Non-exist &lt;code&gt;#anchor&lt;/code&gt; links is now preserved.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disable &lt;code&gt;alert&lt;/code&gt; in embeded iframes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix shortcut key for upload image cannot be set.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix drag files from file sidebar on some Linux distributions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix app not responsive when do line-wise cut on empty line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix some issues about cut line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix indent issue when indent paragraph is enabled on macOS ≥ 13&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix improper behavior when press shift + arrow key then press arrow key on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix typo of the menu item for Greek encoding option on Windows / Linux.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix code language autocomplete not work for &lt;code&gt;~~~&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix security issue STAR-2023-0062&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add menu item of “jump to line start”, fix Ctrl + A/E on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add batch as alias of &lt;code&gt;BAT&lt;/code&gt; in code language selector.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix some meta data on YAML not get read or applied on export.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.7.0-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.7.0-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.6.4-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add Thai language&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support default code language&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bug fix&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix math block on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix sometimes Typora cannot open older md file on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.6.4-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.6.4-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.6.1-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Add option to set default file extensions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to control behaviors when drop file or folders into Typora.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve UI / UX for preferences panel.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix a mermaid rendering bug.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix inline math option in preferences cannot be checked.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.6.1-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.6.1-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.6.0-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add options to disable auto link.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add PicList image uploader option.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade to mermaid 10.1, support timeline diagram.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Version 1.6 no longer supports Windows 7/8.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.6.0-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.6.0-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.5.4-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.5" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid to 9.3, fix some rendering bugs.&lt;/li&gt;Originally in 1.5.0-dev&lt;li&gt;Add yara code syntax highlight.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shift + Tab will outdent selected contents in code block and source code mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve syntax highlight in source code mode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid version which brings bug fix and MindMaps.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Highlight is supported and converted when export to LaTeX.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve export functions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add quantity option for image export.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow open local file link contains “#” in file path.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve paste results from Google Docs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This version supports Windows 7 again. Now Typora subscribe to different update channel on Windows 7 and newer Windows versions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Link url starts like `C:/` will also be recognized as absolute path on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better restore icon for unibody style.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add new UI language: Norwegian, and update some other language translations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The dev versions for Windows / Linux now supports TextBundle format as an experimental feature&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.5.4-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.5.4-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.4.1-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;New&lt;li&gt;Add copy as image option for math and diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to mix files and folders when sorting in file tree.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add sort by creation time option for file tree / file list.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;File tree view and file list view now is configured separately.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Increase max line count for global search results.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fuzzy search in &lt;code&gt;Open Quickly&lt;/code&gt; will now also match folder path.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add new math auto numbering rule — AMS Numbering Rules (where only certain environments produce numbered equations, as they would be in LaTeX).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to always add “./” when generating relative path for images.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;rename image&lt;/code&gt; in context menu. (Which is the same menu item with &lt;code&gt;move images&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve Pascal lang support, add more keyword highlight for Pascal.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add syntax support for Smarty.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve performance when using find function and prevent hangs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make search result more readable compared to &lt;code&gt;==highlight==&lt;/code&gt; texts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Increase max col count in table edit UI.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now user can select multiple cols and apply text align from table tool tip all at once.&lt;/li&gt;Fix&lt;li&gt;Fix bugs about switching files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix triple click on code block.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix code block height not auto changed when enter or exit fullscreen mode on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make font color of completed task more readable in dark themes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix some rendering issue for mermaidjs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove unnecessary horizontal scroll bar on side bar.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix undo deleted file not displayed in file tree view.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix error when switch files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix hint behavior when hover on folders of sidebar menu.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use smaller margin between math block and normal paragraphs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix compatibility issues when search with Tai.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PDF export now supports headers or footers contains non-ASSIC code when export.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve image export quantity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix PDF export not working on Windows when user account contains special characters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix epub export show warnings in epub reader when contains video tag&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix page size setting of PDF not working on macOS when export.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix the setting of margin right and margin left of PDF not correctly applied when export.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix last export path not saved on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix docx import fail on newer pandoc versions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix replace may ignore search results matches with regular expressions contains non-capture groups.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix move images not working for windows.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve performance when md file contains &lt;code&gt;video&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix a caret jump issue when typing after inline math.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix minor issues with spellcheck.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update language translations.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.4.1-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.4.1-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.4.0-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mermaid version.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade mathjax version.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add copy as image option for math and diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to mix files and folders when sorting in file tree.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;File tree view and file list view now is configured separately.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to always add “./” when generating relative path for images.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.4.0-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.4.0-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.3.3-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.3" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support download / copy / move all image files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support auto move image folders when rename current document in Typora.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Show total match count in find and replace panel.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support regular expression in find and replace panel, and also file search.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support save as image file for rich media, like diagram, math, images, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add more options in "copy / paste as" context menu.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update UI translations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve compatibility with Sougo IME.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix abbreviation like e.g. is always marked as misspelled word.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other bug fix and improvements.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.3-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.3-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.3.2-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix activation status not kept in 1.3.1-dev.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.2-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.2-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.3.1-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Add Handi language support and update UI translations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve copied and exported html source content.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update image for replace operation, fix search with html entities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix some bugs about text selection.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix poster support for video element.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix live rendering for footnote.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix parsing rules about hr in lists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix copy table header may include control elements.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix save detection when editing inside code blocks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix display issue for code block line number when window resize and export.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix issues about open links to other file with anchor position.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix select line at first char of line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep unicode quote when import.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix context menu for code fences.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix PDF export pay produce empty page as the last page.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.1-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.1-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.3.0-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Fix iframe rendering.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix spellchecker does not keep learned words.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.0-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.3.0-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.2.2-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upgrade Mermaid library version.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support move and delete images.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Undo a copy image operation will now also remove the copied image.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add new image uploader Picsee (macOS).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve performance when document contains large set of images (macOS).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better encode detection (Windows / Linux).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add docker, py and code language alias, add stata, postgresql, hive syntax highlight.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other bug fix.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.2.2-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.2.2-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.2.0-dev</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Improve performance when editing file with many large images on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.2.0-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.2.0-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.1.1-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve delete current block and delete current line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update i18n translations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix title bar display for auto save.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other bug fix.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.1.1-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.1.1-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.1.0-dev</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;See &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.1/" target="_blank"&gt;detail&lt;/a&gt;.New / Improvements&lt;li&gt;Add Malay language support.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add Slovenian language support.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix typo and update translations in other languages.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow create file when open non-exist file via command line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow create file when open target link that does not have existing file.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow open other files' anchor position directly via file link.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More compact context menu under Windows / Linux.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support copy / cut while line when nothing is selected.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add option to disable or enable physics package.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allow pasting markdown with Command-Option-Shift-V on macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support offline activation and provide web UI to manage used license code.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sign Windows executables and installers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support default / theme font size for exported image.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ensure downloaded image has image file extension.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support loading local image files with user append hashes.&lt;/li&gt;Fix&lt;li&gt;Fix security issue which may cause XSS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix custom font size for exported image.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix multiple BOM be added when saving files with BOM header.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix copy as MathML not working for math block.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix math auto numbering get wrongly numbered labels.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix file tree UI under smaller customer font size.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix always on top cannot be turned off under macOS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix image corrupted if your Typora is zoomed.&lt;/li&gt;</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.1.0-dev</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.1.0-dev</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>1.0.0</title><description>&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;macOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;dmg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (32bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Windows (ARM)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;exe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (64bit)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (ARM)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;deb&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-label"&gt;Linux (ARM)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="download-extension"&gt;tar&lt;/span&gt;Typora finally reaches v1.0 🎉🎉🎉🎉Read More in &lt;a href="https://support.typora.io/What's-New-1.0" target="_blank"&gt;What's New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.typora.io/" target="_blank"&gt;Purchase Now&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Old Beta0.11.181. Add warnings when user try to edit file from backup location.2. Line break should be rendered as whitespace when ignore line break is enabled.3. Fix new file in tile tree will result to duplicate files.4. Fix bug that table with tabs cannot be correct parsed.5. Fix inline math preview issue.6. Fix bug that users cannot jump from some internal links.7. Fix some cursor issue.8. Fix some copy related menu get disabled when selecting multiple blocks.</description><link>https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.0.0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://typora.io/releases/dev#1.0.0</guid><route><provider_id>typora</provider_id><provider_name>Typora</provider_name><route_path>/changelog/dev</route_path><route_name>Dev Release Changelog</route_name></route></item><item><title>TrafegoDNS (ghcr.io/elmerfds/trafegodns:latest)</title><description>TrafegoDNS automatically manages DNS records based on container configuration. It supports both Traefik integration and direct Docker container label mode, making it compatible with any web server or reverse proxy solution.&lt;br&gt;    Key Features:&lt;br&gt;    - Supports multiple DNS providers (Cloudflare, DigitalOcean, Route53)&lt;br&gt;    - Two operation modes: Traefik API integration or direct Docker labels&lt;br&gt;    - Optional cleanup of orphaned DNS records&lt;br&gt;    - Real-time monitoring of Docker container events&lt;br&gt;    - Please refer to the readme before deploying this container: https://github.com/elmerfds/TrafegoDNS</description><link>https://github.com/elmerfds/TrafegoDNS</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/elmerfds/TrafegoDNS</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 23:10:09 GMT</pubDate><category>Tools-Utilities</category><category>Network-Management</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>Dependency-Track-API-Server (dependencytrack/apiserver)</title><description>API Server to be used with Dependency-Track Front-End&lt;br&gt;Dependency-Track is an intelligent Component Analysis platform that allows organizations to identify and reduce risk in the software supply chain. Dependency-Track takes a unique and highly beneficial approach by leveraging the capabilities of Software Bill of Materials (SBOM). This approach provides capabilities that traditional Software Composition Analysis (SCA) solutions cannot achieve.&lt;br&gt;For more details about Dependency-Track see the projects website at dependencytrack.org Please note this application is not lightweight and uses 8-12GB of ram to run</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/dependencytrack/apiserver</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/dependencytrack/apiserver</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:32:36 GMT</pubDate><category>Security</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>CloudBeaver (dbeaver/cloudbeaver)</title><description>Cloud Database Manager (Official Docker Image)&lt;br&gt;As an open-source product it already supports the most popular open source databases, such as PostgreSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, SQLite and Firebird.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/dbeaver/cloudbeaver/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/dbeaver/cloudbeaver/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:09:26 GMT</pubDate><category>Cloud</category><category>Tools-Utilities</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>zwavejs2mqtt (zwavejs/zwavejs2mqtt)</title><description>Fully configurable Zwave to MQTT Gateway and Control Panel</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/zwavejs/zwavejs2mqtt</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/zwavejs/zwavejs2mqtt</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 08:44:42 GMT</pubDate><category>HomeAutomation</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>Verdaccio (verdaccio/verdaccio)</title><description>Verdaccio is a simple, zero-config-required local private NPM registry. No need for an entire database just to get started. Verdaccio comes out of the box with its own tiny database, and the ability to proxy other registries (eg. npmjs.org), also introduces caching the downloaded modules along the way. For those who are looking to extend their storage capabilities, Verdaccio supports various community-made plugins to hook into services such as Amazon's S3, Google Cloud Storage or create your own plugin.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/verdaccio/verdaccio/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/verdaccio/verdaccio/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 07:45:58 GMT</pubDate><category>Tools-Utilities</category><category>Productivity</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>Sourcegraph (sourcegraph/server:3.10.0)</title><description>Sourcegraph docker image.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/sourcegraph/server/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/sourcegraph/server/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 06:12:24 GMT</pubDate><category>Backup</category><category>Cloud</category><category>Network-Web</category><category>Productivity</category><category>Tools-Utilities</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>jitsi-jvb (jitsi/jvb:latest)</title><description>Jitsi Videobridge image for Jitsi Meet</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/jvb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/jvb/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 05:14:42 GMT</pubDate><category>Productivity</category><category>Network-Voip</category><category>Network-Messenger</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>jitsi-jicofo (jitsi/jicofo:latest)</title><description>Jicofo image for Jitsi Meet</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/jicofo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/jicofo/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 05:14:25 GMT</pubDate><category>Productivity</category><category>Network-Voip</category><category>Network-Messenger</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>jitsi-prosody (jitsi/prosody:latest)</title><description>Prosody image for Jitsi Meet</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/prosody/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/prosody/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 05:12:29 GMT</pubDate><category>Productivity</category><category>Network-Voip</category><category>Network-Messenger</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>jitsi-web (jitsi/web:latest)</title><description>Jitsi Meet's web interface image</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/web/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/jitsi/web/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 05:11:33 GMT</pubDate><category>Productivity</category><category>Network-Voip</category><category>Network-Messenger</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>binhex-official-pihole (pihole/pihole)</title><description>Pi-hole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application which acts as a DNS sinkhole and optionally a DHCP server, intended for use on a private network. It is designed for low-power embedded devices with network capability, such as the Raspberry Pi, but can be installed on almost any Linux machine. Pi-hole has the ability to block traditional website advertisements as well as advertisements in unconventional places, such as smart TVs and mobile operating system advertisements.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/pihole/pihole</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/pihole/pihole</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 05:02:39 GMT</pubDate><category>Network-Other</category><category>Other</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>Gitea (gitea/gitea)</title><description>Gitea: Git with a cup of tea - The goal of this project is to make the easiest, fastest, and most painless way of setting up a self-hosted Git service. Using Go, this can be done with an independent binary distribution across all platforms which Go supports, including Linux, macOS, and Windows on x86, amd64, ARM and PowerPC architectures. Want to try it before doing anything else? Do it with the online demo! This project has been forked from Gogs.</description><link>https://registry.hub.docker.com/r/gitea/gitea/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://registry.hub.docker.com/r/gitea/gitea/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 04:36:48 GMT</pubDate><category>Backup</category><category>Cloud</category><category>Productivity</category><category>Tools-Utilities</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>traccar (traccar/traccar)</title><description>Traccar is an open source GPS tracking system. This repository contains Java-based back-end service. It supports more than 170 GPS protocols and more than 1500 models of GPS tracking devices. Traccar can be used with any major SQL database system. It also provides easy to use REST API.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Link to traccar.xml: https://raw.githubusercontent.com/traccar/traccar/master/setup/traccar.xml&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;[b]Add it to your host path before starting the container. [b]</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/traccar/traccar/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/traccar/traccar/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 04:30:32 GMT</pubDate><category>MediaApp-Other</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>Draw.io (jgraph/drawio)</title><description>A lightweight diagram drawing application</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/jgraph/drawio</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/jgraph/drawio</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 04:22:07 GMT</pubDate><category>Productivity</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>cura (lscr.io/linuxserver/cura)</title><description>UltiMaker Cura(https://ultimaker.com/software/ultimaker-cura/) is free, easy-to-use 3D printing software trusted by millions of users. Fine-tune your 3D model with 400+ settings for the best slicing and printing results.</description><link>https://github.com/orgs/linuxserver/packages/container/package/cura</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/orgs/linuxserver/packages/container/package/cura</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 04:11:47 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>goaccess (allinurl/goaccess)</title><description>GoAccess is a real-time web log analyzer and interactive viewer that runs in a terminal in *nix systems or through your browser.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/allinurl/goaccess/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/allinurl/goaccess/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 02:54:58 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>invoiceninja-v5 (maihai/invoiceninja_v5)</title><description>Invoice Ninja v5: an open-source invoicing and time-tracking app built with Laravel https://www.invoiceninja.com.&lt;br&gt;    This container requires a separate MySQL running container and the credentials passed via DB_* variables below.&lt;br&gt;    SSL certificates are generated automatically and stored in certs/ folder in Storage as invoiceninja.crt and invoiceninja.key. Feel free to overwrite this files with others, if you use LetsEncrypt for example.&lt;br&gt;    When migrating for v4 to v5 please follow this tutorial: https://github.com/kiwimato/invoiceninja_v5#upgrade-from-v4-to-v5</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/maihai/invoiceninja_v5</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/maihai/invoiceninja_v5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 02:37:41 GMT</pubDate><category>Productivity</category><category>Tools-Utilities</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>Ryot (ignisda/ryot:latest)</title><description>A self-hosted platform for tracking various facets of your life - media, fitness etc.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/ignisda/ryot</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/ignisda/ryot</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 02:27:49 GMT</pubDate><category>MediaServer-Other</category><category>Productivity</category><category>Tools-Utilities</category><category>Other</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>FDM-Monster (fdmmonster/fdm-monster:latest)</title><description>3D printer farm management platform for local or in-cloud usage using OctoPrint.</description><link>https://hub.docker.com/r/fdmmonster/fdm-monster/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://hub.docker.com/r/fdmmonster/fdm-monster/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:51:59 GMT</pubDate><category>Tools-Utilities</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>nicotine-plus (ghcr.io/fletchto99/nicotine-plus-docker:latest)</title><description>Nicotine plus running in KasmVNC based off of linuxserver's KASMVNC docker image.</description><link>https://github.com/fletchto99/nicotine-plus-docker/pkgs/container/nicotine-plus-docker</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://github.com/fletchto99/nicotine-plus-docker/pkgs/container/nicotine-plus-docker</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:06:03 GMT</pubDate><category>Downloaders</category><route><provider_id>unraid</provider_id><provider_name>Unraid</provider_name><route_path>/community-apps</route_path><route_name>Community Apps</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.12</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug introduced in 3.11 that could cause WizFile to display a blank form when configured to start with Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Korean translation updated&lt;/li&gt;
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.12 </guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.11</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Improved threading when in non Admin mode and when scanning non NTFS drives/network drives/folders,
       resulting in more than 4x faster scanning of SSD drives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed some memory leaks that might occur when rescanning or changing drives that could lead to
       WizFile hanging or crashing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved stability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved handling of multiple monitors with mixed DPI settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Licensing has changed. Commercial users will now purchase licenses based on their business size.
       These licenses will be valid for all versions of WizTree released within one year of purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
       Previously purchased licenses will be automatically converted to "lifetime" licenses which will be valid for all future versions of WizFile

</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.11 </guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.10</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Added global "include" and "exclude" filters - go to Options-&amp;gt;Filters to configure them.&lt;br&gt;
       The "Include Filter" is applied to all searches automatically, as if it had already been typed into the search field.&lt;br&gt;
       The "Exclude Filter" will automatically exclude any matching items from the search results. It is also applied during
       the initial scanning process. This can greatly speed up scans by preventing certain folders from being scanned at all,
       and can also greatly reduce memory use.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       For example, if you use Synology NAS, you can get WizFile to ignore snapshot and recycle folders by setting the
       "exclude filter" to:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;#snapshot|#recycle|@recycle&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       Note that there should not be any spaces between the vertical pipes (vertical pipes are
       interpreted as "OR" and spaces interpreted as "AND"). The example above will exclude any file or folder name that
       contains "#snapshot" OR "#recycle" OR "@recycle".&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       Another example:&lt;br&gt;
       To exclude the "C:\Windows\WinSxS" and "C:\Program Files" folders from being scanned, you would set the exclude
       filter to &lt;br&gt;
	   &lt;samp&gt;C:\Windows\WinSxS\|"C:\Program Files\"&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       Note that double quotes are required around filter items that contain spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI tweaked to look like Windows 11 style. To use WizFile classic theme edit the WizFile.ini file (located in %appdata%\WizFile\WizFile.ini or exe folder for portable) and set:
       &lt;samp&gt;UseWizFileClassicTheme=1&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed rare bug that might cause some folders not to be detected by WizFile when parsing MFT file due to unusual MFT record ordering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unicode characters were not being saved to search drop down history correctly - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emojis were not being displayed correctly in file search and filter fields - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When configured to start with Windows, WizFile will now pause for 60 seconds before starting.
       This it to allow time for virtual drive letters to become available (like Google Drive G:), and to not slow down
       other important startup tasks due to disk scanning.
       If WizFile is already configured to start with Windows and you want to enable this delay, toggle the
       Options-&amp;gt;Start With Windows option off and back on.
       You can edit the delay time by editing the Action in Windows Task Scheduler for the "WizFile" item and changing the
       value in the /delaysecs=xx parameter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WizFile can now be configured to not run as admin - to do this, edit the WizFile.ini file
       (located in %appdata%\WizFile\WizFile.ini or exe folder for portable) and set&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;RunAsAdmin=FALSE&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new Indonesian translation (thanks to Marcellinus Ferdinand Suciadi)&lt;/li&gt;

</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.10 </guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.09</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Regular Expression search added. To perform a regex search, type in a forward slash followed immediately by the regex, e.g.:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;/[0-9]{4}-[0-9]{2}-[0-9]\.csv$&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       If the regex contains spaces, enclose it in double quotes, like this:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;/"[0-9]{4} [0-9]{2} [0-9]\.csv$"&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for DrivePool, Storage Spaces and other similar "virtual" drives added (WizFile would crash or stop working when scanning these types of drive before)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed highlighted text display bug that could occur with certain searches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wildcard search for file extensions was not working correctly when "match entire path" option was used - fixed&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. searching for *.c would include files including ".c" anywhere in the file name, which would include *.cpp or *.c.bak files too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor interface tweaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Czech translation added (thanks to DrTactless)&lt;/li&gt;
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.09 </guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.08</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Search history drop down added to file search. Press down arrow key in search field to display search history items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files with very long file names were not being handled correctly - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date filtering (=today) not working correctly in some time zones - (fixed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Path copy function will now not include a trailing carriage return when only a single file is selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Korean translation updated&lt;/li&gt;
	 
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.08 </guid><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.07</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Explorer windows opened with "explore location" or double clicking on path will now always open on top and become active.
       Previously they may have opened behind other windows and flashed on the task bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Form would not be restored to correct position if taskbar was not positioned at bottom of screen - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark mode hint color was wrong - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hint font size will now also match file list font size if zoomed in or out with Ctrl+MouseWheel&lt;/li&gt;
	 
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.07 </guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.06</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Hovering over a file will now display full path name in status bar at bottom of screen as well as display
       the full name as a tooltip hint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added new "folders" checkbox to make it easy to toggle folders on or off in the search results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context menu when renaming a file did not close the first time after making a selection - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom filter items for 3rd filter box were not being saved correctly - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dragging/dropping files with names containing non ASCII characters would fail - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
	 
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.06 </guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.05</title><description>&lt;li&gt;file name search will now ignore character accents (like é and ö) when searching.&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. searching for "melee" will now correctly match file names containing "mêlée" or "MÊLÉE"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new file length and path length search terms added:&lt;br&gt;
       Use namelen and pathlen to search by file name and path length&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. to find files with path length greater than 255:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;pathlen&amp;gt;255&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       to find file names with exactly 1 character:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;namelen=1&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not (!) operator was not working correctly when followed by quoted search text - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some results were not being included when using "?" wildcard and searching entire path - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File search box and highlighted text were not handling right to left languages like Arabic correctly - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Window animations settings could be reset when WizFile was running full screen - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WizFile will now handle screens with very high DPI (scaling &amp;gt;=200%) correctly. Previously title bar icons were too small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light mode header colors were incorrect on Xp/2003 with themes disabled - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Explore folder" and "command prompt here" functions were not working on older versions of Windows if "launch applications as administrator" option was not enabled (XP/2003) - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WizFile would not start minimized on older versions of Windows (pre Vista). Toggle "start with windows" off and on again to fix.&lt;/li&gt;
	 
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.05 </guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.04</title><description>&lt;li&gt;New "Folders" filter option added to "TYPES" filter dropdown.&lt;br&gt;
       Type in "=folder" or "=folders" in search to display folders only.&lt;br&gt;
       Type in "=file" or = "files" in search to display files only.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Improved stability&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Updated GUI and various cosmetic changes&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Hold down CTRL key and use mousewheel to increase/decrease the search results font size&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Fixed threading issue that might cause WizFile to hang during high file activity or when rescanning drives&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where cluster size may have been incorrect leading to incorrect "allocated size" calculations&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;filtering for files with no extension now possible using "*." filter&lt;/li&gt;
	 
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.04 </guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.03</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Fixed "dark" UI style issues on high DPI screens (some screen elements were not being rendered correctly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinese (Traditional) installer was using incorrect translation language files - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor cosmetic changes&lt;/li&gt;
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.03 </guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.02</title><description>&lt;li&gt;Minimum form size constraints were being ignored so form could be resized too small to be usable - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.02 </guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.01</title><description>&lt;li&gt;WizFile was ignoring the "check for updates" option and checking for updates each time it started - fixed&lt;/li&gt;
</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.01 </guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>WizFile 3.00</title><description>&lt;li&gt;added &lt;b&gt;2 new predefined filter dropdowns&lt;/b&gt; - one for size and one for file modified date. These can be customised by the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added &lt;b&gt;file size, allocated size and modified date&lt;/b&gt; filter support.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       Use operators "=", "&amp;gt;", "&amp;gt;=", "&amp;lt;", "&amp;lt;=" to filter files based on size or modified date. NB: Don't put any spaces between operators and values!&lt;br&gt;

       e.g. to find files less than 100 bytes in size:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;lt;100&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       Append a 'k', 'm', 'g', or 't' to the number to search in Kb, Mb, Gb, Tb&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. to find files between 500MB and 1Gb:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;gt;=500m &amp;lt;=1g&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       'kb', 'mb', 'gb', 'tb' can also be used, e.g.:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;gt;=500mb &amp;lt;=1gb&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       To filter by "allocated" size, use "a=", "a&amp;gt;", etc.&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. To find files with allocated size between 100MB and 200MB:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;a&amp;gt;=100m a&amp;lt;=200m&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
	   
       e.g. to find files with 0 allocated size and greater than zero file size:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;a=0 &amp;gt;0&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       To filter by date, specify a date in the format: yyyy/mm/dd&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. Filter files modified before 2020/01/01:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;lt;2020/01/01&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       Use the constant "today" to reference today's date. Optionally add or subtract a number of days from this constant.&lt;br&gt;

       e.g. to find files modified in the last 7 days:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;gt;=today-7&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       e.g. to find all files larger than 1gb that were modified in the last month (last 30 days):&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;gt;=1gb &amp;gt;=today-30&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

       Place the search item in quotes to force a file name search.&lt;br&gt;
	   e.g. to find file names that contain "=0" instead of displaying files with zero size:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;"=0"&lt;/samp&gt;
	  &lt;/li&gt;

     &lt;li&gt;new &lt;b&gt;"not" operator&lt;/b&gt;. Start the search expression with an exclamation mark (!) to find files that don't match the expression.&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. to find files that don't contain "windows":&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;!windows&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. to find all files that contain "music" but are not of type mp3:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;music !*.mp3&lt;/samp&gt;&lt;br&gt;
       e.g. to find files that are between 1 and 100 bytes in size, but not 50:&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;samp&gt;&amp;gt;=1 &amp;lt;=100 !=50&lt;/samp&gt;
	  &lt;/li&gt;

     &lt;li&gt;new &lt;b&gt;"Launch applications as administrator"&lt;/b&gt; option (off by default).&lt;br&gt;
	   If enabled, any applications launched by WizFile will have administrator rights (this was the default for previous versions
       of WizFile as WizFile always runs as administrator). It's recommended that this option be left off. This also helps Wizfile work better with applications already running non elevated (without administrator rights).&lt;br&gt;
       For example, context menu items like "Add to Windows Media Player list" would not work previously if Windows Media Player has already been launched in non elevated mode (a "Server execution failed" error would have occurred).&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;b&gt;Windows Dark Mode&lt;/b&gt;. UI Theme can be set via new "UI Theme" menu option.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Windows Explorer integration&lt;/b&gt; added. Will be on by default if using the non portable version.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;New &lt;b&gt;"Clear and Reset Filters"&lt;/b&gt; option added (Shift+F6). Clears and resets filters. Hold shift key when clicking on 'Clear' button to reset filters when clearning search results.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;file search speed increased&lt;/b&gt; significantly&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Minimising WizFile will now minimize to task bar instead of tray&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Fixed some MFT decoding bugs which could have caused crashes on some PCs&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Added &lt;b&gt;global hotkey Ctrl+Win+W&lt;/b&gt; to bring WizFile to the foreground if it's active&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;Stability improvements&lt;/li&gt;

</description><link /><guid isPermaLink="false">https://antibody-software.com/wizfile/downloadWizFile 3.00 </guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>wizfile</provider_id><provider_name>WziFile</provider_name><route_path>/updates</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.15 (March 16, 2025)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed large/slow file downloads timing out after 30 seconds (since 7.0.14)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7015_march_16_2025</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7015_march_16_2025</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.14 (March 13, 2025)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit4" id="functionality_changed_or_added"&gt;Functionality changed or added&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added hidden preference &lt;code&gt;extensions.zotero.naturalSorting&lt;/code&gt; to disable natural sorting (“Collection 2” &amp;lt; “Collection 10”)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit5" id="bugs_fixed"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed slow performance at startup in some large databases&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Could result in being stuck on “Loading items…”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed file downloads via authenticated proxies (since 7.0)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed broken reader toolbar after converting between highlight and underline annotations&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed ink eraser not working&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed page number editing in annotation widget&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed annotation not updating when dropped on color/tag in the sidebar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Prevent &lt;abbr title="Domain Name System"&gt;DNS&lt;/abbr&gt;/TCP connections for links in snapshots (due to Firefox prefetch behavior)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed handling of nested &lt;abbr title="HyperText Markup Language"&gt;HTML&lt;/abbr&gt; tags in tab titles&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed red background on search condition tooltip in Advanced Search window&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed edited item fields showing trailing whitespace until refresh&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7014_march_13_2025</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7014_march_13_2025</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.13 (February 21, 2025)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed PDF blurriness at some zoom levels (since 7.0.12)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Fixed “Add Note” removing citations from document when table of contents is present&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7013_february_21_2025</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7013_february_21_2025</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.12 (February 19, 2025)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit8" id="functionality_added_or_changed"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added undo/redo support in reader (e.g., Cmd/Ctrl-Z after deleting annotation)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved performance while downloading large files on some internet connections&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Smoother zooming in PDF reader&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Better handle malformed URLs in WebDAV settings&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Automatically reset file sync history when changing WebDAV &lt;abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator"&gt;URL&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Show the recognized item's title in metadata-retrieval progress window&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't open multiple copies of Translator Editor, Style Editor, and Run JavaScript&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit9" id="bugs_fixed1"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed ScienceDirect CAPTCHA not being shown for PDF downloads after site update&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed potential sync error downloading items with “Type:” in Extra&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed a bug where some files might not be downloaded at sync time after using Reset File Sync History&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed sync error if local child item was added to a parent item while the remote child item was added to collection&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “Add” button in Attachments section of reader item pane depending on editability of current view in library tab&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed potential opening of wrong Firefox profile when launching URLs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed second child linked PDF incorrectly being titled “PDF”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed handling of OpenURL base URLs containing login URLs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed reopening of duplicated closed tab&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “Show Item in Library” in sync error popup not showing child item in trash&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed failure to export some annotated PDFs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed entered tag not being saved if clicking directly to another item&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved support for vertical text in EPUBs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed navigation when clicking some outline entries&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed some text not being copied when selection spans two pages&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't zoom page when pressing modifier key during inertial trackpad scrolling&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Note editor fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed text of search result not being visible in dark mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed freeze/crash using non-Latin input method in math node&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Don't close citation-details popup when pressing up-arrow on closed locator menu&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Trigger document refresh when changing styles with “Automatically update citations” disabled&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Mendeley import improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Made the annotations importer more resilient to missing data&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed notebooks not being imported in some cases&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed excessive memory usage during some imports&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't show button to change creator field mode in feed items&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed attachment preview potentially showing the wrong item when quickly switching between attachments&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added missing shortcut key to Advanced Search menu item&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7012_february_19_2025</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7012_february_19_2025</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.11 (December 6, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit11" id="functionality_added_or_changed1"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Highlight the current outline entry being read for PDFs/EPUBs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added Timestamp to locator list in citation dialog&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reduced memory usage when loading or searching PDF pages&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit12" id="bugs_fixed2"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “Any Field” advanced search condition (since 7.0.10)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed custom Info fields created by plugins not refreshing when moving between items&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed failure loading APA feed&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed failure to automatically relink files on Windows (since 7.0)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Abstract field getting overwritten if active when adding new item&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7011_december_6_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7011_december_6_2024</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.10 (November 26, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit14" id="functionality_added_or_changed2"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Import Calibre and KOReader EPUB annotations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Import notes from Mendeley “Notebook” feature&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Wrap all long fields in the Info pane&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Increased width of search bar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Added option to prevent note, text, and image annotation tools from automatically turning off after use&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Available in Reader section of settings&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Can be set for individual tools via Config Editor (&lt;code&gt;reader.autoDisableTool.*&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Image annotation tool now turns off after use by default&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Added basic image zoom feature for EPUBs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Select next duplicate set when using up/down-arrow in Duplicate Items view&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Option/Alt-click can be used to select a single item&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added File, Edit, and Window menus to note editor window&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved detection of creators in some Atom feeds&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Updated ISBN detection to handle new ISBN ranges&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed packaging issue that caused Tenable (and potentially other security software) to block Zotero&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Accessibility] Make side navigation bar (including Locate menu) keyboard accessible (&lt;a href="https://forums.zotero.org/discussion/comment/479293/#Comment_479293" class="urlextern" title="https://forums.zotero.org/discussion/comment/479293/#Comment_479293" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit15" id="bugs_fixed3"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed ink eraser tool erasing from all pages&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed DOI detection not including last character of DOI&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't block page rendering when search is in progress&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed bold/italic toggling via keyboard when no text is selected in annotation comment/text fields&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed tab title format not changing for unloaded tabs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't show '0000' on invalid date in tab title&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Tab key in reader window changing focus in main window&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed printed EPUBs/snapshots including “Zotero” and “about:srcdoc” in page header&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed failing file sync requests until Zotero restart after unlinking and relinking account&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed potential display issues in locator drop-down in citation dialog&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Restored list of recently modified notes when using Add Note feature in word processor plugin&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed advanced searches using “Any Field” condition not returning results when using “any” matching mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed duplicate item pane when switching to library tab before reader is loaded&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Prevent plugins that modify the items list from breaking loading of items&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't clear search bar if matching item is changed to no longer match search (e.g., removal from collection or field change)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Allow main window to be reopened after closing if other windows are open&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Fixed wrong context menu showing for two-finger taps (since 7.0.8)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Add button in Libraries and Collections pane in reader tabs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed updating of Attachments section after a child attachment is moved to or restored from trash&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed swapped icons for changing creator field mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed handling of feeds with invalid &lt;code&gt;Content-Type&lt;/code&gt; header&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed dark mode getting reset during printing&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't detect MP3 with embedded image as JPEG&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit16" id="developer-specific_changes"&gt;Developer-specific changes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added &lt;abbr title="Application Programming Interface"&gt;API&lt;/abbr&gt; for plugins to create custom info pane rows (&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/zotero-dev/c/LlIz_maLBCU/m/oydLxsIeCwAJ" class="urlextern" title="https://groups.google.com/g/zotero-dev/c/LlIz_maLBCU/m/oydLxsIeCwAJ" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7010_november_26_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_7010_november_26_2024</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.9 (October 30, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit18" id="functionality_added_or_changed3"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Added “Search Outline” feature in sidebar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Don't switch to Annotations tab when clicking annotation with sidebar opened to another tab&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added View → Columns and View → Sort By to all windows&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added Move Column Left menu option in View → Columns as alternative to drag-and-drop column reordering&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Match annotation text and comments in All Fields &amp;amp; Tags quick-search mode rather than Everything mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit19" id="bugs_fixed4"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed CAPTCHA not appearing for ScienceDirect downloads&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Avoid permissions prompt when inserting rich text into Word document on Sequoia&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Fixed swapped “Highlight” and “Underline” tooltips in toolbar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Fixed empty comment not being focused when annotation is clicked&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Add button in Libraries and Collections section&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Libraries and Collection section sometimes not showing entries from other libraries&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed vertically misaligned page in document preview&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes and accessibility improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_709_october_30_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_709_october_30_2024</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.8 (October 18, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit21" id="functionality_added_or_changed4"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added “Move To” and “Copy To” context-menu options as equivalents to collection drag-and-drop&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; “Copy To” can also be used to duplicate collections within the same library&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added “Change Parent Item…” context-menu option as equivalent to attachment/note drag-and-drop&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Support Ctrl-Enter context-menu shortcut on macOS Sequoia&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Added “Copy Link” option to link context menu&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Text annotation font size can now be adjusted by slider in context menu or Shift-Up/Down-Arrow&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Added audible instructions for reader keyboard interaction (new in 7.0.7) when using a screen reader&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; “Rename File from Parent Metadata” now adds a file extension if one is missing for known file types&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit22" id="bugs_fixed5"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed additional causes of reboot loops on installation/upgrade&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Fixed faint highlighting of “Find in Document” matches&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Fixed display of Word plugin installation banner on macOS Sequoia 15.0 (before 15.0.1)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed failure to add certain feeds&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed scrolling in collections pane while holding Ctrl on Windows/Linux&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed renaming behavior for attachments without file extension&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed item pane width changing when switching between items in Stacked mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Fixed arrow keys unexpectedly escaping text and comment inputs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader: Fixed annotations colors not being accessible via keyboard&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed tag autocomplete suggestions sometimes being hidden when viewing a document in a separate window&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Allow EPUBs saved from the web to be dragged out of parent&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes and accessibility improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit23" id="developer-specific_changesfixes"&gt;Developer-specific changes/fixes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Scaffold: Run ESLint continuously, not just after save&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other Scaffold improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_708_october_18_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_708_october_18_2024</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.7 (October 2, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit25" id="functionality_added_or_changed5"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Full keyboard accessibility in PDF reader&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://github.com/zotero/reader/commit/2b81632b5b3b1c916c35c77ec86cce33b98524fc" class="urlextern" title="https://github.com/zotero/reader/commit/2b81632b5b3b1c916c35c77ec86cce33b98524fc" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;; additional documentation to come)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Allows all possible operations, including highlight/underline creation and resizing, to be done via the keyboard&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Coming to EPUBs/snapshots in a future version&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Automatically switch in and out of Stacked layout when resizing window horizontally&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Ink annotation merging&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added labeled Title field in attachment box (in addition to Title header at top)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Add new creator in middle of creator list using Shift-Enter/Shift-Return&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Keep dark margins when disabling “Use Dark Mode for Content”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit26" id="bugs_fixed6"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed potential reboot loop on installation/upgrade in non-admin accounts&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed potential stall on “Loading items…” at startup due to invalid character in tab title&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Fixed potential delay in opening citation dialog from Word&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “Some data in My Library could not be downloaded” sync error after moving saved search to trash&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed zoom potentially getting stuck after scrolling in reader&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed phrase search in “Everything” mode within collection matching entire library&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed potential error when auto-relinking files&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Prioritize DOI over child attachment &lt;abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator"&gt;URL&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed some snapshot annotations jumping to wrong position&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed formatting bugs when printing PDFs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes and accessibility improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_707_october_2_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_707_october_2_2024</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.6 (September 16, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Zotero for Mac only&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Show banner to trigger Word plugin installation on macOS Sequoia, which requires system permissions prompt (“Zotero.app would like to access data from other apps”)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_706_september_16_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_706_september_16_2024</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.5 (September 11, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “Localized string not available for general.warning” startup error instead of proper warning if data directory is &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/kb/data_directory_in_cloud_storage_folder" class="wikilink1" title="kb:data_directory_in_cloud_storage_folder" data-wiki-id="kb:data_directory_in_cloud_storage_folder"&gt;in cloud storage folder&lt;/a&gt; (since 7.0.4)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_705_september_11_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_705_september_11_2024</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.4 (September 11, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit30" id="functionality_added_or_changed6"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Allow attachment preview to use the available screen height at wider pane sizes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Wrap attachment filename field in item pane&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Speed up exports of files that don't contain annotations&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added “Paste and Search” option to Add Item by Identifier context menu&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed potential cause of repeated reboot prompt on upgrade from non-administrator account&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't show rich-text markup in reader window titles&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Show status line in settings when external app access is enabled&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit31" id="bugs_fixed7"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed problems transferring documents into and out of LibreOffice&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed citation dialog becoming invisible on some monitors&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “module record has unexpected status” startup error&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed attachment preview disappearing unexpectedly&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Reader fixes:&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed &lt;code&gt;zotero://open&lt;/code&gt; navigating one page too far&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; EPUB: Fixed returning to the last-read page&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; EPUB/snapshot: Open popup after adding note&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; PDF: Fixed Cmd/Ctrl-G skipping every second result&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “Add Item by Identifier” textbox not expanding when entering multiple rows&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed scrolling in “Manage Lookup Engines” window with many engines&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_704_september_11_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_704_september_11_2024</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.3 (August 26, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit33" id="functionality_added_or_changed7"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Render &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/kb/rich_text_bibliography" class="wikilink1" title="kb:rich_text_bibliography" data-wiki-id="kb:rich_text_bibliography"&gt;supported rich-text markup&lt;/a&gt; in tab titles&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit34" id="bugs_fixed8"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed LibreOffice installation prompt appearing on systems without LibreOffice&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed “User canceled primary password entry” error when setting up syncing in old Zotero profile&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed “Could not find a running Word instance” error when running Windows using hidden Administrator account (Note: Running Windows with the hidden Administrator account is unsafe!)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed incorrect message when existing files can't be deleted during uninstallation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed font size in feed item abstracts&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Progress bar didn't follow color scheme&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit35" id="developer-specific_changesfixes1"&gt;Developer-specific changes/fixes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed locale detection for plugins with locales that don't exactly match Zotero locales&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_703_august_26_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_703_august_26_2024</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.2 (August 20, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit37" id="functionality_added_or_changed8"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Word processor plugin installation improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Word for Windows plugin installation not running at startup&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Show warning if word processor plugin can't be automatically installed or updated at startup (e.g., because Word is open)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Don't show progress window at startup on repeated installation attempts&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed Mendeley attachment import (since 7.0)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improve startup performance with many tabs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Increased line height of Abstract field&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit38" id="bugs_fixed9"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed error viewing trash containing collection when using “Enable bidirectional text editing utilities”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed reversed order of tag colors in items list&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed reader item pane not opening in Stacked mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_702_august_20_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_702_august_20_2024</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0.1 (August 15, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit40" id="functionality_added_or_changed9"&gt;Functionality added or changed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Windows installer improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added option to resolve a permanent reboot prompt when previous installation couldn't be deleted&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Show an appropriate error when trying to install the ARM version on a non-ARM system or the x64 version on a 32-bit system&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Warn when trying to install the x64 version on an ARM system&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Show a clearer error message with documentation link when Zotero can't find a running Word instance&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Enable auto-scroll by default on Linux (configurable via &lt;code&gt;general.autoScroll&lt;/code&gt; hidden pref)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved handling of bidirectional text&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Guess item field direction based on the field itself, the item's language field, and the app locale&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Requires “Enable bidirectional text editing utilities” to be checked in the Advanced pane of the Zotero settings&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit41" id="bugs_fixed10"&gt;Bugs fixed&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed startup error for libraries containing items with DOIs containing certain character sequences&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Removed erroneous horizontal scrollbar in item pane&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed collection name text field closing if editing name during sync&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed two item panes occasionally appearing at the same time&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed item pane notes section not updating after adding note&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed context menu (with Cut/Copy/Paste) not appearing when right-clicking in Add Attachment → Web Link text field&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed blurry creator row buttons on non-HiDPI displays&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed certain wizards (e.g., File → Import) sometimes starting with the wrong title&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Miscellaneous other bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit42" id="developer-specific_changesfixes2"&gt;Developer-specific changes/fixes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fix Debugger tab of Browser Toolbox not showing Zotero sources when passing &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;build_and_run&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_701_august_15_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_701_august_15_2024</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Changes in 7.0 (August 9, 2024)</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;See the &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/blog/zotero-7" class="wikilink1" title="/blog/zotero-7"&gt;Zotero 7 announcement&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Major app redesign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; A beautiful, modern design&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Dark mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Redesigned item pane with collapsible vertical sections and side navigation bar&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Customizable item pane header (Title, Title/Creator/Year, Bibliography Entry)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Two density options: Compact and Comfortable&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; New app icon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Much faster performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Improved reader&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Faster PDF handling&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Support for opening and annotating EPUBs and webpage snapshots&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Support for creating ink, underline, and text annotations&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Hovering over a citation or internal link now opens a popup showing the associated reference or figure&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Annotations can now be resized&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Support for highlight and underline annotations spanning two pages&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Basic table-of-contents extraction for Document Outline tab&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Full functionality is now available in both panes when splitting view&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved compatibility with a wide range of PDFs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Native support for Apple Silicon Macs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;64-bit Windows support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Better handling of large libraries and files&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Windows users should reinstall 64-bit Zotero from the &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/download/" class="urlextern" title="https://www.zotero.org/download/" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt; — existing data won't be affected&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Windows on ARM support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Faster performance on ARM PCs, including Copilot+ PCs, as well as when running Windows 11 in a virtual machine on an Apple Silicon Mac&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Improved accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Greater support for screen readers&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improvements to keyboard navigation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Faster citing of selected and open items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; The citation dialog now automatically suggests items selected in Zotero as well as any open items in the built-in reader&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Can be used as a replacement for the “classic” citation dialog — select an item in Zotero, click Add/Edit Citation, and press Enter/Return&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Restoring of deleted collections and searches from trash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Collection search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Open-tabs menu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Shows a list of all open tabs, with tab search and fast tab closing/reordering&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Attachment previews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; For PDFs, EPUBs, webpage snapshots, and images&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Libraries and Collections list&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; New item pane section lists libraries and collections an item is in&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; An alternative to the &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/kb/collections_containing_an_item" class="wikilink1" title="kb:collections_containing_an_item" data-wiki-id="kb:collections_containing_an_item"&gt;modifier key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Customizable file renaming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Files can now be renamed according to a &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/file_renaming" class="wikilink1" title="file_renaming" data-wiki-id="file_renaming"&gt;much wider array of options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added setting to configure which file types should be automatically renamed&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved plugin architecture&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Restartless loading/unloading&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Built-in support for common integration points (items-list columns, item-pane sections, settings panes, etc.) for increased stability&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; All existing plugins must be updated for Zotero 7&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Better &lt;abbr title="Operating System"&gt;OS&lt;/abbr&gt; compatibility&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Follow system dark mode&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Use system font on macOS&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Use Wayland on Linux if available&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Better compatibility with various Linux desktop environments&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/file_renaming#attachment_title_vs_filename" class="wikilink1" title="file_renaming" data-wiki-id="file_renaming"&gt;Attachment titles&lt;/a&gt; are no longer changed to match the filename when manually renaming files from parent metadata&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved RTL/bidirectional-text support&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Redesigned settings window with full-text/keyword search&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Retrieve Metadata now works on EPUBs as well as PDFs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Emoji tags are now displayed in the items list even when not associated with a color&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added setting to open files in windows instead of tabs&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added column picker to Advanced Search window&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added “Add to Dictionary” option in note editor&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added “Fix Case” text transform to creator context menu for all-uppercase/lowercase names&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added ability to copy &lt;abbr title="Uniform Resource Locator"&gt;URL&lt;/abbr&gt; of snapshot/link in attachment item pane&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Smarter sentence-casing of titles from item pane (ignore acronyms, mixed case, etc.)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; When importing files, import into current collection if not creating a new collection&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved downloading of files from ScienceDirect&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Zotero will show a CAPTCHA window during a download if necessary&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Fixed Word integration when storing documents in OneDrive&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Feed reader improvements&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; “Feeds” header is now a selectable global view of feed items&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Support rich-text/graphical abstracts&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Support additional metadata fields in some feeds&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1 node"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Added Help → “Restart in Troubleshooting Mode…” for easier troubleshooting&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level2"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Temporarily disables all plugins&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Mac] Fixed a bug that could cause the Zotero Connector for Safari to stop working after an app update&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; [Windows] Version number in “Add or remove programs” is now updated on app update&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; PDF indexing no longer requires external executables (pdfinfo/pdftotext)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Removed “Create Timeline” feature&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Fixed rendering problem that could cause black quarter-circles to appear in PDFs on some systems&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Many additional improvements and bug fixes&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 class="sectionedit44" id="developer-specific_changesfixes3"&gt;Developer-specific changes/fixes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="level3"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
For Zotero core and plugin development, see &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/dev/zotero_7_for_developers" class="urlextern" title="https://www.zotero.org/support/dev/zotero_7_for_developers" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;Zotero 7 for Developers&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Also:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Local HTTP &lt;abbr title="Application Programming Interface"&gt;API&lt;/abbr&gt; for accessing Zotero data&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/zotero-dev/c/ElvHhIFAXrY/m/fA7SKKwsAgAJ" class="urlextern" title="https://groups.google.com/g/zotero-dev/c/ElvHhIFAXrY/m/fA7SKKwsAgAJ" rel="ugc nofollow"&gt;details&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Much simpler &lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/dev/client_coding/building_the_desktop_app" class="wikilink1" title="dev:client_coding:building_the_desktop_app" data-wiki-id="dev:client_coding:building_the_desktop_app"&gt;build process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved code editor in Style Editor with inline CSL validation&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Improved code editor in Translator Editor within built-in linting&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="level1"&gt;&lt;div class="li"&gt; Automatically load last-opened translator when opening Translator Editor&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_70_august_9_2024</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#changes_in_70_august_9_2024</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item><item><title>Older Changes</title><description>&lt;div class="level2"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/support/6.0_changelog" class="wikilink1" title="6.0_changelog" data-wiki-id="6.0_changelog"&gt;View the 6.0 changelog&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#older_changes</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.zotero.org/support/changelog#older_changes</guid><route><provider_id>zotero</provider_id><provider_name>Zotero</provider_name><route_path>/versions</route_path><route_name>Version History</route_name></route></item></channel></rss>